<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="53424">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02410694</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AGMT_MM-1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02410694</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ixazomib in Combination With Thalidomide - Dexamethasone in Patients With Relapsed and/or Refractory Multiple Myeloma</brief_title>
  <official_title>Ixazomib in Combination With Thalidomide - Dexamethasone in Patients With Relapsed and/or Refractory Multiple Myeloma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Arbeitsgemeinschaft medikamentoese Tumortherapie</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Arbeitsgemeinschaft medikamentoese Tumortherapie</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Overview of Study Design:

      This is an open phase II, single-arm, multi-center study to evaluate progression free
      survival in patients receiving ixazomib in combination with thalidomide and dexamethasone
      (ITD) followed by an ixazomib maintenance phase of a maximum period of 12 months.

      The patient population will consist of adult male and female patients with multiple myeloma
      (MM) with relapsed and/or refractory disease after at least one prior treatment line.

      In case of enrollment patients will receive ixazomib 4.0mg at days 1, 8, 15, thalidomide
      100mg at days 1 to 28 (50mg in patients aged ≥75 years), and dexamethasone 40mg (20mg in
      patients aged ≥75 years) at days 1, 8, 15 of a 28-day treatment cycle. The proposed number
      of cycles is 8. Treatment will be discontinued in case of progressive disease or in case of
      no response after 4 cycles (≤ SD after 4 cycles). After discontinuation of therapy an end of
      treatment visit (EOT) will be performed within 14 days after the last dose of the last
      combination treatment cycle.

      After 8 cycles of ITD therapy, maintenance treatment with 4.0mg ixazomib (3.0mg in patients
      aged ≥ 75 years at first day of maintenance phase) on days 1, 8, 15 of 28-day cycles will be
      administered to patients with ≥ MR for a maximum period of 12 months. Patients who completed
      less than 8 cycles of ITD treatment do not qualify for maintenance phase.

      Follow-up visits will be performed in 3-monthly intervals until the last patient on ixazomib
      maintenance therapy has concluded or discontinued the maintenance phase.

      A safety analysis will be conducted after enrollment of the first 6 patients and completion
      of at least two cycles in every patient.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>start of combination therapy to progressive disease or death due to any cause whichever occurs first, up to 4.5 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Response Rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>best and first response since start of therapy, up to 4,5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>start of therapy to death, up to 4,5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Renal Response in a subgroup of patients with baseline GFR 15-30ml/min</measure>
    <time_frame>start of therapy to best renal response, up to 4,5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determination of safety by reporting of adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>start of therapy to end of study therapy (appr. 2 yrs)</time_frame>
    <description>Reporting of adverse event as a measure of safety and tolerability</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of prognostic values of risk factors at diagnosis incl. clinical assessment and cytogenetic abnormalities</measure>
    <time_frame>screening to end of study (appr. 2 yrs)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation between altered expressions of specifically selected genes and patient´s response to the treatment regimen</measure>
    <time_frame>screening to end of study (appr. 2 yrs)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">77</enrollment>
  <condition>Multiple Myeloma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ixazomib-Thalidomide-Dexamethasone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Combination therapy of:
Ixazomib 4.0mg at days 1, 8, 15, Thalidomide 100mg at days 1 to 28 (50mg in patients aged ≥75 years), Dexamethasone 40mg (20mg in patients aged ≥75 years) at days 1, 8, 15 of a 28-day treatment cycle.
After 8 cycles of ITD therapy, maintenance treatment with 4.0mg ixazomib (3.0mg in patients aged ≥ 75 years at first day of maintenance phase) on days 1, 8, 15 of 28-day cycles will be administered to patients with ≥ MR for a maximum period of 12 months.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ixazomib</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Ixazomib-Thalidomide-Dexamethasone</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Thalidomide</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Ixazomib-Thalidomide-Dexamethasone</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dexamethasone</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Ixazomib-Thalidomide-Dexamethasone</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Male or female patients 18 yrs or older.

          2. Voluntary written consent

          3. Patients in need of therapy with a diagnosis of relapsed or refractory multiple
             myeloma who had at least one prior treatment line

          4. Patients must have measurable disease defined by at least 1 of the following
             criteria:

               -  Serum M-protein ≥ 10g/l

               -  Urine M-protein ≥ 200mg/24h

               -  Serum free light chain assay: involved serum light chain ≥ 10mg/dl provided that
                  free light chain ration is abnormal

          5. Life expectancy &gt; 3 months

          6. ECOG (Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group) ≤ 2

          7. • ANC ≥ 1.000/mm3 and platelet count ≥ 50.000/mm3

               -  Total bilirubin ≤ 2 x ULN

               -  ALT and AST ≤ 3 x ULN

               -  GFR ≥ 15ml/min as calculated by cockroft-Gault equation

          8. Female patients who:

               -  Are older than 50 years and postmenopausal for at least 1 year before the
                  screening visit, OR

               -  Are surgically sterile, OR

               -  If they are of childbearing potential, agree to practice 2 effective methods of
                  contraception at the same time, from 4 weeks before starting study therapy
                  through 90 days after the last dose of study drug, OR

               -  Agree to practice true abstinence when this is in line with the preferred and
                  usual lifestyle of the subject. (Periodic abstinence [e.g., calendar, ovulation,
                  symptothermal, post-ovulation methods] and withdrawal are not acceptable methods
                  of contraception.)

               -  Are informed and understand the possible consequences of the teratogenic
                  potential of thalidomide

               -  Male patients, even if surgically sterilized (i.e., status post-vasectomy), must
                  agree to one of the following:

               -  Agree to practice effective barrier contraception during the entire study
                  treatment period and through 90 days after the last dose of study drug, OR

               -  Agree to practice true abstinence when this is in line with the preferred and
                  usual lifestyle of the subject. (Periodic abstinence (e.g. calendar, ovulation,
                  symptothermal, post-ovulation methods] and withdrawal are not acceptable methods
                  of contraception.)

               -  Are informed and understand the possible consequences of the teratogenic
                  potential of thalidomide

          9. Disease free of prior malignancies for ≥ 2 years with exception of curatively treated
             basal cell, squamous cell carcinoma of the skin, or carcinoma &quot;in situ&quot; of the cervix
             or breast if they have undergone complete resection.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. lactating females or have a positive serum pregnancy test

          2. Failure to have fully recovered (i.e., ≤ Grade 1 toxicity) from the reversible
             effects of prior chemotherapy

          3. Previous treatment with ixazomib

          4. Previous treatment with bortezomib or thalidomide within the last 3 months prior to
             baseline visit

          5. Primary refractory to, or relapsing during, or within ≤ 6 weeks after end of
             treatment with a proteasome inhibitor and/or thalidomide

          6. Previous anti-cancer treatment within the last 21 days prior to baseline visit (cycle
             1 / day 1), except corticosteroid therapy (40 - 160mg dexamethasone or corticosteroid
             dose equivalent per month)

          7. Major surgery within 14 days before enrollment

          8. Radiotherapy within 14 days before enrollment. If the involved field is small, 7 days
             will be considered a sufficient interval between treatment and administration of the
             ixazomib.

          9. Central nervous system involvement

         10. Infection requiring systemic antibiotic therapy or other serious infection within 14
             days before study enrollment

         11. Evidence of current uncontrolled cardiovascular conditions

         12. Systemic treatment, within 14 days before the first dose of ixazomib, with strong
             inhibitors of CYP1A2 (fluvoxamine, enoxacin, ciprofloxacin), strong inhibitors of
             CYP3A (clarithromycin, telithromycin, itraconazole, voriconazole, ketoconazole,
             nefazodone, posaconazole) or strong CYP3A inducers (rifampin, rifapentine, rifabutin,
             carbamazepine, phenytoin, phenobarbital), or use of Ginkgo biloba or St. John's wort

         13. Ongoing or active systemic infection, active hepatitis B or C virus infection, or
             known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) positive

         14. Any serious medical or psychiatric illness that could, in the investigator's opinion,
             potentially interfere with the completion of treatment according to this protocol

         15. Known allergy to any of the study medications, their analogues, or excipients in the
             various formulations of any agent

         16. Known GI disease or GI procedure that could interfere with the oral absorption or
             tolerance of ixazomib including difficulty swallowing

         17. Diagnosed or treated for another malignancy within 2 years before study enrollment or
             previously diagnosed with another malignancy and have any evidence of residual
             disease. Patients with basal cell, squamous cell carcinoma of the skin, or carcinoma
             &quot;in situ&quot; of the cervix or breast with are not excluded if they have undergone
             complete resection

         18. Patient has ≥ Grade 3 peripheral neuropathy or Grade 2 with pain on clinical
             examination during the screening period

         19. Participation in other interventional clinical trials, including those with other
             investigational agents not included in this trial, within 30 days of the start of
             this trial and throughout the duration of this trial
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>April 2, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>February 9, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ixazomib</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Thalidomide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Glycine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
