<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02380430</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In France, there are no precise data regarding perioperative organization of medical structure and care management of ambulatory surgical patients. Particularly, data on management of pain, nausea and vomiting, as well as venous thromboembolic, prevention and treatment are needed, in several groups of patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Medical Management Survey : Organization of Perioperative Practices in Anesthesia and Ambulatory Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a prospective epidemiological observationnal study involving a sample of 300 ambulatory surgical centers among 1000 french centers. In a first step, a survey on the specific organization and care management of the structure will be carried out. In a second step, data on the management of 3000 patients admitted in these structure will be performed. The will allow an analysis of practices in a selection of acts (which seem to be more frequent and more relevant). Data from three different questionnaires on pain management, PONV prevention and treatment and VTE prevention will be recorded for each patient.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>All patients managed for ambulatory surgery by medical structures during the two days of the survey. For the patient managed for specific ambulatory surgery by medical structures, a more detail survey will be conducted (if applicable). Specific surgery are :Oral surgery ( wisdom tooth extraction surgery), Knee arthroscopy, Abdominal wall surgery (including inguinal hernia surgery), Perianal surgery, Varicose veins surgery, Cholecystectomy/laparoscopy surgery, Lumpectomy, Uterine surgery, Hallux valgus, Hand surgery (except carpal tunnel surgery) None</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Ambulatory surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>Pain management</keyword>
	<keyword>Nausea and vomiting management</keyword>
	<keyword>Questionnaire</keyword>
	<keyword>Survey</keyword>
	<keyword>Management</keyword>
</DOC>