<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02070432</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will investigate the tolerability, recommended dose and pharmacokinetics of LUZ11 following photodynamic therapy (PDT) of patients with advanced head and neck cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Photodynamic Therapy With LUZ11 in Advanced Head and Neck Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>LUZ11 is a new photosensitizer for use in photodynamic therapy (PDT) of solid tumors, such as head and neck cancer. PDT with LUZ11 involves the intravenous administration of LUZ11 followed by irradiation of the target tumor with laser light of an appropriate wavelength. The light causes the drug to react with oxygen, which forms reactive oxygen species (ROS) locally and induces tumor cells death and damages the blood vessels of the tumor thus preventing it from receiving nutrients. The primary objective of this study is to assess the tolerability of LUZ11 following single ascending doses of LUZ11. The secondary objectives of this study are to explore the LUZ11 dose that has anti-tumor effect following photoactivation and to determine LUZ11 pharmacokinetics.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written informed consent Men or nonpregnant, nonbreast feeding women Karnofsky performance status of 60% or greater Histologically confirmed recurrent/refractory squamous cell carcinoma of the head and neck Clearly visible tumor on the oral cavity or cutaneous surface Known hypersensitivity to any of the formulation ingredients Known hypersensitivity to porphyrins Porphyria or other diseases exacerbated by light Tumors known to be eroding into a major blood vessel in or adjacent to the irradiation site Planned skin phototherapy session(s) within the study timeframe Planned surgical procedure within the study timeframe Coexisting ophthalmic disease likely to require slitlamp examination within the study timeframe Existing therapy with a photosensitizing agent Unstable angina and/or congestive heart failure requiring hospitalization within 6 months prior to screening Myocardial infarction within 6 months prior to screening Contraindication to MRI with gadolinium Unacceptable laboratory abnormalities Clinically relevant 12lead ECG abnormalities</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>LUZ11</keyword>
	<keyword>head and neck cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>photodynamic therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Redaporfin</keyword>
</DOC>