<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00486512</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to investigate if long-term treatment with three known drugs (acetylsalicylic acid, 1α 25-dihydroxy cholecalciferol, and calcium carbonate) prevents recurrence of colorectal adenomas.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Chemoprevention of Colorectal Adenomas</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a multicenter, randomized, parallel group, prospective, double blind, placebo controlled clinical trial of chemoprevention in patients at increased risk of developing colorectal cancer (CRC). The Colotech combination treatment (acetylsalicylic acid, 1α 25-dihydroxy cholecalciferol, and calcium carbonate) will be compared to placebo with regards to safety and efficacy during 3 years of treatment. The randomized treatment period will be preceded by a 3-week single blind placebo run-in period, which will assess patient's compliance to treatment. In order to collect data on the durability of treatment effect, follow-up data from a surveillance colonoscopy will be collected two years after the 3-year colonoscopy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Adenoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adenomatous Polyps</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium, Dietary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcitriol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dihydroxycholecalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aspirin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium Carbonate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients 4075 years of age, both sexes. Colonoscopy including the cecum at trial entry The removed adenoma(s) have be to tubular, tubulovillous or villous, and fulfill one of the three following criteria: 1. one adenoma with diameter ≥ 1 cm 2. ≥ 2 adenomas of any size 3. an adenoma of any size and familial disposition for colorectal cancer, as long as the person is a first degree relative with a colorectal cancer patient Familial Adenomatous Polyposis Syndrome Member of a family with hereditary nonpolyposis colorectal cancer (HNPCC) Proctocolectomy (colonic and/or rectum resection permitted). Inflammatory bowel disease (Crohn´s disease, Ulcerative Colitis). Ischemic cardiovascular disease. Patients with known gastroduodenal ulcer at time of inclusion. Cancer within the past 5 years</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>colorectal, adenomas, prevention</keyword>
</DOC>