<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02881801</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study aims to describe the pattern of active and sedentary time in survivors of a critical illness, at three time points during their hospital admission (awakening in the ICU after ≥ 5 days of mechanical ventilation, discharge to ward and discharge from hospital). The specific research objectives are to 1. Determine the duration of active and sedentary parameters including time and bouts in 24 hour periods 2. Examine changes in the active and sedentary parameters including time and bouts between time points of awakening and both ICU and hospital discharge. 3. Conduct a preliminary examination of relationships between activity and sedentary behaviour metrics with measures of muscle strength, physical function and hospital length of stay.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Patterns of Physical Activity and Sedentary Time in Survivors of a Critical Illness During a Hospital Admission</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a prospective observational study that consecutively samples eligible patients with a critical illness, requiring intensive care. This study will use two activity monitors (accelerometers) to measure physical activity and sedentary variables from patients recovering from a critical illness in a single tertiary hospital on three occasions during their acute hospital admission. Accelerometer derived measures will be obtained from continuous 24 hour monitoring periods once patients are sufficiently awake and attentive within the ICU, at ICU discharge and again at acute hospital discharge. Measurements of patients muscle strength and physical function will also be made at the time of accelerometry.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Critical Illness</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult patient ≥ 18 years of age Patient is/was intubated (endotracheal, nasotracheal or tracheostomy) and required ≥ 5 days of mechanical ventilation (irrespective of reason for ventilatory support) Unable to ambulate independently (either with or without gait aids) at least 10 meters within the last 3 months Ordinarily unable to understand written and spoken English sufficient to provide consent (e.g. due to nonEnglish speaking background or preexisting cognitive impairment) Assessed by medical staff as approaching imminent death or withdrawal of medical management</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>accelerometry</keyword>
</DOC>