<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02881073</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary aim is to establish the effectiveness of plasma PlGF measurement in reducing maternal morbidity (with assessment of perinatal safety in parallel) in women presenting with suspected pre-eclampsia prior to 37 weeks' gestation. The long term aim is to demonstrate that knowledge of PlGF measurement enables appropriate stratification of the antenatal management of women presenting with suspected pre-eclampsia, such that those at highest risk receive greater surveillance with a decrease in maternal adverse outcomes, and those at lower risk can be managed without unnecessary admission and other interventions, such that the results would influence international clinical practice in antenatal patient healthcare</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Placental Growth Factor Assessment of Women With Suspected Pre-eclampsia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Pre-eclampsia (PET), a disease of late pregnancy characterised by hypertension and proteinuria, complicates 2-8% of pregnancies and is associated with significant maternal and neonatal morbidity and mortality. Many reports have highlighted the frequent substandard care, often attributed to clinicians not identifying the seriousness of clinical signs suggestive of the disease. Consequently, improvements in prediction of development of PET have the potential to vastly improve clinical outcomes and reduce costs. Placental Growth Factor (PlGF) belongs to the vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) family and represents a key regulator of angiogenic events in pathological conditions. PlGF exerts its biological function through the binding and activation of the receptor Flt-1. In PET, it is thought that endothelial dysfunction leads to an increased level of a circulating decoy receptor, known as soluble Flt-1, (sFlt-1), a soluble receptor for both VEGF-A and PlGF. In 2013, the INFANT team were part of an international group that published the first multicentre prospective study (PELICAN) evaluating the use of PlGF in women presenting with suspected PET, which reported high sensitivity (95-96%) and negative predictive value (95-98%) for low PlGF in determining need for delivery for confirmed PET within 14 days. This study suggests that PlGF testing presents a realistic and innovative adjunct to the management of women with suspected PET, especially those presenting preterm.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pre-Eclampsia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eclampsia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pregnancy Complications</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mitogens</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pregnant women between 20+0 and 36+6 weeks of gestation (inclusive) Singleton pregnancy Aged 18 years or over Able to give informed consent, presenting with any symptoms of suspected preeclampsia Headache visual disturbances epigastric or right upper quadrant pain increasing oedema hypertension dipstick proteinuria suspected fetal growth restriction if the healthcare provider deems that the woman requires evaluation for possible preeclampsia Confirmed preeclampsia at point of enrolment (sustained hypertension with systolic BP ≥ 140 or diastolic BP ≥ 90 on at least two occasions at least 4hrs apart) with significant quantified proteinuria (&gt;300mg protein on 24hr collection or urine protein creatinine ratio &gt;30mg/mmol) &gt;37 weeks gestation Abnormal PET bloods Multiple pregnancy at any time point Decision regarding delivery already made Lethal fetal abnormality Previous participation in PELICAN trial in a prior pregnancy Plan to use off protocol PIGF testing Unable/unwilling to give informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Placental Growth Factor</keyword>
	<keyword>Maternal Morbidity</keyword>
	<keyword>Neonatal Morbidity</keyword>
	<keyword>Pre-eclampsia</keyword>
	<keyword>Heath Economics</keyword>
</DOC>