<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02881372</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a single-center, prospective, pilot clinical trial in which children ages 5-17 years with eosinophilic esophagitis (EoE) who have a known food that triggers EoE flares receive oral desensitization with that specific food antigen, followed by reintroduction of that food into the diet.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>EoE Food Desensitization</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Eosinophilic esophagitis (EoE) is a clinicopathologic disorder of the esophagus triggered by food and/or environmental allergens and is characterized by symptoms of esophageal dysfunction and eosinophilia of the esophagus. Current therapy is centered on controlling inflammation with steroids and/or food antigen avoidance. Such treatment options have significant side effects and reduce quality of life, especially in children. The purpose of the study is to discover a way for flare-provoking foods to be reintroduced into the child's diet without the need for medical therapy. The study would involve children ages 5-17 years with biopsy-proven EoE who have a known flare-inducing food trigger. Following baseline blood work and esophagogastroduodenoscopy (EGD), the investigators will initiate oral desensitization treatment in which the child swallows a spray solution containing his or her specific food allergen extract in systematically increasing concentrations twice daily for 5 months. This desensitization phase would be followed by repeat blood work and EGD. If the child has more than a 50% increase in the peak esophageal eosinophil count from baseline, they will be withdrawn from the study. The next phase of the study would involve reintroduction of the actual food for 4 weeks followed by repeat blood work and EGD. Success would be defined by having a peak eosinophil count &lt;15 per high power field on the final esophageal biopsy. Oral food desensitization has been well-studied in patients with food allergies but never in patients with pre-existing EoE. In those studies, the adverse events included mild reactions, such as watery eyes, rhinitis, sneezing, throat pruritus, transient erythema and abdominal pain. These reactions usually did not require stopping desensitization and were well controlled by antihistamines and steroids. Benefits include children having a less restricted diet and eliminating the need for steroid therapy. This study should yield valuable information regarding the management of EoE, thereby improving the current understanding of its pathogenesis.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Esophagitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eosinophilic Esophagitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Pediatric patient, ages 517 years, with known diagnosis of EoE based upon esophageal biopsy demonstrating ≥15 eos/hpf and lack of symptomatic or histological response to proton pump inhibitor (PPI) therapy and/or normal esophageal hydrogen ion concentration (pH) evaluation. 2. Known or suspected flareinducing food trigger based upon supporting histological evidence. 3. Signed informed consent for the subject's participation in the study provided by the parent/ legal guardian and child/adolescent assent for subjects 717 years. 4. Assent by the patient's pediatric gastroenterologist for the patient's participation in the study. 1. Presence of other disorders associated with similar clinical, histological or endoscopic features, such as PPIresponsive esophageal eosinophilia, esophageal eosinophilia associated with gastroesophageal reflux disease (GERD), Crohn's disease, infectious esophagitis (i.e. herpes simplex virus or candida), drugassociated esophagitis, collagen vascular disease, hypereosinophilic syndrome and eosinophilic gastroenteritis. 2. Previous or current diagnosis of cancer or leukemia. 3. History of chemotherapy within the past 3 months. 4. History of esophageal stricture or food impaction. 5. History of anaphylaxis or other severe adverse reaction to the specific food trigger being tested.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>oral food desensitization</keyword>
	<keyword>food elimination</keyword>
	<keyword>food reintroduction</keyword>
</DOC>