<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02881762</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a single-site, longitudinal, open-label, interventional study for evaluating the effect of maraviroc on hepatitis C viral levels in patients infected with both hepatitis C and human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) and taking antiretroviral therapy for HIV.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Maraviroc Efficacy for Hepatitis C</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Recently, in-vitro studies (experiments performed in a laboratory, not on a person) have demonstrated that maraviroc, a medication that is used in human immunodeficiency (HIV) therapy, appears to have significant hepatitis C antiviral effect, comparable to sofosbuvir-a potent anti-hepatitis C medication. In this study, the investigators will evaluate the antiviral effect of maraviroc on hepatitis C virus in people infected with both hepatitis C and HIV, and whom have never been treated for hepatitis with direct antiviral agents. Participants will take maraviroc for 4 weeks in addition to their regular HIV antiretrovirals (ART). The investigators will measure the hepatitis C viral load before, during, and after the 4-week maraviroc time.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Maraviroc</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. 18 years old 2. Hepatitis Cinfected without plans to undergo hepatitis C treatment for duration of the study 3. Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infected 4. Currently receiving antiretroviral therapy with HIV viral load &lt;50 IU/ml for ≥ 12 months a. One virologic blip ≤ 400 copies/ml permissible within the 12 months 5. CD4 T cell counts &gt; 100 cells/mm3 6. Noncirrhotics and cirrhotics can be included 7. Willing to sign informed consent 1. Age &lt; 18 2. Unable to comply with study visits, research study visits, or is planning to relocate during the study. 3. Have any condition that the investigator considers a contraindication to study participation 4. Pregnancy or breast feeding 5. Decompensated liver disease (ChildPugh C) 6. Imminent treatment for hepatitis C infection 7. Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) or alanine aminotransferase (ALT) &gt;2.5 times the upper limits of normal 8. Concomitant use of drugs known to impact or be impacted in terms of pharmacokinetics or drugdrug interactions with either raltegravir, dolutegravir, or maraviroc. This includes: Inducers of UGT1A1 (such as rifampin, phenytoin, phenobarbital rifabutin, St. John's wort) Cytochrome P3A inhibitors (such as ketoconazole, itraconazole, clarithromycin, nefazodone, and telithromycin) Cytochrome P3A inducers (such as rifampin, carbamazepine, phenobarbital and phenytoin)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>hepatitis C virus (HCV)</keyword>
	<keyword>Maraviroc</keyword>
	<keyword>Human immunodeficiency virus (HCV)</keyword>
</DOC>