<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02350257</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to test the effectiveness of internet-delivered and therapist-guided internet-based cognitive behavior therapy (ICBT) for children with anxiety disorders (including social anxiety disorder, separation anxiety disorder, generalized anxiety disorder, panic disorder and specific phobia) in a randomized trial where participants will be allocated to either ICBT or to a supportive control condition. Non-responders (defined as those participants who still uphold their primary anxiety disorder after the ICBT treatment) will be offered traditional (face-to-face) CBT. Follow-ups are conducted at 3 and 12 months after treatment completion.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Internet-Based CBT for Children With Anxiety Disorders: Implementation in Clinical Settings</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>A primary diagnosis of any of the following anxiety disorders, as defined by DSMV (social anxiety disorder, separation anxiety disorder, generalized anxiety disorder, panic disorder or specific phobia) Age between 8 and 12 years Ability to read and write Swedish Daily access to the internet A parent that is able to coparticipate in the treatment Participants on psychotropic medication must have been on a stable dose for the last 6 weeks prior to baseline assessment Diagnosed with autism spectrum disorder, psychosis, bipolar disorder or severe eating disorder Present risk of suicide Ongoing substance dependence Completed CBT for any anxiety disorder within the last 6 months (defined as at least 5 sessions of CBT including in vivo exposure sessions)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>8 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>cognitive behavior therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>child</keyword>
	<keyword>randomized controlled trial</keyword>
	<keyword>internet</keyword>
</DOC>