<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00373841</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to identify genetic and biologic markers that may predict the loss of lung function due to idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. The studies will compare genetic and biologic markers of samples to changes in symptoms. The ultimate goal is to predict if or when patients are likely to experience a rapid decline in lung function due to disease progression.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Genomic and Proteomic Analysis of Disease Progression in Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis (IPF)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>People who are diagnosed with idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis are asked to participate in this study. The subject must be treated at the Dorothy P. and Richard P. Simmons Center for Interstitial Lung Disease. Subjects, if consented, are required to perform tests so that research data can be collected. At the initial visit, patients are subject to having a blood draw, pulmonary function testing, echocardiograms, and CT scans as well as completing several questionnaires designed to measure how the patient is feeling. Follow up visits are then scheduled in 3-4 month intervals. Every 3-4 months blood samples will be collected while every 6-8 months the questionnaires will administered. If the patient enters a stage of accelerated decline in lung function, a bronchoscopy will be performed to collect residual bronchoalveolar lavage fluid for testing. All of the results of clinical and laboratory testing will be placed into the subjects research file.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Disease Progression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Idiopathic Interstitial Pneumonias</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients who are 18 or older Diagnosis of Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis Treated at the Simmons Center Other Lung Illness</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lung</keyword>
	<keyword>Fibrosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Idiopathic</keyword>
	<keyword>Biomarkers</keyword>
	<keyword>Genomics</keyword>
	<keyword>Longitudinal</keyword>
</DOC>