<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01476475</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary Objective: - The purpose of this study was to compare insulin glargine/ lixisenatide fixed ratio combination (FRC) versus insulin glargine on glycemic control over 24 weeks, as evaluated by glycosylated hemoglobin (HbA1c) reduction in type 2 diabetic participants treated with metformin. Secondary Objectives: - To compare insulin glargine/lixisenatide FRC versus insulin glargine over 24 weeks on: - Glycemic control in relation to a meal as evaluated by post-prandial plasma glucose and glucose excursions during a standardized meal test; - Percentage of participants reaching HbA1c &lt;7% or ≤6.5%; - 7-point Self-Monitored Plasma Glucose (SMPG) profile; - Body weight; - Insulin glargine dose - Fasting Plasma Glucose (FPG); - Percentage of participants requiring rescue therapy during the 24-week open label treatment period; - To assess safety and tolerability of insulin glargine/lixisenatide FRC.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Insulin Glargine/Lixisenatide Fixed Combination Versus Insulin Glargine Alone on Top of Metformin in Type 2 Diabetic Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Approximately 27 weeks including a 24-week treatment period.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Glargine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Participants with type 2 diabetes mellitus diagnosed for at least 1 year. Metformin treatment at a stable dose of at least 1.5 g/day for at least 3 months prior to screening. Exclusion criteria: Age &lt; legal age of adulthood (18 years). Screening HbA1c &lt;7% or &gt;10%. Screening FPG &gt;250 mg/dL (&gt;13.9 mmol/L). Pregnancy or lactation, women of childbearing potential with no effective contraceptive method. Type 1 diabetes mellitus. Treatment with glucoselowering agent(s) other than metformin in a period of 3 months prior to screening. Use of insulin within the last 6 months. Previous use of insulin, except for episode(s) of shortterm treatment (≤15 consecutive days) due to intercurrent illness. Amylase and/or lipase &gt;3 times the upper limit of the normal laboratory range (ULN) at screening. Calcitonin ≥20 pg/ml (5.9 pmol/l) at screening. Alanine Transferase (ALT) &gt;3 ULN at screening. History of unexplained pancreatitis, chronic pancreatitis, pancreatectomy. Personal or immediate family history of medullary thyroid cancer (MTC) or genetic conditions that predisposes to MTC (e.g. multiple endocrine neoplasia syndromes). Uncontrolled or inadequately controlled hypertension at the time of screening with a resting supine systolic or diastolic blood pressure &gt;180 mmHg or &gt;110 mmHg, respectively. Within the last 6 months prior to screening: history of heart failure requiring hospitalization, myocardial infarction, or stroke. Planned coronary, carotid or peripheral artery revascularisation procedures. Body Mass Index (BMI) ≤20 or &gt;40 kg/m^2. Any previous treatment with lixisenatide The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a participant's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>