<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01476098</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is designed to loook at the affect of oral SB-705498 on cough following an inhaled capsaicin challenge</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Investigate the Effect of SB-705498 on Chronic Cough</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capsaicin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female between 30 75 (Part A) and 1875 (Part B) years of age inclusive. Nonchild bearing women or women of child bearing potential if they agree to use contraception as indicated by the protocol Nonsmoker for at least 6 months with a pack history &lt;5 pack years (Pack years = (No. of cigarettes smoked/day/20) x No. of years smoked). Body weight &gt; 50 kg and body mass index (BMI) within the range 19 30.0 kg/m2 (inclusive). Capable of giving written informed consent. Agree to use contraception listed as acceptable Normal 12lead ECG at screening. Chronic cough (Part B only) Good general health, apart from chronic cough (part B only), as determined by a responsible physician. A history of gastrointestinal, hepatic, renal or multiple cardiovascular risk factors. Positive prestudy drug/alcohol screen. Positive prestudy Hepatitis B surface antigen or positive Hepatitis C antibody result within 3 months of screening. A positive test for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) antibody (if determined by the local standard operating procedures (SOPs)). History of regular alcohol consumption within 6 months of the study. Exposure to more than four new chemical entities within 12 months prior to the start of the study. Participation in a clinical trial with a new molecule entity or any other clinical trial within 30 days of the start of the study. Use of prescription or nonprescription drugs, as well as of vitamins, herbal and dietary supplements (including St John's Wort) within 7 days prior to study. known history of lung cancer current treatment with oral corticosteriods or other immunosupressive agents FEV1 less than 80% of predicted value at screening Any subject who does not reach C5 following 250uM oral capsaicin History of drug or other allergy that, in the opinion of the Investigator or GSK Medical Monitor, contraindicates their participation. Donation of blood or blood products in excess of 500mL within a 56 day period prior the start study. Pregnant females as determined by positive serum or urine human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG) test at screening or prior to dosing. Lactating females. Unwillingness or inability to follow the procedures outlined in the protocol. Cotinine levels indicative of smoking or history or regular use of tobacco or nicotinecontaining products within 6 months prior to screening. consumption of red wine, seville oranges, grapefruit or grapefruit juice from 7 days prior to dosing.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>