<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02236403</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Blepharitis is a endemic inflammatory disease caused mainly by Demodex folliculorum and Demodex Brevis, This mites are often associated with anaerobic bacteria that produces a skin inflammation, so a intervention that reduces the number of mites and bacteria would be desirable. Ivermectin a macrolid compound have demonstrated activity against scabies and lice in humans and in animals and a single application have show a good response in lice eradication. In this study , investigators will determinate the security and effectiveness of this compound in the eradication of mites</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Treatment of Demodex Blepharitis With Ivermectin Gel 0.1% Plus Metronidazole 1%</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Blepharitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ivermectin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metronidazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>• Patients with symptomatic Demodex blepharitis for duration of at least 3 months. Age range: 18 yeras and older. Both genders and all ethnic groups comparable with the local community. Able to understand and willing to sign a written informed consent Able and willing to cooperate with the investigational plan. Able and willing to complete all mandatory followup visits. • Patients who are currently engaged in another clinical trial, unwilling or unable to give consent, to accept randomization, or to return for scheduled visits. Children under 18. Pregnant women or expecting to be pregnant during the study. Systemic immune deficient conditions such as AIDS or under systemic immunosuppressant. Concomitant use of ophthalmic topical medications (excluding nonpreserved tear substitutes). Concomitant use of systemic antibiotics or steroids. Contact lens wear Active ocular infection or allergy Unable to close eyes or uncontrolled blinking Previous allergic reaction to metronidazole and / or ivermectin</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Blepharitis , Demodex, Ivermectin, Metronidazole</keyword>
</DOC>