<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00826644</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Belotecan (Camtobell, CKD-602, Chong Kun Dang Pharm., Korea) is a new camptothecin derivative, that exhibits anticancer effects by inhibiting topoisomerase I. The investigators will have a randomized prospective multicenter trial of Belotecan/Cisplatin versus Etoposide/Cisplatin in patients with previously untreated, extensive-stage small cell lung cancer. Primary endpoints - to assess Response Rate Secondary endpoints - to assess Overall response duration, Time to progression, Overall survival</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Trial of Belotecan/Cisplatin in Chemotherapy Naive Small Cell Lung Cancer Patient</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Small Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Belotecan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Camptothecin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>ECOG Performance status 0~2(those with performance status 2 must have been stable with no deterioration over the previous 2 weeks) Histologically or cytologically confirmed small cell lung cancer Patient without chemotherapy and radiotherapy Measurable lesion according to RECIST with at least one measurable lesion not previously irradiated, unless disease progression has been documented at that site Life expectancy of at least 3 months Provision of written informed consent As judged by the investigator, any evidence of severe or uncontrolled systemic disease Serum bilirubin greater than 3 times the upper limit of reference range(ULRR) Aspartate aminotransferase (AST/SGOT) or alanine aminotransferase (ALT/SGPT)greater than 2.5 times ULN if no demonstrable liver metastases (or &gt; 5 times in presence of liver metastases) Evidence of any other significant clinical disorder or laboratory finding that makes it undesirable for the subject to participate in the study Pregnancy or breastfeeding women(women of childbearing potential). Women of childbearing potential must practice acceptable methods of birth control to prevent pregnancy Evidence of brain metastasis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Camptothecin</keyword>
	<keyword>Response rate</keyword>
</DOC>