<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01928693</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This Phase II study will evaluate the safety and efficacy of three fluoroquinolone ophthalmic agents to determine the optimal treatment in patients with infectious corneal ulcers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Comparison of Three Fluoroquinolone Topical Eyedrops in the Treatment of Infectious Corneal Ulcers.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a prospective, single masked, comparative, mono-therapeutic trial evaluating three fluoroquinolone agents that are approved and marketed for the treatment of conjunctivitis. Approximately 120 patients who have corneal ulcers greater than 2 mm but less than 6 mm in size who meet all other inclusion criteria will be enrolled into this study. Patients will be randomized in a 2:1:1 ratio to receive besifloxacin 0.6% ophthalmic suspension, gatifloxacin 0.5% ophthalmic solution, or moxifloxacin 0.5% ophthalmic solution.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Corneal Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gatifloxacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Moxifloxacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluoroquinolones</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>7-(3-aminohexahydro-1H-azepin-1-yl)-8-chloro-1-cyclopropyl-6-fluoro-1,4-dihydro-4-oxo-3-quinolinecarboxylic acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Norgestimate, ethinyl estradiol drug combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ophthalmic Solutions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients must be between the ages of 1890 years of age. 2. Patients must be able to understand the nature of this study, give written informed consent prior to study entry, and comply with study requirements. 3. Patients must have a corneal ulcer greater than 2mm but less than 6mm in size. 4. Patients must have corneal ulcer present in only one eye. 5. Patients must agree not to wear contact lenses while on study. 1. Patients with multifocal ulcers. 2. Signs of any other viral or fungal infection. 3. Treatment with antibiotics within 14 days of study entry. 4. Treatment with systemic or topical ocular antiviral agents or systemic or topical steroids or topical ocular nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDS) during the prior 14day period. 5. Known hypersensitivity or allergy to steroids (Loteprednol etabonate) or to any of the ingredients in the three study drugs (Besifloxacin 0.6% or Gatifloxacin 0.5% or Moxifloxacin 0.5%). 6. Contact lens only with no spectacles available. 7. Ocular surgery (including laser surgery) in either eye within 6 weeks prior to entry into this study. 8. Participation in any investigational study within the past 30 days. 9. Pregnant women, minors, or those not able to consent for themselves.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>infectious corneal ulcers</keyword>
</DOC>