<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02334748</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this extension protocol is to collect safety data (serious and non-serious adverse events) and to provide continuous canakinumab to patients in France who completed study CACZ885G2301E1, CACZ885G2306 or CACZ885N2301 until a decision regarding reimbursement in France is effective for canakinumab (Ilaris®) in these indications.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Canakinumab in Patients With Systemic Juvenile Idiopathic Arthritis or Hereditary Periodic Fevers Who Participated in the CACZ885G2301E1, CACZ885G2306 or CACZ885N2301 Studies</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fever</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Juvenile</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Familial Mediterranean Fever</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amyloidosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hereditary Autoinflammatory Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Criteria applicable for patients with Systemic Juvenil Idiopathic Arthritis SJIA): Patients who have completed the international studies CACZ885G2301E1 or CACZ885G2306 without any significant safety issue according to Investigator's opinion. Patients who have completed the international CACZ885G2306 study and who successfully withdrew canakinumab treatment per protocol but with a disease relapse within one year from withdrawal will be allowed to participate in CACZ885GFR01 study. Criteria applicable for patients with HPF (TRAPS, HIDS, crFMF): Patients who have completed the international CACZ885N2301 study without any significant safety issue according to Investigator's opinion. Criteria applicable for all patients: Parent's or legal guardian's written informed consent and child's assent, if appropriate, or patient's written informed consent for patients ≥ 18 years of age must be obtained before any study related activity or assessment is performed. History of recurring infections Hypersensitivity to the active substance or to any of the excipients other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>