<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02334254</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate the safety for the combination of Rivaroxaban and Ticagrel versus triple antithrombotic regimen (Vitamin K Antagonist (VKA), Clopigogrel and Aspirin) in patients with atrial fibrillation and coronary artery disease undergoing percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Rivaroxaban in Patients With Atrial Fibrillation and Coronary Artery Disease Undergoing Percutaneous Coronary Intervention</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label (both physician and participant know the treatment that the participant receives), randomized (study medication is assigned by chance), multicenter clinical study assessing the safety of the combination of rivaroxaban and ticagrel versus triple antithrombotic regimen (warfarin, clopigogrel and aspirin) in patients, who have paroxysmal, persistent, or permanent non-valvular atrial fibrillation (AF) and concomitant coronary artery disease undergoing percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI). A target of 420 participants will be randomized into the study, with approximately 210 participants in each treatment strategy group. Primary comparisons will be made of the rates of major and clinically relevant bleeding, assessed by the modified International Society of Thrombosis and Haemostasis (ISTH) classification. The study consists of a screening phase, a 12-month open-label treatment phase, and an end-of-treatment/early withdrawal visit. The total duration of participation in the study for each participant is approximately 12 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Clopidogrel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rivaroxaban</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Warfarin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>a longterm indication for oral anticoagulation treatment (until at least 1 year after the study) a severe coronary lesion (at least 75% stenosis on angiography or fractional flow reserve lower than 0•80) with indication for PCI age 1880 years history of intracranial bleeding; cardiogenic shock; contra indication to use of antiplatelet or anticoagulation drugs; peptic ulcer in the previous 6 months; thrombo cytopenia (platelet concentration lower than 50~10⁹/L); major bleeding (according to the Thrombolysis in Myocardial Infarction [TIMI] criteria) in the past 12 months; and pregnancy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>safety</keyword>
	<keyword>rivaroxaban</keyword>
	<keyword>ticagrel</keyword>
	<keyword>triple antithrombotic regimen</keyword>
	<keyword>undergoing PCI</keyword>
</DOC>