<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01762410</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Clinical study of oral PI3K/mTOR inhibitor P7170 in patients with advanced refractory solid tumors. The primary objective is to determine the maximum tolerated dose and dose limiting toxicity of oral PI3K/mTOR inhibitor P7170 in patients with advanced refractory solid tumors</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Study of Oral PI3K/mTOR Inhibitor in Patients With Advanced Refractory Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>An open label multicentric Phase 1 study of oral PI3K/mTOR inhibitor P7170 in patients with advanced refractory solid tumors.The study will follow an Accelerated Titration Design (ATD) with 100% dose increments until significant toxicity as described below; followed by standard dose titration with 40% dose increments. Dose and schedule (alternate dosing regimen eg. OD, BID, intermittent) will be determined by the dose escalation outlined in the protocol and considering pharmacokinetics of the study drug determined from earlier cohorts.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients having histologically and/or cytologically confirmed nonhaematological malignancy that is metastatic or unresectable and for which standard curative/palliative treatment does not exist or is no longer effective or is not tolerated by patient. Patients of either sex, of all races and ethnic groups, and more than 18 years of age. ECOG (Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group) performance status less than 2. Patients with life expectancy of at least 4 months. Patients with measurable or evaluable disease per Response Evaluation Criteria In Solid Tumors (RECIST) version 1.1. Patients must have adequate organ and marrow function as defined below: Absolute neutrophil count more than equal to 1500/cmm Platelets more than equal 100,000/cmm Total bilirubin within normal limits of the institution. AST/ALT less than equal 2.5 X institutional upper limit of normal (ULN) or less than equal 5 X institutional upper limit of normal (ULN) in the presence of liver metastases Creatinine less than equal 1.5 X institutional upper limit of normal (ULN) Women of childbearing potential and men willing to agree to use adequate contraception (hormonal or barrier method of birth control; abstinence) prior to study entry, during the duration of study participation and for at least 4 weeks after withdrawal from the study, unless they are surgically sterilised. Ability to understand and the willingness to provide a written informed consent document. 1. Patients who have received any prior chemotherapy, radiotherapy, biologic/targeted anticancer therapy or surgery within 4 weeks (3 months for monoclonal antibodies, radioactive monoclonal antibodies or any radio or toxin immunoconjugates) before study drug administration and have not recovered (to &lt; Grade 1) from the toxic effects from any prior therapy. 2. Patients having received any other investigational agents within 4 weeks prior to the date of enrolment and have not recovered completely (to &lt; Grade 1) from the side effects of the earlier investigational agent. 3. Patients with known brain metastases (except for patients who have previouslytreated CNS metastases, are asymptomatic, and have had no requirement for steroids or antiseizure medication for two months prior to first dose of study drug.) 4. Patients with a history of myocardial infarction or uncontrolled cardiac dysfunction during the previous 6 months. 5. Patients with diabetes mellitus requiring insulin therapy at screening or patients with clinically significant diabetic complications, such as neuropathy, retinopathy, peripheral vascular disease or nephropathy. 6. Clinically significant medical condition of malabsorption, inflammatory bowel disease, or chronic diarrheal condition that might affect the absorption of the investigational agent. 7. Patients on chronic anticoagulation treatment. Prophylactic anticoagulation with lowmolecular heparin is allowed. 8. Patients with intercurrent illness including, but not limited to ongoing or clinically significant active infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements. 9. Patients with a known history of allergic reaction to any other medication considered to be clinically significant by the investigator. 10. Women who are pregnant or nursing. 11. Patients with immune deficiency and at increased risk of lethal infections, for example, known h/o HIV, HBV or HCV.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Advanced refractory solid tumors</keyword>
</DOC>