<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01762982</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to evaluate the irritation potential of benzalkonium chloride disinfectant spray when placed in contact with normal human skin.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Patch Test of Benzalkonium Chloride Disinfectant Spray</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Benzalkonium chloride is recognized as safe and effective for short term use as first aid antiseptic drug products. In this study, benzalkonium chloride disinfectant spray will be compared to a positive control, and two negative control for irritancy potential on normal skin according to Chinese Patch Test Guideline (China Health Authority 2002). The skin irritation assessment will characterize the test products individually in terms of symptomatology using a 5-point categorical scale ranging from 0 (no visible reaction) to 4 (Erythema,edema˛ extreme blistering).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Benzalkonium Compounds</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Disinfectants</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Consent: Demonstrates understanding of the study and willingness to participate as evidenced by voluntary written informed consent and has received a signed and dated copy of the informed consent form. 2. Compliance: Understands and is willing, able and likely to comply with all study procedures and restrictions, and will agree to not participate in any other study during the entire length of the study. 3. General Health: Good general health with (in the opinion of the investigator) no clinically significant and relevant abnormalities of medical history and vital signs at the screening. 4. Contraception: Females of childbearing potential who are, in the opinion of the investigator, practising a reliable method of contraception. 1. Pregnancy: Woman who is pregnant or who has a positive urine pregnancy test (just for females of childbearing potential) at the baseline. 2. Breastfeeding: Woman who is breastfeeding. 3. Allergy/Intolerance: Known or suspected intolerance or hypersensitivity to the study materials or have selfreported "sensitive skin" or a history of dermal hypersensitivity. 4. Clinical Study/Experimental Medication: Participation in another clinical study or receipt of an investigational drug within 30 days of the screening visit, including those who have taken part in any predictive irritation study or sensitisation test. 5. Substance abuse: Recent history (within the last 1 year) of alcohol or other substance abuse. 6. Personnel: An employee of the sponsor or the study site or members of their immediate family. 7. Participant who is currently taking any of the following medications: Any topical or systemic treatments that may mask or interfere with the test results, specifically topical and/or systemic corticosteroids, non steroidal antiinflammatory drugs (e.g. ibuprofen, aspirin), antihistamines and immunosuppressive in the past 30 days. And those taking medications which in the opinion of the clinical investigator may affect test results. Topical antiinflammation treatment in the aimed application area in the past 2 months. 8. Participant who has a history of any acute or chronic disease that might interfere with or increase the risk on study participation. (e.g., atopic dermatitis/eczema, systemic lupus erythematosus, rheumatoid arthritis, other autoimmune diseases, asthma and other chronic respiratory disease). 10. Participant who has damaged skin in close proximity to test sites (e.g., sunburn, uneven skin pigmentation, tattoos, scars, birthmarks or other disfigurations). And those who are suffering from any active skin disorders, conditions, or any visible skin disease which might be confused with a skin reaction from the test materials. 11. Participant who requires use of any emollient on the upper back throughout the study or who use of any emollient or other skin care product on the upper back in the past 3 days.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>