<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01369095</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to evaluate the efficacy of study drug (BMS-820836) as compared with continued Duloxetine/Escitalopram in the treatment of patients with treatment resistant depression (TRD).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Fixed Doses of BMS 820836 in the Treatment of Patients With Treatment Resistant Major Depression</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Duloxetine Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Citalopram</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexetimide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Men and women of age 1865 years (Argentina minimum age will be 24 years of age) Patients must be able to understand the nature of the study, agree to comply with the prescribed dosage regimens, report for regularly scheduled office visits, and communicate to study personnel about adverse events and concomitant medication use. Patients with a diagnosis of Major Depressive Disorder, currently experiencing a Major Depressive Episode, as defined by Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders Fourth Edition (Text Revision)[DSM IV TR] criteria. The current depressive episode must be &gt; 8 weeks in duration and &lt; 3 years duration. In the current Major depressive disorder (MDD) episode, patients should report a history of inadequate response to 13 adequate trials of antidepressant treatment. Patients must have a 17item Hamilton Depression Rating Scale (HAMD17) total score ≥ 18 at Screening and Baseline. Patients who report an inadequate response (less than 50% reduction in depressive symptom severity) to more than three adequate trials of antidepressant treatments during the current depressive episode. Patients who have failed Duloxetine and Escitalopram at an adequate dose and for an adequate duration in their current episode.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>