<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="184326">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00694473</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2007P-002178</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00694473</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Continuous Glucose Monitoring With a Subcutaneous Sensor During Critical Illness and Surgery</brief_title>
  <official_title>Continuous Glucose Monitoring With a Subcutaneous Sensor During Critical Illness and Surgery</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Massachusetts General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Abbott Diabetes Care</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Massachusetts General Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      We hypothesize that measurements of interstitial fluid (ISF) glucose by the FreeStyle
      Navigator (Abbot Diabetes Care), a continuous glucose monitoring system, will correlate with
      blood glucose (BG) values in surgical and ICU patients with a clinically useful degree of
      accuracy.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Critically ill patients treated with intensive insulin therapy will be monitored for up to
      72 hours with the Freestyle Navigator continuous glucose monitor. The device display will be
      disabled so that continuous glucose monitoring results will not be available to care givers,
      although low (&lt;60 mg/dL) and high (&gt;250 mg/dL) threshold audio alarms will be enabled. Blood
      glucose monitoring will be performed according to the usual practice for patients treated
      with intensive insulin therapy in each intensive care unit, except that additional blood
      glucose measurements will be performed in response to Freestyle Navigator threshold alarm.
      All blood glucose management decisions will be made according to intensive insulin therapy
      protocol in each unit. Freestyle Navigator data will be downloaded from the device after
      each subject has completed the monitoring period. Blood glucose values obtained in the
      course of usual care, or in response to Freestyle Navigator threshold alarms, will be
      compared with time-matched Freestyle Navigator values to assess device accuracy and alarm
      sensitivity and specificity.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2010</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sensitivity and specificity of Navigator threshold alarms for hypoglycemia (&lt;60 mg/dl).</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sensitivity and specificity of Navigator threshold alarms for hyperglycemia (&gt;250 mg/dl).</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Point-by-point accuracy of the Navigator vs. reference BG</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sensitivity and specificity of Navigator projected low blood sugar alarm criteria calculated for events defined by a low reference BG value (&lt; 60 mg/dL)</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sensitivity and specificity of Navigator projected high blood sugar alarm criteria calculated for events defined by a high reference BG value (&gt; 250 mg/dl)</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Multivariate analysis seeking correlation between accuracy of the Navigator and vasopressor use, abnormal body temperature, peripheral or dependent edema, and severity of illness</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number and duration of excursions outside of the ICU target range reported by Navigator for at least 15 consecutive minutes and not detected by BG testing</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">65</enrollment>
  <condition>Critical Illness</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Freestyle Navigator</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Continuous monitoring with the Freestyle Navigator for 72 hours or until discharge from the ICU</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Freestyle Navigator</intervention_name>
    <description>Continuous glucose monitoring with the Freestyle Navigator for 72 hours or until discharge from the ICU</description>
    <arm_group_label>Freestyle Navigator</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients admitted to the general surgical ICU (SICU), medical ICU (MICU), cardiac
             surgery intensive care unit (CSICU), or neurological intensive care unit (NeuroICU),
             are being treated with IIT, and have an arterial line in place

          -  Patients scheduled for open cardiac surgery or craniotomy that have diabetes mellitus
             or will be given high dose glucocorticoids. All of these patient will have an
             arterial line placed at the time of surgery as a part of their usual care

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Age less than 18 years

          -  Enrollment in another clinical trial that modifies their glucose management (e.g.
             trial of modified IIT algorithm or modified glucose monitoring regimen)

        In order to obtain adequate representation of patients with physiological alterations that
        might decrease correspondence between blood and ISF glucose, we will recruit 50 subjects
        in each of five groups:

          1. Patients undergoing craniotomy who are either diabetic or will be given high dose
             corticosteroids

          2. Diabetic patients undergoing open cardiac surgery

          3. Patients admitted to one of the participating ICUs with an arterial line in place and
             receiving IIT who are vasopressor dependent, defined by continuous infusion of at
             least 60 mg/min phenylephrine, 5 mg/min norepinephrine, or 10 mg/kg/min of dopamine,
             or any combination of two agents for at least 90 continuous minutes in the last 8
             hours

          4. Patients admitted to one of the participating ICUs with an arterial line in place and
             receiving IIT with pitting peripheral or dependent edema, defined by the persistence
             of pitting to at least 5 mm depth for 5 seconds after pressure is applied to a
             dependent area of the trunk or two limbs.

          5. Critically ill patients admitted to one of the participating ICUs with an arterial
             line in place and receiving IIT who do not fall into groups 1-4.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Steven J. Russell, M.D., Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Massachusetts General Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Massachusetts General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>September 20, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>June 6, 2008</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Massachusetts General Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Steven J. Russell, MD, PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant in Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>hyperglycemia</keyword>
  <keyword>hypoglycemia</keyword>
  <keyword>insulin</keyword>
  <keyword>critical illness</keyword>
  <keyword>intensive insulin therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>continuous glucose monitoring</keyword>
  <keyword>CGM</keyword>
  <keyword>interstitial fluid glucose</keyword>
  <keyword>intensive care unit</keyword>
  <keyword>Blood glucose</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Critical Illness</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
