<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02322229</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to observe the anatomical and functional outcomes of ocriplasmin (JETREA®) over a 6-month follow-up period.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ocriplasmin for Vitreomacular Traction/Symptomatic Vitreomacular Adhesion</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Subjects will be recruited from approximately 10 centers in Australia and New Zealand.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tissue Adhesions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of VMT/sVMA, with evidence of focal VMT visible on Spectral Domain Optical Coherence Tomography (SDOCT). Read, sign, and date an Institutional Review Board/Ethics Committeeapproved informed consent form. Willing and able to attend all study visits. Other protocolspecified inclusion criteria may apply. Women of childbearing potential if pregnant, test positive on a urine pregnancy test, intend to become pregnant during the study period, breastfeeding, or not in agreement to use adequate birth control methods to prevent pregnancy throughout the study. Hypersensitivity to ocriplasmin or any of the JETREA excipients. Active or suspected intraocular or periocular infection in either eye. Participation in any interventional clinical trial within 30 days prior to baseline. Presence of epiretinal membrane (ERM) over the central macula in the study eye. Broad VMT/sVMA &gt; 1500 microns in the study eye. History of vitrectomy in the study eye. History of laser photocoagulation to the macula in the study eye. Any relevant concomitant ocular condition in the study eye that, in the opinion of the Investigator, could be expected to worsen or require surgical intervention during the study period. Macular hole of &gt; 400 microns diameter in the study eye. High myopia in the study eye. Pseudoexfoliation, Marfan's syndrome, phacodonesis, or any other finding in the study eye that, in the Investigator's opinion, suggests lens/zonular instability. Aphakia in the study eye. History of retinal detachment in the study eye. Recent ocular surgery or ocular injection in the study eye within the past 90 days (including laser therapy). Proliferative diabetic retinopathy or ischemic retinopathies in the study eye. Retinal vein occlusions in the study eye. Exudative agerelated macular degeneration (AMD) in the study eye. Vitreous hemorrhage in the study eye. Other protocolspecified exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>VMT</keyword>
	<keyword>sVMA</keyword>
	<keyword>vitrectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>ocriplasmin</keyword>
</DOC>