<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02322775</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this trial is to confirm the safety and clinical benefit of benralizumab administration in asthma patients with mild to moderate persistent asthma in order to gain an understanding of the benefit/risk of benralizumab across the spectrum of asthma disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of Benralizumab in Adult Patients With Mild to Moderate Persistent Asthma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written informed consent for study participation must be obtained prior to any study related procedures being performed and according to international guidelines and/or applicable European Union (EU) guidelines. Female and male aged 18 to 75 years, inclusively, at the time of Visit 1. Weight of ≥40 kg. Evidence of asthma as documented by postbronchodilator (postBD) reversibility in FEV1 of ≥ 12% demonstrated at Visit 2. Documented use of 1 of the following types of asthma therapy at time of informed consent: Low to mediumdose ICS (ie, 100 to 500 μg fluticasone dry powder formulation equivalents total daily dose) with or without other controller medications, eg, an LTRA and/or theophylline or Lowdose ICS/LABA fixed combination therapy (eg, the lowest regular maintenance dose approved in the local country will meet this criterion) Morning prebronchodilator (preBD) FEV1 of &gt; 50% to ≤ 90% predicted at Visit 2. Clinically important pulmonary disease other than asthma (eg, active lung infection, COPD, bronchiectasis, pulmonary fibrosis, cystic fibrosis, hypoventilation syndrome associated with obesity, lung cancer, alpha 1 antitrypsin deficiency, and primary ciliary dyskinesia) or ever been diagnosed with pulmonary or systemic disease, other than asthma, that are associated with elevated peripheral eosinophil counts (eg, allergic bronchopulmonary aspergillosis/mycosis, ChurgStrauss syndrome, hypereosinophilic syndrome). Any disorder, including, but not limited to, cardiovascular, gastrointestinal, hepatic, renal, neurological, musculoskeletal, infectious, endocrine, metabolic, hematological, psychiatric, or major physical impairment that is not stable in the opinion of the Investigator and could: Affect the safety of the patient throughout the study nfluence the findings of the studies or their interpretations, Impede the patient's ability to complete the entire duration of study. Known history of allergy or reaction to the investigational product formulation. History of anaphylaxis to any biologic therapy. History of GuillainBarré syndrome. A helminth parasitic infection diagnosed within 24 weeks prior to the date informed consent is obtained that has not been treated with, or has failed to respond to standard of care therapy. Acute upper or lower respiratory infections requiring antibiotics or antiviral medication within 30 days prior to the date informed consent is obtained or during the screening/runin period. Any clinically significant abnormal findings in physical examination, vital signs, hematology, clinical chemistry, or urinalysis during screening period, which in the opinion of the Investigator, may put the patient at risk because of his/her participation in the study, or may influence the results of the study, or the patient's ability to complete entire duration of the study. Positive hepatitis B surface antigen, or hepatitis C virus antibody serology, or a positive medical history for hepatitis B or C. Patients with a history of hepatitis B vaccination without history of hepatitis B are allowed to enroll. A history of known immunodeficiency disorder including a positive human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) test. History of cancer: Patients who have had basal cell carcinoma, localized squamous cell carcinoma of the skin or in situ carcinoma of the cervix are eligible provided that the patient is in remission and curative therapy was completed at least 12 months prior to the date informed consent was obtained. Patients who have had other malignancies are eligible provided that the patient is in remission and curative therapy was completed at least 5 years prior to the date informed consent was obtained</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Asthma, Bronchial Diseases, Respiratory Tract Diseases, Lung Diseases, Obstructive Lung Diseases,</keyword>
</DOC>