<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02650947</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Hypothesis: 1. Long-term consumption of sucralose may effect glucose metabolism, incretin hormone secretion and gut microbiota in healthy adults. 2. Long-term consumption of sucralose may alter food behaviour in healthy adults.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sucralose Effects on Glucose Metabolism and Gut Microbiota</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Artificial sweeteners such as sucralose, are among the most widely used food additives worldwide. Artificial sweetener consumption is considered safe and beneficial owing to their low caloric content. However, many emerging evidences showed artificial sweeteners may induce glucose intolerance. The objectives of this study were to determine the effect of sucralose on glycemic response, insulin secretion, insulin sensitivity, incretin response, gut microbiota and food behavior in healthy subjects.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Incretins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy volunteers without underlying disease Normal oral glucose tolerance test Agree to participate by written informed consent Shift workers History of diabetes mellitus or prediabetes (impaired fasting glucose and/or glucose tolerance test) Malabsorption problem Regular consumption of nonnutritive sweeteners Liver impairment (aspartate aminotransferase (AST) and/or alanine aminotransferase (ALT) &gt; 3folds upper normal limit) Renal impairment (serum creatinine &gt;1.5 mg/dL) Use of medications affecting glucose level such as glucocorticoid, estrogen, androgen Pregnant and lactating woman Smoking within 6 months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Sucralose</keyword>
	<keyword>Insulin Secretion</keyword>
	<keyword>Insulin Sensitivity</keyword>
	<keyword>Incretin</keyword>
	<keyword>Gut Microbiota</keyword>
	<keyword>Food and Eating Behaviour</keyword>
	<keyword>Healthy Volunteers</keyword>
</DOC>