<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03016078</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The overall rationale for this investigation is to evaluate the clinical performance potential for Mepilex Border Post-Op Ag in the ability to minimize the risk of skin related post-operative wound complications such as blistering, maceration and redness at the incision and surrounding skin.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of a Self-adherent Absorbent Silver Dressing Coated With a Soft Silicone Layer After Elective Primary Total Hip or Knee Arthroplasty</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>1. Age ≥ 18 years 2. Available for a followup visit including dressing change 7 days after surgery 3. Plan for elective primary hip or knee arthroplasty 4. Plan for incision size ≤18 cm 5. Provision of informed consent i.e. subject must be able to understand and sign the Patient Information and Consent Form 6. Undergoing elective primary arthroplasty of the hip or knee. Exclusion Criteria 1. Known allergy/hypersensitivity to any of the components of the dressing 2. Multitrauma 3. Undergoing arthroplasty due to tumor 4. Previous incision at the same knee or same side of the hip 5. Wound at the surgical site prior to surgery 6. Neurological deficit of operated side (hemiplegia, etc.) 7. Documented skin disease at time of enrollment, as judged by the investigator 8. Previously enrolled in the present investigation 9. Inclusion in other ongoing investigations at present that would preclude the subject from participating in this investigation as judged by the investigator 10. Involvement in the planning and conduct of the clinical investigation (applies to all MHC staff, investigational site staff and third party vendor) 11. Dressing size does not fit the incision area (&gt;18 cm) 12. Complications that would increase wound risks if investigational dressing is applied</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>