<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03016754</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is designed as a multi-center prospective observational study of newly diagnosed Heart Failure (HF) patients to test the hypothesis that additional Ejection Fraction (EF) recovery occurs between 90 and 180 days as Guideline Directed Medical Therapy (GDMT) is achieved. Although the study doesn't start until day 90, all eligible, consenting patients will be entered into a registry at the start of wearable cardioverter defibrillator (WCD) use. The pre-study registry will allow us to collect early (90 day) outcomes and data in those patients who are likely to be eligible for the study at day 90, or are eligible, but refuse the study at day 90.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Heart Failure Optimization Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will be conducted at thirty to sixty sites, initially in US and Europe. It will be used to observe the rate of recovery of ventricular function (EF&gt;35%) between 90 and 180 days in newly diagnosed HF patients who were prescribed the WCD ≤ 10 days post-discharge after hospitalization for a primary reason of new onset HF (≤30 days since first HF hospitalization), with ischemic or non-ischemic cardiomyopathy, and have already used a WCD for 90 ± 14 days. For the first 90 days of WCD use, patients will be enrolled in a pre-study registry. The FDA-approved WCD will be prescribed for up to 6 months of use after hospital discharge, with the option for longer use under physician discretion. Approximately 870 subjects will enroll into the pre-study registry and 750 subjects into the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Arrest</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Death</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Death, Sudden, Cardiac</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Part 1 Patients (≥18 years old) who were prescribed the WCD ≤ 10 days postdischarge after hospitalization for a primary reason of new onset HF (≤30 days since first HF hospitalization), with ischemic or nonischemic cardiomyopathy, and have used the WCD for no more than 30 days. Patients who had an EF ≤ 35% during index hospitalization (must be last measurement if performed multiple times). Part 2 Patients (≥18 years old) who were prescribed the WCD ≤ 10 days postdischarge after hospitalization for a primary reason of new onset HF (≤30 days since first HF hospitalization), with ischemic or nonischemic cardiomyopathy, and have already used a WCD for 90 ± 14 days. Patients who had an EF ≤ 35% during index hospitalization (must be last measurement if performed multiple times). Of note, EF at 90 ± 14 days posthospitalization does not need to be low to be included in the study. Patients under 18 years old. Patients who have an active unipolar pacemaker. Patients with a physical or mental condition that could impair their ability to properly interact with the device. Patients currently participating in another clinical study. Patients with any skin condition that would prevent wearing the device. Patients with an advanced directive prohibiting resuscitation. Patients who are indicated for cardiac resynchronization therapy or have a QRS duration of ≥135 ms. Patients with recent myocardial infarction or coronary revascularization (since start of WCD wear; i.e. 090 days of WCD wear).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>sudden cardiac death</keyword>
	<keyword>SCD</keyword>
	<keyword>sudden cardiac arrest</keyword>
	<keyword>SCA</keyword>
	<keyword>heart failure</keyword>
	<keyword>HF</keyword>
</DOC>