<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03016858</DOC>
	<brief_summary>With the development of video-assisted thoracoscopic surgery (VATS) techniques and technology for anesthesia control, non-intubated anesthesia with spontaneous ventilation has been widely applied in VATS. A multicenter randomized parallel controlled study was applied in this study to assess the feasibility and safety of thoracoscopic bullectomy surgery under intravenous anesthesia with spontaneous ventilation versus tracheal intubation general anesthesia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Trial of Thoracoscopic Bullectomy Surgery Under Spontaneous Ventilating Anesthesia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Intubated anesthesia with single lung mechanical ventilation (IASLV) is considered the standard of care in VATS. However, this type of anesthesia has been associated with several adverse effects, which can trigger complications and increase the overall surgical risk. In order to avoid intubated-anesthesia-related adverse effects, nonintubated strategies have been proposed in recent years.Encouraged by the satisfactory results with a preliminary experience of nonintubated VATS, the multicenter randomized parallel controlled study is established to comparatively analyze the outcome of patients undergoing either nonintubated intravenous anesthesia with spontaneous ventilation (NIIASV) or IASLV VATS thoracoscopic bullectomy surgery，especially in safety during operation, complication rate, muscle recovery after surgery, the difference the postoperative hospitalization time.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Postoperative Complications</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<criteria>volunteering to participate in clinical trials and having the ability of responsibility can be signed informed consent. 1650 years old preoperative chest CT diagnosed with "localized lung bulla" and needing surgical treatment Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group(ECOG) score standard ≤ 1 ASA（American Society of Anesthesiologists score） ≤ 2 Heart ejection fraction( EF)≥ 50% refusing to participate in clinical trials A history of tuberculosis or other diseases could cause pleural adhesion or more pleural effusion BMI ≥ 25 kg/m^2 other not suitable situations</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>