<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03016481</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a 3-year comparative effectiveness study funded by the Patient Centered Outcomes Research Institute (PCORI) and will test an adapted priority-based patient navigation versus care as usual among 300 survivors of intimate partner violence (IPV) recruited from, and/or referred from, University of Rochester Medical Center providers. The goal is to improve patient safety, depression, and health function over the course of 12 months. In the Community Health Worker -Personalized Support for Progress (CHW-PSP) arm, created and tested in our first UR PCORI grant, in addition to meeting with a social worker, patients will work with a Community Health Worker (CHW) to complete a prioritization tool and meet as needed over the course of the next 6 months to navigate services and overcome barriers. In addition, patients will receive referrals to other professionals based on their prioritization and meet with the CHW at the time and place of their choice. Patients in the Care as Usual- Social Worker (CAU-SW) arm, will do intake with a social worker, who follows hospital procedures for intake and referrals, does a needs assessment, and offers safety planning in referral.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Healing Through Education, Advocacy and Law (HEAL) in Response to Violence</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Subjects must be English speaking URMC patients, who are 18 years of age or older, and/or the nonoffending parent on a CPS report for a URMC pediatrics patient, and who have experienced an IPV or emotional abuse event within the past 3 months. IPV is defined as endorsing any of the following items: 1. Slapped, kicked, pushed, choked, or punched? 2. Forced or coerced to have sex? 3. Threatened you with a knife or gun to scare or hurt you? 4. Made you feel afraid that you would be physically hurt? 5. Repeatedly used words, yelled, or screamed in a way that frightened you? 6. Threatened you, put you down, or made you feel rejected? Yes No Additional inclusion criteria include depression based on PHQ9 score of &gt;10. Subjects are ineligible if they have active psychosis or alcohol or substance dependence based on 3 months threshold on the MiniInternational Neuropsychiatric Interview (MINI). Additionally, patients who are unable to understand the consent form or study procedures, are imminently suicidal, or are currently working with a CHW will be excluded.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>