<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02450162</DOC>
	<brief_summary>- Background and study aims : The investigators conducted this study to compare the movement of extraocular muscle after two types of recession surgery with non-invasive tool called AS-OCT. - Who can participate? patients who will undergo two types (conventional method and hang-back method) of typical bilateral lateral rectus recession surgery for correcting intermittent exotropia - What does the study involve? Volunteers will attend a clinic for four visits over three months. They will undergo AS-OCT at every visits during follow up period. AS-OCT is non-invasive test to evaluate operation site. The test only requires their cooperation when they undergo AS-OCT. - What are the possible benefits and risks of participating? This is non-invasive test for your postoperative follow up. Therefore, there will be no risks about this test. - Where is the study run from? Samsung Medical Center - When is the study starting and how long is it expected to run for? From April 2015 to Dec 2015</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Lateral Rectus Muscle and Anterior Segment Optical Coherence Tomography (AS-OCT) in Two Recession Surgeries</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is a following study of our prior study about AS-OCT in strabismus. The aim of this study is to compare the longitudinal changes of lateral rectus (LR) muscle insertion between two types of bilateral recession surgery. An AS-OCT scan of the LR muscle was performed every visits. Data on gender, age, degree of deviation (prism diopter), and spur-LR insertion distance using AS-OCT were collected at postoperative months 1,3 in each group.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Exotropia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients who will undergo bilateral lateral rectus recession surgery for correcting intermittent exotropia previous ocular surgery other ocular diseases except intermittent exotropia amblyopia</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>