<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00838110</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multi-center, randomized, double-blind placebo-controlled safety study conducted in 2 study cohorts. In Cohort 1, subjects with Alzheimer's disease (n=250) will receive Dimebon 20 mg or placebo TID for 26 weeks. In Cohort 2 AD subjects (n=500) will be treated with Dimebon 20 mg or placebo TID for 12 weeks After completion of the randomized portion of the study, subjects in both Cohorts will have the opportunity to enroll in a Dimebon open label extension study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase 3 Study To Evaluate The Safety And Tolerability Of Dimebon Patients With Mild To Moderate Alzheimer's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of Alzheimer's Disease. MMSE 1226 inclusive. If on existing antidementia therapy, have been on a stable dose of antidementia therapy (cholinesterase inhibitors and/or memantine) for at least 60 days prior to dosing in study. If not taking existing antidementia therapy, have not received therapy with cholinesterase inhibitors and/or memantine within 60 days prior to dosing in this study. Have major structural brain disease (e.g., ischemic infarcts, subdural hematoma, hemorrhage, hydrocephalus, brain tumors, multiple subcortical ischemic lesions, or a single lesion in a critical region [e.g., thalamus, hippocampus]). Have any major medical illness or unstable medical condition within six months of screening that may interfere with the patient's ability to comply with study procedures and abide by study restrictions. Have not been on a stable dose of antidementia therapy for at least 60 days prior to dosing or intend to start antidementia therapy during the double blind portion of the study. Reside in a nursing home or assisted care facility with need for 24hour care and supervision.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Alzheimer's Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Dimebon</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
	<keyword>Tolerability</keyword>
</DOC>