<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02566356</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this study, investigators will examine the behavioral effects and neurophysiological mechanisms of the pro-social neuropeptide oxytocin in patients with recent-onset schizophrenia. Such research is a necessary first step towards identifying whether intranasal oxytocin administration can serve as an adjunct treatment for social impairments in schizophrenia. Aim 1: To examine the effects of exogenous oxytocin on patterns of neural activation as measured by fMRI during a well-characterized affect-labeling task in patients with recent-onset schizophrenia and healthy comparison subjects. Hypothesis A: Patients will exhibit amygdalar hyperactivity and PNS hypo-activity when passively viewing faces, which will be normalized by administration of oxytocin. Hypothesis B: Patients will exhibit hypo-activity of the vPFC when affectively labeling faces and this hypo-activity will be normalized by oxytocin administration.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Adult Study Oxytocin - fMRI</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxytocin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria for Patients: Male SCIDIV confirmed diagnosis of schizophrenia or schizoaffective disorder Clinically stable No changes to medications for the past week Inclusion Criteria for Healthy Controls: Male SCIDIV confirmed no diagnosis of a current Axis I disorder within the last year Exclusion Criteria for Patients and Healthy Controls: Meeting criteria for current substance abuse or dependence or illicit drug use within the last month (nicotine use is acceptable) as determined by a Urine Toxicology Drug Screening Any illness that affects the nasal passages and impairs the delivery of a nasal spray Presence of any neurological or significant medical disorder, including medical illnesses that could interfere with physiological recording such as cardiac arrhythmias A pacemaker, extensive dental work, or any magnetic metal implants and upper body tattoos Pregnancy Claustrophpbia Hearing difficulties A history of seizures Failure to receive a passing score on the reading test Additional Exclusion Criteria for Patients and Healthy Controls: Taking any psychotropic medication or any medication that affects the autonomic or cardiovascular systems. Schizophrenia or other psychotic disorder in a first degree relative Failure to receive a passing score on the MOCA</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Oxytocin</keyword>
	<keyword>Syntocinon</keyword>
	<keyword>Social Cognition</keyword>
	<keyword>Schizophrenia</keyword>
	<keyword>Functional Magnetic Resonance Imaging (fMRI)</keyword>
</DOC>