<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00934583</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will examine the ability of an Internet-based program to prevent college-aged women from developing eating disorders.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Testing an Internet-Based Intervention for Preventing Eating Disorders</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Approximately 2% to 4% of college-aged women suffer from eating disorders (EDs), and many more are at risk of developing them. A previous Internet-based intervention called Student Bodies (SB), which focused on body image concerns, was effective in reducing risk factors for EDs among college-aged women. However, the original SB program did not account for certain other risk factors, such as depression and compensatory behaviors like self-induced vomiting, over-exercising, or use of diuretics. Image and Mood (IaM) is an enhanced version of the SB program and takes into account depressive symptoms and the use of compensatory behaviors. This study will examine whether IaM will reduce ED risk factors in a large population of college women who are at high risk of developing EDs. Participation in this study will last 10 weeks. Participants will be randomly assigned to either receive the IaM program or be placed on a wait list. The IaM program, which will be delivered through the Internet, will provide information about nutrition, exercise, body image, and coping skills—including examples and exercises. It will also include an online message board monitored by a study psychologist. Each week the IaM participants will monitor their behavior, keep a journal about their experiences, and answer self-report questionnaires. Assessments of eating disorder symptoms; weight and shape concerns; depressive symptoms; and incidence of substance abuse, anxiety, or depressive disorders will be completed post-treatment and at 1- and 1.5-month follow-ups. Those assigned to the wait list will complete these assessments and then receive the IaM program after the last follow-up.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Feeding and Eating Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria for Primary Aim: Access to a computer with an Internet connection Weight Concerns Scale score greater than or equal to 47 Presence of one additional risk factor, including a history of teasing, a history of depression, or low levels of compensatory behaviors (defined as less than four times per month) Inclusion Criteria for Secondary Aim: Access to a computer with an Internet connection Weight Concerns Scale score greater than or equal to 47 Exclusion Criteria for Both Primary and Secondary Aims: Current diagnosis of an eating disorder Treated for an eating disorder within the past 6 months Currently receiving psychological treatment for an eating disorder or depressive disorder Started a new psychiatric medication within the past 2 months Exhibiting a level of psychopathology that would interfere with participation (e.g., acutely suicidal)</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>25 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Bulimia Nervosa</keyword>
	<keyword>Binge Eating</keyword>
	<keyword>Binge-Eating Disorder</keyword>
</DOC>