<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00792454</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The mortality rate of treated patients with end stage renal disease(ESRD)is 22 deaths patient-years at risk in 2006. Incident patients with ESRD are most vulnerable within the first 90 days of dialysis, with an annualized mortality rate of 50 deaths/100 patient years. The vast majority of these deaths are due to cardiovascular causes. As cardiac rehabilitation programs have shown a 20% reduction in one year overall mortality rate post myocardial infarction the investigator proposes that a similar type of rehabilitation program will also have a benificial effect on morbidity and mortality in patients with chronic kidney disease(CKD)and ESRD.The overall goal of this project is to study whether a renal rehabilitation program based on guided exercise implemented in patients with stage III and stage IV CKD can influence the mortality rate of these patients prior to and during the first 90 days of dialysis Hypothesis:The application of a guided exercise program (renal rehabilitation) instituted in patients with stage III or Stage IV CKD will decrease the mortality rate prior to the initiation of renal replacement therapy. Hypothesis:The application of renal rehabilitation during the late stages of CKD will decrease the mortality risk during the first 90 days of renal rehabilitation therapy. Hypothesis:A guided exercise program will have an immediate and prolonged effect on activity levels, mental health and adaption to chronic illness in patients with advanced CKD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Reduction of Mortality Prior to and During the First 90 Days of Dialysis Through a Renal Rehabilitation Program</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>greater than 18 yo stage III CKD (GFR&lt;60ml/min) stage IV CKD (GFR&lt;30ml/min) active angina pectoris lower extremity amputation with no prosthesis orthopedic disorder severly exacerbated by activity chronic lung disease resulting in significant shortness of breath or oxygen desaturation at rest cerebro cascular disease manifested by ongoing TIAs malignant carcinoma</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic kidney disease</keyword>
	<keyword>End stage renal disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiovascular disease</keyword>
</DOC>