<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00792844</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Main research Question: The investigators would like to find out if both the Bio-K (lactobacillus acidophilus and lactobacillus casei) drink and capsule are equally effective in the prevention of diarrhea associated with antibiotic use. Why is this research project important? About 25% of patients who use antibiotics may develop diarrhea as a side effect. Symptoms are mild and consist of watery diarrhea and abdominal pain. Some patients may develop a more severe form of diarrhea, called clostridium difficile-associated diarrhea. Clostridium difficile-associated diarrhea may lead to more serious consequences like inflammation of the large bowel and in some cases, death. There are some studies that suggest Bio-K drink, a probiotic preparation containing lactobacillus acidophilus and lactobacillus casei, decreases the risk of diarrhea from antibiotic use. As a result, St. Joseph's Healthcare has recently to use Bio-K routinely to try to reduce risk of patients developing diarrhea. No other Hamilton hospitals use Bio-K routinely as there is not strong evidence about the effectiveness of Bio-K for the prevention of diarrhea. This study will provide more information about Bio-K's effectiveness in the prevention of diarrhea associated with antibiotic use as both a capsule and a drink.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of Two Formulations of Bio-K</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diarrhea</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Bacterial Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibiotics, Antitubercular</mesh_term>
	<criteria>speak English capable of providing consent reachable by telephone within the next three months willing to comply with study protocols age over 65 years prescribed clindamycin, fluoroquinolones or cephalosporin for more than one dose ICU patients transplant patients patients on immunosuppressant medications (prednisone greater than 50 mg/day for 7 days, azathioprine, cyclosporine, cyclophosphamide, tacrolimus, sirolimus, methotrexate, mycophenolate, antiTNF agents, interleukin2 chemotherapy) HIV patients with CD4+ count less than 250 cells/mm3 neutropenic patients with total neutrophil count less than 500 patients with prosthetic heart valves</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2008</verification_date>
</DOC>