<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03009994</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Cesarean section is one of the most frequently performed major operations worldwide. It accounts for between 1% and 70% of deliveries depending on the facilities or country assessed. In Egypt, the cesarean section rate is 22%, with higher rates seen in private hospitals. In 2015 ,incidence of cesarean section rate in Woman Health Hospital in Assiut university is 51.3% of all deliveries. Different Operational techniques For cesarean section have been defined aimed at reducing surgical time, making the surgery easier and more efficient, lowering costs,decreasing the risk of adverse effects and postoperative morbidity, as well as length of hospital stay. Also, Intraoperative blood loss is one of important complications during cesarean section. A systematic review included twenty one studies, in 2011, revealed that increase incidence of intraoperative blood loss and blood transfusion with increase number of cesarean deliveries.also anemia in the pregnancy increase maternal morbidities included intraoperative blood loss. In Egypt, prevalence of Iron deficiency anemia among pregnant women about 51% of pregnant women. After baby born by cesarean section and the placenta has been extracted, uterine incision is sutured either by temporary removal of the uterus from the abdominal cavity (exteriorization of the uterus) to facilitate uterine incision repair or it is repaired within the abdominal cavity (in situ repair). There had been few randomized controlled trials comparing intraoperative and postoperative morbidity following exteriorization of the uterus with non-exteriorization. The conclusions drawn from these trials have been conflicting.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Exteriorization Versus Non-exteriorization of the Uterus During Repair of Uterine Incision in a Repeated Cesarean Section</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pregnant women in 28 weeks Women who will undergo repeated lower segment cesarean section First cesarean section Placenta previa. Rupture uterus. Classical caesarean section.(upper segment cesarean section) Sever Preeclampsia. Chorioamnionitis. prolonged or obstructed labour. Fibroid. Polyhydramnios. Multiple pregnancy.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>