<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03009084</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate the communication and data sharing between the primary care physician and the nephrologist about patients with chronic kidney disease. Also therapeutic interventions that change behavior and telemonitoring of the blood pressure will be explored and compared to the usual care. The most important aim of this study is to improve the quality of care for the patient with chronic kidney disease in cooperation with the primary care physician and the nephrologist.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multidisciplinary Care for Patients With Chronic Kidney Disease to Increase Their Self-management.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Through questionnaires with primary care physicians, nephrologists from the University Hospitals of Leuven and patients with chronic kidney disease, the problems will be known. After the exploration there will be an intervention with patients who meet the in- and exclusion criteria. Around 150-200 patients will be included with a 1:2 randomisation in the control and intervention group. The relevant clinical data and the factors of lifestyle will be questioned at the baseline. The intervention group will receive individualized therapy by a nurse, for example to quit smoking, to eat healthier and to do more physical activities. This therapy is based on the most important risk factors and will be determined before the start of the therapy. Further on, these patients will also be motivated to take their blood pressure more frequently by using a telemonitoring system.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Predialysis, hemodialysis, peritoneal dialysis, transplantation Included in the care program of chronic kidney diseases Dutchspeaking Signed and approved informed consent No Dutchspeaking Impaired cognitive condition or medically unstable</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>