<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01418794</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Polymer carried by drug-eluting stents may increase inflammatory response and thrombosis. Our previous study showed that polymer-free rapamycin-coated stents brings dose-dependent reduction in restenosis. This prospective, multicenter, randomized controlled clinical trials aimed to explore efficacy and safety of the YUKON drug eluting stent in diffuse coronary artery disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of the YUKON Drug Eluting Stent in Diffuse Coronary Artery Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Acute Coronary Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age from 1885 years old, male or nonpregnant women asymptomatic ischemia, stable or unstable angina, old myocardial infarction patients at least one target lesion length ≥ 20 mm (Visual method) Target lesion diameter 2.5mm4.0 mm (Visual method) Target lesion diameter stenosis ≥ 70% Patients who has indications for coronary artery bypass graft (CABG) surgery Patients who is voluntary, understand the purpose of the study, willing to accept angiography and clinical followup Acute myocardial infarction for less than 1 week Bridge vascular disease Instent restenosis lesions Patient with bleeding tendency, history of active peptic ulcer, History of cerebral hemorrhage or subarachnoid hemorrhage, history of stroke within half year, contraindications to anticoagulant therapy and antiplatelet Allergic to aspirin, clopidogrel or ticlopidine, heparin, contrast agent, rapamycin and metal Life expectancy is less than 12 months Patient who has participated in other clinical trials but does not meet the deadline of the primary endpoint Poor patient compliance Heart transplant recipient Patient who had other stent implanted within 1 year Patient who has multivessel disease(Long lesions) and has already received other stent implantation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acute Coronary Syndromes</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug eluting stent</keyword>
	<keyword>Diffused lesion</keyword>
</DOC>