<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02274662</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary purpose is to provide access of thymus tissue transplantation to patients who have immunodeficiency, hematologic malignancies, or severe autoimmune disease related to poor thymic function. With no thymus function, bone marrow stem cells do not develop into T cells, which fight infection. Eligible participants undergo thymus transplantation and biopsy. Immune suppression may be given depending on the immune status and clinical condition of the participant. Immune function testing is continued for one year post-transplantation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Expanded Access Protocol Thymus Transplantation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The participants enrolled have a high likelihood of death if they do not receive a thymus transplant because of lack of thymus function. As there are many types of patients who may be enrolled, study results will not have statistical significance. The study objective is to make thymus transplantation available on an expanded access basis. Data will be collected on survival, naïve T cell development, T cell chimerism, and transplant related toxicities, as well as any unexpected study related serious adverse events. Participants undergo thymus transplantation and allograft biopsy. Immune suppression may be given depending on the immune status and clinical condition. Protocol specified studies continue until approximately one year post-transplantation. Study participation lasts two years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tacrolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antilymphocyte Serum</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>an immunodeficiency, malignancy, or severe autoimmunity for which development of naïve T cells would be expected to lead to lead to clinical improvement. written consent (or consent of parent/legal guardian as applicable) review of medical testing, laboratory studies, and physical examinations are used to to determine whether the patient is clinically stable and will potentially benefit from thymus transplantation. Each participant is reviewed with the Data Safety and Monitoring Board (DSMB). Unrepaired cyanotic congenital heart disease Uncontrolled infections. "Uncontrolled" defined as requiring a ventilator, dialysis, or vasopressor support or anticipated as requiring such support within 6 months. Pregnancy For females of childbearing potential, a serum pregnancy test is done after consent, at the same time another blood draw is done if possible. Females of childbearing potential must agree to contraceptive measures as indicated in the consent form. A second serum pregnancy test is done within 48 hours prior to administration of study interventions involving FDA pregnancy class D drugs, chemotherapy drugs, or other drugs or interventions known to pose risks to a potential fetus. Test positive for HIV</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>