<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02274246</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to validate the technique for the detection of left atrial fibrosis through segmentation of endocardial and epicardium landmarks of the images obtained with 3 Tgadobutrol-enhanced magnetic resonance with the software GIMIAS速 in a cohort of healthy volunteers, without atrial fibrillation or known cardiovascular risk factors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Validation of the Efficacy of the Tool GIMIAS速 for the Assessment of Left Atrial Fibrosis in a Group of Healthy Volunteers (RESTORE-HV)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>3D reconstructions obtained by GIMIAS速 will be evaluated. Processing images will be carried out by two independent operators, and will calculate the kappa interobserver agreement . Subsequently, the processed images are compared with images previously obtained in 10 patients with persistent atrial fibrillation adjusted for sex and age. A qualitative visual comparison will be made.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy volunteers capable of being subjected to the prespecified tests of the study. Healthy volunteers that sign the informed consent after being informed. Healthy volunteers with: A medical history of atrial fibrillation, hypertension or diabetes mellitus. A medical history of heart disease, structural, ischemic or arrhythmic. A medical history of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease/obstructive sleep apnoea/hypopnoea syndrome Sport habits: intense sport activities during three or more hours in a week Any assumption that contraindicates the magnetic resonance and/or the use of gadolinium or other contrast mediums, including a medical history of previous allergic or not allergic reactions with the use of gadolinium or other contrast mediums, bronchial asthma or allergic diseases. Pregnancy or breast feeding.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Segmentation</keyword>
	<keyword>GIMIAS速 program</keyword>
	<keyword>Atrial fibrillation</keyword>
	<keyword>Left atrial fibrosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Healthy volunteers</keyword>
</DOC>