<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01757522</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) and mechanical ventilation can lead to right ventricular dysfunction and ultimately right ventricular failure by increasing pulmonary vascular resistances and pressure load. This can be prevented by modifying ventilator settings, using vasopressors or inotropes or even by prone positionning.But to do so, right ventricular dysfonction has to be detected. Echocardiography has emerged as a first line tool to diagnose right heart failure. Recently, strain analysis showed promising results to detect early right ventricle abnormalities in other settings such as pulmonary hypertension or scleroderma. We therefore decided to determine whether 2D strain could help detect early right ventricular dysfunction in ARDS.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Detection of Right Ventricular Dysfunction by 2D Strain During Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrom (ARDS)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Newborn</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Adult</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Lung Injury</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ventricular Dysfunction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ventricular Dysfunction, Right</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Heart Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>ARDS group Need for mechanical ventilation ARDS criteria met: Respiratory failure not fully explained by cardiac failure, Pao2/FiO2&lt;200, bilateral opacities on Chest imaging, all symptoms appeared within 1 week Predictable duration of mechanical ventilation shorter than 48 hours Contraindication to transesophageal echocardiography ALI group: Need for mechanical ventilation ALI criteria met: Respiratory failure not fully explained by cardiac failure, Pao2/FiO2&lt;300, bilateral opacities on Chest imaging, all symptoms appeared within 1 week Predictable duration of mechanical ventilation shorter than 48 hours Control Group: Need for mechanical ventilation for a nonrespiratory cause Need for FiO2&gt;30% Known cardiac abnormalities Cardiac drugs intake during last 24 hours</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>