<DOC>
	<DOCNO>NCT00516178</DOCNO>
	<brief_summary>A large body evidence accumulate show n-3 PUFAs exert extensive cardiac effect . The development commercial solution FO open perspective therapeutic application patient acute cardiac conditions.the 3 follow hypothesis address patient require cardiac surgery cardiopulmonary bypass myocardial infarction : perioperative /post-PTCA intravenous fish oil modifies composition membrane phospholipid platelet cardiac cell , blunts physiological response cardiac surgery/myocardial infarction , reduce incidence arrhythmia , reduce occurrence systolic dysfunction .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intravenous Fish Oil Critically Ill Cardiac Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A. Randomized trial 40 cardiac surgery patient Early rapid infusion fish oil ( 3 time 24 hour ) cardiac surgery patient . B. Randomized trial 20 myocardial infarction patient ( abandonned ) Continuous infusion dose 24hrs myocardial infarction patient Additional trial healthy volunteer ( investigate physiological change cardiac study ) : -Open trial 8 healthy lean volunteer investigate impact 0.6 g/kg FO dose IV ( Week 1 : 3hrs ) , orally week 2 , platelet n-3 PUFA incorporation , platelet function , heart rate peak flow response stress test .</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Critical Illness</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Coronary artery disease require elective surgical repair cardiopulmonary bypass Acute myocardial infarction require ICU management Absence consent Ventricular ejection fraction &lt; 35 % Beating heart surgery emergency surgery Hypercholesterolemia &gt; 5 mmol/l Thrombolysis Chronic steroid therapy Acute chronic renal failure prior surgery ( plasma creatinine &gt; 150 umol/l ) Chronic coagulation disorder Premenopausal female Consumption 3 time fish per week</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Fish oil supplement</keyword>
	<keyword>n-3 PUFA</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiac function</keyword>
	<keyword>Membrane incorporation</keyword>
	<keyword>Inflammation</keyword>
	<keyword>Clinical outcome</keyword>
</DOC>