<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00024401</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy use different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. PURPOSE: Phase II trial to study the effectiveness of DHA-paclitaxel in treating patients who have metastatic colorectal cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>DHA-Paclitaxel in Treating Patients With Metastatic Colorectal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. Determine the objective tumor response rate, duration of response, and time to disease progression in patients with metastatic colorectal cancer treated with DHA-paclitaxel. II. Determine the overall survival of patients treated with this drug. III. Determine the toxicity profile of this drug in these patients. IV. Assess the quality of life of patients treated with this drug. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Patients receive DHA-paclitaxel IV over 2 hours on day 1. Treatment repeats every 21 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Quality of life is assessed at baseline, every 2 courses, and at end of study treatment. Patients are followed every 3 months. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 18-50 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically or cytologically confirmed cancer of the colon or rectum Clinical evidence of metastatic disease Failed 1 prior chemotherapy regimen for metastatic disease Measurable disease No known or clinical evidence of CNS metastasis PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 18 and over Performance status: ECOG 01 Life expectancy: Not specified Hematopoietic: Absolute neutrophil count at least 1,500/mm3 Platelet count at least 100,000/mm3 Hepatic: Bilirubin no greater than 1.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) SGOT or SGPT no greater than 2.5 times ULN Renal: Creatinine no greater than 1.5 times ULN Cardiovascular: No uncontrolled ventricular arrhythmia No myocardial infarction within the past 3 months No superior vena cava syndrome Neurologic: No peripheral neuropathy greater than grade 1 No uncontrolled major seizure disorder No spinal cord compression Other: No unstable or serious concurrent medical condition No concurrent serious infection requiring parenteral therapy No other prior malignancy except: Curatively treated nonmelanoma skin cancer or carcinoma in situ of the cervix OR Other cancer curatively treated with surgery alone that has not recurred for more than 5 years No psychiatric disorder that would preclude study Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception during and for 6 months after study PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: No concurrent immunotherapy Chemotherapy: See Disease Characteristics No more than 1 prior chemotherapy regimen for metastatic disease No prior taxanes At least 28 days since prior chemotherapy and recovered No other concurrent chemotherapy Endocrine therapy: No concurrent hormonal therapy Radiotherapy: At least 28 days since prior largefield radiotherapy and recovered No concurrent radiotherapy Surgery: At least 14 days since prior major surgery and recovered</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2002</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage IV colon cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV rectal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent colon cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent rectal cancer</keyword>
</DOC>