<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02939157</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Assessment of pocket sized ultrasound (Vscan GE Healthcare) for diagnosing heart failure in primary care patients, with a comprehensive cardiac ultrasound examination (Siemens Acusan P10) performed at a specialized the eco.lab, as reference.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pocket-sized Ultrasound for Point-of-care Diagnosis of Heart Failure</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Waiting times for cardiac ultrasound is a cause of delay in identification of heart failure, which means delayed treatment, or that treatment recommendations are based on insufficient knowledge. Heart failure is a common condition; about 10% of 80-year-old people are affected and most patients are treated within primary care. A new ultrasound technology with integrated software support for interpretation (pocket-sized ultrasound) promises to improve care for heart patients and lead to earlier treatment with effective drugs. In cooperation with Norwegian researchers and the Region of Jämtland Härjedalen, this project opens opportunities for a significant medical innovation. The new concept, pocket-sized ultrasound for diagnosis of heart failure, has not previously been validated in patients seen in primary care. A new study may provide very important information that is directly applicable in the care of heart failure patients. We aim to recruit 250 study patients from the waiting list of patients referred from GPs, to ultrasound at the dpt. Of Clinical Physiology, Östersund Hospital, due to a suspicion of heart failure. The examinations will be carried out during the same day, with the investigators blinded to each other. The new concept of ultrasound has a potential to provide more cost-effective identification and monitoring of patients with heart failure in primary care.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Study patients fulfil all of the following criteria: 1. Age 20 and over 2. Recruited from primary care clinics, in the Region of Jämtland Härjedalen, Sweden. 3. Referred to comprehensive cardiac ultrasound (reference method) from GPs, due to suspected heart failure. 4. Provide written informed consent before enrolment. 1. Non consenting patients. 2. Patients in need of acute medical attention.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diagnostic Ultrasound</keyword>
	<keyword>Primary Care</keyword>
</DOC>