<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03062566</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The PreTBI III study aims to investigate the prognostic potential of prehospital and repeated in-hospital S100B, NSE and GFAP measurements as predictors of neurological outcome in patients suffering severe TBI. Knowledge on prehospital S100B, GFAP and NSE levels as predictors of neurological outcome and mortality may underline the potential of a point-of-care analysis. Possibly, the early biomarker levels may contributed to accurate monitoring of biomarker dynamics and hereby support neurosurgeons and anaesthetists in the clinical decision-making regarding treatment and level of care offered to the patient. Hypotheses: 1. Prehospital S100B level is a significant predictor of unfavourable neurological outcome (dichotomized disability rating scale (DRS) and glasgow outcome scale extended (GOS-E) measures) in severe TBI patients. 2. Prehospital GFAP level is a significant predictor of unfavourable neurological outcome (dichotomized DRS and GOSE measures) in severe TBI patients. 3. Prehospital NSE level is a significant predictor of unfavourable neurological outcome (dichotomized DRS and GOSE measures) in severe TBI patients. 4. combined panel of prehospital S100B, GFAP and NSE levels is a significant predictor of unfavourable neurological outcome (dichotomized DRS and GOSE measures) in severe TBI patients. 5. Unfavourable neurological outcome (dichotomized DRS and GOSE measures) in severe TBI patients can be predicted by dynamics in repeated measurements of S100B, GFAP and NSE.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prognostic Potential of Prehospital Biomarkers in TBI Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients presenting with Glasgow Coma Score (GCS) GCS 38 suffering relevant trauma and displaying relevant clinical indices compatible with TBI as evaluated by EMS staff. Patients are considered incompetent due to ongoing alteration of mental state. &gt;6 hours elapsed after trauma, unknown time of trauma, multi trauma, known dementia, chronic psychosis or active central nervous system (CNS) pathology.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>biomarkers</keyword>
	<keyword>point-of-care analysis</keyword>
</DOC>