<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01031082</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to identify and characterize the bacteria causing acute otitis media episode in HIV-positive and HIV-negative children (&gt;=3 months to &lt;5 years) in South Africa. Middle ear fluid sampling either by tympanocentesis or by careful sampling of spontaneous otorrhoea will be done; nasopharyngeal aspirate and urine sample will also be collected from the subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Identify and Characterize Bacteria Causing Acute Otitis Media in South African Children</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Otitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Otitis Media</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria for all subjects: Age: &gt;= 3 months and &lt; 5 years at the time of enrolment. Signs, symptoms, and conditions: One of the functional or general signs of otalgia,, conjunctivitis, fever and either Paradise's criteria or Spontaneous otorrhoea of less than 24 hours. Subject will be included as a treatment failure case. Written informed consent obtained from parent or guardian prior to study start. Inclusion criteria for HIVpositive subjects: Documented HIVpositive status as given in subject's medical records. or Subjects referred from paediatric HIV clinic. Inclusion criteria for HIVnegative subjects (including presumed negative children) Children who have been tested HIVnegative. Children whose mothers volunteer to have tested HIVnegative whilst pregnant with the index case and the child is free to any World Health Organization Grade II stigmata of HIV/acquired immunodeficiency syndrome. Children who do not fulfil the World Health Organization staging for HIV infection / immunosuppression. Hospitalised during the diagnosis of acute otitis media or during treatment. Otitis externa or otitis media with effusion. Presence of a transtympanic aerator. Systemic antibiotic treatment received for a disease other than acute otitis media in the 72 hours prior to enrolment. Receiving antimicrobial prophylaxis for recurrent acute otitis media but excluding cotrimoxazole or isoniazid prophylaxis in HIV exposed children. Provision of antibiotic by paediatrician/ENT specialist at the enrolment visit prior to the sampling of the middle ear fluid or spontaneous Otorrhoea. Children on antibiotics for acute otitis media who are clinically improving.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>3 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>5 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2010</verification_date>
</DOC>