<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00426244</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine to what extent and by what physiological mechanisms Osteopathic Manipulative Medicine (OMM) affects selected conditions related to pregnancy, labor and delivery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Osteopathic Manipulative Medicine in Pregnancy: Physiologic and Clinical Effects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The osteopathic philosophy of health is built on a model in which basic body functions are coordinated and integrated by the musculoskeletal system. Osteopathic medical students are taught to consider these aspects in assessing, diagnosing, and treating the individual patient. As a treatment method that reflects the osteopathic philosophy, osteopathic manipulative medicine (OMM) is a body-based modality in which the patient is evaluated and treated as a whole to improve physiologic functioning and remove impediments to optimal health and functioning. During pregnancy, a woman's body is challenged by significant and extensive physiological and biomechanical changes. Some physiological changes, such as increased fluid volume and sympathetic tone, may lead to consequences such as edema, preterm labor, and meconium-staining of the amniotic fluid. The biomechanical state of the woman's body is also drastically affected; as the fetus grows and the uterus expands, the center of gravity shifts forward, rotating the pelvis anteriorly and increasing the lordosis of the low back, and may also affect the motion of the hips and legs. These postural changes also have consequences such as low back pain, decreased functional status, and altered gait. Both these physiologic and biomechanical consequences can have a significant long-term impact on the health of the mother and child. OMM is theorized to facilitate the body's adjustment to the physiological and biomechanical demands of pregnancy and improve the outcomes of pregnancy, labor and delivery. Clinical case studies report reduced back pain, shorter labor, and fewer incidences of peripartum complications in patients who receive prenatal OMM. However, to date we have found no published systematic investigations of the efficacy of OMM in managing the adverse effects that pregnancy has on a woman's musculoskeletal system, nor have we found any published systematic studies to prove the mechanisms of action of OMM in managing pain, edema, or gait in pregnant patients. Thus, the overall question that guides this proposal is: to what extent and by what physiological mechanisms does Osteopathic Manipulative Medicine (OMM) affect selected conditions related to pregnancy, labor and delivery? Based on the principles and theories of OMM and the limited previous studies, the hypothesis of this study is that OMM improves clinical outcomes including low back pain, functional status, incidence of meconium-stained amniotic fluid, and complications of labor and delivery, and that the physiological changes related to improved autonomic regulation, peripheral hemodynamic regulation, and biomechanical changes related to gait are, in part, responsible for these clinical benefits.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Low Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The woman must have medical clearance from her obstetrician at each study visit Must be less than or at 30 weeks gestation at the start of the study Deemed high risk by the obstetrician (including but not limited to: abruptio placenta, placenta previa, severe preeclampsia/eclampsia, vaginal bleeding, gestational diabetes) Age 17 years or younger. Females 17 years of age and younger are considered pediatric high risk pregnancies and therefore ineligible for inclusion If a patient receives any other manual therapies such as massage, physical therapy, or chiropractic therapy, during the trial, she will be dropped from the study Subjects with a history of syncope either before or during this pregnancy will be excluded from participation in the substudy</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Osteopathic Manipulative Medicine</keyword>
	<keyword>Osteopathic Manipulative Treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>Pregnancy</keyword>
	<keyword>Physiologic</keyword>
	<keyword>Gait</keyword>
	<keyword>Low back pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Heart rate variability</keyword>
</DOC>