<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00565799</DOC>
	<brief_summary>PROTOCOL SUMMARY Type of Study: Pilot, randomized and single center trial Test Procedure: Omentectomy Aim 1. Determine the effect of omentectomy on 1) insulin sensitivity, 2) beta cell function and 3) plasma markers of inflammation We hypothesize that removal of omental fat increases insulin sensitivity and pancreatic sensitivity to glucose, and decreases systemic inflammation. Aim 2. Identify genes and proteins in adipocytes from obese patients that affect clinical presentation versus those that are affected by obesity for future study. We hypothesize that the genetic samples will help us to identify genes and proteins in adipocytes from obese patients that affect clinical presentation versus those that are affected by obesity and help us to design future obesity genetic studies. Total Enrollment Number: 30 patients who are scheduled to undergo bariatric surgery for weight loss at New York University Medical Center will be invited to participate in this study. Subjects will be randomly assigned, by using a computer-generated randomization scheme, in a single-blind fashion to either the omentectomy (n=15) or control group (n=15).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Pilot Study of Metabolic Effects of Omentectomy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Inclusion Criteria: - Patients who consented to undergo LAGB for weight loss and consent to participate in this study - BMI ≥35 kg/m2 - Confirmed T2DM treated with oral agents and/or only diet therapy - Age 18-64 years Exclusion Criteria: - Insulin therapy - Weight change (&gt;2% body weight) within 4 weeks before surgery - Patients with T2DM for more than 10 years Research Design- Pilot Study Event Week (approximate) Medical Screening (in conjunction with routine pre-op visit) -4 OGTT &amp; randomization -2 Preliminary genetic testing for the future study (blood sample) -2 Surgery with or without omentectomy 0 Preliminary genetic testing for the future study (fat sample) 0 Weight stabilization visit (in conjunction with routine post-op visit) 2 Weight stabilization visit (in conjunction with routine post-op visit) 4 OGTT 6 STUDY PLAN Study has approved by IRB, NYU School of Medicine Committee, GCRC, and Bellevue Hospital. Study initiation date: November 01, 2007 Enrollment period: Nov. 2007 to Nov. 2008 Study period: Nov. 2007 to Jan 2008</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Weight Loss</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients who consented to undergo LAGB for weight loss and consent to participate in this study BMI ≥35 kg/m2 Confirmed T2DM treated with oral agents and/or only diet therapy Age 1864 years Insulin therapy Weight change (&gt;2% body weight) within 4 weeks before surgery Patients with T2DM for more than 10 years</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>DM</keyword>
</DOC>