<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00565448</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective is to estimate the Complete Response rate of docetaxel to the combination of cisplatin-5-fluorouracil (TCF) compared to cisplatin-5-fluorouracil (CF) in the Induction treatment of Nasopharyngeal Carcinoma (NPC). The secondary objectives are to determine: - the safety of TCF in comparison to CF after induction treatment of NPC, - the pharmacokinetics of docetaxel when added to CF, - the Overall Response rate of TCF and CF on completion of induction and consolidation (chemo-radiotherapy) treatment of NPC, and to compare overall survival between TCF and CF.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Docetaxel in Combination With Cisplatin-5-fluorouracil for the Induction Treatment of Nasopharyngeal Carcinoma in Children and Adolescents</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Planned treatment duration: - induction period: 9 weeks of induction treatment - consolidation period: 9 weeks of chemoradiation treatment. The consolidation treatment was the same for all participants: radiation therapy for 7-8 weeks and 3 cycles of cisplatin 100 mg/m² every 3 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nasopharyngeal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histological diagnosis of nasopharyngeal carcinoma World Health Organization (WHO) type II or III Children and adolescents newly diagnosed with Stage IIBIV NPC with measurable disease, who are &gt;1 month to ≤21 years of age at the time of diagnosis. In France, participants must be ≥1 year to ≤21 years of age at the time of diagnosis Participants with short life expectancy Prior chemotherapy or radiotherapy to the nasopharynx or neck for the treatment of nasopharyngeal carcinoma Inadequate renal function evidenced by unacceptable laboratory results The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a participant's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Month</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Nasopharyngeal carcinoma</keyword>
</DOC>