<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02426372</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this open-label, dose-ranging, exploratory study is to evaluate the safety, tolerability, compliance, mechanism of action and efficacy of QBECO site specific immunomodulation for the induction of clinical response and remission in subjects with moderate to severe ulcerative colitis</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of QBECO in Moderate to Severe Ulcerative Colitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis, Ulcerative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female subjects who have reached age of majority Willing to learn and able to selfadminister study drug Diagnosis of UC established at least 6 months before screening visit, by clinical and endoscopic evidence. Currently experiencing moderate to severe active UC defined as a Mayo score of 612 (inclusive) at Screening. Endoscopic evidence of active mucosal disease, as assessed by flexible sigmoidoscopy, with an Endoscopic Finding Subscore of ≥2 at Screening. Rectal Bleeding Subscore of ≥1 at Screening. Physician's Global Assessment Subscore of ≥2 at Screening. Male/female subjects who agree to practice effective methods of contraception History of colonic or rectal surgery other than hemorrhoid surgery or appendectomy Currently receiving total parenteral nutrition Disease limited to ulcerative proctitis Diagnosed with Crohn's disease, indeterminate colitis, microscopic colitis or, ischemic or infectious colitis Any known allergy or hypersensitivity to killed wholecell bacterial vaccines or phenol Known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection or other immunosuppressive disorder Concurrently participating in another study or receiving other experimental or investigational therapies within past 3 months Females who are currently pregnant or lactating Any history of malignancy. Exceptions may apply for cervical cancer and some forms of skin cancer</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Ulcerative Colitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Inflammatory Bowel Disease</keyword>
</DOC>