<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00077207</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as carboplatin, vincristine, and temozolomide, work in different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. Giving more than one drug may kill more tumor cells. PURPOSE: This pilot study is studying giving carboplatin and vincristine together with temozolomide in treating children with progressive and/or symptomatic low-grade glioma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Carboplatin, Vincristine, and Temozolomide in Treating Children With Progressive and/or Symptomatic Low-Grade Glioma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Determine the feasibility and toxicity of an induction and maintenance regimen comprising carboplatin, vincristine, and temozolomide in children with progressive and/or symptomatic low-grade gliomas. Secondary - Determine response rate in patients treated with this regimen. - Determine 3-year progression-free survival and overall survival of patients treated with this regimen. - Correlate response and progression-free survival with the genomic profile of tumors in patients treated with this regimen. OUTLINE: This is a pilot study. - Induction therapy: Patients receive carboplatin IV over 1 hour on days 1, 8, 15, and 22; vincristine IV on days 1, 8, 15, 22, 29, and 36; and oral temozolomide on days 43-47. Four weeks after the completion of induction therapy, patients achieving stable or responding disease proceed to maintenance therapy. - Maintenance therapy: Patients receive carboplatin and temozolomide as in induction therapy and vincristine IV on days 1, 8, and 15. Treatment repeats every 10 weeks for a total of 6 courses in the absence of disease progression. Patients are followed every 3 months for 1 year, every 4 months for 1 year, every 6 months for 1 year, and then annually thereafter. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 30-50 patients will be accrued for this study within 2 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nervous System Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Central Nervous System Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Temozolomide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dacarbazine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vincristine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed progressive and/or symptomatic lowgrade glioma, including any of the following: WHO grade I or II astrocytoma Grade I or II oligodendrogliomas Mixed oligodendrogliomas Gangliogliomas Measurable disease Progressive and/or symptomatic supratentorial or spinal cord tumors that cannot be removed for anatomical reasons are allowed Optic pathway tumors allowed provided there is evidence of progressive disease by MRI and/or symptoms of deteriorating vision, progressive hypothalamic/pituitary dysfunction, or diencephalic syndrome Dorsally exophytic brainstem gliomas that were previously resected more than 50% are allowed provided the residual tumor shows progression (with or without symptoms) No diffuse brain stem tumors No type 1 neurofibromatosis PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age 10 and under Performance status ECOG 02 Lansky 50100% Life expectancy Not specified Hematopoietic Hemoglobin ≥ 8.0 gm/dL Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,000/mm^3 Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm^3 Hepatic Bilirubin ≤ 1.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) ALT &lt; 2.5 times ULN Renal Creatinine clearance or radioisotope glomerular filtration rate ≥ 70 mL/min OR Creatinine ≤ 0.8 mg/dL (age 5 and under) OR ≤ 1.0 mg/dL (age 6 to10) Other Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception during and for 2 months after study participation PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy No concurrent immunomodulating agents Chemotherapy No other concurrent anticancer chemotherapy Endocrine therapy Prior corticosteroids allowed No concurrent corticosteroids except for the treatment of increased intracranial pressure Radiotherapy Not specified Surgery See Disease Characteristics Prior surgery allowed Other No other prior therapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>10 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>untreated childhood cerebellar astrocytoma</keyword>
	<keyword>untreated childhood visual pathway and hypothalamic glioma</keyword>
	<keyword>childhood spinal cord neoplasm</keyword>
	<keyword>childhood oligodendroglioma</keyword>
	<keyword>childhood low-grade cerebral astrocytoma</keyword>
</DOC>