<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01585584</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to test the potential antiviral efficacy of triple-combination therapy with Peginterferon α-2b + ribavirin + boceprevir (PRB) in patients with HCV genotype 3 who previously failed Peginterferon α + ribavirin (non-responders or relapsers).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Triple-Therapy in Patients With HCV Genotype 3 Who Previously Failed Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>i) Obtain preliminary information on the association between important baseline and on-treatment factors and SVR in this patient population. Variables to be examined may include gender, age, advanced fibrosis or cirrhosis (F3 or F4 estimated by Fibroscan), baseline viral load, RVR, wk 8 viral load, end-of-treatment viral response. ii) Evaluate adverse events. iii) Evaluate viral resistance.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Protease Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects will be eligible for the study if they meet the following inclusion criteria: 1. 18 years of age or older 2. Infected with HCV genotype 3 (mixed genotypes are NOT permitted) 3. Have received at least 12 weeks of previous treatment with peginterferonα + ribavirin 4. Detectable serum HCVRNA 5. No significant comorbid conditions 6. Liver biopsy is not necessary 7. Cirrhotic patients will be eligible to participate if ChildPugh class A (maximum 15% of subjects) Subjects will be excluded from participation in this study if the following conditions are present: 1. Significant comorbidities: uncontrolled psychiatric conditions including severe depression, cardiovascular, respiratory, renal or metabolic conditions, active carcinoma. 2. Active substance abuse within the past 12 months 3. Coinfection with hepatitis B or HIV 4. Decompensated cirrhosis (ChildPugh class B or C) 5. Significant cytopenia any of the following: platelets &lt;80 x 109/L, neutropenia &lt;1.2 x 103/L, Hb &lt;120 g/l for men or 110 g/l for women 6. Lack of informed consent 7. Previous nullresponders (&lt;2 log10 decrease at week 12 with previous PR therapy)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Boceprevir</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatitis C Genotype 3</keyword>
</DOC>