<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01057888</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators will design and implement a randomized clinical trial to test, on a community-wide level, the effectiveness of managed care based tracking/reminder/recall on improving vaccination coverage among adolescents. The investigators propose a randomized controlled trial to evaluate the effectiveness of reminder/recall for adolescents: 10,599 adolescents within the managed care organization (MCO) will be randomized into one of three arms: 1) mailed reminders, 2) autodialer telephone messages or 3) standard of care of their practice (no messages from the intervention). Hypothesis 1: Reminder/recall will increase the receipt of immunizations and preventive services Hypothesis 2: Telephone (autodialer) reminders will be more effective than mailed reminders Hypothesis 3: The impact of reminders will be greatest for the most high-risk subgroups which have low baseline immunization rates. Hypothesis 4: Mailed reminders will be more costly (and less effective) than telephone reminders.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Vaccination Reminder/Recall Systems for Adolescent Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Member of the Monroe Plan for Medical Care (managed care organization) Patient of a participating practice Ages 10.75 to &lt;18 years of age Member of the Monroe Plan for Medical care for less than 6 months ICD9 diagnosis of 999.4 for anaphylactic reaction to a vaccine or its components. Encephalopathy within 7 days of a previous dose of a pertussis containing vaccine not attributable to another identifiable cause GuillainBarre ICD9 code is 357.0</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>11 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Immunization status for:</keyword>
	<keyword>Tdap</keyword>
	<keyword>Menactra</keyword>
	<keyword>HPV (if female)</keyword>
	<keyword>Well child care visit</keyword>
</DOC>