<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01449695</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate whether a nurse-based intervention, consisting of structural informative consulting and motivational counseling, on top of usual care with or without personalized web-based visualization of cardiovascular risk levels, improves the medication adherence in high risk cardiovascular patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intervention to Improve Medication Adherence in Cardiovascular Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Poor adherence to medication is one of the limitations in the treatment of cardiovascular disease. As a consequence the risk of premature death, hospital admissions and related costs is increasing. Therefore, detection of apparent poor adherence and interventions to improve adherence, are of great importance to enhance cardiovascular risk management over time. This study is a prospective randomized trial, which compares 1) usual care with 2) the effect of a personalized visualization of cardiovascular risk levels (website) to support self management and 3) the additional effect of a communication intervention by a nurse on adherence on top of 2). Adherence is determined and continuously monitored with a dedicated calculation of refill data obtained from patient's pharmacy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All subsequent patients, included in the hospitalscreening program with manifestations of atherosclerotic disease (acute coronary syndrome, peripheral arterial disease or stroke/TIA) or elevated cardiovascular risk due to hypertension, diabetes or hyperlipidemia. Age below 18 years, actual pregnancy, problems with Dutch language or logistic problems, which may hinder intervention on adherence behavior. Severe comorbidity, including mental handicap, according to their physician.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>PAD</keyword>
	<keyword>CVA</keyword>
	<keyword>ACS</keyword>
</DOC>