<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01449448</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Injection with corticosteroid is one of the most common non-operative interventions in the treatment of subacromial impingement; however, its use is limited by its potential side effects (e.g. tendon rupture, subcutaneous atrophy, articular cartilage changes). The objective of this study was to compare the efficacy of subacromial injection of triamcinolone compared to injection of ketorolac. Thirty-two patients diagnosed with external shoulder impingement syndrome were included in this double-blinded randomized controlled clinical trial. Each patient was randomized into the Steroid group or NSAID group.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Subacromial Injection With Corticosteroid Versus Nonsteroidal Anti-inflammatory Drugs (NSAID) in Shoulder Impingement Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>After a single injection into the subacromial space, the patients were instructed to perform home physical therapy and follow-up in four weeks. Each patient was evaluated in terms of arc of motion, Visual Analog Scale and the UCLA Shoulder Rating Scale. The outcome measures were taken at the preinjection state, immediately post injection, and at 4 weeks follow-up.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bursitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Shoulder Impingement Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone hexacetonide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone Acetonide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ketorolac</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ketorolac Tromethamine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone diacetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Inflammatory Agents, Non-Steroidal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Shoulder pain characteristic of subacromial impingement syndrome with passive and/or active abduction in the 60120 arc of motion (positive impingement sign) 2. Diagnosis of subacromial bursitis based on tenderness to palpation anterior/lateral to the acromion. Pain may be exacerbated with the shoulder held in internal rotation (positive Hawkins test) 1. Age &lt;18 years 2. Symptoms less than one month 3. Previous shoulder injections within the past 3 months 4. Evidence of osacromiale or other confounding shoulder pathology on plain radiographs 5. Evidence of shoulder osteoarthritis 6. Full thickness rotator cuff tear evidenced by MRI, cuff weakness after lidocaine injection, or positive droparm sign 7. Systemic inflammatory condition 8. Pending litigation or workrelated claims related to the shoulder 9. Previous shoulder surgery on the affected shoulder 10. Evidence of local infection 11. Evidence of adhesive capsulitis 12. Previous history of gastrointestinal ulcers or bleeding disorders 13. Evidence of shoulder instability</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>pain relief</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypermobility, Joint</keyword>
	<keyword>increased strength</keyword>
	<keyword>increased patient satisfaction</keyword>
</DOC>