<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00086840</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase II trial is studying how well CCI-779 works in treating patients with relapsed or refractory chronic lymphocytic leukemia. Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as CCI-779, work in different ways to stop cancer cells from dividing so they stop growing or die</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>CCI-779 in Treating Patients With Relapsed or Refractory Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. Determine the activity of CCI-779 in patients with relapsed, refractory, or transformed chronic lymphocytic leukemia. OUTLINE: Patients are stratified according to disease (relapsed or refractory chronic lymphocytic leukemia [CLL] vs transformed CLL). Patients receive CCI-779 IV over 30 minutes on days 1, 8, 15, and 22. Treatment repeats every 28 days for up to 6 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Patients achieving an objective response may receive 3 consolidation courses of therapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, Chronic, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Large B-Cell, Diffuse</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hodgkin Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL) Relapsed, refractory, or transformed disease Relapsed disease defined as symptomatic loss of a prior partial or complete response to a regimen containing a purine analog and/or a monoclonal antibody AND evidence of disease progression Primary resistant disease defined as failure to achieve an objective response to a regimen containing a purine analog and/or a monoclonal antibody Transformed CLL (Richters transformation), must meet both of the following criteria: Histologically confirmed lymphoma Measurable disease No CNS disease Performance status ECOG 02 Bilirubin ≤ 2 mg/dL (unless elevated due to Gilbert's disease) SGOT and SGPT &lt; 3 times upper limit of normal Creatinine ≤ 2 mg/dL (unless due to organ leukemic involvement) No symptomatic congestive heart failure No unstable angina pectoris No cardiac arrhythmia Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception HIVpositive patients allowed provide CD4 counts are normal and no AIDSdefining disease is present No history of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biological composition to CCI779 No ongoing or active infection No psychiatric illness or social situation that would preclude study compliance No other concurrent uncontrolled illness See Disease Characteristics No concurrent prophylactic hematopoietic colonystimulating factors See Disease Characteristics More than 2 weeks since prior cytotoxic chemotherapy and recovered More than 2 weeks since prior radiotherapy and recovered No other concurrent investigational or antitumor agents No other concurrent cytotoxic agents No concurrent combination antiretroviral therapy for HIVpositive patients</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>