<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03036423</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to test whether certain brain training activities can promote cognitive, emotional, and physical health in caregivers of a spouse with dementia. Numerous studies show that family dementia caregiving can be stressful, and can increase mental and physical health risks. This study aims to understand how to reduce those risks.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cognitive Training for Older Caregivers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Stress, Psychological</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Englishspeaking (consent process and assessments will be conducted in English only) Currently living with, and the primary caregiver for, a spouse with dementia—for the purposes of this study, "spouse" may also include couples who had divorced or were legally separated from each other, or who had never married each other but were in established relationships ('significant others'). Currently experiencing moderate to high levels of perceived stress and caregiver burden. Spousal caregivers will be screened for stress levels and caregiving burden using the 10item Perceived Stress Scale (PSS 10) and the Modified Caregiver Strain Index (MCSI), respectively. Caregivers scoring above the population mean (approx.) on the PSS 10 (&gt; 11), reporting at least moderate caregiver strain (score &gt; 5) on the MCSI will be eligible for participation. cognitive impairment or dementia (identified by the Montreal Cognitive Assessment (MoCA) score &lt; 24) current major depression (current Major Depression diagnosis and/or Geriatric Depression Scale (GDS 15) score &gt; 10) no recent (within 2 months) major surgery History of events that cause neurological injury (e.g., stroke, transient ischemic attack, traumatic brain injury or head injury with loss of consciousness) Serious psychiatric or alcohol/substance use disorders, including current alcohol dependence, current nonalcohol psychoactive substance use dependence, psychotic disorders or features (current and lifetime), bipolar disorder (determined from Mini International Neuropsychiatric Exam (MINI) modules) Autoimmune disorder (e.g., Crohn's disease, lupus, rheumatoid arthritis) Active neoplastic disease or receiving immunosuppressive therapy for cancer (or &lt; 6 months postchemo or radiation) or other diseases (&lt; 3 months prior to enrollment) No significant immunodeficiency disorder (e.g., alymphocytosis, hepatitis B or C, HIV) Serious cardiovascular disease (e.g., congestive heart failure, pacemaker) or myocardial infarction within past 6 months Physical condition precluding required activities as part of the computerized cognitive training (e.g., inability to use a computer mouse; inadequate visual acuity)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>