<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03036813</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A Phase 3, Double-blind, Randomized, Placebo-controlled, Multicenter Study of GBT440 Administered Orally to Patients With Sickle Cell Disease</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Evaluate the Effect of GBT440 Administered Orally to Patients With Sickle Cell Disease (GBT_HOPE)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized, placebo-controlled, double blind, parallel group, multicenter study of participants, age 12 to 65 years, with SCD. The key purpose for the study is to establish efficacy and safety of GBT440 as compared with placebo.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anemia, Sickle Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male or female study participants with sickle cell disease 2. Participants have had at least 1 episode of vasoocclusive crisis (VOC) in the past 12 months. 3. Age 12 to 65 years 4. Hemoglobin (Hb) ≥6.0 and ≤10.5 g/dL during screening 5. For participants taking hydroxyurea (HU), the dose of HU (mg/kg) must be stable for at least 3 months prior to signing the ICF. 1. More than 10 VOCs within the past 12 months that required a hospital, emergency room or clinic visit 2. Patients who are receiving regularly scheduled blood (RBC) transfusion therapy (also termed chronic, prophylactic, or preventive transfusion) or have received a RBC transfusion for any reason within 28 days of signing the ICF 3. Hospitalized for sickle cell crisis or other vasoocclusive event within 14 days of signing the ICF (i.e., a vasoocclusive event cannot be within 14 days prior to signing the ICF) 4. Hepatic dysfunction characterized by alanine aminotransferase (ALT) &gt;4 × upper limit of normal 5. Severe renal dysfunction (estimated glomerular filtration rate at the Screening visit; calculated by the central laboratory) &lt;30 mL/min/1.73 m^2 or on chronic dialysis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>