<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="44717">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02524158</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>O7768-R</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02524158</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Yoga for Veterans With CLBP</brief_title>
  <official_title>Yoga Therapy to Improve Function Among Veterans With Chronic Low Back Pain</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>VA Office of Research and Development</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>VA Office of Research and Development</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Chronic low back pain (CLBP) is a prevalent condition among VA patients, but many current
      treatment options have limited effectiveness. In addition to chronic pain, people with
      chronic low back pain experience increased disability, psychological symptoms such as
      depression, and reduced health-related quality of life. This randomized controlled study
      will examine the impact of yoga therapy for improving function and decreasing pain in VA
      patients with chronic low back pain. Although not every VA patient with chronic low back
      pain will choose to do yoga, it is an inexpensive treatment modality that is increasingly
      appealing to many VA patients. If yoga is effective, it could become an additional low-cost
      option that the VA can offer to better serve Veterans with chronic low back pain.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Outcomes Assessor</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Roland-Morris Disability Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 12 weeks, 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcomes is the change in Roland-Morris Disability score between baseline and 12-weeks. The questionnaire consists of 23 questions that ask about limitations experienced for a variety of daily activities. The scale has been shown to be reliable and is well validated. It has been used in another yoga RCT, allowing for comparisons.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain Intensity - Brief Pain Inventory</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 12 weeks, 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>The short version of the Brief Pain Inventory (BPI) is a self-rated questionnaire designed to assess the severity of pain and the impact of pain on daily functions in the past day and week69. The time required to do the BPI test ranges from 5 minutes (short form) to 10 minutes (long form). The BPI takes about 5 minutes to complete and has been validated with low back pain patients70. It has been shown to respond to both behavioral and pharmacological pain interventions. The BPI measures severity of pain, impact of pain on daily function, location of pain, pain medications, and amount of pain relief. Items are answered utilizing a scoring algorithm, but &quot;worst pain&quot; or the mean of the 4 severity items can be used as measures of pain severity and the mean of the 7 interference items can be used a as a measure of pain interference. The BPI has acceptable reliability (Cronbach's alpha ranges from .77 to .91).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain Interference - Brief Pain Inventory</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 12 weeks, 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>The short version of the Brief Pain Inventory (BPI) is a self-rated questionnaire designed to assess the severity of pain and the impact of pain on daily functions in the past day and week69. The time required to do the BPI test ranges from 5 minutes (short form) to 10 minutes (long form). The BPI takes about 5 minutes to complete and has been validated with low back pain patients70. It has been shown to respond to both behavioral and pharmacological pain interventions. The BPI measures severity of pain, impact of pain on daily function, location of pain, pain medications, and amount of pain relief. Items are answered utilizing a scoring algorithm, but &quot;worst pain&quot; or the mean of the 4 severity items can be used as measures of pain severity and the mean of the 7 interference items can be used a as a measure of pain interference. The BPI has acceptable reliability (Cronbach's alpha ranges from .77 to .91).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Center for Epidemiologic Studies Short Depression Scale (CES-D 10)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 12 weeks, 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Depression will be assessed using the Center for Epidemiologic Studies Short Depression Scale (CES-D 10)71. Derived from the full CES-D72, there are 10 items that ask about the frequency of mood symptoms, rated on a 4-point Likert scale ranging from 0 (Never) to 3 (All of the Time). A number of items are reverse-scored and a score of 10 or greater is considered depressed. Normative data on people with assorted chronic illnesses are available for comparisons.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Brief Anxiety Inventory (BAI)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 12 weeks, 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>The Brief Anxiety Inventory (BAI) measures the severity of anxiety symptoms, particularly those that distinguish anxiety from depression. The BAI consists of 21 items, is self-administered and can be completed in 5 to 10 minutes. Items are scored on a scale of 0 to 4 and are summed to generate a total score. The BAI was developed using a sample of psychiatric outpatients73. Its reliability and validity are well established.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Short-form 12 (SF12)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 12 weeks, 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Health-related quality of life will be measured using the Short-form 12 (SF12). Based on the longer SF-36, the SF-12 was developed with the objective of finding a short yet meaningful measure of generic HRQOL or global health status. The 12 items recommended for inclusion in the SF-12 were selected from the SF-36 and tested through a series of stages75. The PCS-12 and MCS-12 show similar levels of precision to the summary scores derived from the longer 36-item measure. Furthermore, sensitivity to change was similar for the shorter version.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Self-efficacy for managing low back pain</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 12 weeks, 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Self-efficacy for controlling CLBP reflects levels of confidence in the ability to influence the intensity of back pain symptoms and the impact that CLBP has on daily life. The questions are based on self-efficacy items developed by Lorig et al. in mixed chronic diseases76. The wording of the items has been adapted to be specific to CLBP (see Appendix 2). The measure consists of 6 items, rated on a 6-point Likert scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fatigue Severity Scale (FSS)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 12 weeks, 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Fatigue (absence of energy) will be measured with the Fatigue Severity Scale (FSS). The FSS is a self-administered instrument developed to assess the impact and severity of fatigue77. It consists of 9 items describing the functional impact of fatigue on daily life rated on a scale from 1 (strongly disagree) to 7 (strongly agree) with the total fatigue score ranging from 9-63 or an average score ranging from 1.0-7.0. Higher scores reflect greater fatigue severity and less energy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Attendance/ Home practice</measure>
    <time_frame>total # of sessions attended at end of 12 week intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Two indicators of the amount of yoga practiced by each participant will be used. Actual attendance of yoga sessions will be assessed using VA medical record data. Self-reported practice of yoga at home will be assessed using a weekly participant yoga log. The self-report yoga log assesses whether they practiced yoga each day, the amount of time practiced, the use of instructions, the difficulty of poses, and the estimated level of physical activity or exertion.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Range of Motion</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 12 weeks, 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Spinal Range of Motion (ROM) will be measured using a Saunders Digital Inclinometer, a portable device which isolates lumbar ROM (flexion and extension). The device is placed along the spine and uses a precise optical angular scanner. The device error is negligible. Gross flexion accuracy was measured at 99% accurate and pelvic flexion accuracy was measured at 98% accuracy79. The device has been used in other yoga interventions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Grip Strength</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 12 weeks, 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Grip strength in both hands of each participant will be measured using an adjustable, hydraulic grip strength dynamometer (Jamar Hydraulic Hand Dynamometer).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Lower Limb Strength and Balance</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 12 weeks, 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>The Single Leg Stance (SLS) is a commonly used measure of both lower leg strength and balance</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Lumbar Spine Stabilization Endurance</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 12 weeks, 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Prone and supine bridge maneuvers will be used to assess core stabilization.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">152</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Low Back Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Yoga</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The yoga intervention will consist of 2x weekly, 60-minute Hatha Yoga classes for 12 weeks, geared toward a CLBP population. Classes begin with a few minutes of simple seated breathing exercises. Depending on their mobility, participants can sit either on the floor or on a chair. This is followed by gentle warm-up stretches. Participants are then led through a series of standing postures, seated postures and floor postures. The difficulty of the poses will gradually increase over the duration of the 12 weeks, and appropriate modifications are offered to participants whenever needed. Deep and rhythmic breathing will be emphasized throughout. Each class will end with a supine resting pose.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Delayed Treatment Control - Usual Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants randomly assigned to this arm are allowed to continue all existing treatments. Participants and their primary care physician are asked to not change treatments unless medically necessary. participants are asked to not do yoga for 6 months. They are given free yoga and a yoga mat after 6 months.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Yoga Therapy for CLBP</intervention_name>
    <description>Classes begin with a few minutes of simple seated breathing exercises. Depending on their mobility, participants can sit either on the floor or on a chair. This is followed by gentle warm-up stretches. Participants are then led through a series of standing postures, seated postures and floor postures. The difficulty of the poses will gradually increase over the duration of the 12 weeks, and appropriate modifications are offered to participants whenever needed. Deep and rhythmic breathing will be emphasized throughout. Each class will end with a supine resting pose.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Yoga</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Has a VA primary care provider

          -  Diagnosis of chronic low back pain &gt; 6 months

          -  Willing to attend a yoga program or be assigned to delayed treatment with yoga

          -  Willing to complete 4 assessments

          -  English Literacy

          -  Has not begun new pain treatments or medications in the past month

          -  Willing to not change pain treatments (e.g., discontinue a treatment; increase
             medication dose) during the 12-week intervention period unless medically necessary

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  back surgery within the last 12 months

          -  back pain due to specific systemic problem (eg, lupus, scleroderma, fibromyalgia)

          -  morbid obesity (BMI &gt; 40)

          -  Significant sciatica or nerve compression &lt; 3 months or chronic lumbar radicular pain
             &gt; 3 months

          -  Unstable, serious coexisting medical illness (eg, CHF, cancer, COPD, morbid obesity;
             dementia)

          -  Unstable, serious psychiatric illness (e.g., unmanaged psychosis, active substance
             dependence)

          -  Insufficient data to rule out acute, metastatic disease, (unless primary care
             physician approves)

          -  Attended or practiced yoga &gt; 1x in the last 12 months

          -  Positive Romberg test (with or without sensory neuropathy)
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Erik J Groessl, PhD BA BS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>VA San Diego Healthcare System, San Diego, CA</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>VA San Diego Healthcare System, San Diego, CA</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Diego</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92161</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 3, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>August 10, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Yoga</keyword>
  <keyword>Mind-Body Therapies</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic Low Back Pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Military Veterans</keyword>
  <keyword>VA patients</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Low Back Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
