<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02166528</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Female pelvic floor dysfunction (FPD) is due to defects in the pelvic support structures, degradation, damage or dysfunction. The main problem of which is pelvic organ prolapse(POP), urinary incontinence(UI) and genital tract injury. Although it does not pose a serious threat to life, but affect the patient's quality of life seriously in the physical, psychological, social behavior and other aspects. With the growing aging population, the incidence rate has gradually increased, and increasing demands for people's quality of life simultaneously, more and more attention was raised to PFD as common chronic diseases. In recent years, the basic research, epidemiology, prevention, diagnosis and treatment of PFD have made great progress, especially in developing gynecological urology theory and reconstructive pelvic surgery. But overall the basic research of PFD is lagging behind, especially susceptibility gene localization and functional studies did not get enough attention.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Study of Genes Localization for Female Pelvic Floor Dysfunction</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>1. female aging from 30 to 70year old; 2. preoperative diagnosis of gynecologic malignancies; 3. have the ability to comply with Research programs; 4. voluntarily participate in the study and signed an informed consent form 1. patients with severe cardiovascular diseases, kidney, liver and other vital organs diseases, bone marrow disease and mental illness; 2. patients suffering from autoimmune diseases; 3. patients with acute infectious disease or infection early phase of infection; 4. patients with urinary tract infection; 5. patients with infection or erosion of anogenital skin; 6. for any other reason, the researchers considered unsuitable for inclusion.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>female pelvic floor dysfunction</keyword>
	<keyword>pelvic organ prolaps</keyword>
	<keyword>urinary incontinence</keyword>
	<keyword>massively parallel sequencing</keyword>
</DOC>