<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02166047</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will evaluate the safety, tolerability, and efficacy of GS-9620 in virologically suppressed adults with chronic hepatitis B virus (HBV) infection who are currently being treated with oral antivirals (OAV). Participants will be randomized in 3 sequential cohorts. Within each cohort, participants will be randomized in a 1:3:3:3 ratio to placebo or one of the doses of GS-9620 (1, 2, or 4 mg) and all participants will continue on their current oral antiviral treatment for the entire duration of the study. Cohorts A, B, and C will consist of a different treatment period of 4, 8, or 12 weeks, respectively, and will be followed to Week 48. After Cohort A completes treatment, a safety review will be conducted by an external data monitoring committee prior to beginning Cohort B. Another safety review will be conducted after Cohort B completes treatment prior to beginning Cohort C.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of GS-9620 for the Treatment of Chronic Hepatitis B Virus in Virally-Suppressed Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Must have the ability to understand and sign a written informed consent form; consent must be obtained prior to initiation of study procedures Documented evidence of chronic HBV infection (e.g. HBsAg positive for more than 6 months) with detectable HBsAg levels at screening Have been on approved HBV OAV treatment for ≥ 1 year prior to screening, with HBV DNA below lower limit of quantitation (LLOQ), measured at least once, 6 or more months prior to screening, and HBV DNA &lt; 20 IU/ml at screening Currently taking an approved HBV OAV (tenofovir, entecavir, adefovir, lamivudine or telbivudine, either as single agents or in combination) with no change in regimen for 3 months prior to screening Willing to provide blood sample for tolllike receptor 7 (TLR7) and interleukin 28 B (IL28B) singlenucleotide polymorphism (SNP) assessment Must be willing and able to comply with all study requirements Extensive bridging fibrosis or cirrhosis Lab parameters not within defined thresholds for neutropenia, anemia, thrombocytopenia, leukopenia, or other evidence of inadequate liver function Coinfection with hepatitis C virus (HCV), HIV, or hepatitis D virus (HDV) Evidence of hepatocellular carcinoma Malignancy within 5 years prior to screening, with the exception of specific cancers that are cured by surgical resection (basal cell skin cancer, etc). Participants under evaluation for possible malignancy are not eligible Significant cardiovascular, pulmonary, or neurological disease Any of the following conditions that may worsen in response to interferon (IFN): Autoimmune disease (e.g. lupus erythematosus, rheumatoid arthritis, inflammatory bowel disease, sarcoidosis, moderate or severe psoriasis) Poorly controlled diabetes mellitus Significant psychiatric disorders Thyroid disorder (unless controlled under treatment) Significant pulmonary diseases (e.g. chronic obstructive pulmonary disease) Retinal disease Immunodeficiency disorders Received solid organ or bone marrow transplant Received prolonged therapy with immunomodulators (e.g. corticosteroids) or biologics (e.g. monoclonal Ab, interferon) within 3 months of screening Use of another investigational agents within 3 months of screening Current alcohol or substance abuse judged by the investigator to potentially interfere with compliance Females who are pregnant or may wish to become pregnant during the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hepatitis B</keyword>
	<keyword>HBV</keyword>
	<keyword>GS-9620</keyword>
	<keyword>TLR-7 Agonist</keyword>
</DOC>