<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01620398</DOC>
	<brief_summary>There are no studies exploring the benefits of a diet composed of typical Brazilian food in the secondary prevention of cardiovascular diseases. Randomized studies show that the Mediterranean diet is beneficial for patients with established cardiovascular disease or in risk for CVD development. Indeed, nutritional composition of the Mediterranean Diet is one of main references for dietary guidelines for treatment and prevention of CVD in Brazil and the world. However, in many countries, such as Brazil, most foods of the Mediterranean diet are not widely available, may be expensive or are not part of population eating habits. So, the prescription of the Mediterranean diet intervention for cardiovascular disease to the Brazilian population may not be feasible, leading to a low adherence. In this context, patients with established CVD have a low compliance to nutritional prescription. The BALANCE Program, considers 3 concepts: a) A dietary prescription guided by nutritional content recommendations from the Brazilian national guidelines; b) A nutritional education program based on fun, playful strategies and suggestions of affordable foods; and c) Intensive follow-up through one-on-one visits, group sessions, and phone calls. This is the first proposal to use these concepts concurrently with the objective to increase adherence of secondary prevention patients to the diet proposed by the guidelines. Therefore, this trial will investigate the effects of the Program on reducing cardiovascular events - such as cardiac arrest, acute myocardial infarction (AMI), stroke, myocardial revascularization, amputation for peripheral arterial disease, and hospitalization for unstable angina - or death in patients with established CVD. Moreover, it will evaluate the effects of the dietary program on reducing CV factors, such as BMI, waist circumference,</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Brazilian Cardioprotective Nutritional Program Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The BALANCE Program will investigate the effect of the Program in reducing cardiovascular events, such as cardiac arrest, acute myocardial infarction, stroke, myocardial revascularization, amputation for peripheral arterial disease, hospitalization for unstable angina, or death in patients with established cardiovascular disease. Moreover we aim to evaluate the effect of the dietary program on reducing cardiovascular risk factors, such as body mass index, waist circumference, blood pressure, total cholesterol, low density lipoprotein (LDL), triglycerides and fasting glucose. Also it is our objective to compare the dietary patterns after interventions, the effect of the intervention among nutrients and energy consumption and, finally, to evaluate the BALANCE Program comprehension. The BALANCE Program is a randomized, multicenter, national trial with allocation concealment and intention-to-treat analysis. We will randomize patients aged 45 years or more with any evidence of established cardiovascular disease to the BALANCE program or control groups. BALANCE Program is composed by 3 concepts: a) a diet that provides 50-60% of energy from carbohydrate, 10-15% from protein, 25-35% from total fat, &lt;7% from saturated fatty acids, &lt;10% polyunsaturated fatty acids, &lt;20% monounsaturated fatty acids, &lt;1% trans fats, &lt;200 mg/day cholesterol, 20-30 g/day fiber, and &lt;2,400 mg/day sodium; b) Nutrition education program based on ludic strategies and indication of affordable foods; c) An intense follow up by individual and group visits and phone calls. For Control group, generalized advices to follow a low fat, low energy, low sodium and low cholesterol diet are given. The primary composite outcome is the occurrence of cardiovascular death, cardiac arrest, acute myocardial infarction, stroke, and myocardial revascularization, amputation for peripheral arterial disease or hospitalization for unstable angina. Blinded assessors will adjudicate clinical events and analysis will follow the intention-to-treat principle. We enrolled 2536 patients in 34 sites. Enrollment was open in March 2013 and ended in March 2015 and patients will be followed up to 48 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Any evidence of coronary artery disease (CAD) over the past 10 years, as defined by any of the following criteria: History of angina (clinical diagnosis, even without exams) History of stroke History of abnormal segmental wall motion in cardiac echocardiography (even without symptoms) or a fixed segmental defect in radionuclide imaging test (even if no symptoms) History of a positive stress test with radionuclide stress test on echocardiography or pharmacologic cardiovascular stress testing demonstrating ischemic heart disease History of coronary angiography or coronary angiography atherosclerotic stenosis ≥ 50% diameter in any coronary artery ECG with pathological Qwaves in two contiguous leads. Any evidence of stroke or TIA in the past 10 years, as defined by any of the following criteria: Medical diagnosis of stroke or TIA Evidence of previous stroke Peripheral Arterial Disease (PAD) in the last 10 years, defined by a diagnosis of current or previous history of any of the following criteria: Intermittent claudication amputation Vascular surgery for atherosclerotic disease Value ankle/arm &lt;0.90 for systolic blood pressure in either leg at rest Angiography or Doppler showing&gt; 70% stenosis in an artery noncardiac Current or previous hospitalization for unstable angina Refusal to provide Informed Consent Statement neurocognitive or psychiatric condition that prevents obtaining reliable clinical data (defined by clinical trial investigators) Life expectancy less than 6 months Pregnancy or lactation Severe hepatic encephalopathy Renal Failure with indication for dialysis Congestive heart failure Patients with organ transplants prior Wheelchair Difficulty in receiving oral diet</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>cardiovascular diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>secondary prevention</keyword>
	<keyword>diet</keyword>
</DOC>