<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02168465</DOC>
	<brief_summary>1. Design and develop web-based self-management intervention to improve catheter-related outcomes and quality of life in people with spinal cord injury (SCI). 2. Conduct a pilot study to assess the feasibility (i.e., acceptability and usability of the website application) and preliminary effectiveness of this new self-management intervention. 3. Develop and test the reliability of new/modified measures (intermittent catheter self-efficacy and self-management).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Internet Self-Management for People With Intermittent Urinary Catheters</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Stages involve: (1) Develop an Internet-based intervention to improve self-management and outcomes related to clean intermittent catheterization (CIC) among people with SCI (2) Pretest the Internet application with five persons with SCI using CIC; and (3) Conduct a web-based six-month intervention pilot study in a group of 30 with SCI using CIC. Outcomes are: catheter-related adverse health outcomes (e.g., UTI, urine leakage), CIC self- management, CIC self-efficacy, health related expenditures and quality of life. Information from this study will be used to modify the Internet application for a future Phase 2 trial in a larger study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Spinal Cord Injuries</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Individuals will be included if they are English speaking adults over 18 years with an SCI and are interested in participating. Inclusion criteria are: 1. use of CIC for regular bladder drainage, 2. expect to use CIC indefinitely or for at least nine months, and 3. access to and ability to use a computer and telephone. Computer and telephone use may be voice activated for those with little hand use. Study participants do not need to perform CIC entirely themselves, as people with limited hand dexterity may have caregivers who do the procedure. They do need to be able to use the computer and telephone however. Additional inclusion criteria for the five persons in the "intervention and pretesting group" (described below in III, 1) include: 1. having used CIC for regular bladder drainage for at least one year and 2. expect to use CIC indefinitely or for at least one more year. People will need to have used CIC for at least a year so that they are well experienced in CIC because the two Peer Leaders will be selected from this group. People will be excluded if they cannot communicate in English, Are terminally ill, or are expected to discontinue CIC within the next nine months. NonEnglish speaking people will not be included because translated instruments (e.g., Spanish) are not available for all measures and doing this as a part of this small study might compromise the integrity of this first test of preliminary effectiveness.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>self-efficacy</keyword>
	<keyword>self-management</keyword>
	<keyword>web-based intervention research</keyword>
</DOC>