<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02168920</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate the efficacy (based on mean change in Cohen-Mansfield Agitation Inventory [CMAI] total score from baseline as the primary efficacy variable), dose-response, and safety of aripiprazole at 2, 3, and 6 mg/day in comparison with placebo in patients with agitation associated with Alzheimer's type dementia</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Aripiprazole for the Treatment of Patients With Agitation Associated With Dementia of the Alzheimer's Type</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This trial is a multicenter, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel-group, comparison trial to assess the efficacy and safety of aripiprazole in patients with agitation associated with Alzheimer's type dementia. Screening period is 4 weeks. Patients are randomly assigned to one of 4 groups, and treatment period is 10 weeks. Period of post-treatment observation is 30 days.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dementia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Psychomotor Agitation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aripiprazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients whose legal representatives can provide informed consent (Informed consent from the patients where possible). Patients who satisfy both of the following diagnostic criteria: Diagnosis of major neurocognitive disorder due to Alzheimer's disease according to Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of mental disorders (DSM5) Diagnosis of probable Alzheimer's disease according to National Institute of Neurological and Communicative Disorders and Stroke and the Alzheimer's Disease and Related Disorders Association (NINCDSADRDA) Hospitalized patients or care facility patients Patients with an MiniMental State Examination (MMSE) score of 1 to 22 Patients with complications of dementia or memory impairment other than Alzheimer's type dementia Dementia patients with a Modified Hachinski Ischemic Score of 5 or higher Patients with psychological symptoms or behavioral disorders that are clearly due to other medical conditions or substances Patients with a complication or history of stroke or transient ischemic attack, except for asymptomatic stroke Patients with heart failure classified as New York Heart Asscoiation (NYHA） III or IV Patients who require drug therapy for arrhythmia or ischemic heart disease Body weight of less than 30 kg Patients with a high risk of suicide Patients with a complication or history of seizure disorder Patients with a complication or history of neuroleptic malignant syndrome, tardive dyskinesia, paralytic ileus, or rhabdomyolysis Patients with thyroid disease (except if the disease has been stabilized with drug therapy for 3 months or longer prior to time of informed consent)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>89 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Alzeheimer</keyword>
</DOC>