<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="45059">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02519712</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>15-141</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02519712</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Treatment of Elderly AML Patients With Induction Chemotherapy Followed by G-CSF-Mobilized Stem Cells From Haploidentical Related Donors</brief_title>
  <official_title>Treatment of Elderly AML Patients With Induction Chemotherapy Followed by G-CSF-Mobilized Stem Cells From Haploidentical Related Donors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to test a method of bone marrow transplantation that results in
      only temporary donor immune function. In other words, the donor immune cells are given in a
      way that will allow them to attack leukemia briefly before being destroyed by their own
      immune system, or &quot;rejected.&quot; The investigators want to test whether temporary donor immune
      function is enough to improve the odds of achieving a remission without exposing the patient
      to the toxicities of a full bone marrow transplant. To do this, the investigators will use
      standard chemotherapy for AML followed by an infusion of donor stem cells. The donor will be
      a family member who is haploidentically, or half matched, to the patient such as a child or
      sibling. Chemotherapy designed to treat AML should not be strong enough to prevent them from
      rejecting the donor stem cells. The investigators will then follow the patient to see how
      long the donor stem cells stay in them. The study will test whether this process is feasible
      and can result in improved chances of obtaining a remission.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 28, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>No masking</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Complete Remission (CR)</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Peripheral Blood Counts: The peripheral blood neutrophil count should be ≥1,500/μl (sustained without growth factor support), and the platelets count should be ≥100,000/μl (without transfusion). No circulating blasts (in the absence of growth factor) should be detected.
Bone Marrow Aspirate: The cellularity of the bone marrow should approximate normal. There must be evidence of maturation of all cell lines. The bone marrow aspirate should contain &lt; 5% blasts. Auer rods should not be detected.
Extramedullary Leukemia: Extramedullary leukemia, such as CNS or soft tissue involvement, must not be present.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">15</enrollment>
  <condition>Acute Myeloid Leukemia (AML)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Induction Chemotherapy Followed by G-CSF-Mobilized Stem Cells</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This is a single center trial to assess the feasibility of standard induction chemotherapy followed by a single dose of unmanipulated G-PBSC for the treatment of elderly patients with newly diagnosed AML.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Induction Chemotherapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients with newly diagnosed AML will receive standard induction chemotherapy with daunorubicin and cytarabine (7+3 scheme). Patients who achieve CR may undergo consolidation chemotherapy at the discretion of the treating leukemia physician.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Induction Chemotherapy Followed by G-CSF-Mobilized Stem Cells</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>G-PBSC Infusion</intervention_name>
    <description>G-CSF-mobilized peripheral blood cells will be collected from the donors in the Donor Room according to standard MSKCC BMT guidelines. Patients will be infused by infusion of unmanipulated G-PBSC from a haploidentical related donor.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Induction Chemotherapy Followed by G-CSF-Mobilized Stem Cells</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Age ≥ 60.

          -  Patients with a new diagnosis of histologically confirmed (according to WHO
             classification 2008) acute myeloid leukemia (either primary or secondary AML) are
             included.

          -  Patients with a diagnosis of myelodysplastic syndrome with &gt;/= 10% bone marrow blasts
             with no response or progression of disease after at least 4 cycles of a
             hypomethylating agent (5-azacytiine or decitabine).

          -  Patients must have a healthy blood-related donor (parent, child, sibling) willing to
             undergo apheresis after G-CSF administration.

          -  Karnofsky performance status &gt; 70%.

          -  Hepatic function - total bilirubin &lt; 2 and, AST &lt; 2.5 x upper limit of normal, unless
             liver is involved with disease or a history of Gilbert's disease.

          -  Renal function - adequate renal function as demonstrated by a serum creatinine &lt;2
             mg/dl.

          -  LVEF ≥ 50% as determined by echocardiogram or MUGA.

          -  Ability to give informed consent.

        Donor Eligibility:

          -  Donor is blood-related and HLA-haploidentical to the recipient.

          -  Donor ≥18 years old

          -  Donor has undergone serologic testing for transmissible diseases as per blood banking
             guidelines for organ and tissue donors. Tests include but are not limited to:
             HepBsAg, HepBsAb, HepBcAb, HepC antibody, HIV, HTLV I and II, VZV, CMV and VDRL, and
             West Nile Virus . Donor must have normal negative test results for HIV, HTLV I and
             II, and West Nile Virus.

          -  Donor has a CXR and EKG performed.

          -  Donor is not allergic to G-CSF.

          -  Donor must be able to undergo leukapheresis

          -  Donor is not pregnant.

          -  Donor does not have concurrent malignancy or autoimmune disease.

          -  Ability to give informed consent.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients with a diagnosis of acute promyelocytic leukemia (according to WHO
             classification 20080

          -  Major surgery or irradiation within two weeks.

          -  Previous therapy with cytotoxic agents for AML. Persons with previous treatments for
             myelodysplasia/myeloproliferation such as hydroxyurea, interferon, hypomethylating
             agents (5-azacitidine or decitabine), lenalidomide, or JAK/STAT inhibitors may
             participate but must have &gt;1 week off therapy prior to enrollment.

          -  Active CNS disease.

          -  Uncontrolled infection.

          -  Pregnant or lactating women - they are excluded, given the potential teratogenic
             effects of chemotherapy and agents used in the therapy.

          -  Male and female patients of child-bearing potential unwilling to use effective means
             of contraception.

          -  HIV or HTLV I/II seropositivity.

          -  Concurrent active malignancy other than AML requiring therapy.

          -  Clinically significant cardiac disease (NY Heart Association Class III or IV) or
             pulmonary disease.

          -  Inability or unwillingness to comply with the treatment protocol, follow-up, or
             research tests

        Donor Exclusion:

          -  Donor has cardiac risk factors precluding ability to undergo leukapheresis.

          -  Donor has evidence of concurrent malignancy or autoimmune disease.

          -  Donor is pregnant
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Brian Shaffer, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Brian Shaffer, MD</last_name>
    <phone>212-639-2212</phone>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Katharine Hsu, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>646-888-2667</phone>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Brian Shaffer, MD</last_name>
      <phone>212-639-2212</phone>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Katherine Hsu, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>646-888-2667</phone>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Brian Shaffer, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.mskcc.org/</url>
    <description>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>February 22, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>August 6, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Induction Chemotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>G-CSF-Mobilized Stem Cells</keyword>
  <keyword>Haploidentical Related Donors</keyword>
  <keyword>15-141</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Lenograstim</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
