<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02984553</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to accurately assess weekly physical activity levels of postmenopausal women using lactate thresholds to individualize the accelerometer cut-points.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Objective Physical Activity Assesment in Postmenopausal Women</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This observational study aims to accurately assess weekly physical activity levels of postmenopausal women using lactate thresholds to individualize the accelerometer cut-points. Postmenopausal women will be recruited from local advertisements in public health centers. Each woman will perfom on different days a progressive discontinuous submaximal walking-running test and several constant speed tests wearing an accelerometer to identify the individual lactate threshold (LT), the maximal lactate steady state (MLSS) and the corresponding accelerometer activity counts/min (cpm). Participants then will wear an actigraph accelerometer (wGT3X-BT) for seven days. Linear regression equations will be developed for each participant to determine accelerometer activity counts for each intensity level: 1) sedentary behaviour (&lt;200 cpm), 2) light intensity (200 cpm to activity counts at LT), 3) moderate intensity (activity counts between LT and MLSS) and 4) vigorous intensity (activity counts &gt;MLSS). Physical activity levels will be measured using both, individualized approach and Sasaki, Jonh and Freedson´s (2011) absolute cut-points obtained through walking and running activities eliciting 3-6 MET intensities (2689-6166 cpm), considering it a "moderate" effort.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Age between 50 and 70 years Surgical or natural menopause (no menstrual periods during at least the last 6 months) Body mass index less than 39kg/m2 (obesity class III) Osteoporosis Presence of lowtrauma fractures or severe arthrosis at hip, knees or feet Functional limitation to walk fast or altered gait patters and instability Presence of any chronic disesase that would impair the cardiovascular (e.g. myocardial infarction, stroke, chronic heart failure), musculoskeletal (osteoporosis, lowtrauma fractures) and respiratory systems (COPD) or any disease or medication known to affect bone metabolism (glucocorticoids)</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>accelerometry</keyword>
	<keyword>aerobic fitness</keyword>
	<keyword>metabolic thresholds</keyword>
	<keyword>moderate to vigorous physical activity</keyword>
</DOC>