<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02984163</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary purpose of this proposed 5-year hybrid effectiveness and implementation study is to evaluate the relative benefit from, and implementation of an Alberta wide clinic-to-community-based cancer and exercise model of care - the Alberta Cancer Exercise (ACE) Program. The investigators hypothesize that the strategy will improve the physical well-being and QoL of survivors (on and off cancer treatment) while preventing the development of secondary cancers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Alberta Cancer Exercise Hybrid Effectiveness-Implementation Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A total of 1000 adult cancer survivors will be enrolled in the 5-year study. The investigators will build capacity by expanding ACE training and programming to sites beyond the large urban centers. The investigators plan for implementation in 7 Alberta YMCAs and/or City Recreation facilities within 3 years, as well as to formally establish partnerships within AHS to build further capacity across the province within existing AHS programming (e.g., CancerControl Rehab Services, Alberta Healthy Living Program and Primary Care Network). Eligible and consenting participants will be screened for exercise safety, and following fitness testing will be triaged to appropriate exercise programming in their community. The exercise intervention will take place at YMCAs and municipal fitness centres across the province. The community-based exercise program will be administered by exercise specialists who have undergone the ACE Cancer and Exercise: Training for Fitness Professionals course. Survivors will take part in a combination of aerobic, resistance, balance, and flexibility exercises delivered in a circuit-type class setting or group personal training format, twice weekly for a 12-week period. Effectiveness outcomes include physical fitness, physical activity, quality of life, and healthcare utilization. These outcomes are known factors associated with the secondary prevention of cancer. The RE-AIM framework will be used to evaluate program reach, effectiveness, adoption, implementation and maintenance. The Alberta Quality Matrix for Health will serve as a framework to inform program sustainability beyond the funding period. Through this research, the investigators will better understand the effectiveness of the ACE program, and evaluate processes to support future implementation and sustainability.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>1. have a diagnosis of cancer; 2. be over the age of 18 years; 3. be able to participate in lowintensity levels of activity at minimum; 4. be pretreatment, or receiving active cancer treatment (i.e., surgery, systemic therapy and radiation therapy), or have received cancer treatment within the past 3 years; or have ongoing significant cancer or treatmentrelated impairments (requiring supportive exercise intervention); 5. be able to provide informed written consent in English. Exclusion criteria: 1) Inability or deemed unsafe to participate in physical activity program</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>exercise</keyword>
</DOC>