<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03045302</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the protocol is evaluate the safety, the pharmacodynamics and the pharmacokinetic of repeated administration of BIM23B065 in subjects with acromegaly.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Assessment of BIM23B065, Given as Repeated Subcutaneous Injection in Subjects With Acromegaly</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Acromegaly</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Provided written informed consent prior to any study related procedures. Subjects will have a documented diagnosis of acromegaly. Subjects will have active acromegaly confirmed by a mean serum concentration of GH over 2 hours &gt; 2.5 µg/L at screening analysed by central laboratory. Subjects who have had pituitary surgery must be &gt;8 weeks postsurgery. 18 to 75 years of age. Negative pregnancy test (female subjects). Female who is either of nonchildbearing potential or who is not pregnant at screening and agrees to use highly effective contraception during whole duration of the study. Nonchildbearing potential is defined as being postmenopausal for at least 1 year, or women with documented infertility (natural or acquired). Male subjects must agree that, if their partner is at risk of becoming pregnant, they will use a medically accepted, effective method of contraception (i.e. condom) for the duration of the treatment period of the study. The subject has received longacting Somatostatin Analogues (SSA) within 12 weeks prior screening (e.g.octreotide long acting release (LAR), lanreotide Autogel, pasireotide LAR). The subject has received shortacting SSA within 1 week (e.g. octreotide SC) prior to screening. The subject has received a dopamine agonist within 6 weeks (e.g., bromocriptine or cabergoline) prior to screening. The subject has received GH antagonist within 12 weeks prior to screening (e.g., pegvisomant). The subject had undergone radiotherapy to the pituitary gland at any time prior to study entry. It is anticipated that the subject will undergo pituitary surgery or radiation to the pituitary gland during the study, or will require additional medical therapy for acromegaly (including SSA, pegvisomant, or dopamine agonists) during the study. If the subject has any history of postural hypotension or evidence of postural hypotension at screening (&gt;= 20 mm Hg decrease in Systolic blood pressure (SBP), &gt;= 10 mm Hg decrease in diastolic blood pressure, or &gt;=30 bpm increases in pulse rate, after standing for 2 minutes from resting supine position of at least 10 min). Subject with poorly controlled diabetes mellitus (presence of ketoacidosis or a glycosylated hemoglobin level &gt;10%). Subject with diabetes treated with insulin for less than 6 weeks prior to study entry, or with an unstable insulin dose in the 6 weeks prior to study entry or HbA1c&gt;10%. Subject is taking betablockers (which can inhibit compensatory increases in HR during hypotensive episodes). Subject is being treated for hypertension and in the opinion of the investigator their antihypertensive medication puts them at increased risk of postural hypotension. Subject is hypotensive at screening as defined as systolic &lt; 90 mmHg and/or diastolic &lt;60 mmHg. Subject has clinically significant hepatic abnormalities and/or alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and/or aspartate aminotransferase (AST) ≥2 x ULN and/or alkaline phosphatase (AP) ≥2 x ULN and/or total bilirubin ≥1.5 x ULN and gammaglutamyl transferase (GGT) ≥2.5 x ULN during the Screening period (local laboratory results). Subject has a compression of the optic chiasm causing visualfield defects. Subject is receiving any oestrogencontaining Hormone Replacement Therapy (HRT). Subject has clinically significant pancreatic abnormalities and/or amylase and/or lipase ≥2 x ULN during the Screening period (local laboratory results). Any significant renal abnormalities, including confirmed proteinuria and/or creatinine ≥1.5x ULN during screening assessed by the local laboratory.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>