<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03018821</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Although the incidence of Hepatitis B has been decreased a lot recently years, there are still quite a few chronic hepatitis B patients in China. The anti-virus drugs of western medicine such as Entecavir and Tenofovir have been proved effective on decreasing the serum hepatitis B virus (HBV) level, on the other hand, Chinese materia medica showed effective on TCM syndromes of chronic hepatitis B (CHB) such as hypochondriac pain, jaundice and abdominal mass. Besides, the hepatic fibrosis could be delayed after the appropriate treatment of TCM. This study is a multicenter, randomized, open label, parallel group clinical trial to evaluate the efficacy of two different traditional Chinese medicine (TCM) herbal treatment on chronic hepatitis B.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Study of Two Different Chinese Traditional Medicine Treatment on Chronic Hepatitis B</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Extracts</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Entecavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tenofovir</mesh_term>
	<criteria>18&lt;=age at treatment&lt;=65 years old Was diagnosed as chronic hepatitis B (ICD10:K73.901) and one of the following Chinese syndromes: hypochondriac pain (TCD:BNG010), jaundice(TCD:BNG020) or abdominal mass (TCD:BNG040). Combined with other virus hepatitis or alcoholic hepatitis Combined with autoimmune disease Combined with liver cancer or cirrhosis Combined with severe hepatitis with or without complications Combined with unstable cardiocerebrovascular disease Combined with severe lung, kidney, endocrine system, nervous system and hematological system diseases Combined with Tuberculosis Chronic hepatitis patients with ongoing INF treatment Woman with pregnancy or breasting feeding Mental disorder and can not express self clearly Cannot speak Chinese Allergic constitution or allergy to multiple drugs Refuse to enroll into the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>