<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03018301</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate the analgesic effect of low-dose intravenous ketamine in pregnant mothers undergoing cesarean section under Bupivacaine spinal anesthesia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intravenous Ketamine and Postoperative Pain Following Cesarean Section.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>- No premedication will be given, and patients will be monitored by electrocardiogram, non-invasive arterial blood pressure, and pulse oximetry when they entered the operating room. - 18 gauge IV cannula will be inserted and all patients will be preloaded with 10 ml/kg of lactate ringer over 20 min period. - All participants will have spinal anesthesia using bupivacaine. The dose of the drug, as well as the method of injection will be identical for all individuals; 10 mg (2 cc 0.5%), in the L4-L5 space using needle 25 G, midline, with the patient in a sitting position. - After administering bupivacaine, and prior to surgery the height of the sensory block will be assessed bilaterally (complete loss of sensation to ice) in a ascending fashion starting from T12 dermatome. - Once adequate anesthesia to at least T6 dermatome will be achieved, the operation will be allowed to begin. When systolic blood pressure decrease to ＜ 90 mmHg, or 30% of the pre-anesthetic blood pressure, it will be corrected by administering 5 mg ephedrine. - Patients will be asked to report any intraoperative pain using visual pain score(VPS)of 0(no pain) 10(worst pain).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pain, Postoperative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ketamine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Eligible women ASA class 1 and 2, are at term (≥37 week gestation), Scheduled for elective cesarean section whose anesthetic plan is for spinal anesthesia with Bupivacaine and intravenous pethidine and paracetamol for post operative analgesia. • Body mass index ≥40 kg/m2, Known allergy to any of the study medications, Contraindication to the spinal anesthesia, History of substance abuse, History of hallucinations, Chronic opioid therapy, Chronic pain.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>