<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00568061</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess whether or not inhaled nitric oxide can decrease myocardial infarction (MI) size at 48-72 hours in patients presenting with an ST segment elevation MI (STEMI) who undergo successful percutaneous coronary intervention.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Nitric Oxide in Myocardial Infarction Size</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of the trial is to assess whether or not inhaled nitric oxide can decrease myocardial infarction (MI) size as a fraction of left ventricular (LV) size at 48-72 hours in patients presenting with an ST segment elevation MI who undergo successful percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI). The primary endpoint for this study will be myocardial infarction size as a fraction of left ventricular size at 48-72 hours as measured by contrast-enhanced cardiac MRI.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nitric Oxide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Acute myocardial infarction and electrocardiographic evidence of ST elevation No clinical evidence of congestive heart failure All patients must undergo successful percutaneous coronary intervention for TIMI 0 or 1 coronary flow with resulting TIMI 2 or 3 flow Greater than 18 years of age Signed IRB approved informed consent Prior myocardial infarction Requirement for urgent cardiac surgery Previous CABG or PCI Left bundle branch block Heart block that is expected to require a temporary pacemaker for greater than 72 hours Prior use of thrombolytic therapy for the current event Unable to tolerate magnetic resonance imaging or unable to tolerate gadolinium contrast media, including patients with a calculated creatinine clearance less than 60ml/min/1.73m² BSA Active or recent hemorrhage requiring an invasive procedure for evaluation or transfusion within 6 weeks prior to presentation, or hemorrhagic stroke within the 6 weeks prior Neutropenia (WBC &lt;2000 (mm)³), Anemia (HCT &lt;30%, Thrombocytopenia (Thrombocytes &lt;50,000 (mm)³). It is not necessary to confirm blood counts prior to start of study drug in the absence of clinical suspicion. Known or suspected aortic dissection. Prior history of pulmonary disease requiring chronic oxygen therapy. Pregnancy, lactating, and women of childbearing potential. Medical problem likely to preclude completion of the study. Use of investigational drugs or device within the 30 days prior to enrollment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>INOT44</keyword>
	<keyword>NOMI</keyword>
</DOC>