<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01142778</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This randomized, open-label study will assess the effect of adding Avastin (bevacizumab) to Herceptin (trastuzumab) plus docetaxel in neoadjuvant therapy in patients with early stage HER2-positive breast cancer. After 2 cycles of Herceptin and docetaxel once every 3 weeks, patients with a response of &lt;70% on Positron Emission Tomography will be randomized 2:1 to receive cycles 3 to 6 of Herceptin (6mg/kg iv) and docetaxel (100mg/m2 iv) with or without Avastin (15mg/kg iv). Patients with a response of &gt;/=70% will receive Herceptin plus docetaxel for cycles 3 to 6. After surgery, all patients will receive a further 12 cycles of Herceptin plus standard of care treatment and will be followed for up to 5 years. Anticipated time on study treatment is 18 weeks.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Avastin (Bevacizumab) Added to Herceptin (Trastuzumab) Plus Docetaxel in the Neoadjuvant Setting in Patients With Early Stage HER2-Positive Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trastuzumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>female patients, &gt;/=18 years of age early stage HER2positive breast cancer scheduled to receive neoadjuvant therapy with the objective of conservative surgery ECOG performance status 0, 1 or 2 partially or totally lobular carcinoma inflammatory breast cancer bifocal and/or bilateral tumour metastases previous treatment with chemotherapy, radiation therapy or hormone therapy for breast cancer previous history of cancer (other than curatively treated basal and squamous cell carcinoma of the skin and/or in situ carcinoma of the cervix) relapsing within the 5 years before study entry or in situ contralateral breast carcinoma</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>