<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02402972</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To investigate whether intraoperative intraportal chemotherapy combined with adjuvant chemotherapy as treatment could improve disease-free survival (DFS) in patients with curative colorectal cancer resection compared with adjuvant chemotherapy alone. This is a prospective, blind (doctors who done outcome measures were masked), multi-center, 2-arm randomized controlled trial.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Multi-center Randomized Controlled Trial of Intraportal Chemotherapy Combined With Adjuvant Chemotherapy (mFOLFOX6) for Stage II and III Colon Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colonic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Floxuridine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age ≥ 18 and ≤ 75 years; 2. Primary tumor has undergone histologically confirmed colon adenocarcinoma; Colon cancer was defined by the presence of the inferior pole of the tumor above the peritoneal reflection (at least 15 cm from the anal margin). 3. Together with clinical or radiological evidence of Stage II (T34, N0, M0) or Stage III (T14, N12, M0) disease (according to the 2007 revision of the International Union Against Cancer TNM staging system) 4. Performance status (ECOG) 0~1 5. Adequate hematological function: Neutrophils≥1.5 x109/l and platelet count≥100 x109/l; Hb ≥9g/dl (within 1 week prior to randomization) 6. Adequate hepatic and renal function: Serum bilirubin≤1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN), alkaline phosphatase ≤5x ULN, and serum transaminase (either AST or ALT) ≤ 5 x ULN(within 1 week prior to randomization); 7. Written informed consent for participation in the trial. 1. Previous exposure to prior cancer therapy (chemotherapy, radiotherapy or intervention therapy) for colon cancer. 2. Patients with known hypersensitivity reactions to any of the components of the study treatments. 3. Other previous malignancy within 5 years, with exception of a history of a previous basal cell carcinoma of the skin or preinvasive carcinoma of the cervix 4. Pregnancy (absence confirmed by serum/urine βHCG) or breastfeeding 5. Known drug abuse/ alcohol abuse 6. Legal incapacity or limited legal capacity 7. Preexisting peripheral neuropathy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>adjuvant chemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>intraportal chemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>prevention</keyword>
</DOC>