<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02654561</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to estimate the efficacy of unfractionated heparin(UFH) on ICU mortality in severe sepsis with suspected DIC.The Second objective is to estimate the effect of UFH on 28-day mortality,and the change of the Japanese Association for Acute Medicine(JAAM) score and SOFA score. The third one is to evaluate the safety of UFH in severe sepsis patients with suspected DIC.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Unfractionated Heparin on Severe Sepsis With Suspected Disseminated Intravascular Coagulation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>During the study, the whole process of data validation and registry procedures will be implemented by the Principal Investigator of the study, and monitored by the Ethics Committee of the First Affiliated Hospital of China Medical University.There are 2 research supervisors(2 ICU doctors) to assess the accuracy,completeness and representativeness of registry data, and to report the study process and research results to Principal Investigator.Investigators have also edited a data dictionary including each variable used by the registry and normal ranges of all detection indexes. The standard operating procedures have been formulated to address the registry and data analysis. The feasibility and significance have been assessed carefully and funded by the Health and Family Planning Commission of Liaoning Province(No.LNCC-B01-2014).The sample size is 700 participants over about 1 year through statistic calculation. The plan for missing data and statistical analysis will be implemented by specialized statisticians of China Medical University.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sepsis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Toxemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Disseminated Intravascular Coagulation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium heparin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heparin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clinical diagnosis of severe sepsis or/and septic shock suspected DIC:the score of Platelets plus International Normalized Ratio in the JAAM criteria is equal or more than 3 scores consent declined pregnant or breastfeeding the length during ICU is less than 24 hours with other types of shock have bleeding or high risk for bleeding have an indication for therapeutic anticoagulation have a known or suspected adverse reaction to UFH including HIT are currently enrolled in another trial known or suspected cirrhosis or other severe hepatic diseases terminal illness with a life expectancy of less than 28 days</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Severe sepsis</keyword>
	<keyword>Disseminated intravascular coagulation</keyword>
	<keyword>Unfractionated heparin</keyword>
</DOC>