<DOC>
	<DOCNO>NCT02037178</DOCNO>
	<brief_summary>The main objective study evaluate inter-observer concordance measure maximum value external antero-posterior diameter sub-renal aorta ( cross-sectional longitudinal ultrasound view measure ) . The first measure make general practitioner private practice ; second reading make expert vascular medicine .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Screening Arteriopathy General Medicine : Preliminary Feasibility Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The secondary objective study : A . To assess prevalence Abdominal Aortic Aneurysm ( AAA ) detect ultrasound measurement anterior posterior longitudinal outer diameter sub-renal abdominal aorta high cardiovascular risk population consult general practitioner ( define accord recommendation state French Society Vascular Medicine ) . B . To assess prevalence Peripheral Obliterative Arteriopathy Legs ( POAL ) measure Systolic Pressure Index ( SPI ) toe ( ratio arterial pressure upper limb versus low limb ) . Measures make general practitioner population . C. To assess quality interpretability ultrasound recording ultrasound acquistion failure rate . These second measure make expert vascular medecine . This evaluation use 3-level scale : 1. appropriate image obtain recognize expert - uninterpretable 2. poor image quality - interpretable 3. image good good quality - interpretable D. To calculate impact risk cofactor hypertension , smoking , age family history among patient diagnose AAA . E. Evaluation general practitioner train qualitative quantitative point view 4 h training organize Dr. Bobbià .</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Arterial Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patient must give his/her inform sign consent The patient must insure beneficiary health insurance plan The patient fall one follow 4 group define French Society Vascular Medecin ( 2006 ) : ( 1 ) Men woman 6075 year age active smoker exsmokers ( 2 ) Men 75 year age ( 3 ) Women 75 year age smoke know hypertension ( 4 ) Men woman 50 year age family history aneurysm abdominal aorta The patient exclusion period determine previous study The patient judicial protection , tutorship curatorship The patient refuse sign consent It impossible correctly inform patient The subject allergy gel use ultrasound examination .</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Peripheral Obliterative Arteriopathy leg</keyword>
	<keyword>Screening generalist</keyword>
	<keyword>Ultrasound</keyword>
</DOC>