<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02854423</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Both biodegradable polymer-based biolimus-eluting stents (BP-BES) and durable polymer-based everolimus-eluting stents (DP-EES) have been shown to improve long-term clinical outcomes as compared with early generation DES. BP-BES with DP-EES have been directly compared in 2 randomized trials, showing no differences between the two devices in all-comer patients during long-term follow-up. It is unknown whether these results are consistent in real-world patients with diabetes mellitus during long-term follow-up. To evaluate the safety and efficacy profile of biodegradable polymer-coated biolimus-eluting stents (BP-BES) as compared to durable polymer-coated everolimus-eluting stents (DP-EES) in patients with diabetes mellitus during long-term follow-up. Consecutive diabetic patients undergoing percutaneous coronary interventions with BP-BES or DP-EES implantation were included in a multicenter registry between January 2007 and May 2012. Long-term clinical outcomes between BP-BES and DP-EES will be compared using propensity score matching. The pre-specified primary endpoint is the occurrence of major cardiac adverse events (MACE) - a composite of all-cause death, myocardial infarction (MI) or target-vessel revascularization (TVR). Secondary endpoints are the individual components of the primary endpoint as well as definite stent thrombosis (ST).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of Biodegradable Polymer vs Durable-polymer in Diabetic Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>age &gt; 18 years diabetes mellitus percutaneous coronary interventions with biolimus eluting stent or everolimus eluting stent implantation signed informed consent planned procedure requiring antiplatelet therapy withdrawal within 12 months from index coronary angioplasty patients with contraindication to dual antiplatelet therapy (aspirin plus ticlopidine or clopidogrel) known allergy to stent drugs</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>95 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>