<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00183794</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is for patients with advanced ovarian cancer that has reappeared after treatment with conventional therapy. The purpose of this study is to determine if the combination of docetaxel and gemcitabine will be effective in reducing or eliminating the tumor(s) in patients with ovarian cancer. Docetaxel is approved by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) for the treatment of breast and lung cancer; gemcitabine is approved by the FDA for the treatment of pancreatic and lung cancer. Neither docetaxel nor gemcitabine are approved for the treatment of ovarian cancer. Both drugs have been shown to decrease the size of ovarian cancer tumors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Trial of Docetaxel in Combination With Gemcitabine in Platinum-Resistant Ovarian Cancer and Primary Peritoneal Carcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Primary Objective: 1. To determine the response rate, time to progression and survival (secondary) of the combination of docetaxel and gemcitabine administered on a weekly basis to patients with platinum-resistant ovarian cancer Secondary Objective: 1. To determine the toxicity of this combination regimen in patients with platinum-resistant ovarian cancer 2. To evaluate the toxicity and safety profile of a short course (one dose) of premedication with steroids to patients receiving weekly gemcitabine and docetaxel OUTLINE: Patients receive gemcitabine IV over 30 minutes on days 1 and 8, and docetaxel IV over 60 minutes on day 8. Treatment repeats every 21 days until PD, unacceptable toxicity, or patient's withdrawal.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peritoneal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically proven diagnosis of epithelial ovarian ca Must have platinumresistant disease. (Defined as progression during the most recent platinumbased chemotx or relapse &lt; 6 months after the most recent platinumbased chemotx regimen.) Measurable or evaluable disease. (Patients whose dz is manifested only as an elevated CA125 [greater than or equal to 100] are eligible. If an elevated CA125 is the only manifestation of dz, it must be confirmed on 2 separate times, at least 2 weeks apart. Patients with positive cytology only are not eligible.) Greater than or equal to 18 years of age GOG performance status less than or equal to 2 AGC/ANC greater than or equal to 1.5; platelets greater than or equal to 100,000; hemoglobin (Hgb) greater than or equal to 8.0. Creatinine less than or equal to 2.0 Total bilirubin less than or equal to upper limit of normal (uln) SGOT and/or SGPT less than or equal to 2.5 x uln if alkaline phosphatase less than or equal to uln, or alkaline phosphatase less than or equal to 4 x uln if transaminases are less than or equal to uln. (If both SGOT/SGPT &gt;1.5 x uln and alkaline phosphatase &gt; 2.5 x uln, patient is not eligible.) Fully recovered from acute toxicities secondary to prior treatment (tx) Signed informed consent Prior treatment with gemcitabine or docetaxel Underlying medical, psychiatric, or social conditions that would preclude patient from receiving treatment Peripheral neuropathy greater than or equal to Grade 2 No prior tx with cisplatin or carboplatin</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Primary Peritoneal</keyword>
</DOC>