<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00183586</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will compare specific family therapy, standard family systems therapy, and standard individual psychotherapy to determine which is most effective in treating adolescent anorexia nervosa.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparing the Effectiveness of Three Types of Therapy for the Treatment of Anorexia Nervosa in Adolescents</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In adolescents, anorexia nervosa severely affects physical, emotional, and social development. Despite the seriousness and prevalence of adolescent anorexia nervosa, few studies have focused on the effectiveness of various types of psychotherapy treatment. Family-based therapy may be an effective approach to treating adolescent anorexia nervosa. This study will compare specific family therapy (FT), standard family systems therapy (FS), and standard individual psychotherapy (IT) to determine which is most effective in treating adolescent anorexia nervosa. The study also aims to determine potential predictors and moderators of outcomes, as well as the cost-benefit ratio of each treatment. Participants in this open-label study will be randomly assigned to one of three treatment groups. Group 1 will receive FT, Group 2 will receive FS, and Group 3 will receive IT. All participants will receive a total of 24 hours of their assigned therapy over a period of 12 months. Study visits will occur at baseline, immediately post-intervention, and again six months and one year post-intervention. Weight change will be assessed, as well as changes in concerns about weight and shape. The cost-benefit ratio of the treatments will also be evaluated.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anorexia Nervosa</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Feeding and Eating Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anorexia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Meets Diagnostic and Statistical Manual (4th Edition) (DSMIV) criteria for anorexia nervosa Any psychotic illness</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Treatment outcomes study</keyword>
	<keyword>Anorexia</keyword>
	<keyword>Anorexia nervosa</keyword>
</DOC>