<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="192157">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00590980</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2006-0599</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>5R01NS059745</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00590980</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Vertebrobasilar Flow Evaluation and Risk of Transient Ischemic Attack and Stroke (VERiTAS)</brief_title>
  <acronym>VERiTAS</acronym>
  <official_title>The Vertebrobasilar Flow Evaluation and Risk of Transient Ischemic Attack and Stroke (VERiTAS) Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sepideh Amin-Hanjani</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Illinois at Chicago</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Patients with blockage of the blood vessels that supply blood to the back of the brain,
      known as vertebrobasilar disease (VBD), are at risk of having a stroke or temporary symptoms
      of a stroke known as transient ischemic attack (TIA). The risk of repeated stroke associated
      with VBD may be affected by several risk factors, including the degree to which the blockage
      reduces the blood flow to the brain. Patients with VBD have different levels of blockage
      ranging from partial blockage to complete blockage, which can affect the blood flow to the
      brain by variable amounts. The purpose of this research is to determine if patients with
      symptomatic VBD who demonstrate low blood flow to the back of the brain on magnetic
      resonance (MR)imaging are at higher risk of developing another stroke or TIA than patients
      with normal blood flow.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Approximately 700,000 strokes occur annually in the U.S. making it the third leading cause
      of death and the leading cause of permanent disability among adults. Over one third of
      strokes occur in the posterior circulation, the leading cause of which is vertebrobasilar
      occlusive disease secondary to atherosclerosis. Symptomatic vertebrobasilar disease (VBD)
      carries a high annual risk of stroke, averaging 10-15% per year despite medical therapy.
      This represents a potentially treatable high risk stroke etiology. Advances in endovascular
      angioplasty and stenting have created new treatment options, but these interventions carry
      significant risks, and the selection criteria for appropriate candidates remains uncertain.
      Determining predictors of stroke in this population is the first step toward identifying
      those high risk patients most suitable for consideration of intervention. Our preliminary
      studies suggest that the risk of stroke in VBD is strongly related to the extent to which
      intracranial blood flow is compromised.

      The objective is to conduct a longitudinal study of patients with symptomatic VBD. Our
      central hypothesis is that patients with symptomatic VBD who demonstrate limitation of blood
      flow on quantitative magnetic resonance angiography (QMRA) are at higher risk of stroke.The
      primary aim of this proposal is to test the hypothesis that among patients with VBD, those
      with distal blood flow compromise are at higher risk of subsequent posterior circulation
      stroke than those with normal flow.

      Secondary exploratory aims of the proposal are to determine:the correlation between large
      vessel flow measured by QMRA and tissue level perfusion measured by MR perfusion in the
      posterior circulation, and the predictive value of each; other predictive factors for stroke
      in this population; hemodynamic effects of varying degrees of vertebrobasilar stenosis;
      changes in hemodynamic status of patients on medical therapy over time; utility of QMRA as a
      non-invasive screening and monitoring tool in VBD.

      The study consist of a prospective multi-center observational cohort study of patients with
      symptomatic angiographically confirmed vertebrobasilar atherostenosis (≥ 50%), or
      occlusion). Upon enrollment, patients will undergo hemodynamic assessment with noninvasive
      MR imaging (including QMRA and MR perfusion), the results of which will be kept blinded from
      treating physicians and the patients. Patients will be prospectively designated as
      demonstrating compromised or normal distal cerebral flow based upon an existing validated
      algorithm of individual posterior circulation vessel flow measurements. Baseline
      demographic, clinical and laboratory data will be gathered. Subsequently, patients will have
      monthly clinical follow-up and be re-imaged with QMRA at 6 month intervals for a minimum of
      12 months. The primary endpoint will be stroke incidence in the vertebrobasilar territory at
      one year. Survival analysis methods, with censoring of patients not achieving endpoint at
      the end of the study period, will be used for comparison of patients with compromised versus
      normal blood flow.

      The overall goal of the study is to define the population of patients with symptomatic VBD
      at highest risk of recurrent ischemic events. The information gained can significantly
      impact the selection criteria and likelihood for success of future clinical trials aimed at
      assessing the efficacy of endovascular or surgical interventions for the treatment of VBD.
      Moreover, the ability to define a low risk population in whom the risks of expensive
      invasive interventions would be unnecessary will have an equally important impact on the
      management of the disease both from a clinical and cost perspective. Data regarding the
      hemodynamic effects and changes over time of vertebrobasilar occlusive disease may also
      enhance our understanding of the basic pathophysiology and mechanisms of stroke in this
      morbid disease entity.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Fatal and nonfatal ischemic stroke in the vertebrobasilar territory</measure>
    <time_frame>one year</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ischemic stroke in any vascular territory</measure>
    <time_frame>one to two years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>All ischemic stroke and vascular death</measure>
    <time_frame>one to two years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Aggregate of any ischemic stroke, myocardial infarction and vascular death</measure>
    <time_frame>one to two years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>All stroke (ischemic and hemorrhagic)</measure>
    <time_frame>one to two years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>All death (vascular and nonvascular)</measure>
    <time_frame>one to two years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neurological impairment as determined by the NIH Stroke Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>one to two years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neurological disability as determined by the modified Barthel Index</measure>
    <time_frame>one to two years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Handicap as determined by the modified Rankin Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>one to two years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">82</enrollment>
  <condition>Vertebrobasilar Insufficiency</condition>
  <condition>Ischemic Attack, Transient</condition>
  <condition>Cerebrovascular Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Brain Ischemia</condition>
  <condition>Stroke</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Observation</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with intracranial or extracranial vertebrobasilar occlusion or stenosis ≥ 50% presenting with vertebrobasilar distribution TIA or stroke.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Neurology/Neurosurgery Clinic
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Stroke or TIA in the vertebrobasilar territory

          -  Conventional or CT angiographic demonstration of ≥50% stenosis or occlusion of
             extracranial or intracranial vertebrobasilar artery

          -  Symptoms within 60 days of enrollment

          -  Age 18 and above

          -  Able to provide informed consent

        Exclusion Criteria:

        Neurologic criteria:

          -  Major disabling stroke prohibiting the ability to return for follow-up assessment

          -  Any neurological disease which would confound follow-up assessment

        Medical criteria:

          -  Any severe co-morbidity condition with less than 12 month life expectancy

          -  Known cardiac disease associated with cardioembolic risk specifically atrial
             fibrillation, prosthetic valves, endocarditis, left atrial/ventricular thrombus,
             cardiomyopathy with EF&lt;25%, cardiac myxoma

          -  Blood dyscrasias, specifically polycythemia vera, essential thrombocytosis, sickle
             cell disease

        Disease criteria:

          -  Non-atherosclerotic disease vertebrobasilar disease including dissection,
             fibromuscular dysplasia, vasculitis, radiation induced vasculopathy

          -  Unilateral vertebral stenosis or occlusion

        Patient criteria:

          -  Unable or unwilling to undergo MRI or cerebral angiography or CTA

          -  Pregnancy concurrent participation in an interventional trial for treatment of
             vertebrobasilar disease.

          -  Renal dysfunction will be exclusionary if it precludes angiography. No subjects will
             be excluded based upon gender, race, ethnic group, religion or socioeconomic status.
             Children will not be recruited as atherosclerotic VBD is a condition that affects
             adults primarily in later life and is not a disease that occurs or is relevant in
             children.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sepideh Amin-Hanjani, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Illinois, Department of Neurosurgery</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California at Los Angeles - UCLA</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90095</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Illinois at Chicago</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Jeffrey Kramer, MDSC at Mercy Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60616</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Washington University</name>
      <address>
        <city>St. Louis</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>63110</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Columbia University</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10032</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UHN-Toronto Western Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>M5T 2S8</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://veritas.neur.uic.edu/</url>
    <description>VERiTAS Study website</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Amin-Hanjani S, Du X, Zhao M, Walsh K, Malisch TW, Charbel FT. Use of quantitative magnetic resonance angiography to stratify stroke risk in symptomatic vertebrobasilar disease. Stroke. 2005 Jun;36(6):1140-5. Epub 2005 May 12.</citation>
    <PMID>15890993</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>January 30, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>December 28, 2007</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Illinois at Chicago</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sepideh Amin-Hanjani</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor, Department of Neurosurgery, University of Illinois at Chicago</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Stroke</keyword>
  <keyword>TIA (transient ischemic attack)</keyword>
  <keyword>Brain</keyword>
  <keyword>Blood Flow</keyword>
  <keyword>Quantitative magnetic resonance angiography (QMRA)</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ischemic Attack, Transient</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cerebrovascular Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Brain Ischemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Vertebrobasilar Insufficiency</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
