<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01587144</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to determine the effectiveness of an investigational drug called lucanthone, when combined with temozolomide (TMZ) and radiation in the treatment of Glioblastoma Multiforme (GBM).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Study of Lucanthone When Used in Combination With Temozolomide(TMZ) and Radiation to Treat Glioblastoma Multiforme(GBM)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an international, multicenter, randomized, double blind placebo controlled phase II study to evaluate the safety and efficacy of lucanthone administered as an adjunct to patients receiving primary treatment of GBM with temozolomide and radiation. Eligible patients will be randomized to lucanthone or placebo arm in ratio of 1:1. The treatment period will be in two phases ; an initial six weeks of concomitant therapy with temozolomide and radiation, followed by a maintenance phase of six cycles of temozolomide given on Days 1 to 5 of a 28- day cycle (+/- 3 days). Lucanthone / placebo will be given as an add on in both concomitant and maintenance phases.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Temozolomide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dacarbazine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lucanthone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Main 1. 18 and 70 years of age in India, 18 years and above in US 2. Histologically proven GBM who May or may not have undergone surgery Is scheduled to receive treatment with temozolomide and radiation. 3. Karnofsky score ≥ 70%. Main 1. Diagnosis of recurrent brain tumor. 2. Received temozolomide previously. 3. Absolute neutrophil count ≤ 1.5 X 109/L. 4. Screening platelet count &lt; 100 K/uL. 5. Screening bilirubin &gt; 1.6 mg/dL. 6. Screening creatinine &gt; 2.25 mg/dL in men and 1.8 mg/dL in women. 7. Screening ALT or AST &gt; 2.5 times the upper limit of the laboratory reference range. 8. Unstable medical condition or significant comorbid pathophysiology (e.g. active infection, poorly controlled diabetes, unstable angina, severe heart failure) that would interfere with his/her participation in the study. 9. Enrolled, or plans to enroll, in a concurrent treatment protocol with another investigational product. 10. Receiving, or plans to receive, an anticancer therapy other than temozolomide during the study. 11. Received prior chemotherapy or radiation therapy within four weeks of enrollment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>GBM</keyword>
</DOC>