<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02490527</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to gain insight into the side-effects of statin consumption, and assess the ability of epicatechin (a compound in dark chocolate) to counteract or reverse these changes. The investigators' prior research has shown that epicatechin can improve skeletal muscle structure and mitochondrial (which gives us energy) structure.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Epicatechin on Statins for Mitochondrial Dysfunction and Impaired Exercise Capacity</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patient Inclusion Criteria: 1. Must be between 40-60 years of age. 2. Must have a VO2max greater than 25 ml/kg/min. Patient Exclusion Criteria: 1. Liver, thyroid, or kidney disease. 2. Currently taking drugs that interfere with statin metabolism. 3. Acute or chronic infectious disease; autoimmune/inflammatory disease, cancer, COPD, anemia, diabetes, psychiatric illness. After the investigators enroll the first six patients, preliminary data analysis will be performed at the end of the 3 months to determine if the dose of epicatechin should adjusted by checking the levels of epicatechin in the blood. Then, the investigators will make the necessary changes and continue with enrollment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hydroxymethylglutaryl-CoA Reductase Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Simvastatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient Must be between 3060 years of age LDL&gt;100mg/dL VO2 max greater than 25 ml/kg/min Patient Liver or kidney disease Currently taking drugs that interfere with statin metabolism Currently taking blood thinners Acute or chronic infectious disease; autoimmune/inflammatory disease, cancer, COPD, anemia, psychiatric illness, insulindependent diabetes smokers or illicit drug users adverse cardiovascular event (ex: heart attack) history of knee surgery or active history of knee pain</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>myopathy</keyword>
	<keyword>muscular weakness</keyword>
	<keyword>cramping</keyword>
	<keyword>fatigue</keyword>
</DOC>