<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00422838</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Aim To evaluate the effects of peginterferon and ribavirin therapy on the immune response in chronic HCV genotype 1,2 or 3 patients before, during and after treatment. Background Treatment of chronic hepatitis C (HCV) has shown a remarkable success. However, genotype 1 patients have reduced response rates. A better understanding and improvement of these results can now be considered the greatest challenge. In chronically infected patients, HCV-specific immune responses are generally weak, narrowly focused, and often dysfunctional. The presence of HCV-specific cells suppressing the immune response (regulatory T-lymphocytes=Treg) are able to suppress the immune response. These Treg are possibly responsible for the impaired immune response. Previous studies have indicated increased Treg frequency and activity of immune regulating mechanisms, locally in the liver, as a result of HCV re-infection. Hence, these Data highlight the importance of monitoring intrahepatic immune responses in addition to peripheral immune responses. Using the minimally-invasive technique of fine-needle aspiration biopsy (FNAB), it is now possible to obtain safe and frequent liver samples to monitor local antiviral immune responses in chronic HCV patients during antiviral therapy. Rationale and hypothesis of the study Our previous studies and current literature support the concept that Treg may contribute to HCV persistence by suppressing HCV-spec immune responses. The current study is designed to examine if peginterferon and ribavirin therapy affects the activity of Treg and DC, and if this results in enhanced HCV-specific immune responses. Design Single centre, translational and observational open label study with one arm of 20 genotype 1 patients and one arm of 7 genotype 2/3 patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Investigating Immunological Effects of Treatment for Chronic Hepatitis C Patients.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2b</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female patients between 1870 years of age, with evidence of a chronic hepatitis C Genotype 1,2 or 3 infection. No previous treatment with, peginterferon or conventional interferon plus ribavirin combination therapy. Indication for antiviral therapy of hepatitis C according to current clinical guidelines. Written informed consent. History or other evidence of severe illness, malignancy or any other condition which would make the patient, in the opinion of the investigators, unsuitable for the study. Presence of contraindications for antiviral therapy with peginterferon or ribavirin.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hepatitis C</keyword>
	<keyword>Liver</keyword>
	<keyword>immunology</keyword>
	<keyword>regulation</keyword>
	<keyword>Genotype 1,2,3</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic</keyword>
	<keyword>Pegylated interferon</keyword>
	<keyword>Ribavirin</keyword>
</DOC>