<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00422162</DOC>
	<brief_summary>An eight-week, randomized, double blind, two parallel groups, study to assess clinical response of duloxetine 60 milligrams (mg) and 120 mg per day in patients hospitalized for severe depression.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study Evaluating Duloxetine in Patients Hospitalized for Severe Depression</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Duloxetine Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female patients of ≥ 18 years of age that meet criteria for severe Major Depressive Disorder, without psychotic features (according to Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders Fourth Edition, [DSMIV] and confirmed by Mini International Neuropsychiatric Interview [MINI]). With a total score MontgomeryAsberg Depression Rating Scale (MADRS) ≥ 30 and 6item Hamilton Depression Rating Scale (HAMD6) ≥ 12 and Clinical Global Impression of Severity (CGISeverity) ≥ 4 at both screening and baseline. Requirement of hospitalization (not for social or other nonmedical reasons) at screening visit and at least up to Visit 4. Patients willing and able to comply with the requirement for hospitalization and with all scheduled visits, tests and procedures required by the protocol. Informed consent document must be signed at screening visit, in accordance with Good Clinical Practice (GCP) and local regulatory requirements, prior to any study procedure. More than two previous episodes of major depression that did not respond (according to investigator's opinion) to adequate doses and duration of two different antidepressant therapies. Lack of response to at least two antidepressant therapies given at adequate doses for at least 6 weeks for the current depressive episode. Concurrent presence of symptoms fulfilling criteria for any Axis I disorder other than anxiety disorders (with exception of the ObsessiveCompulsive Disorder (OCD)) or Major Depressive Disorder, in the investigator's judgment. Any previous diagnosis of a bipolar disorder, schizophrenia or OCD. Depression with catatonic features (according to DSMIV), depression with postpartum onset, or organic mental disorders. The presence of an Axis II disorder</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2011</verification_date>
</DOC>