<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01076192</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effectiveness and safety of adalimumab as used in routine clinical practice in adult patients with moderate to severe chronic plaque psoriasis in Spain.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Adalimumab (HUMIRA®) in Patients With Moderate to Severe Psoriasis (PS) in Spain (PROMISE)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PROMISE is a 2 year post-authorization study of patients taking adalimumab for Psoriasis. Patients who volunteer to participate will be asked to provide information about their medical history and experiences with adalimumab. No study specific testing will be performed. Patients will be asked to provide data on their experiences with adalimumab approximately every 6 months, or as determined by the study doctor. No drug will be provided as a result of participation in the registry. All treatment decisions are independent of participation in the registry. A total of 547 subjects were enrolled: 532 in the ITT population were analyzed for efficacy (excluding 15 for lack of follow-up visits (n=8), non-fulfillment of the criteria of moderate to severe PS (n=6) and failure to initiate treatment at the baseline visit (n=1)); 542 were analyzed for safety (excluding 5 due to lack of evaluable safety data).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Psoriasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adalimumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient 18 years of age or older. Patient diagnosed with moderate to severe chronic plaque PS beginning treatment with adalimumab in accordance with the authorized conditions of use. Patient gives informed consent in writing. Patients who cannot be treated in accordance with the local product label Patient participating or going to participate in a clinical trial during the study followup Patient with difficulties for adequately reading, understanding and completing a questionnaire</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Moderate Psoriasis</keyword>
	<keyword>Psoriasis</keyword>
	<keyword>Severe Psoriasis</keyword>
	<keyword>Adalimumab</keyword>
	<keyword>Effectiveness</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
	<keyword>Clinical practice</keyword>
</DOC>