<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01076257</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This research centers on the comparison of the immediate efficacy (right after therapy) and the maintained efficacy (3 months and 6 months) between "Modified Constraint-Induced Movement Therapy" (mCIMT) group and control group at different age.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Modified Constraint-induced Movement Therapy in Children With Brain Damage</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>"Modified Constraint-Induced Movement Therapy" is one of the most recent treatments for children with Brain damage. This well-designed and follow-up RCT study compared home-based CIT with a control intervention (traditional rehabilitation, TR) by combining kinematic analysis and clinical evaluation, which is possible to examine whether functional improvement is accompanied by a change in motor control. We hypothesized that home-based CIT would induce better motor control strategies (shorter RT, MT, lesser MUs, MGA, and PMGA, and larger peak velocity (PV)) for greater functional gains than TR. Furthermore, the beneficial effects would be maintained at 3 and 6 months of follow-up. Findings of this study allow clinicians to understand the underlying motor control changes for functional improvement after home-based CIT.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cerebral Palsy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Development learnednonuse 2. Age range 4y/o15y/o 3. Wrist ext 10˚, MP j't ext 10˚ in affected U/E 4. Can fallow up the simple instruction 5. Modified Ashworth Scale ≦2 6. Pediatric Motor Activity Log ≦2.5 (average) 1. Related muscle skeleton surgery 2. Selective dorsal rhizotomy 3. Botulinum toxin in 6 months 4. Visual perception impaired 5. Hearing perception impaired 6. Balance ability impaired (in constrained)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>15 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>brain damage</keyword>
	<keyword>constraint induced movement therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>kinematic</keyword>
	<keyword>function</keyword>
	<keyword>outcome</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality of life</keyword>
</DOC>