<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00567736</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to evaluate the efficacy of Disci/Rhus toxicodendron. comp.® in patients with chronic low back pain compared to waiting list group, or placebo.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Disci/Rhus Toxicodendron Comp.®, in Patients With Chronic Low Back Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Chronic low back pain is a significant health problem in industrialized countries. Use of complementary medicine is increasing in patients with low back pain. Until now there is no evidence for the efficacy of Disci/Rhus toxicodendron. comp.® in patients with chronic low back pain.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Low Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female patients, 30 to 75 years Willingness of following the study protocol Clinical diagnosis of chronic low back pain Low back pain since at least 3 months Average pain intensity of at least 40 mm on VAS (0100 mm) in the last 7 days In the last 4 weeks only oral NSAD and muscle relaxation treatment Effective oral contraception in woman Informed consent Previous treatment with DISCI comp. Treatment with other than NSAID Routine use of pain drugs for other diseases Protrusio or prolapse of one or more intervertebral discs with neurological symptoms Previous spine surgery (Suspicious) infectious spondylopathy Low back pain because of malignant or infectious disease Other causes of back pain symptoms (e.g. M. Bechterev, M. Reiter) Congenital deformity of spine (without minor lordosis or kyphosis or scoliosis (Suspicious) osteoporosis with compression fracture (Suspicious) spinal stenosis Spondylolysis or spondylolisthesis Physiotherapy in the last four weeks or planed during trial Begin of a new treatment for low back pain Complementary treatment in the last four weeks or planed during trial Patients who are not able to cooperate in a sufficient way Patients with alcohol or substance abuse Participation in another clinical trial Severe chronical or acute disease which does not allow study participation Patients with bleeding disorders or oral anticoagulation treatment Pregnancy and breast feeding Patients with application for pension Patients involved in planning or coordination of the study Hypersensitivity against drug components</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>low back pain</keyword>
	<keyword>complementary therapies</keyword>
</DOC>