<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02638935</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary aim of this study is to evaluate if VTIQ in addition to BI-RADS® categorization can improve the diagnostic accuracy with respect to detection of malignancies, in particular for BI-RADS® categories 3 and 4a. The idea of the study is to restage all patients in categories 3 and 4a according to a predefined VTIQ cut-off value of 3.5 m/s (37 kPa).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Virtual Touch Tissue Imaging Quantification (VTIQ - 2D-SWE) in the Assessment of BI-RADS® 3 and 4 Lesions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Elastography is a method of imaging tissue stiffness. It is based on shear wave velocity information that can be mapped to create an image of the stiffness in the region of interest. Sonoelastography is used to differentiate benign from malignant lesions since malignant lesions alter tissue elasticity. Adding Shear Wave elastographic features to BI-RADS® feature analysis- especially in lesions scored BI-RADS® 3 and 4a- improved specificity of breast US mass assessment without loss of sensitivity. The BI-RADS® categories are defined by the risk for a malignant lesion varying from benign BI-RADS® 2 lesions, up to a 2% malignancy rate in BI-RADS® 3 and 2- 95% in BI-RADS® 4 (4a 2-10%; 4b 10-50%; 4c 50-95%). Based on these probabilities, biopsies are recommended for BI-RADS® 4 and 5 lesions and short-term follow-up examinations for BI-RADS® 3. Consequently, up to 2% of the in Ultrasound visible breast cancers are not directly detected as such and put into the BI-RADS® 3 category. In contrast, in the BI-RADS® 4a category more than 90% of the biopsies are unnecessary. The main aim of the confirmatory study is to use Virtual Touch Tissue Imaging Quantification in order to reduce unnecessary benign biopsies without a reduction of the number of detected cancers. This multi-center study involves 11 sites in 6 countries. Anticipated study start is December 2015. Recruitment takes place in the course of the patient's routine visit at a certified breast unit. All study participants will receive VTIQ in addition to standard ultrasound. The standard BI-RADS® Ultrasound (US) category (BI-RADS® 3-4c) and VTIQ values will be correlated with the histological result. Additionally, local (BI-RADS® given at each site) and central expert BI-RADS® assessment will be compared (BI-RADS® assessment and assessment of the variables leading to the BI-RADS® value separately) to assess the inter-rater reliability. In addition, the BI-RADS® assessments will be compared with the histological results.Enrollment goal is a total of 1000 cases, split into groups of a minimum of 300 BI-RADS® 3, 400 BI-RADS® 4a, 100 BI-RADS® 4b, 100 BI-RADS® 4c. Monitoring will be performed by the Coordination Center for Clinical Trials (KKS Heidelberg). Completeness, validity and plausibility of data will be checked in time of data entry (edit-checks) and using validating programs, which will generate queries. The investigator or the designated representatives are obliged to clarify or explain the queries. If no further corrections are to be made in the database it will be closed and used for statistical analysis. All data management procedures will be carried out on validated systems and according to the current Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs) of the Institute of Medical Biometry and Informatics.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female Age ≥18 years Patients with a lesion &gt; 0.5 cm in largest diameter size, initially scored BIRADS® 3, 4a, 4b or 4c in Bmode ultrasound Informed consent about histological examination (core cut biopsy (CCB), vacuumassisted biopsy (VAB), fine needle aspiration (FNA) or surgery) has already been given in the course of clinical routine Signed informed consent of study participation Pregnant or lactating women Women with breast implants on the same side as the lesion Women that underwent local radiation or chemotherapy within the last 12 months Women with history of breast cancer or breast surgery in the same quadrant Lesions in or close to scar tissue (&lt; 1cm) Skin lesions or lesions that have been biopsied previously Lesion larger than 4 cm in the longest dimension No lesion should be included when more than 50% of the lesion is further down than 4 cm beneath the skin level.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Virtual Touch Tissue Imaging</keyword>
	<keyword>VTIQ</keyword>
	<keyword>Elastography</keyword>
	<keyword>Breast Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>BI-RADS</keyword>
	<keyword>Differentiation of breast lesions</keyword>
	<keyword>Breast Lesion</keyword>
</DOC>