<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00452452</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the safety, tolerability and immunogenicity of a 13-valent Pneumococcal conjugate vaccine (13vPnC) in older infants and children who have not previously been immunized with Pneumococcal vaccine.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Evaluating 13-valent Pneumococcal Conjugate Vaccine Catch-Up Regimens in Older Infants and Children</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pneumococcal Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heptavalent Pneumococcal Conjugate Vaccine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Aged from 7 months to &lt;72 months at time of enrollment. 2. Available for entire study period and whose parent/legal guardian could be reached by telephone. 3. Healthy as determined by medical history, physical examination, and judgment of the investigator. 4. Parent/legal guardian had to be able to complete all relevant study procedures during subject participation. 1. Previous vaccination with licensed or investigational pneumococcal vaccine. 2. A previous anaphylactic reaction to any vaccine or vaccinerelated component. 3. Contraindication to vaccination with pneumococcal vaccine. 4. Bleeding diathesis or condition associated with prolonged bleeding time that would contraindicate intramuscular injection. 5. Known or suspected immune deficiency or suppression. 6. History of cultureproven invasive disease caused by S pneumoniae. 7. Major known congenital malformation or serious chronic disorders. 8. Significant neurological disorder or history of seizure including febrile seizure, or significant stable or evolving disorders such as cerebral palsy, encephalopathy, hydrocephalus, or other significant disorders. Does not include resolving syndromes due to birth trauma such as Erb palsy. 9. Receipt of blood products or gammaglobulin (including monoclonal antibodies) in the last 3 months. 10. Participation in another investigational or interventional trial. Participation in purely observational studies is acceptable. 11. Child is a direct descendant (child or grandchild) of a member of the study site personnel.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>7 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>5 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pneumococcal Vaccines</keyword>
</DOC>