<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01976793</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This Non-Interventional Study (NIS) is intended to evaluate the duration of treatment with an initial antidepressant taken as monotherapy in patients in whom treatment was changed because of suboptimal response at physician's discretion. This will address unmet medical needs of patients with a depressive episode related to RDD (ICD-10, Version 2010), who have failed to respond adequately to initial treatment with an antidepressant and contribute to an understanding of the usual approaches that physicians adopt to monitor initial treatment efficacy in RDD (Recurrent Depressive Disorder). The study will also focus on second-line therapy in hard to treat patients, describing the different pharmacotherapeutic strategies.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Retrospective Observational Study DIANA Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Female or male aged between 18 and 65 years Inpatients and outpatients diagnosed with an episode of major depression relating to RDD (ICD10, Version 2010) during the period from January 1, 2012 till September 30, 2013 3. Initially treated with antidepressant monotherapy, using a flexible dosage regimen if required, for at least 2 weeks 4. Initial treatment changed because of a suboptimal response at physician's discretion, which is clearly documented in the patient's medical chart. Patients currently participating in any other clinical or noninterventional trial, or have completed their participation with the last 30 days. 2. Patients with current psychiatric or general medical conditions which require concomitant use of lithium, thyroid hormones, or atypical antipsychotics 3. Patients with unstable general medical condition. 4. Patients who were pregnant or were suspected to be pregnant during the period when a patient had received treatment for MDE (Major Depressive Episode).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Recurrent depressive disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Depression</keyword>
	<keyword>Depressive episode</keyword>
	<keyword>Atypical antipsychotics</keyword>
</DOC>