<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01976390</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is being done to compare the effectiveness and safety of two different kidney transplant immunosuppression drugs, Zortress (the study drug) and Rapamune (which is used in the current standard immunosuppression regimen).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparing Everolimus and Sirolimus in Renal Transplant Recipients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Zortress is FDA approved, is used as standard of care at some other institutions, and may also be given as standard of care if it is believed to be the best immunosuppression regimen for a particular kidney transplant recipient. The rationale for testing Zortress vs. Rapamune is to determine which of these drugs is more effective in preventing chronic rejection of the transplanted kidney. Because these two drugs are related to each other there is no current literature addressing the replacement of Rapamune with Zortress in an immunosuppression regimen, therefore the goal of this study is to compare these two immunosuppression drugs.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients must give written informed consent before any assessment is performed. 2. Primary renal transplant recipients between ages 18 and 75 years of age. 3. Females capable of becoming pregnant must have a negative pregnancy test prior to transplantation and practice an effective form of birth control for the duration of the study and 12 weeks after discontinuation of the study drug if applicable. 1. Total cholesterol &gt; 300 mg/dl or triglycerides &gt; 400 mg/dl despite lipid lowering therapy 2. Preexisting bone marrow suppression (White Blood Cell count of &lt; 3000, platelets &lt; 100,000) 3. Active infection (Hepatitis B Virus, HIV) 4. Malignancy (except for adequately treated squamous or basal cell skin carcinoma) unless patient has written clearance from an Oncologist or if patient has had no malignancy for at least 2 years prior to the transplant 5. Allergy or intolerance to Zortress, Rapamune, cyclosporine, or Antithymocyte globulin</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Kidney</keyword>
	<keyword>Kidney transplant</keyword>
	<keyword>Renal failure</keyword>
	<keyword>End Stage Renal Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>kidney transplant recipient</keyword>
</DOC>