<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03037060</DOC>
	<brief_summary>There is a need to better understand the mechanisms underlying alcohol use and dependence in order to advance the clinical treatment of alcohol dependence. Here, the investigators will use Positron Emission Tomography to determine if there is an up-regulation of D3 receptors in the brains of subjects with alcohol use disorders. The investigators will also investigate the relationship between D3 binding and major phenotypes associated with alcohol use disorders, namely: alcohol cue induced craving and motivation to self-administer alcohol in the laboratory.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Exploring Regulation and Function of Dopamine D3 Receptors in Alcohol Use Disorders: A [11C]-(+)-PHNO Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Alcohol dependence is a devastating illness with social and medical costs estimated to be 180 billion dollars annually in the US. In the clinical treatment of alcoholism, reducing alcohol consumption in heavy drinkers is a major clinical challenge. As such, there has been much emphasis in both clinical and preclinical research to identify the substrates that mediate craving, excessive drinking and addiction. Identifying the neurobiological mechanisms of alcohol dependence may lead to the development of new and better treatment strategies. Preclinical studies indicate that the D3 receptor is involved in alcohol-cue response and in the motivation to drink alcohol. However, there is currently no data available in human subjects exploring the relationship between D3 and those behavioral responses in subjects with alcohol use disorders. Aim #1: To measure the [11C]-(+)-PHNO PET binding levels in the brains of subjects with alcohol use disorders. Aim #2: To determine the relationship between D3 receptor binding and alcohol cue induced craving and motivation to self-administer alcohol in the laboratory. To achieve designated goals, the investigators will recruit 25 male and female subjects who are non-treatment seekers. After a period of abstinence from alcohol, participants will come to the Centre for Addiction of Mental Health for a [11C]-(+)-PHNO PET scan. Participants will also have additional sessions during which other alcohol-related measures will be assessed (i.e. alcohol cue induced craving and motivation to self-administer alcohol in the laboratory).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alcohol Drinking</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ethanol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dopamine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects will meet diagnostic criteria for alcohol use disorder (mild through severe). Willing to abstain from drugs and alcohol prior to study visits Current nonregular smokers assessed by selfreport and negative CO A negative urine screen for illicit psychoactive drug use Willing and capable to provide written informed consent Willing to participate in cue exposure and intravenous alcohol administration sessions DSM diagnosis of drug dependence other than alcohol Any severe Axis I disorder aside from alcohol use disorder Any medical condition requiring immediate investigation History of seizures, past or current neurological illness or serious head trauma Suicidal ideation Pregnancy tested by urine or blood screen or lactation Current past or anticipated exposure to radiation exceeding permissible limits as set by the CAMH PET Centre Metal implants or paramagnetic objects within the body which may interfere with the MRI Claustrophobia or a history of panic attacks Any other problem that, in the investigators' opinion, would preclude participation in trial (i.e., complicated withdrawal). History of seeking treatment for alcohol problems or currently attempting to reduce/quit drinking History of negative responses to venipuncture procedures (e.g., fainting/vasovagal response) Medications or medical disorders for which alcohol consumption is contraindicated</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Alcohol use, problem</keyword>
</DOC>