<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02648204</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial is conducted globally. The aim of this trial is to investigate efficacy and safety of semaglutide versus dulaglutide as add-on to metformin in subjects with type 2 diabetes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Semaglutide Versus Dulaglutide as add-on to Metformin in Subjects With Type 2 Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dulaglutide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulin Fc Fragments</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female, age at least 18 years at the time of signing informed consent. HbA1c (glycosylated haemoglobin) 7.0 10.5% (53 91 mmol/mol) (both inclusive) Subjects on stable diabetes treatment with metformin (minimum of 1500 mg/day or maximal tolerated dose documented in the patient medical record) for 90 days prior to screening Female who is pregnant, breastfeeding or intends to become pregnant or is of childbearing potential and not using an adequate contraceptive method (adequate contraceptive measures as required by local regulation or practice) Any condition, which in the investigator's opinion might jeopardise subject's safety or compliance with the protocol Treatment with any medication for the indication of diabetes or obesity other than stated in the inclusion criteria in a period of 90 days before screening. An exception is shortterm insulin treatment for acute illness for a total of equal to or below 14 days History of pancreatitis (acute or chronic) Screening calcitonin equal to or above 50 ng/L Family or personal history of Multiple Endocrine Neoplasia Type 2 or Medullary Thyroid Carcinoma Renal impairment defined as eGFR (electronic case report form) below 60 mL/min/1.73 m^2 as per CKDEPI (Chronic Kidney Disease Epidemiology Collaboration) Subjects presently classified as being in New York Heart Association Class IV Planned coronary, carotid or peripheral artery revascularisation on the day of screening Proliferative retinopathy or maculopathy requiring acute treatment History or presence of malignant neoplasms within the last 5 years (except basal and squamous cell skin cancer and insitu carcinomas) Anticipated initiation or change in concomitant medications (for more than 14 consecutive days or on a frequent basis) known to affect weight or glucose metabolism (e.g. orlistat, thyroid hormones, corticosteroids)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>