<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02648269</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This Study will first evaluate the safety and pharmacokinetics of a single intravenous dose of SEL-110, a nanoparticle containing rapamycin, in subjects with elevated blood uric acid levels. This will be followed, in separate subjects, by evaluation of the safety, pharmacokinetics, pharmacodynamics and immunogenicity of a single intravenous dose of SEL-212, SEL-037 (pegsiticase) plus SEL-110, in subjects with elevated blood uric acid levels. Uricase is an enzyme that converts uric acid to the readily soluble allantoin that is then excreted and SEL-110 is designed to prevent unwanted anti-drug-antibodies (ADAs) from forming.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Pharmacodynamics of SEL-212 (Pegsiticase + SEL-110) in Subjects With Elevated Blood Uric Acid Levels</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This Study will first evaluate the safety and pharmacokinetics of a single intravenous dose of SEL-110, a nanoparticle containing rapamycin, in subjects with elevated blood uric acid levels. This will be followed, in separate subjects, by evaluation of the safety, pharmacokinetics, pharmacodynamics and immunogenicity of a single intravenous dose of SEL-212, SEL-037 (pegsiticase) plus SEL-110, in subjects with elevated blood uric acid levels. Uricase is an enzyme that converts uric acid to the readily soluble allantoin that is then excreted and SEL-110 is designed to prevent unwanted anti-drug-antibodies (ADAs) from forming. Cohorts of subjects in the SEL-110 only arms of the study will be given a single, ascending intravenous dose of SEL-110 and then monitored for safety and rapamycin levels (pharmacokinetics) over 30 days. Cohorts of subjects in the SEL-212 arms of the study will be given a single, ascending intravenous dose of SEL-110 with a fixed dose of SEL-037 and then monitored for safety, rapamycin levels, SEL-037 levels, uric acid levels and anti-drug-antibodies (ADAs) to SEL-037 for 30 days. One additional control group with receive a single intravenous infusion of SEL-037 at a fixed dose and then monitored for safety, SEL-037 levels, uric acid levels and anti-drug-antibodies (ADAs) to SEL-037 for 30 days</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Uric Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female subjects ages 21 to 70 inclusive. Female subjects must be of nonchildbearing potential; Has at the screening visit a serum uric acid ≥ 6 mg/dL, with or without a history of gout; The use of allopurinol, febuxostat (Uloric®), or probenecid as uric acidlowering therapy is permissible if dosing has been stable for at least the month prior to the screening visit; Has adequate venous access and able to receive IV therapy; Evidence of a personally signed and dated informed consent document indicating that subject has been informed of all pertinent aspects of the study; Prior exposure to any experimental or marketed uricase (for arms receiving SEL037 or SEL212); History of any allergy to pegylated products; Glucose6phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency or known catalase deficiency; History of hematological or autoimmune disorders, is immunosuppressed or immunocompromised; Presently taking a drug classified as CYP3A4 inducer or inhibitor; Has participated in a clinical trial within 30 days of the Screening;</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>