<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02648009</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The prevalence of congestive heart failure (CHF) in Canada is high, representing one of the health care system's most expensive diagnoses. Despite major advances in medicine, the mortality and morbidity from CHF remains great. Currently, magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) is used for non-invasive imaging of the cardiovascular system to enable the structure and anatomy of the organ to be visualized. However, current MRI methods have limitations when assessing and aiding in the management of CHF. A new imaging method has recently been developed that is showing great promise as a tool in the management of patients with CHF. Rapid imaging of biochemical reactions within myocytes using MRI has recently become possible through the use of the Dynamic Nuclear Polarization (DNP) and dissolution method. DNP-dissolution results in an intravenous contrast agent that is "hyperpolarized", producing a magnetic signal that is enhanced by up to 100,000 fold. The particular agent is carbon-13 labelled pyruvate. In this study, we demonstrate the first 13C-metabolic images of the human heart, along with the required hardware and data acquisition methods.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Metabolic Imaging of the Heart Using Hyperpolarized (13C) Pyruvate Injection</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>For this study, the heart of healthy subjects and those with hypertension or hypertrophy will be imaged using Hyperpolarized Pyruvate 13C Injection. If images are successfully obtained, then insights into heart failure treatments that normalize the detrimental metabolic changes may enable earlier treatment and slow disease progression to CHF, ultimately reducing the high rates of morbidity and mortality associated with this disease. Prior to enrolment, all participants will be screened in order to ensure they meet the study's inclusion and exclusion criteria and MRI eligibility. On the day of their scan, each participant will have an intravenous line inserted and receive a glucose drink, prior to scanning. The reason for this glucose drink is that a fed versus fasted state has been found to give markedly different measurements in animal models and a choice of meal would be a source of variability. The metabolic imaging will occur shortly after this drink. For each scan, a 1.47 g sample of [1-13C]-pyruvic acid will be hyperpolarized using a SpinLab polarizer (General Electric Co.). The solid-state sample will be dissolved to a concentration of 250 mM pyruvate at biological pH. A 0.1 mmol/kg dose (approximately 20 mL) of this solution will be injected through an intravenous line, followed by a 25 mL saline flush. The 13C image acquisition will begin at the end of the injection and will record data during every heartbeat within the single breath-hold. Heart rate and blood pressure will be monitored non-invasively, prior to the participant being positioned within the MR scanner. Heart rate will continue to be monitored during and after the scan and the participant will be monitored by the Study's Qualified Investigator or medical designate for up to 1 hour post injection. The 13C imaging will be preceded by the standard cardiovascular MRI workup including breath-hold cine imaging to measure ejection fraction and LV mass (~30 minutes of scan time). All clinical procedures will be completed at SHSC under the supervision of the Qualified Investigator, or medical designate. Each participant will receive a follow up telephone call on the 7th day following the procedure to ascertain if any study related adverse events have occurred. The length of this study for participants is a single visit that will require approximately three hours of their time. The entire study is expected to take about one year and the results should be known approximately after one year.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertrophy</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥1500 cells/µl Hemoglobin ≥9.0 gm/dL Platelets ≥100,000 cells/µL Glomerular filtration rate( based on MDRD Equation) &gt; 60ml/min/1.73m2 Written consent Age: 19 to 50 in Arm 1, 30 to 75 in Arms 2A, 2B, and 2C Group 2A participants have diagnosed hypertension and hypertrophy Group 2B participants have diagnosed nonobstructive hypertrophic cardiomyopathy Exclusion Criteria Contraindications to MRI or MRI contrast agents On dialysis A history of renal disease Multiple myeloma Peripheral vascular disease The use of specific medications, including aminoglycosides, vancomycin, amphotericin B or immunosuppressants Claustrophobia Have received, or are scheduled to receive, another investigational medicinal product from 1 month prior to 1 month after inclusion in this study BMI of less than 18.5 or greater than 32</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>