<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02648659</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study assessed the effect of tailored eradication therapy according to Clarithromycin resistance in Helicobacter pylori patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Pilot Study on Tailored Eradication Therapy According to Clarithromycin Resistance in H.Pylori Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study assessed the effect of tailored eradication therapy according to Clarithromycin resistance in Helicobacter pylori patients. The patients with gastric or duodenal ulcer by endoscopy were registered at the study and inspected Rapid Urease test, Biopsy, IgG-Hp antibody. The tailored eradication therapy was prescribed to patients that confirmed Helicobacter pylori positive in two or more of among the three tests for 14 days. Through this, This study is to assess the effectiveness of eradication rate and to evaluate safety and tolerability of Ilaprazole 10mg qid treatment</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Peptic Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metronidazole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Clarithromycin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amoxicillin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>• 20 year old ≤ Male or female &lt; 80 year old Among Patients with gastric or duodenal ulcer by endoscopy, Subject who is identified Helicobacter pyloripositive in the conduct of two or more of the following tests ; Rapid Urease test, Biopsy test, IgGHp antibody test. Subject who fully understands conditions of clinical trial Subject who agrees to participate and spontaneously sign the ICF Known hypersensitivity to experimental and concomitant drugs Subjects who are taking contraindicated medications for experimental and concomitant drug. Subjects with abnormal levels in the laboratory tests Total Bilirubin, Creatinine&gt; 1.5 times upper limit of normal AST, ALT, Alkaline phosphatase, BUN&gt; 2 times upper limit of normal Administrated of PPI, antibiotic medication within 2 weeks prior to commencement of the study. Pregnant and/or lactating women Reproductive aged women not using contraception Uncontrolled diabetics Uncontrolled hypertension Uncontrolled liver dysfunction Alcoholics Subjects with a history or possibility of digestive malignancy within 5 years Subjects with a history of gastrectomy or esophagectomy Subjects with hereditary diseases such as Galactose intolerance, Lapp lactose deficiency, glucosegalactose malabsorption Subjects participating in a clinical trial before another trial within 30 days Inconsistence judged subject by researcher</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>