<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02648308</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Results from the 5As Team (5AsT) Study have identified critical gaps in medical school curricula on obesity, leading to a wave of new family physicians who are unconfident and poorly equipped to manage obesity with their patients. In an effort to address this gap, all first year medical residents training in family medicine at the University of Alberta during the 2015/2016 year will be required to take a 2 day workshop in Obesity Management as part of the Doctor-Patient Relationship Course. The workshop will focus on knowledge, intangible skills and practicing the 5AsT approach to obesity management with patients of all demographics. The objective of the 5AsT MD2 study is to evaluate the impact of this workshop on the residents' attitudes and beliefs about obesity, as well as their level of confidence in using key aspects of the 5As of obesity management to help their patients. Participants will be asked to complete and submit pre- and post- knowledge assessments, narrative reflections and questionnaires assessing their beliefs and attitudes towards people living with obesity as part of their core requirements for the course. For those who consent to participate in the study and release their de-identified course assignments, we will evaluate the impact of the workshop using both quantitative and qualitative methods. The results will assist us in gaining information that may help us improve and further refine curricular materials for physicians and medical trainees.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Extension of the 5As Team Study for Improved Provider Obesity Management to Physicians and Medical Trainees (Part 2)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Background: Obesity is a complex chronic condition that negatively impacts individuals, society, and the healthcare system. Family physicians are one of many health practitioners tasked with the long-term care of patients with obesity and its associated co-morbidities. However, focus groups conducted by the 5As Team (5AsT) have identified critical gaps in medical school curricula on obesity, leading to a wave of new family physicians who are unconfident and poorly equipped to manage obesity with their patients. To address this education gap, the 5As team developed a comprehensive training module on obesity management for family medicine residents at the University of Alberta. Study Objectives: This study aims to evaluate the impact of this module on the residents' attitudes and beliefs about obesity, as well as their level of confidence in using key aspects of the 5As of obesity management to help their patients. Methods: Based on focus groups conducted with medical students and practicing physicians during a summer project last year, a list of learning objectives was made to address known deficiencies in obesity education. These learning objectives were adapted to a two-day training module on obesity management for first year family medicine residents. All 2015/2016 first year medical residents are required to take a 2 day Obesity Management Workshop as part of their Doctor-Patient Relationship course. The first day consists of a lecture on weight bias and an opportunity to experience using a bariatric suit in a simulated living environment. The second day consists of a patient presentation, an introduction to the 5As of obesity management, interactive group discussions, and standardized patient interviews. Existing materials from the 5AsT intervention and Canadian Obesity Network were used to develop knowledge assessments, educational readings, narrative reflective assignments, and four standardized patient cases. These materials are to be used for the module, which will span an expected 62 family medicine residents at the University of Alberta. Consent: Residents will be informed about the 5AsT MD2 study on the first day of the 2-day workshop and asked if they would like to participate. If a resident declines to participate, they will still be able to take part in the workshop and will still be required to complete the course materials listed above, however, their course materials will not provided to the research team. Study Procedures: Those residents who have consented to participate in the study, will be asked to place their required course materials into a sealed envelope and will then submit them to a neutral, third party. The neutral, third party is an employee in the Department of Family Medicine and has no responsibilities with regards to evaluation of the medical residents. The neutral, third party will record that the resident has completed their assignment for the course, assign an Identification (ID) number to each resident and label each document as well as the envelope with the resident's ID number. Using a paper cutter, the neutral, third party will then remove the resident's name from each document. A master list will be kept by the neutral, third party, which will allow her to track which ID number corresponds to which resident so that she can appropriately label all of the post-workshop documents with the resident's assigned ID number. Only the neutral, third party will have access to the master last with the residents names. Following the workshop on the second day, the residents who have consented to participate, will, once again, submit their post-workshop course materials, in a sealed envelope, to the neutral third party. The neutral, third party will once again record that the resident completed their assignment for the course, label their documents and envelope with the correct ID number and then remove the resident's name from the documents. The de-identified materials of those residents who have consented to participate will then be given to study staff. The narrative reflective exercises for both part 1 and part 2 of the workshop are due 2 weeks post-workshop event. NB The Timing for data collection is at the beginning of the first day of the workshop and at the end of the second day of the workshop. Results: Participants will complete validated ATOP (Attitudes Toward Obese Persons) and BAOP (Beliefs About Obese Persons) questionnaires, as well as knowledge assessment questionnaires to measure their level of confidence in performing key aspects of obesity management. All questionnaires will de-identified, but responses will be tracked both before and after the training module to quantify the change seen in each study participant. Participants will also write two de-identified narrative reflections to be used for qualitative analysis. The first is on the weight bias bariatric suit experience, and the second is on the application of the lessons of the workshop in clinical practice.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participants must be first year medical residents training in family medicine at the University of Alberta. They will be recruited from the Obesity Management Workshop that is a required component of their course on DoctorPatient Relationships. All participants must be over the age of 18 and be able to communicate effectively in English. If participants are unable to communicate effectively in English, they will not be able to participate in the study. The Obesity Management Workshop will be presented in English and participants must be able to understand the presentation and written documents that they are being asked to complete.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Education, Medical</keyword>
</DOC>