<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02526693</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Konan RAPDx (Konan Medical USA, Irvine, CA) is a newly patented pupillography device.The aims of this study are to assess the ability of the RAPDx to distinguish between healthy subjects and patients with confirmed glaucoma using standard testing sequences, assess the ability of the RAPDx to distinguish between healthy subjects and patients with confirmed glaucoma using a customized testing sequence developed for use at the Wills Eye Hospital Glaucoma Research Center and to determine the combination of demographic, clinical, and RAPDx testing parameters which allow for maximum sensitivity and specificity in discriminating healthy subjects from those with glaucoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Is the RAPDx Pupillograph Able to Distinguish Between Glaucoma Subjects and Healthy Subjects?</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The RAPDx utilizes digital, high-definition, infrared machine-vision with eye-tracking and automated blink detection technology to analyze and quantify the pupillary response to light. During the scheduled appointment, all patients will receive an undilated fundus examination by the attending ophthalmologist. The data of the following tests will be recorded, Demographic information, Visual acuity, Intraocular pressure (IOP) measured by Goldmann applanation tonometry,DDLS score,Vertical cup/disc ratio, gonioscopy (if not documented in the chart within the past 2 years) and Humphrey visual field examination. Each patient will undergo RAPDx testing with two different testing sequences. They are separated by a 10-second resting period during which the patient is instructed to close his or her eyes. The exam may be paused at any time and re-alignment may be performed during any pause. The two testing sequences are: 1. Standard Factory Setting: 0.1-second stimuli with 2-second inter-stimuli pauses 2. Custom Setting: 3-second stimuli with 1-second inter-stimuli pauses</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glaucoma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Glaucoma patients: characteristic optic nerve damage on slit lamp examination (defined as a definite notch in the neuroretinal rim, asymmetric intereye c/d ratio &gt;0.2 or DDLS&gt;2, or absence of neuroretinal rim not due to another known cause) with corresponding glaucomatous VF deficits (defined as a cluster of 3 or more points on pattern deviation plot depressed below the 5% level, at least 1 of which is depressed below the 1% level; OR corrected pattern standard deviation/pattern standard deviation significant at P &lt;0.05; OR glaucoma hemifield test "outside normal limits") with good reliability indices (fixation losses, falsepositive rate, and falsenegative rate each &lt; 33%). Healthy subjects: normal optic nerve exam with normal and reliable visual fields (Humphrey MD &gt;2 or Octopus MD ≤0.8; fixation losses, falsepositive rate, and falsenegative rate each &lt; 33%) and open angles on gonioscopy. Abnormal ocular motility that prevents binocular fixation (e.g. strabismus, nystagmus). Any condition preventing adequate visualization and examination of the pupil or optic nerve (e.g. dense corneal opacities or lens opacities). Active infection of the anterior or posterior segments of the eye. Any intraocular surgical or laser procedure within the previous 4 weeks. Any nonglaucomatous condition that may cause an RAPD, anisocoria or corectopia (ex. optic neuropathy, Horner's syndrome, previous iris injury due to trauma or surgery, etc.). Subjects under the age of 18 or subjects presently housed in a correctional facility.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>