<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02581384</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This research study is studying stereotactic body radiotherapy (SBRT) as a possible treatment for lung relapse of Ewing Sarcoma, Rhabdomyosarcoma, or Wilms Tumor. SBRT is a form of targeted radiotherapy that can treat very small tumors using a few large doses.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Stereotactic Body Radiotherapy (SBRT) for Pulmonary Metastases in Ewing Sarcoma, Rhabdomyosarcoma, and Wilms Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This research study is a Pilot Study, also known as a Phase I-II study, which means it is the first time investigators are examining this study intervention for patients with lung recurrence of Ewing Sarcoma, Rhabdomyosarcoma, or Wilms Tumor. This study tests the most appropriate dose, safety and efficacy of SBRT for the treatment of lung recurrence of Wilms tumor, rhabdomyosarcoma, or Ewing sarcoma in children. Standard radiotherapy is typically used to treat Ewing sarcoma and is used to treat lung recurrence. SBRT is being used to treat adults with small inoperable lung cancers; in such cases, SBRT has been shown to be effective and well-tolerated. SBRT is also used to treat bone metastases in adults and children.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoma, Ewing</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhabdomyosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Wilms Tumor</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of Ewing sarcoma, rhabdomyosarcoma or Wilms tumor or other primary renal tumor Age 8.0 to age 18.99 years Must be capable of treatment without general anesthesia Lesion size 8 mm 3 cm Pulmonary metastases found at relapse (does not have to be first relapse); no more than 3 lesions per hemithorax Greater than 5 weeks from doxorubicin at the time of consent, with radiation to be initiated no less than 6 weeks from doxorubicin Greater than 3 weeks from intravenous chemotherapy except doxorubicin Informed consent/assent Life expectancy &gt; 3 months Pulmonary function FEV1 ≥ 50% of predicted Females, minorities and other underrepresented populations that are at risk to develop Ewing sarcoma and the other included malignancies Prior wholelung or hemithorax irradiation of greater than or equal to 12 Gy (focal radiotherapy to the thorax is not an exclusion) Lesion larger than 3 cm in diameter Diffuse multiple (&gt; 3 per lung) metastases Active or new metastatic disease outside of the lung Lesions within 2 cm of central structures defined as: Tumor within or touching the zone of the proximal bronchial tree, defined as a volume 2 cm in all directions around the proximal bronchial tree (carina, right and left main bronchi, right and left upper lobe bronchi, intermedius bronchus, right middle lobe bronchus, lingular bronchus, right and left lower lobe bronchi).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>8 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>19 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Ewing Sarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Rhabdomyosarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Wilms Tumor</keyword>
</DOC>