<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00299104</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a phase III, randomized, controlled, double-blind, parallel group, international study in approximately 750 patients with active Rheumatoid Arthritis (RA) who are naive to Methotrexate (MTX) therapy. Rheumatoid Factor (RF)-positive and RF-negative patients will be enrolled and will be allocated equally between 3 treatment arms.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate Rituximab in Combination With Methotrexate in Methotrexate-Naive Patients With Active Rheumatoid Arthritis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methotrexate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Adult patients 1880 years of age RA for ≥ 2 months; Receiving outpatient treatment Patients naive to, and considered to be candidates for, methotrexate treatment Exclusion criteria: Rheumatic autoimmune disease other than RA, or significant systemic involvement secondary to RA Inflammatory joint disease other than RA, or other systemic autoimmune disorder Diagnosis of juvenile rheumatoid arthritis, or RA before the age of 16 Surgery within 12 weeks of study Previous treatment with any approved or investigational biologic agent for RA, an antialpha4integrin antibody or costimulation modulator, or celldepleting therapy Concurrent treatment with any biologic agent or DMARD other than methotrexate</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Rituxan</keyword>
	<keyword>MTX</keyword>
	<keyword>RA</keyword>
	<keyword>IMAGE</keyword>
	<keyword>WA17047</keyword>
</DOC>