<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01686724</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study tests the effectiveness of a newly developed integrated school-home behavioral intervention for behaviors related to Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD). The intervention is implemented by school-based mental health professionals within school settings.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of the Collaborative Life Skills Program</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperkinesis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Attending a participating school and in 25th grade Referral by LSP as a child with apparent ADHDrelated problems ≥ 6 symptoms (item score ≥ 2) of Inattention or HyperactivityImpulsivity on the pooled parent and teacher Child Symptom Inventory ≥ 3 on the Impairment Rating Scale by parent and teacher (crosssituational impairment) FSIQ or VIQ ≥ 80 (necessary for cognitive demands of the child skills curriculum) Caretaker consents to participate in treatment, child assents to participate Presence of conditions that are incompatible with this study's treatment. severe visual or hearing impairment, severe language delay, psychosis, pervasive developmental disorder Parent or child does not read or speak English or does not read or speak Spanish for our Spanish language implementation of CLS (inability to complete assessment measures or participate in group treatments). Child is in an allday special education classroom (children in these classrooms are frequently receiving intensive behavior modification programs such that the intervention would be expected to require modification for use in these settings) Children taking psychotropic medication for any reason other than to treat ADHD Children planning to change (start or stop) psychotropic medication Children who have changed a regimen of psychotropic medication (started or stopped) within 30 days prior to screening</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>7 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>11 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Psychosocial Intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>Behavioral Intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>School-home collaborative intervention</keyword>
</DOC>