<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00936078</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Living kidney donors and non-donor controls will be studied before and after the living donor transplant. The donor and non-donor will be followed for up to 5 years. The purpose of this study is to see if there are any differences between the two groups in regards to blood pressure, rate of hypertension, kidney function and psychological well being and economical status.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Living Kidney Donor Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Transplantation is the preferred treatment option for patients with kidney failure. Compared to dialysis, patients who receive a transplant have a substantial reduction in the risk of death, an improved quality of life, and decreased health care costs. The demand for kidneys has resulted in long waiting lists for deceased donor kidneys. Therefore, living kidney donations have been on the increase over the years in order to meet this demand for kidneys. Living donation also has the added benefit of a shorter waiting time, increased graft success and increased recipient survival compared to deceased donor transplantation. Aside from the advantages for the recipient, living transplantation is a complex medical practice which we must conduct in a safe and ethical manner. The premise for accepting living donors is that the "minimal" risk of short and long-term medical harm realized by the donor is outweighed by the definite advantages to the recipient and potential psychosocial benefits of altruism to the donor. The short-term potential medical consequences for living kidney donors have been well established. Yet, the long-term implications of living kidney donation are far less certain. Potential medical risks include hypertension, proteinuria, reduced kidney function, premature cardiovascular disease and death. Estimates of these outcomes vary substantially in the literature. As well, the potential long-term medical risks are also communicated inconsistently across transplant community. It is accepted that most living donors experience increased self-esteem, feelings of well-being and an improved quality of life after their altruistic act. However, some donors have negative psychosocial outcomes which require further clarification. There is also a financial burden to the donor from the donation process. Concerns about future life, disability and medical insurance have been raised. These issues will be addressed through this research study on the long term implications of donation.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Be able to speak and read English and/or French, and Be able to provide informed consent, and Be between the ages of 18 70 AND Subjects must either: Be approved by the LHSC team (or applicable medical team at the participating sites) as eligible to donate their kidney, OR Meet study eligibility for controls (nondonors) as follows: Meet blood pressure criteria as follows; Blood pressure &lt; 140 mmHg systolic and &lt; 90 mmHg diastolic based on an average of last 3 blood pressure measurements taken during the interview, or Average blood pressure &lt; 140 mmHg systolic and &lt; 90 mmHg diastolic based on a minimum of 12 readings taken at home. Meet local lab criteria as follows; Documented predonation serum creatinine &lt; 115µmol/L (1.3 mg/dL) in men or &lt; 90µmol/L (1.0mg/dL) in women, or CockcroftGault estimated glomerular filtration rate &gt; 80 mL/min. Urine dipstick test for protein is negative or a random urine albumin to creatinine ratio &lt; 8 mg/mmol (70 mg/g) Urine dipstick test for hematuria is negative. Test should not occur during menses, and test should be repeated if there is evidence of urinary tract infection. Have a Body mass index of &lt; 35 kg/m2 Be involved in another clinical study that would affect the outcome of this study. AND Control (nondonors)subjects must not: Ever have received dialysis, even for a short period of time Ever have had a kidney transplant Be taking any hypertension class medication for any reason Have any history of hypertension, currently or in the past Have plasma glucose of &gt;7 mmol/L after a 6 hr fast, or a two hour oral glucose test of 11.1 mmol/L, or Have a history of diabetes during pregnancy Have been symptomatic for kidney stones any time in the past 3 years Have a known contraindication to anesthesia or surgery, or Be currently pregnant or have been pregnant in the past month, or Have a medical condition that would prevent him or her from becoming a kidney donor (e.g. History of renal disease, Permanent protein in urine, Cancer other than cured nonmelanoma skin cancer, Cardiovascular disease, Pulmonary disease)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>kidney transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>cohort study</keyword>
	<keyword>qualitative research</keyword>
	<keyword>health services research</keyword>
	<keyword>hypertension</keyword>
</DOC>