<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00936013</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to determine whether the combination treatment of Chinese medicinal herbs and oseltamivir is more effective than single oseltamivir in treating novel influenza A (H1N1) pneumonia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Chinese Medicinal Herbs Treatment on Novel Influenza A (H1N1)Pneumonia: Multi-centre, Prospective, Randomized Controlled Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The antiviral agent, oseltamivir, is recommended by the World Health Organization (WHO) to treat recent outbreak novel influenza A (H1N1) virus infection around world. But limited stock and resistant strain emergence raised increasing concerns. Chinese medicinal herbs, are derived from plants and usually incorporate one or more herbs as the basic drug(s) to treat the disease. The investigators performed RCT to indicate that a combination treatment of Chinese medicinal herbs and oseltamivir is more effective than single oseltamivir in treating novel influenza A (H1N1) pneumonia.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oseltamivir</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Confirmed novel influenza A(H1N1) case with laboratory evidence 70 ys ≥ age ≥14ys Within 72hr after the onset of symptoms(body temperature≥37.5℃ with at least one respiratory symptom (cough, sore throat, or nasal symptom) New lung infiltration showed by chest radiology(xray or CT) Age&lt;14ys or &gt;70ys Pregnancy Severe chronic underlying diseases: severe COPD(FEV1/EVC &lt;70% and FEV1 &lt;30% predicted or respiratory failure or congestive heart failure), severe liver disfunction（ALT or AST ≥3 times normal elevation), renal disfunction（Cr&gt;2mg/dL), chronic heart failure(NYHA ⅢⅣ grade） Immunocompromised patients(cancer, organ transplant, AIDS and a history of treatment with immunosuppressive drug and glucocorticoids in the past 3 months) Taken Chinese medicinal herbs, antiviral or antibiotic drug in the past 2 weeks Inoculation influenza vaccination One of the following items appeared at the enrollment respiratory failure：PaO2&lt;60mmHg and/or PCO2&gt;50mmHg or PaO2/FiO2≤300 circulation failure: despite adequate fluid resuscitation and cardiac output, systolic &lt;90mmHg or requirement inotropic support renal function failure: despite adequate fluid resuscitation and cardiac output, urine ≤ 0.5ml/kg.h, Cr or BUN≥1 time normal elevation liver function failure: total bilirubin&gt;34μmol/L or ALT/AST ≥3 times normal elevation Other unappropriated enrollment situations considered by investigator</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>14 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>novel influenza A(H1N1)</keyword>
	<keyword>chinese medicinal herbs</keyword>
</DOC>