<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00936429</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a single-center, double-blind, randomized, Phase 1 study to assess the safety and tolerability of HBV-001 D1 in healthy adult subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of HBV-001 D1 in Healthy Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a single-center, double-blind, randomized, Phase 1 study to assess the safety and tolerability of HBV-001 D1 in healthy adult subjects. This will be an upward titration of two dose levels of HBV-001 D1 (10 µg and 50 µg of DEN1-80E) in 16 subjects across two cohorts. Participants in each cohort will receive HBV-001 D1 vaccine or placebo on Visits 1, 3 and 5.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dengue</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aluminum Hydroxide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males or females age 18 to 45. Body weight ≥ 110 pounds (50 kg). Satisfactory medical condition established by medical history and physical examination. Females must be of nonchild bearing potential (i.e., surgically sterile) or, if of childbearing potential must be abstinent or willing to employ adequate means of contraception. Positive serum test for HIV, Hepatitis B surface antigens (HBsAg) and/or Hepatitis C antibodies. Abuse of drugs or alcohol within 12 months prior to screening. Use of corticosteroids or immunosuppressive drugs within 30 days of screening (use of topical or nasal corticosteroids is allowed). Any confirmed or suspected immunosuppressive or immunodeficient condition. Receipt of any vaccination within 30 days prior to screening. Receipt of blood products within 6 months of screening. Previous flavivirus vaccination (e.g., Japanese encephalitis or yellow fever) or flavivirus vaccination planned during the study period. History of flavivirus infection. No easy access to a fixed or mobile telephone. History of residing in a country endemic for dengue, Japanese encephalitis virus, or Yellow Fever virus for a period of &gt; 1 year. Donation of ≥ 450 mL of blood within the previous 12 weeks.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dengue fever</keyword>
	<keyword>Dengue hemorrhagic fever</keyword>
	<keyword>Dengue shock syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>Hawaii Biotech</keyword>
</DOC>