<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00936468</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is designed to determine the optimal dose of JVRS-100 and assess safety, tolerability and immunogenicity of Fluzone® vaccine administered with JVRS-100 adjuvant at one of three dose levels compared to Fluzone® vaccine administered alone, in 472 adults aged ≥65 years.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety, Tolerability and Immunogenicity of Fluzone® With and Without JVRS-100 in Elderly Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Approximately 472 subjects will be enrolled in this study. The study population will include elderly male and female subjects aged ≥65 years who are living in the community (including assisted living environments) and who are very fit to moderately frail. One hundred subjects (approximately 25 in each treatment arms) will be vaccinated, and 14 days will elapse during which safety parameters are monitored by a Data and Safety Monitoring Board (DSMB), before randomizing the remaining 372 subjects.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Be adult volunteers aged ≥65 years Live in the community, independently or in an assisted living environment Be Class 15, as defined by the CSHACFS If female, will be postmenopausal Will be available for the duration of the trial (21day On Study Period) and FollowUp (4 and 9 months after vaccination) Be 'probably not demented' on the MiniCog test Provide informed consent Agree to defer receipt of vaccination of novel H1N1 (swine) influenza until after completion of the Day 28 study procedures Known allergy to eggs or other components of the vaccine. History of severe reaction of any kind to conventional influenza vaccines Be Class 67 in the CSHACFS or be institutionalized (e.g., in a nursing home) Requiring nursing homelevel equivalent care at home or within a community assisted living environment Chronic administration of immunosuppressants or other immunemodifying drugs within 6 months prior to the administration of the study vaccine. Significant cardiovascular disease (e.g., NYHA class 3 through 4 congestive heart failure; myocardial infarction within the past 6 months; unstable angina; coronary angioplasty within the past 6 months; uncontrolled ventricular cardiac arrhythmias); resting heart rate &gt;100; A history of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease or history of other lung disease requiring chronic steroid treatment in excess of a bioequivalent dose of 10 mg prednisone daily; a combined history of lung disease and anemia. Evidence of significant (more than 10 pounds) of unintentional weight loss in the last year. Changed residence or become hospitalized in the last 6 months. Combined history of depression and anemia. Administration of immunoglobulins and/or any blood products within the 3 months preceding the administration of the study vaccine or during the study. Any confirmed or suspected immunosuppressive or immunodeficient condition, based on medical history and physical examination. Use of any investigational product within 60 days preceding the administration of the study vaccine, or planned use during the study period. Seropositive to HIV or HCV or positive for HBsAg Body temperature &gt;38.1°C (100.6°F) or acute illness within 3 days prior to vaccination (subject may be rescheduled) History of excessive alcohol consumption, drug abuse, or significant psychiatric illness. Be 'probably demented' on the MinCog test Need for guardian assistance in completing informed consent Has received vaccination for novel H1N1 (swine) influenza</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Elderly influenza vaccine</keyword>
</DOC>