<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="17301">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02881658</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CTC1521</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02881658</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of 3-Week Consumption of Soya Beverage Enriched With Plant Sterols on Serum LDL-C</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Soya Beverage Fortified With Plant Sterol on Major Serum Lipids in Normocholesterolemic, Healthy Southern Chinese Individuals</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The University of Hong Kong</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The University of Hong Kong</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a local, single-center, two-arm, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled
      clinical trial that examines the LDL-C-lowering effect of the consumption of a soya beverage
      enriched with plant sterol for 3 weeks. This study also examines if there is other
      health-benefits by consuming the plant sterols fortified soya beverage in terms of serum
      total triglyceride, total and HDL cholesterol, other cardiometabolic risk factors and
      musculoskeletal-related traits including handgrip strength, gait speed, peak expiratory flow
      rate, bio-impedance and body balance.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Cardiovascular disease (CVD) is the third commonest cause of deaths in Hong Kong and
      accounting for 14.4% of all deaths in 2012. Robust data attest the causal role of
      low-density lipoprotein cholesterol (LDL-C) in the development and progression of CVD.
      Reduction of LDL-C levels achieved by pharmacological agents in conjunction with diet change
      has been demonstrated to significantly reduce CVD morbidity and mortality. Moreover, it has
      been frequently reported that dietary incorporation of plant sterols/stanols could reduce
      blood LDL-C level in both healthy and dyslipidaemic individuals with great inter-individual
      variability of LDL-C response. Therefore, functional food enriched with plant
      sterols/stanols not only may provide additional LDL-C lowering benefit in dyslipidaemic
      patients as an adjunct to traditional pharmacologic therapy, but also play a role in primary
      prevention of CVD in the general population.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>May 2016</start_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double Blind (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean of serum low-density lipoprotein cholesterol (LDL-C) via blood test at baseline and week 3</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to week 3</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of low density lipoprotein cholesterol (LDL-C) via blood test at baseline and week 3</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to week 3</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of high-density lipoprotein cholesterol (HDL-C) via blood test at baseline and week 3</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to week 3</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of total cholesterol via blood test at baseline and week 3</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to week 3</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of triglycerides (TAG) via blood test at baseline and week 3</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to week 3</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of serum creatinine via blood test at baseline and week 3</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to week 3</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes of fasting blood glucose via blood test at baseline and week 3</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to week 3</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes of cardiometabolic risk factors via measuring anthropometry at baseline and week 3</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to week 3</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes of cardiometabolic risk factors via measuring blood pressure at baseline and week 3</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to week 3</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes of cardiometabolic risk factors via measuring body temperature at baseline and week 3</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to week 3</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes of musculoskeletal-related traits via measuring hand grip strength at baseline and week 3</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to week 3</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes of musculoskeletal-related traits via measuring Bio-Impedance at baseline and week 3</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to week 3</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes of musculoskeletal-related traits via measuring peak expiratory flow rate at baseline and week 3</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to week 3</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes of musculoskeletal-related traits via measuring 6 metres gait speed at baseline and week 3</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to week 3</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes of musculoskeletal-related traits via measuring centre of pressure excursion index for left and right foot at baseline and week 3</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to week 3</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Dyslipidemia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Plant sterols-enriched soya beverage</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Daily consumption of 2g of plant sterols as provided by one pack of 250 ml of plant sterols-enriched soya beverage for consecutive 3 weeks, each pack consumed once with main meal (i.e breakfast, lunch or dinner).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Soya beverage</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Daily consumption of one pack of 250 ml of soya beverage (without plant sterols) for consecutive 3 weeks, each pack consumed once with main meal (i.e breakfast, lunch or dinner).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Plant sterols-enriched soya beverage</intervention_name>
    <description>the study product is a 2g plant sterols-enriched in 250ml soya beverage</description>
    <arm_group_label>Plant sterols-enriched soya beverage</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Soya beverage</intervention_name>
    <description>the placebo product is a 250 ml soya beverage</description>
    <arm_group_label>Soya beverage</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Southern Chinese male or female ≥ 18 years;

          -  In good general health as evidenced by medical history;

          -  Have the ability to understand the requirements of the study, provide written
             informed consent, including consent for the use and disclose of research-related
             health information, and comply with the study data collection procedures. Provide
             signed and dated informed consent form

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Subject with familial hypercholesterolemia;

          -  On regular medication(s) which affect gastrointestinal functions and blood lipids
             level for the past 3 months, such as, but not limited to:

               -  Antibiotics of &gt;1 week duration

               -  GI related medications such as antacids

          -  Having blood lipid lowering medications such as statins, selective cholesterol
             absorption inhibitors (e.g. ezetimibe), fibrates, niacin, resins, omega- 3

          -  Heavy-smokers (more than 1 pack per day)

          -  Subject with heavy alcohol intake (&gt;40 g/day for men ; &gt;30 g/day for women) (32), or
             having history of alcohol abuse within 12 months prior to the study

          -  Subjects with taste aversion to placebo/intervention soya beverages

          -  Subject refusing to stop the consumption of plant sterols-enriched products if any
             during the study (other than the studied product) or having regular consumption of
             sterols/stanols cholesterol-lowering supplements/functional foods or other related
             products such as:

               -  Sterol/ Stanol - containing margarines, milk, yoghurt drink and soya beverages

               -  Sterol / Stanol supplements

               -  Fish oils &amp; omega-3 supplements

          -  Subject receiving systemic treatment or topical treatment likely to interfere with
             evaluation of the study parameters

          -  Subject currently involved in a clinical trial or in an exclusion period following
             participation in another clinical trial

          -  Pregnancy or lactation

          -  Having soy allergy

          -  Being a vegan

          -  Being an athlete

          -  Concurrently participating in weight management or dietary program

          -  On diet pills, such as, but not limited to chitosan and dulcolax

          -  With history of sitosterolemia

          -  Having history of hypercholesterolemia, diabetes, thyroid disease, severe kidney
             diseases, cardiovascular diseases, chronic gastrointestinal disorders, cancers and
             AIDs ( acquired immune deficiency syndrome)

          -  Having history of malabsorption syndrome arising from diseases such as, but not
             limited to celiac disease, short bowel syndrome, cystic fibrosis, pancreatitis,
             diseases of gall-bladder, liver or pancreas, intestinal infection, injury, surgery
             and radiotherapy

          -  Taking over-the-counter Chinese medications or supplements with cholesterol/lipid
             lowering and related claims

          -  High blood cholesterol at screening [Total cholesterol level ≥6.22mmol/L]

          -  High LDL cholesterol [LDL cholesterol level ≥4.15mmol/L]

          -  High blood triglyceride at screening [Triglyceride ≥3.39mmol/L]

          -  Anything that would place the individual at increased risk or preclude the
             individual's full compliance with or completion of the study.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Bernard Man Yung Cheung</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Li Ka Shing Faculty of Medicine, The University of Hong Kong</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ching Lung Cheung</last_name>
    <phone>28315085</phone>
    <email>lung1212@hku.hk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Li Ka Shing Faculty of Medicine, The University of Hong Kong</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pokfulam</city>
        <country>Hong Kong</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ching Lung Cheung</last_name>
      <phone>28315085</phone>
      <email>lung1212@hku.hk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Hong Kong</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>August 23, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>August 14, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>The University of Hong Kong</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Professor Bernard Cheung</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Department of Medicine, HKU</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Plant sterols</keyword>
  <keyword>Low-Density Lipoprotein Cholesterol</keyword>
  <keyword>Phytosterols</keyword>
  <keyword>Soya Beverage</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Dyslipidemias</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
