<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01796652</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Acute pancreatitis (AP) is considered a disease requiring in-hospital treatment. We studied the feasibility of home management in AP.The aim of study was to compare 30 day readmission rates in patients with mild non-alcoholic acute pancreatitis (NAAP) randomized to home monitoring versus hospitalization.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Home Treatment of Acute Pancreatitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Between 11/11-5/12, 84 patients with mild NAAP were randomized to home or hospital groups after a short (≤24 hours) hospital stay. AP was defined as ≥2 or more of the following: characteristic abdominal pain, amylase and/or lipase ≥3X the upper limit of normal, and/or imaging findings. Patients with an Imrie's score ≤5 and a harmless acute pancreatitis score (HAPS) ≤2 were included. Patients in both groups received intravenous lactated Ringer for 3 days and pain was treated with intramuscular diclofenac. A nurse visited all patients in the home group on the 2nd, 3rd and 5th day. All patients recalled for follow-up on the 7th, 14th, and 30th days.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of AP based on 2 out of 3 findings: characteristic abdominal pain, amylase and/or lipase levels ≥3 times the upper limit of normal, and/or abdominal imaging demonstrating changes of acute pancreatitis Presentation within 48 hours of symptom onset Imrie's scores of ≤5 and HAP score ≤2 within 24 hours of presentation to the hospital Lack of hemoconcentration (hematocrit ≥44%) on presentation since hemoconcentration has been shown to be a risk factor for pancreatic necrosis. The presence of organ failure by the Atlanta criteria on the first day of presentation The presence of clinical signs and/or symptoms of sepsis Alcoholic acute pancreatitis A history of abdominal imaging demonstrating a dilated pancreatic duct and/or pancreatic calcifications Coagulopathy (international normalized ratio &gt;1, and/or platelet count &lt;50,000/mm3 Comorbidities requiring hospitalization regardless of the presence of AP e.g. acute myocardial infarction, malignancy, cirrhosis, chronic kidney disease, and chronic pulmonary disease)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acute interstitial pancreatitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Home therapy</keyword>
</DOC>