<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01796964</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the efficacy and safety of ESBA1008 versus EYLEA® in the treatment of exudative age-related macular degeneration.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety Study of ESBA1008 Versus EYLEA®</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study consisted of 16 visits (Screening, Baseline [Day 0], and 14 post-baseline assessment visits) that occurred at 4-week intervals through Week 56. Enrolled subjects were randomized 1:1 to receive ESBA1008 or EYLEA. All subjects received active intravitreal (IVT) injections at baseline with 2 additional loading doses of the assigned investigational product at 4-week intervals (ie, at Weeks 4 and 8) and then received further injections at 8-weeks intervals at Weeks 16, 24, and 32. Subjects in the ESBA1008 group also received an injection at Week 44, while subjects in the EYLEA group also received injections at Weeks 40 and 48. To maintain the study masking, subjects in the ESBA1008 group received sham injections at Weeks 40 and 48 (when the subjects in the EYLEA group received active injections), while subjects in the EYLEA group received a sham injection at Week 44 (when the subjects in the ESBA1008 group received an active injection). All subjects were followed up to Week 56. Week 40 visit was the end of assessment period for the 8-week treatment cycle.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Wet Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Give written informed consent; be able to make the required study visits and follow instructions. Diagnosis of wet agerelated macular degeneration, as specified in protocol. Bestcorrected visual acuity (BCVA) as specified in protocol Other protocolspecified inclusion criteria may apply. Either eye: Any active ocular or periocular infection or active intraocular inflammation. Study eye: Any approved or investigational treatment for exudative AMD other than vitamin supplements. Study eye: Any current or history of macular or retinal disease other than exudative AMD. Study eye: Any concurrent intraocular condition that, in the opinion of the Investigator, could require medical or surgical intervention during the course of the study to prevent or treat vision loss, or that limits the potential to gain visual acuity with the investigational product. Study eye: Uncontrolled glaucoma. Study eye: Any ocular disease that, in the opinion of the Investigator, could compromise the visual acuity. Study eye: History of eye surgery, as specified in protocol. Study eye: Use of corticosteroids, as specified in protocol. Any medical condition that, in the opinion of the Investigator, would preclude scheduled study visits, completion of the study or safe administration of investigational product. Any screening laboratory result that, in the opinion of the Investigator, would make the patient unsuitable for study participation. History of hypersensitivity to any component used in the study, as assessed by the Investigator. Women of childbearing potential: Lactating, pregnant, plan to become pregnant, or not using adequate birth control, as specified in protocol. Participation in an investigational drug or device study within time period specified in protocol. Other protocoldefined exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Age-Related Macular Degeneration</keyword>
	<keyword>Wet</keyword>
	<keyword>Exudative</keyword>
	<keyword>AMD</keyword>
	<keyword>Intravitreal injection</keyword>
	<keyword>Retina</keyword>
</DOC>