<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01510132</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this multi-center, open label, single arm, post-marketing surveillance study is to assess the safety of Travacom in patients with open-angle glaucoma or ocular hypertension who are insufficiently responsive to beta-blockers, prostaglandins, or other intraocular pressure-lowering (IOP) medication and when use of Travacom is considered appropriate.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Travacom Post Marketing Surveillance Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glaucoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glaucoma, Open-Angle</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ocular Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Travoprost</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Timolol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>18 years of age or older. Openangle glaucoma or ocular hypertension insufficiently responsive to betablockers, prostaglandins, or other intraocular pressurelowering (IOP) agents and when the use of Travacom is considered appropriate. Discontinued use of all other ocular hypotensive medications prior to receiving the study medication for the entire course of the study. Mean IOP not greater than 36 mmHG in either eye. Read, sign, and date (or legal representative) the Informed Consent prior to the start of any studyrelated procedures. Other protocoldefined inclusion criteria may apply. Women of childbearing potential (not postmenopausal for at least one year or not surgically sterile) who are currently pregnant, have a positive result on the urine pregnancy test at Screening, intend to become pregnant during the study period, are breastfeeding, or do not agree to use an adequate birth control method to prevent pregnancy throughout the study. Chronic, recurrent, or severe inflammatory eye disease, such as scleritis, uveitis, or herpes keratitis. History of clinically significant or progressive retinal disease. Best corrected visual acuity (BCVA) score worse than 20/80 Snellen. Bronchial asthma or related history that would preclude safe administration of a topical betablocker. Severe, unstable, or uncontrolled cardiovascular, hepatic, or renal disease or related history that would preclude safe administration of a topical betaadrenergic blocking agent. History of spontaneous or current hypoglycemia or uncontrolled diabetes. Known medical allergy, hypersensitivity, or poor tolerance to any component of Travacom deemed clinically significant in the opinion of the Principal Investigator. Use of any additional topical or system ocular hypotensive medication during the study. Participation in any other investigational study within 30 days prior to Screening visit. Other protocoldefined exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>OAG</keyword>
	<keyword>OHT</keyword>
</DOC>