<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01510288</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Ipilimumab, an antibody that blocks cytotoxic T-lymphocyte antigen 4, and GVAX have demonstrated anti-tumor activity in prostate cancer. Pre-clinical studies with this combination have demonstrated potent synergy. The purpose of this study is to investigate, using a phase-I 3+3 dose escalation design followed by an expansion cohort, the safety and efficacy of combined treatment with GVAX and ipilimumab in castration-resistant metastatic prostate cancer (CRPC) patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase 1 Trial of Ipilimumab and GVAX in Patients With Metastatic Castration-resistant Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A promising immunotherapeutic approach in prostate cancer is whole-cell vaccination. Irradiated allogeneic tumor cells expressing GM-CSF generate a long-lasting and specific anti-tumor immunity in preclinical models. Results from several phase I and II trials showed Prostate GVAX (GVAX) to be well tolerated and suggested improved survival. Cytotoxic T-lymphocyte-associated antigen 4 (CTLA-4) is a crucial immune checkpoint molecule that down-regulates T-cell activation and proliferation. Ipilimumab, a fully human monoclonal antibody (IgG1) that blocks CTLA-4, promotes antitumor immunity, and has been demonstrated in two phase III trials to improve overall survival in metastatic melanoma patients. Pre-clinical studies of the anti-CTLA-4 antibody in combination with GM-CSF secreting tumor cell vaccines demonstrated a potent synergy. In this phase I study the investigators examine in CRPC patients whether ipilimumab can be safely combined with GVAX. In addition, the investigators will treat an additional 16 patients at a dose level of 3•0 mg/kg to determine the safety profile and antitumor effects of GVAX and ipilimumab in patients with CRPC.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males age 1880 years Histologic diagnosis of adenocarcinoma of the prostate Metastatic prostate cancer deemed to be unresponsive or refractory to hormone therapy Detectable metastases by bone scan, CT scan or MRI Two consecutive rising PSA values obtained at least two weeks apart and both obtained at least 46 weeks after discontinuation of hormone therapy. Second PSA value must be &gt; 5.0 ng/mL. LHRH agonist should not be discontinued. Testosterone &lt; 50 ng/dL. Must have had orchiectomy or is currently receiving an LHRH agonist. WBC &gt; 3.0 x 109/L, ANC &gt; 1.5 x 109/L, hemoglobin &gt; 6.2 mmol/L, and platelets &gt; 100 x 109/L Serum creatinine &lt; 177 umol/L Bilirubin &lt; 1.5 times the upper limit of normal AST &lt; 3 times the upper limit of normal ECOG performance status 02 Life expectancy of at least 6 months If sexually active, willing to use barrier contraception during the treatment phase of the protocol The ability to understand and willingness to sign a written informed consent Transitional cell, small cell, neuroendocrine, or squamous cell prostate cancer Bone pain severe enough to require routine narcotic analgesia use Clinical evidence of brain metastases or history of brain metastases Seropositive for HIV, Hepatitis B antigen positive and/or Hepatitis C viremic Prior chemotherapy or immunotherapy for prostate cancer Radiation therapy within 4 weeks of the first treatment Surgery within 4 weeks of the first treatment. Must have recovered from all side effects. Flutamide within 4 weeks of the first treatment Megesterol acetate (Megace), finasteride (Proscar), bicalutamide (Casodex),nilutamide, aminoglutethimide, ketoconazole or diethylstilbestrol within 6 weeks of the first treatment. Systemic corticosteroid use within 4 weeks of the first treatment History of autoimmune disease History of another malignancy, except for the following: adequately treated basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer, superficial bladder cancer, adequately treated Stage I or II cancer currently in complete remission or any other cancer that has been in complete remission for at least 5 years</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>GVAX</keyword>
	<keyword>Ipilimumab</keyword>
	<keyword>prostate cancer</keyword>
</DOC>