<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01532843</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Treatment with a nucleoside analogue and subsequent viral decline has shown to partially restore immune hyporesponsiveness in chronic hepatitis B patients. Recent pilot studies investigating whether the effect of lowering viral load with nucleoside analogue therapy prior to the initiation of peginterferon results in higher sustained off-treatment responses showed contradictory findings. The aim of this study is to investigate sustained off-treatment response to peginterferon alfa-2b in chronic HBeAg-positive hepatitis B patients who are pretreated with nucleos(t)ide analogues, thereby lowering viral load</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Lowering Viral Load With Nucleos(T)Ide Analogues Prior to Peginterferon Alfa-2b Treatment to Increase Sustained Response in HBeAg-positive Chronic Hepatitis B</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2b</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Chronic hepatitis B (HBsAg positive &gt; 6 months) HBeAg positive, antiHBe negative within 4 weeks prior to initiation of peginterferon alfa2b HBV DNA &lt; 2000 IU/ml within one month prior to initiation of peginterferon alfa2b after a minimum of 12 months treatment with either Entecavir (one of all 3 brands) or Tenofovir ALT &lt; 5x ULN Compensated liver disease Age ≥ 18 years and ≤ 70 years Written informed consent Treatment with any investigational drug within 30 days of entry to this protocol Treatment with Telbivudine Severe hepatitis activity as documented by ALT &gt; 5 x ULN History of decompensated cirrhosis (defined as jaundice in the presence of cirrhosis, ascites, bleeding gastric or esophageal varices or encephalopathy) Preexistent neutropenia (neutrophils &lt; 1,500/mm3) or thrombocytopenia (platelets &lt; 90,000/mm3) Coinfection with hepatitis C virus or human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) Other acquired or inherited causes of liver disease: alcoholic liver disease, obesity induced liver disease, drug related liver disease, autoimmune hepatitis, hemochromatosis, Wilson's disease or alpha1 antitrypsin deficiency Alpha fetoprotein &gt; 50 ng/ml Hyper or hypothyroidism (subjects requiring medication to maintain TSH levels in the normal range are eligible if all other inclusion/exclusion criteria are met) Immune suppressive treatment within the previous 6 months Contraindications for alfainterferon therapy like suspected hypersensitivity to interferon or Peginterferon or any known preexisting medical condition that could interfere with the patient's participation in and completion of the study. Pregnancy, breastfeeding Other significant medical illness that might interfere with this study: significant pulmonary dysfunction in the previous 6 months, malignancy other than skin basocellular carcinoma in previous 5 years, immunodeficiency syndromes (e.g. HIV positivity, autoimmune diseases, organ transplants other than cornea and hair transplant) Any medical condition requiring, or likely to require chronic systemic administration of steroids, during the course of the study Substance abuse, such as alcohol (&gt; 80 g/day), I.V. drugs and inhaled drugs in the past 2 years. Any other condition which in the opinion of the investigator would make the patient unsuitable for enrollment, or could interfere with the patient participating in and completing the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hepatitis B</keyword>
	<keyword>sustained response</keyword>
	<keyword>peginterferon</keyword>
	<keyword>nucleos(t)ide analogues</keyword>
</DOC>