<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00586638</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Control processes are classes of brain activity that initiate, coordinate, synchronize, and regulate elemental cognitive functions for the conduct of goal-directed behavior. The proposed research investigates whether exposure to a computer-based training protocol designed to enhance cognitive control processes will improve cognitive performance in healthy older adults.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Training Cognitive Control Processes in Older Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The proposed research investigates whether exposure to a computer-based training protocol designed to enhance cognitive control processes will improve cognitive performance in healthy older adults. Cognitively normal adults aged 60-75 will be randomized into three experimental groups: 1) Video game play with training strategy; 2) Video game play without training strategy (Active Control); 3) Minimal contact (Passive Control). Subjects in Groups 1 and 2 will be instructed to play the complex, high-demand video game, Space Fortress, for 36 one-hour sessions over 12 weeks. Subjects in Group 3 will receive all assessments but will not play the computer game.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neurologic Manifestations</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neurobehavioral Manifestations</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 6075 Willingness to adhere to training protocol Adequate English proficiency Known history of cognitive impairment, dementia, stroke, seizure disorder, or other neuropsychiatric condition judged to impact cognitive performance Taking medications known to influence cognitive performance Sensory (e.g. visual, auditory) or physical (e.g. severe arthritic, orthopedic, neurologic) impairment incompatible with use of a standard computer workstation. Enrolled in a concurrent study that could affect the outcome of this study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>cognition</keyword>
	<keyword>cognition disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>executive function</keyword>
	<keyword>cognitive control</keyword>
	<keyword>attentional control</keyword>
	<keyword>biomedical enhancement</keyword>
	<keyword>cognitive enhancement</keyword>
	<keyword>computerized</keyword>
	<keyword>computer-based</keyword>
	<keyword>video game</keyword>
</DOC>