<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00586326</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study has been designed to compile information on the efficacy of the MammoSite RTS providing sole radiation therapy for patients with pure DCIS.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>MammoSite as Sole Radiation Therapy Technique for Ductal Carcinoma In-Situ</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Data relevant to the evaluation of the efficacy and safety of the MammoSite RTS system in providing radiation therapy to patients with DCIS will be collected. The MammoSite is a radionuclide applicator designed to deliver internal radiation therapy (brachytherapy) in patients with breast tumors following breast tumor resection surgery (lumpectomy).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma in Situ</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Ductal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Intraductal, Noninfiltrating</mesh_term>
	<criteria>PreSurgery: Unicentric pure DCIS Lesions should have a greatest dimension of 3 cm or less as determined by presurgery mammography and MRI PostSurgery: Negative histological margins confirmed prior to beginning radiation therapy. Margins are positive if there is tumor at the inked margin. Classified as low (NG1), intermediate (NG2) or high (NG3) nuclear grade DCIS, using the Philadelphia Consensus Conference Guidelines are eligible Clinically node negative Distance from the balloon surface to the surface of the skin &lt; 5mm as determined by CT imaging. Distant metastases. Invasive or insitu lobular carcinoma (postsurgery assessment). Nonepithelial breast malignancies such as sarcoma or lymphoma. DCIS that is multicentric in the ipsilateral breast. Pregnant or lactating. Prior nonhormonal therapy for the present breast cancer, including radiation therapy and/or chemotherapy. Collagen vascular diseases Coexisting medical conditions with life expectancy &lt; 2 years. Serious psychiatric or addictive disorder Previously treated contralateral breast carcinoma Synchronous bilateral breast carcinoma. Other malignancy, except nonmelanoma skin cancer, &lt; 5 years prior to participation in the study; the disease free interval from any prior carcinoma must be continuous. Patients with diffuse disease</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>MammoSite</keyword>
	<keyword>DCIS</keyword>
</DOC>