<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02326948</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This case-control study matched by age and sex was performed to evaluate the region specific risk factors for gallbladder cancer in Jeju island, Korea.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Alcohol Consumption and Gallbladder Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In order to estimate region-specific risk factors for gallbladder cancer (GBC) in Jeju island, Korea the investigators performed a case-control study. Among 124 GBC patients and 7088 health controls, the investigators randomly selected 78 cases and 78 age-sex matched controls (1:1 matching) and compared their demographic features, combined diseases, and personal histories about known risk factors until now.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Alcohol Drinking</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gallbladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ethanol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Case group : newly diagnosed gallbladder cancer patients in Digestive Disease Center, Department of Internal Medicine in Cheju Halla General Hospitalduring 20082013 Control group : 1:1 agesex matched controls underwent health care screening program in Department of Health Promotion Center in Cheju Halla General Hospital for 20082012. Case group Ambiguous diagnosis primary tumor involving common bile duct follow up loss without pathologic confirmation Incomplete clinical records Couldn't be assessed the results of operation or radiologic imaging. Control group Cases unavailable for gallbladder imaging (abdominal ultrasonography ,computed tomography, or magnetic resonance imaging) Cases underwent previous cholecystectomy before enrollment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Gallbladder cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Case-control study</keyword>
	<keyword>Risk factor</keyword>
	<keyword>Alcohol consumption</keyword>
	<keyword>Polypoid lesions of gallbladder</keyword>
	<keyword>Biliary stone</keyword>
</DOC>