<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01558232</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this clinical study is to examine acute changes in stability, force allocation, work, and mobility from using a wearable, portable, battery-operated robotic orthosis (the Tibion Bionic Leg) in subacute post-stroke persons undergoing lower extremity physical therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Prospective Study to Evaluate Use of the Tibion Bionic Leg in Sub-Acute Post-stroke Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Samples text.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Single stroke with residual unilateral lowerextremity weakness Subacute poststroke period (&gt;3 and &lt;12 months) Eligible to participate to lower extremity physical therapy Age 40 years or greater Able to ambulate at least 10 meters Able to ambulate without a leg brace Ambulation speed less than 0.8 meters/second Minimum to moderate assist for transfer or ambulation by physical therapist evaluation Subject must understand the nature of the study and provide written informed consent prior to enrollment. Subject must be willing and able to attend all study sessions Medically unstable Age younger than 40 years Acute poststroke (&lt; 3 months) Chronic poststroke (&gt; 12 months) Statuspost multiple strokes Statuspost traumatic brain injury Ambulation speed greater than 0.8 meters/second Currently using a KneeAnkleFoot Orthosis (KAFO) Not eligible for lower extremity physical therapy Concomitant degenerative neurological conditions Not able to ambulate at least 10 meters without assistance Greater than moderate assist during transfer or ambulation by physical therapist evaluation Unable to ambulate without a leg brace Unable to follow instructions, complete followup, or provide informed consent. Currently enrolled in another investigational device or drug trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>Tibion</keyword>
	<keyword>Bionics</keyword>
	<keyword>Rehab</keyword>
	<keyword>Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Robotics</keyword>
	<keyword>Intention</keyword>
</DOC>