<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03042091</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This randomized clinical trial studies how well neomycin and metronidazole hydrochloride with or without polyethylene glycol work in reducing infection in patients undergoing elective colorectal surgery. Polyethylene glycol, may draw water from the body into the colon, flushing out the contents of the colon. Antibiotics, like neomycin and metronidazole hydrochloride, may stop bacteria from growing. It is not yet known whether it's better to give preoperative neomycin and metronidazole hydrochloride with or without polyethylene glycol in reducing surgical site infection after colorectal surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Neomycin and Metronidazole Hydrochloride With or Without Polyethylene Glycol in Reducing Infection in Patients Undergoing Elective Colorectal Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To estimate the difference in rates of surgical site infection following elective colorectal resections in patients given a preoperative mechanical bowel prep with oral antibiotics as compared to preoperative oral antibiotics alone. SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To determine rates of post-operative clostridium difficile infection, adynamic ileus, cardiopulmonary complications, urinary tract infection, length of stay and mortality in patients given preoperative oral antibiotics with a mechanical bowel prep versus preoperative antibiotics alone.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Inflammatory Bowel Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Surgical Wound Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diverticulitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Bacterial Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neomycin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibiotics, Antitubercular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metronidazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients undergoing ileocolic resections, partial and total colectomies, and rectal resections for neoplasm, inflammatory bowel disease, or diverticulitis Subjects with the mental capacity to give informed consent Patients undergoing emergent colorectal resections Patients who are decisionallyimpaired and lack the mental capacity to give informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>