<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01466738</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety and clinical characteristics of a quantity of human rhinovirus Type 16 (HRV-16) in healthy volunteers. This source of HRV-16 will be subsequently used in viral challenge studies with new compounds that are intended to treat respiratory diseases.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Human Rhinovirus Type 16 (HRV-16) Following Administration in the Nose of Healthy Adult Volunteers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label study in which all participants know the investigational substance being tested. Participants will be inoculated in the nose with HRV-16 and evaluated for the occurrence of cold symptoms and other indicators. There will be 3 phases: a screening phase, an HRV-16 infection phase, and a follow-up phase. The dose of virus being tested in this study has been previously used in other challenge studies. The total length of participation in the study will be about 4 weeks. Participant safety will be monitored.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Demonstrate an understanding of the study and sign an informed consent form prior to any studyrelated procedures Healthy with no clinically significant abnormalities as determined by medical history Women must be neither pregnant nor lactating (producing breast milk) and have a negative urine pregnancy test at Screening Visit 1 Women of childbearing potential and all men must agree to use adequate birth control measures (as determined by the investigator) and must agree to continue to use such measures and not plan a pregnancy until after the Day 6 visit Men must agree not to donate sperm during the study through the Day 6 visit Have a documented serumneutralizing antibody titer of &gt; 2fold dilution to HRV16 in the blood sample within approximately 40 days of Screening Visit 2 Live with a family member who cares for the elderly, infants, or small children (eg, nursing home or day care provider), or live with someone who has a chronic lung disease, premature infant, or immunocompromised individual Require a prescription or overthecounter medication on a regular basis (3 or more times per week), except contraceptive preparations, hormone replacement therapy, or topical acne medication Have a history of chronic disease that the Investigator believes are clinically significant Have a history of chronic headaches (eg frequent migraines, cluster headaches) with 3 or more headaches per week</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Healthy volunteer</keyword>
	<keyword>Rhinovirus</keyword>
	<keyword>Cold virus</keyword>
	<keyword>HRV-16</keyword>
</DOC>