<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01466647</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a open single-center, explorative, Phase I pilot dose finding study including patients treated with AXL1717 in addition to standard chemotherapy of gemcitabine HCL and carboplatin.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of the IGF-1R Inhibitor AXL1717 in Combination With Gemcitabine HCL and Carboplatin to Treat Non-small-cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Open single-center, explorative, Phase I pilot study including patients treated with AXL1717 in addition to standard chemotherapy of gemcitabine HCL and carboplatin. Patients will be treated within the study for 2 treatment cycles of 3 weeks each. Survival data will be obtained. Tumor assessment will be conducted at baseline and then at the end of the study period. Concomitant supportive therapies will be allowed.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. At least 18 years of age. 2. Histologically or cytologically confirmed diagnosis of locally advanced, or metastatic squamous nonsmallcell lung cancer (stage IIIB or IV) and scheduled for treatment with cytotoxic chemotherapy (Gemcitabine HCL/Carboplatin) 3. Preserved major organ functions, i.e: BLeukocyte count ≥ 3.0 x 109/L BNeutrophil count ≥ 1.5 x 109/L BPlatelet count ≥ 75 x109/L BHaemoglobin ≥ 100 g/L (transfusions are allowed) PTotal bilirubin level ≤ 1.5 times the upper institutional limit of the "normal" (i.e. reference)range PASAT or PALAT ≤ 2.5 times upper institutional limit of the "normal" range, ≤5 times if liver metastases have been documented PCreatinine ≤ 1.5 times upper institutional limit of the "normal" range 12lead ECG with normal tracings; or clinically nonsignificant changes that did not require medical intervention 4. Signed written informed consent. The presence of any of the following criteria will exclude the patient from participating in the study: Ongoing infection or other major recent or ongoing disease that, according to the investigator, poses an unacceptable risk to the patient Grade 3 or higher constipation within the past 28 days or grade 2 constipation within the past 14 days before randomization. (Patients with grade 2 constipation within the past 14 days could be rescreened if constipation decreases to ≤ grade 1 with optimal management of constipation.) Known malignancy in Central Nervous System (CNS) Disease and dementia and neuropathy grade more than 1 Other active malignancy during the previous 3 years Major surgical procedure within 4 weeks Prior antitumor therapy apart from radiation therapy Women Of Child Bearing Potential (WOCBP) For purposes of this study, WOCBP include any female who has experienced menarche and who is not postmenopausal. Post menopause is defined as: Amenorrhea ≥ 12 consecutive months without another cause Pregnancy or lactation Current participation in any other interventional clinical trial Performance status &gt; ECOG 2 after optimization of analgesics Life expectancy less than 3 months Contraindications to the investigational product, e.g. known or suspected hypersensitivity. Lack of suitability for participation in the trial, for any reason, as judged by the Investigator.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>NSCLC</keyword>
</DOC>