<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01466413</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an early phase study comparing two fixed dose of the study compound ELAPR and a Restylane® Vital Light (control), by multiple intradermal injections to a 3cm x 3cm area of the upper arm dermis. All subjects will receive three treatments, 3 weeks apart. Each treatment will consist of 16 injections in total, each 10mm apart in a grid formation over a 3cm x 3cm area of the mid - to deep dermis of the medial aspect of the upper arm. Each injection will consist of 20-30ul of product delivered using a 30Gx¼" needle.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Two Formulations of ELAPR Compared to Restylane® Vital Light Following Repeat Implants in the Upper Arm Dermis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Each subject will also receive Restylane® Vital Light (control) to the opposite arm following the same treatment regimen and using the same technique. A 4mm skin biopsy will be taken from each of the implant sites from Cohort A subjects (including replacements) on Day 169, and from Cohort B subjects (including replacements) on Day 85. The biopsy will encompass the needle point tattoo at the centre of the implant site. The biopsy site will be closed with a single stitch followed by standard aftercare procedures with stitch removal 7 to 10 days later.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hyaluronic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 35 to 50 years Male or Female Good general health status Able to give informed consent Clinically significant abnormalities of haematology or biochemistry testing Bleeding diathesis anticoagulant drugs thrombocytopenia or clinically significant prolonged APTT or PT Chronic use of aspirin, other nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs or other antiplatelet agents History of keloid formation Systemic corticosteroids within last 12 weeks Diabetes or other metabolic disorders that may interfere with the subject's response to treatment in the opinion of the investigator Any serious medical condition which in the opinion of the investigator would have a strong possibility of requiring systemic corticosteroid medication Pregnancy/lactation Previously received Tropoelastin A history of anaphylaxis or allergic reactions including any known hypersensitivity to Hyaluronic acid or lidocaine Sensitivity to Restylane® Vital light or Restylane products Use of any other investigational product on the intended implant site in the previous 12 months. Sensitivity to topical local anaesthetic cream (EMLA®) or have the following conditions where EMLA is contraindicated: dermatitis, Methaemoglobinaemia, Glucose6phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency or "Mollusca Contagiosa"</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Intrinsic Aging of Skin</keyword>
</DOC>