<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="118301">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01562912</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NERG-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01562912</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficiency Study Evaluating the Use of the PVAC Catheter Technology for Performing Ablation in Patients With Atrial Fibrillation</brief_title>
  <acronym>CAPCOST</acronym>
  <official_title>The Prospective, Multicenter Canadian Atrial Fibrillation PVAC Cohort Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Newmarket Electrophysiology Research Group Inc</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Medtronic</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Newmarket Electrophysiology Research Group Inc</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Atrial fibrillation (AF) is the most common arrhythmia affecting the Canadian population. AF
      is associated with increased risk of stroke, heart failure, and even mortality1. AF can also
      cause debilitating symptoms and adversely affect a patient's quality of life and functional
      status. These are amongst several reasons why a strategy of sinus rhythm may be pursued over
      a strategy of allowing AF to persist2-6.

      Percutaneous catheter ablation has emerged as an effective alternative to antiarrhythmic
      drugs (AAD) for maintaining sinus rhythm7. The cornerstone of AF ablation procedures today
      is electrical disconnection or &quot;isolation&quot; of the pulmonary vein (PV) antra from the rest of
      the left atrium (LA)8-13. In experienced hands, the success rate of PV isolation off AAD is
      about 80-90% in patients with paroxysmal AF, but repeat procedures are required in up to 40%
      of patients14-18. Thus, after one ablation, the success rate may only be 50-70% off drugs.

      Current standard ablation procedures for PV antral isolation employ mapping systems with
      which reconstructions of the LA and PV anatomy can be created. Visualization may be
      supplemented by integration of CT or MRI images and/or intracardiac echocardiography.
      Robotic navigation systems have also been employed to assist in ablation. The result is that
      ablation technology has become very complex and costly. Furthermore, all of these
      technologies are based on a single point unipolar radiofrequency (RF) ablation catheter
      where lesions are created point-by-point around the PVs to eventually obtain electrical
      isolation. This results in a lengthy procedure, often more than 4 hours, which requires a
      high degree of operator skill. Creation of contiguous, transmural lesions is also
      challenging with standard single-point RF.

      Recently, a novel multipolar catheter ablation system has been evaluated for achieving PV
      isolation (PVAC catheter, Ablation Frontiers, Medtronic Inc., Minneapolis, MN). Based on an
      over-the-wire circular mapping and ablation design, the catheter can be advanced into the PV
      antrum, and multiple lesions around the circumference of the catheter can be delivered
      simultaneously using duty-cycled unipolar and bipolar RF energy. In early reports, the
      system can achieve complete PV isolation with reduced fluoroscopy and procedural times and
      uses lower powers to achieve more reliable lesion sets19-21. Long-term efficacy also seems
      comparable to standard RF ablation22,23.

      This novel technology has the potential to broaden the application of AF ablation, by making
      the procedures less time-consuming and less complex without compromising on procedural
      efficacy. However, published data on outcomes related to use of PVAC technology are limited
      to studies with relatively small sample sizes ranging from 12 to 102 patients20-25. Data has
      been restricted to experiences from a small number of European centers performing moderate
      numbers of PVAC procedures and there is no prospective, multicenter data. The investigators
      therefore know little about the efficiency of PVAC procedures, which in turn, may allow for
      an assessment of the cost-effectiveness of using this technology.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a multicenter, open label, prospective, cohort study. Patients undergoing ablation
      with PVAC technology in up to 15 centers across Canada will be enrolled, ablated, and
      followed for one year post-ablation. Both primary and secondary objectives of the study will
      be determined from this cohort of patients. Comparisons to the traditional ablation methods
      will be made by collecting data from a prospective group of control subjects who are
      undergoing AF ablation with traditional ablation technology at the same centers by the same
      operators. Control patients will be enrolled in a 1:2 ratio compared to the PVAC cohort.
      While the final ratio of control to PVAC patients must be 1:2 by study end for each
      operator, the ratio may vary while the study is conducted to allow some flexibility in
      patient recruitment. However, the absolute difference between [# of PVAC patients] and 2x[#
      control patients] should not exceed 5 at any given time for any operator in any study center
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>February 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Procedure Duration and Fluoroscopy time</measure>
    <time_frame>At the time of the initial ablation procedure and repeat ablations.</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of emergency room visits, hospitalizations and urgent clinic visits.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year follow-up post ablation</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of emergency room visits, hospitalizations and urgent clinic visits one year prior to ablation and 3, 6, 9, and 12 months post ablation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of Life measurements (CCS-SAF, AFEQT and SF-12)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year post ablation</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of Life measurements (CCS-SAF , AFEQT and SF-12) questionnaires at baseline, 3, 6 , 9 and 12 months.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total ablation procedure costs.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year post ablation</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">230</enrollment>
  <condition>Atrial Fibrillation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects who are undergoing AF ablation with traditional ablation technology at the same centers by the same operators. Control patients will be enrolled in a 1:2 ratio compared to the PVAC cohort.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PVAC Cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The PVAC is deployed in the left atrium over a 0.032-inch guidewire inside the PV and advanced until it is wedged within the antrum proximal to the ostium. Energy is delivered through selected electrode pairs with local potentials as well as adjacent electrode pairs, allowing bipolar current to flow to the target electrode(s) from both sides. Each application lasts for 60 seconds. When the temperature does not rise above 50°C within 15 seconds, the application should be discontinued to improve position. The PVAC may be manipulated within the antrum to ablate in a pattern of overlapping circular lesions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Radiofrequency Ablation Procedure</intervention_name>
    <description>Application of radiofrequency energy will be delivered during PV antral isolation procedure and should be performed with a standard, open irrigated ablation catheter and a mapping system as the investigator would perform the procedure normally.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>THERMOCOOL Catheter, Biosense Webster</other_name>
    <other_name>EnSite NavX Velocity, St Jude</other_name>
    <other_name>LASSO Circular Mapping Catheter, Biosense Webster</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Radiofrequency Ablation Procedure</intervention_name>
    <description>Application of radiofrequency energy with the Pulmonary Vein Ablation Catheter(PVAC)to eliminate potentials arising from the pulmonary veins.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PVAC Cohort</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PVAC Catheter, Medtronic Inc., Ablation Frontiers</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients aged 18 years or greater.

          -  Patients undergoing first-time catheter ablation for AF.

          -  Patients with paroxysmal AF. Paroxysmal AF will be defined as self-terminating
             episodes less than 7 days duration. Patients should have had at least 3 episodes of
             AF in a one year period.

          -  Patients with symptomatic AF that is refractory to at least one antiarrhythmic
             medication. &quot;Symptomatic&quot; patients are those who have been aware of their AF anytime
             within the last 5 years prior to enrollment. Symptoms may include, but are not
             restricted to, palpitations, shortness of breath, chest pain, fatigue, or any
             combination of the above.

          -  At least one episode of AF must have been documented by ECG, Holter, loop recorder,
             telemetry, or transtelephonic monitoring within 24 months of enrollment in the study.

          -  Patients must be able and willing to provide written informed consent to participate
             in the clinical study.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients with persistent AF (defined as an episode of AF lasting &gt;7 days).

          -  Patients with AF felt to be secondary to an obvious reversible cause.

          -  Patients with contraindications to systemic anticoagulation with heparin or warfarin
             or a direct thrombin inhibitor.

          -  Patients who have previously undergone AF ablation.

          -  Patients with left atrial size &gt;/= 55 mm (2D echocardiography, parasternal long axis
             view).

          -  Patients who are or may potentially be pregnant.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Atul Verma, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Newmarket Electrophysiology Research Group</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hamilton Health Sciences</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamilton</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>London Health Sciences Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>N6A 5A5</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Southlake Regional Health Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Newmarket</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>L3Y 2P9</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>McGill University Health Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montreal</city>
        <state>Quebec</state>
        <zip>H3G 1A4</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Sacré-Coeur de Montréal</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montreal</city>
        <state>Quebec</state>
        <zip>H4J 1C5</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institut universitaire de cardiologie et de pneumologie de Québec</name>
      <address>
        <city>Quebec City</city>
        <state>Quebec</state>
        <zip>G1V 4G5</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>April 6, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>February 20, 2012</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>radiofrequency</keyword>
  <keyword>ablation</keyword>
  <keyword>atrial fibrillation</keyword>
  <keyword>PVAC</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
