<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00692159</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is being performed to evaluate the safety and tolerability of TRC102 in combination with Alimta. In addition to safety, this study will also evaluate pharmacokinetics and tumor response.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of TRC102 in Combination With Pemetrexed in Cancer Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is being performed to evaluate the safety and tolerability of TRC102 in combination with Alimta. In addition to safety, this study will also evaluate pharmacokinetics and tumor response.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pemetrexed</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patient has given informed consent The patient is willing and able to abide by the protocol The patient has cancer and curative therapy is unavailable or standard therapy has failed The patient is at least 18 years of age The patient has adequate ability to perform activities of daily living The patient has recovered from significant toxicities of previous therapy The patient has adequate organ function as assessed by laboratory testing The patient has had prior treatment with highdose chemotherapy requiring stem cell rescue The patient is currently on treatment on another therapeutic clinical trial or has received an investigational drug within 4 weeks prior to first dose on this study The patient has had prior surgery, radiation or systemic therapy within 4 weeks of starting the study The patient has a history of CNS cancer The patient has an unstable medical condition including (not limited to) cardiac disease, HIV/AIDS, history of stroke, hepatitis or significant paricardial, pleural or peritoneal effusion The patient is pregnant or breastfeeding</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>TRC102</keyword>
	<keyword>Methoxyamine HCL</keyword>
	<keyword>Pemetrexed</keyword>
	<keyword>Alimta</keyword>
	<keyword>Tracon</keyword>
	<keyword>Phase 1</keyword>
	<keyword>Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>BER</keyword>
	<keyword>Base Excision Repair</keyword>
	<keyword>Small Molecule</keyword>
	<keyword>Anti-folate</keyword>
	<keyword>Solid Tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>Neoplastic Processes</keyword>
	<keyword>Pathologic Processes</keyword>
	<keyword>Pathological Conditions, Signs and Symptoms</keyword>
</DOC>