<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01175057</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this study feasibility of the MeDiNa concept is looked at, which means telemedical services for homely rehabilitation. With the help of microsystems technology, the relevant vital signs are measured at the patient`s home, then transmitted to the MeDiNa- Homebox- Tablet PC (by bluetooth) and then transferred into a central database, the MeDiNa eHealth- portal (by HSDPA, UMTS). These parameters can be continuously monitored by authorized network participants such as the family doctor or the patients themselves. In future, beyond cost advantages this will help to supervise risk patients or inspire patients to take more care of their health during homely rehab.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>MeDiNa Pilot Study for Evaluation of the MeDiNa Concept of Homely Rehabilitation After Myocardial Infarction</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients after myocard infarction who undergo homely rehab post stationary are divided into two groups of 10 patients each. The patients of group A undergo home monitoring for 4 weeks with the MeDiNa Homebox and afterwards 4 weeks without home monitoring. Group B starts vice versa, without home monitoring first and then undergoes home monitoring for 4 weeks (cross over,controlled intra-individually). During home monitoring with the MeDiNa Homebox patients measure vital parameters (weight, blood pressure, ECG (by chest strap including micro sensors), pulse and activity (also by chest strap including accelerometer) several times a day. The pseudonomized data which are transferred via the MeDiNa Homebox- Tablet PC to the MeDiNa eHealth Internet Portal (UMTS, HSDPA) to which the responsible authorized medicines will have access will be evaluated descriptively.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<criteria>female and male patients minimum 60 years old myocardial infarction post stationary rehabilitation at home Internet access or mobile phone reception possible able to give informed consent patients with dementia aphasic impairment serious pulmonary diseases motional resriction (e.g. amputee)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>feasibility</keyword>
	<keyword>compliance</keyword>
	<keyword>telemedical home monitoring</keyword>
	<keyword>post stationary rehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword>patients with myocardial infarction</keyword>
</DOC>