<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02121236</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an in vivo study which aims to evaluate the diagnostic accuracy of ultrasonography in detecting benign radiolucent lesion in the both jaws. The ultrasonography-based diagnosis of contents will be compared to those findings obtained from the histological examination (i.e. the gold standard). The second part of this study will examine the measuring accuracy by comparing ultrasonography-based 3D measurements with those obtained from CBCT images of the lesion assuming that CBCT 3D measurements are the gold standard.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Diagnostic Accuracy of Ultrasonography in Detecting Benign Radiolucent Lesions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Jaw is a common anatomical site for development of odontogenic and nonodontogenic lesions, and because of the wide variation of these lesions, the diagnosis is complex. Many techniques have been used to arrive at the final diagnosis such as conventional radiographs, computed tomography (CT), low dose cone beam CT, MRI.The use of ultrasonography has been shown to be important in evaluating the solid and cystic components of jaw lesions. Although ultrasound imaging technology is a safe and a minimally invasive procedure, and has been in use in medicine for many years, its use in dental medicine has been limited and mainly restricted to soft tissue applications. Studies evaluating the role of ultrasonography in the diagnosis of bone lesions of the jaw are limited.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>the presence of a radiolucent or mixedappearance intraosseous lesion in the upper or lower jaw requiring surgical removal no previous trauma to the maxillofacial region. no previous surgical intervention in the same area of the lesion. the presence of a completely radiopaque lesion indicating solid content. patients with systemic conditions associated with bony pathology such as hyperparathyroidism, Paget disease, ﬁbrous dysplasia, multiple myeloma, etc...</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>CBCT</keyword>
	<keyword>Ultrasonic diagnosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Benign radiolucent lesions</keyword>
	<keyword>Histopathology</keyword>
</DOC>