<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02208167</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a phase 1, single-site study is to evaluate the safety and immunologic and virologic efficacy of ex vivo expanded HIV-1 multi-antigen specific T-cell (HXTC) therapy in HIV-infected individuals with viral suppression on antiretroviral therapy (ART).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase I Study of HIV 1 Antigen Expanded Specific T Cell Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The main hypothesis of this study is that the administration of autologous ex vivo expanded HIV-specific T-cells (HXTCs) primed to recognize multiple HIV-1 antigens in HIV-infected participants who initiated ART during acute and chronic HIV infection will be safe, increase HIV-1 antigen specific T-cell immune responses and decrease low level viremia. In addition, secondary objectives are to: 1. Determine the feasibility of manufacturing HXTC from participants who started cART during acute and chronic HIV infection. 2. Explore the ability of autologous ex vivo expanded HIV-1 specific T-cells (HXTC) to increase HIV-1 specific immune responses in participants initiated on cART during acute and chronic HIV infection. 3. Explore the ability of autologous ex vivo expanded HIV-1 specific T-cells (HXTC) to impact latent HIV infection as measured by a quantitative viral outgrowth assay (QVOA) and integrated proviral DNA quantification, and low level viremia as measured by a single copy assay (SCA) in participants initiated on cART during acute and chronic HIV infection.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>1. ≥ 18 years and ≤65 years of age 2. Confirmation of HIV 1 infection Chronic HIV infection (CHI) is defined as documentation of a positive HIV test result by any licensed ELISA test kit and confirmed by Western blot or Multispot HIV 1/HIV 2 assay prior to screening. HIV culture, HIV antigen, plasma HIV RNA, or a second antibody test by a method other than ELISA is acceptable as an alternative confirmatory test. Acute HIV infection (AHI) is defined as: 1) a negative or indeterminate enzyme immunoassay (EIA) plus a reproducibly detectable HIV by amplification methods, or 2) a positive 4th generation HIV Ag/Ab Combination assay and either a negative/indeterminate HIV rapid test or a negative/indeterminate Western blot, or 3) a negative HIV RNA test within 45 days of a positive EIA and ART initiation. Note: the HIV definitions above are pertinent to the time of diagnosis and treatment initiation. 3. AHI participants are defined as HIV infected patients on suppressive ART that was initiated within 45 days of AHI diagnosis as defined in protocol section 5.1.2. 4. CHI participants are defined as HIV infected patients who initiated ART with chronic HIV as defined in protocol section 5.1.2. 5. On potent antiretroviral therapy, defined as at least 2 nucleoside/nucleotide reverse transcriptase inhibitors plus a nonnucleoside reverse transcriptase inhibitor, integrase inhibitor, or a protease inhibitor without interruption (defined as missing doses for more than two (2) consecutive days or more than four (4) cumulative days) in the 12 weeks prior to entry. Other potent fully suppressive antiretroviral combinations will be considered on a case by case basis. Prior changes in or elimination of medications for easier dosing schedule, intolerance, toxicity, or other reasons are permitted if an alternative suppressive regimen was maintained. 6. Stable ART regimen for minimum of 3 months. NOTE: The ART regimen is defined by current treatment guidelines. Participants may have had one or more changes in their ART regimen for tolerance, change of guidelines, or dosing simplification. 7. Ability and willingness of participant to continue cART throughout the study. 8. Plasma HIV 1 RNA below detected limit by conventional assays (limit of detection: 75, 50, 40, or 20 copies/mL) for ˃1 year. A single unconfirmed plasma HIV RNA ˃ limit of detection but ˂ 1000 c/mL allowed within the prior 12 months; but none in the preceding 6 months. 9. Plasma HIV 1 RNA ˂ 50 copies/mL at screening. 10. CD4+ cell count ˃ 350 cells/mm3 at screening. 11. No active HCV infection (measureable HCV RNA) within 90 days of enrollment. 12. No active HBV infection (measureable HBV DNA or HBVsAg+) within 90 days of enrollment. 13. All female participants participating in sexual activity that could lead to pregnancy must agree to use at least two of the following reliable methods of birth control (at least one of which is a barrier method) for at least 21 days prior to study entry and until 12 weeks after the last dose of the study product: condoms (male or female) with or without a spermicidal agent, diaphragm or cervical cap with spermicide, Intrauterine Device, hormonebased contraceptive, tubal ligation, NuvaRing. 14. All male participants participating in sexual activity that could lead to pregnancy must agree to use condoms for at least 21 days prior to study entry and until 12 weeks after the last dose of the study product. 15. Ability and willingness of subject to give written informed consent. 16. Ability and willingness to provide adequate locator information. 17. Ability and willingness to communicate effectively with study personnel; considered reliable, willing, and cooperative in terms of compliance with the Protocol requirements. 18. Adequate vascular access for HXTC infusion and leukapheresis. 19. Potential participant must have adequate organ function as indicated by the following laboratory values: Absolute neutrophil count (ANC): ≥ 1,500 /mcL Platelets: ≥ 125,000 / mcL Hemoglobin: ≥ 12 g/dL Coagulation: Prothrombin Time or INR: ≤ 1.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) Chemistry K+ levels: Within normal limits Renal: Serum creatinine (or calculated creatinine clearance* for those with creatinine &gt; 1.3 ULN): ≤ 1.3 times upper limit of normal (ULN); OR Creatinine clearance* ≥ 60 mL/min for potential participants with creatinine levels &gt; 1.3 times institutional ULN Hepatic Serum total bilirubin: Total bilirubin &lt; 1.5 times the upper limit of the normal range. If total bilirubin is elevated, direct bilirubin must be &lt; 2 times the ULN range. NOTE: If participant is on an atazanavir containing therapy then a direct bilirubin should be measured instead of the total bilirubin and must be ≤ 1.0mg/dL. AST (SGOT) and ALT (SGPT): ≤ 2.0 times ULN Alkaline Phosphatase: ≤ 2.5 times ULN *Creatinine clearance should be calculated per institutional standard. 1. Prior use of any HIV immunotherapy or vaccine within 12 months prior to Screening. 2. Use of any of the following within 90 days prior to entry: immunomodulatory, cytokine, or growth stimulating factors such as systemic corticosteroids, cyclosporine, methotrexate, azathioprine, antiCD25 antibody, IFN, interleukin 2 (IL 2), Coumadin, warfarin, or other Coumadin derivative anticoagulants. 3. Received any infusion blood product, immune globulin, or hematopoietic growth factors within 90 days prior to study entry. 4. Pregnancy or breastfeeding. 5. History or other evidence of severe illness, malignancy, immunodeficiency other than HIV, or any other condition that would make the subject unsuitable for the study in the opinion of the investigator. 6. Use of topical steroids over a total area exceeding 0.5mg/kg/day within 30 days prior to Screening. 7. Any active malignancy that may require chemotherapy or radiation therapy. 8. Compulsorily detained (involuntarily incarcerated) for treatment of either a psychiatric illness or a physical illness, e.g., infectious disease. Prisoner recruitment and participation is not permitted. 9. Any licensed or experimental nonHIV vaccination (e.g., hepatitis B, influenza, pneumococcal polysaccharide) within 4 weeks prior to study entry. 10. Unable to have a person available to drive participant home at infusion visits.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Antigen Expanded Specific T Cell Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>HXTC</keyword>
	<keyword>Antiretroviral Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Acute HIV infection</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic HIV infection</keyword>
	<keyword>Leukapheresis</keyword>
</DOC>