<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02208921</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This non-interventional, multi-centric, cross-sectional study is aimed to determine the prevalence of Chronic Kidney Disease in Indian patients with Type 2 Diabetes (T2DM). 3000 patients will be enrolled from 30 investigative sites all over the country. Each investigative site will be expected to enrol 100 subjects. All the procedures will be completed in a single day.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An Observational, Cross Sectional Study to Assess the Prevalence of Chronic Kidney Disease (CKD) in Type 2 Diabetes Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an observational, multicenter, cross-sectional study to be conducted at 30 sites in India. Endocrinologist/ Diabetologist from multiple private clinics will evaluate the Type 2 Diabetes patients. The study will be conducted over 9-10 months and will be started after obtaining written approval of Independent Ethics Committee (IEC) and written Informed consent of the patient. . Each investigative site will be expected to enrol 100 subjects. All the procedures will be completed in a single day.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Known cases of T2DM. 2. Male and female patients aged 18 years and above. 3. Must provide written Informed consent. 1. Patients with known type1 diabetes. 2. Patients with any form of acute kidney injury based on investigator's discretion. 3. Patients on maintenance dialysis or known renal transplant patients. 4. Patients who have participated in any interventional study within past 3 months prior to entry in this study. 5. Pregnant women. 6. Patients with symptomatic Urinary Tract Infection (UTI) or with history of hematuria.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Type 2 Diabetes</keyword>
</DOC>