<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01306448</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will assess the safety of the vibrating capsule in healthy volunteers first and than for constipation relief constipated individuals.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety Evaluation of the Vibrating Capsule</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Healthy volunteers will be followed for safety for 7 days after taking the capsule. Constipated individuals will be first followed for 2 weeks and than they will use the capsule for 7.5 weeks period. Safety and efficacy will be evaluated.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Constipation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients age 1860 years Ability of subject to understand character and individual consequences of clinical trial Written informed consent must be available before enrollment in the trial For women with childbearing potential, adequate contraception Patient with Diverticulosis Patient must not use protocoldefined prohibited medicine History of or current diagnosis of cardiovascular ischemic disease (e.g., angina pectoris, myocardial infarction, transient ischemic attack or stroke and including findings suggestive of ischemia on an ECG such as changes in ST segment and T waves, and / or Q wave) Clinical evidence of significant (as judged by the Investigator) respiratory, cardiovascular, renal, hepaticbiliary, endocrine, psychiatric or neurologic diseases or presence of abdominal adhesions Presents of pacemakers History of or current eating disorder such as anorexia or bulimia or compulsory overeating. Diagnosis of megarectum or colon, a history of intestinal obstruction, congenital anorectal malformation, clinically significant rectocele, or any evidence of intestinal structural abnormality including gastrointestinal resection that affected bowel transit or any evidence of intestinal carcinoma, of inflammatory bowel disease or of alarm symptoms such as weight loss, rectal bleeding, or anemia. Actively participating in another clinical trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>constipation</keyword>
	<keyword>gastro</keyword>
	<keyword>vibrating capsule</keyword>
	<keyword>safety</keyword>
</DOC>