<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00699751</DOC>
	<brief_summary>ALSYMPCA (ALpharadin in SYMPtomatic Prostate CAncer) is an international Phase III clinical study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of Radium-223 dichloride in patients with hormone refractory prostate cancer and skeletal metastases.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase III Study of Radium-223 Dichloride in Patients With Symptomatic Hormone Refractory Prostate Cancer With Skeletal Metastases</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The aim of the study was to compare, in patients with symptomatic hormone refractory prostate cancer (HRPC) and skeletal metastases, the efficacy of best standard of care plus Radium-223 dichloride versus best standard of care plus placebo, with the primary efficacy endpoint being overall survival (OS). Patients were randomised in a 2:1 allocation ratio (Radium-223 dichloride:Placebo). The study treatment consisted of 6 intravenous administrations of Radium-223 dichloride or placebo (saline) each separated by an interval of 4 weeks. The patient were followed until 3 years after first study drug administration. Within the U.S., the trial was conducted under an IND sponsored by Bayer HealthCare Pharmaceuticals. All patients received BSoC (Best Standard of Care). This study has the original PCD as 14 October 2010, when a total of 316 deaths had been observed; this resulted in the Independent Data Monitoring Committee's (IDMC's) recommendation to stop the study as the primary efficacy analysis of overall survival had crossed the pre-specified boundary for efficacy. Later an updated analysis of primary endpoint in the first addendum was done with cut-off of 15 July 2011.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Second Primary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hormones</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Succinylcholine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Radium Ra 223 dichloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically or cytologically confirmed adenocarcinoma of the prostate Known hormone refractory disease Multiple skeletal metastases (≥ 2 hot spots) on bone scintigraphy No intention to use cytotoxic chemotherapy within the next 6 months Either regular (not occasional) analgesic medication use for cancer related bone pain or treatment with EBRT (External Beam Radiation Therapy) for bone pain Treatment with an investigational drug within previous 4 weeks, or planned during the treatment period Eligible for first course of docetaxel, i.e. patients who are fit enough, willing and where docetaxel is available Treatment with cytotoxic chemotherapy within previous 4 weeks, or planned during the treatment period, or failure to recover from adverse events due to cytotoxic chemotherapy administered more than 4 weeks ago Systemic radiotherapy with strontium89, samarium153, rhenium186 or rhenium188 for the treatment of bony metastases within previous 24 weeks Other malignancy treated within the last 5 years (except nonmelanoma skin cancer or lowgrade superficial bladder cancer) History of visceral metastasis, or visceral metastases as assessed by abdominal/pelvic CT or chest xray within previous 8 weeks</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hormone Refractory Prostate Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Bone Metastases</keyword>
	<keyword>Radium-223</keyword>
</DOC>