<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02955641</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy and need for prescribing anti-inflammatory topical drops to patients undergoing laser peripheral iridotomy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Necessity of Anti-inflammatory Drops After Laser Peripheral Iridotomy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Primary closed angle glaucoma is responsible to almost half glaucoma related blindness around the world. Laser peripheral iridotomy (LPI) is a common and simple treatment used for both treatment and prevention of acute angle closure event. Anti-inflammatory drops are commonly prescribed to patients undergoing LPI in order to prevent or reduce post-treatment discomfort. However, to date, there are no specific guidelines for post LPI anti-inflammatory treatment, nor sufficient clinical evidence regarding the efficacy of such treatment. In the current study, the investigators aim to evaluate the effect of topical steroids and non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) on post LPI symptoms and inflammation markers.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glaucoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glaucoma, Angle-Closure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nepafenac</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Inflammatory Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ophthalmic Solutions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of primary narrow/closed angle by gonioscopy Able to give consent Ability to attend followup visits Corneal disease preventing sufficient evaluation of the angle Secondary closed angle (e.g. uveitis related) Pregnant women Previous eye surgery other than laser refractive correction</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Laser peripheral iridotomy</keyword>
	<keyword>topical anti-inflammatory drops</keyword>
</DOC>