<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02226822</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is intended to prospectively research the treatment reality and long-term disease control of Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus (T2DM) patients who are initiating 2nd line anti-diabetes treatment in sites across Japan.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>DISCOVERing Treatment Reality of Type 2 Diabetes in Real World Setting in Japan</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is a single country, multicenter, observational, prospective, longitudinal cohort study which will include adult patients with documented history of T2DM who are initiating a second line oral or parenteral anti-diabetes mediation after their first line anti-diabetic therapy in real world setting. The follow-up period is 3 years. Patients will undergo clinical assessments and receive standard medical care as determined by the treating physician. Patients will not receive experimental intervention or experimental treatment as a consequence of their participation in the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Written consent obtained 2. Aged &gt; = 20 years 3. Diagnosed with type 2 diabetes mellitus 4. Initiating a second oral or parenteral antidiabetic therapy added to oral antidiabetic monotherapy or switching from the monotherapy to another monotherapy with different drug class 1. Diagnosis of Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus 2. Current pregnancy 3. Current treatment for any cancer 4. Current dialysis treatment or renal transplantation 5. Current treatment with any oral steroids 6. Participation in any randomized control trials 7. Presence of any condition/circumstance which in the opinion of the investigator could significantly limit the complete follow up of the patient (e.g. tourist, nonnative speaker who does not understand the local language where interpreter are not available, psychiatric disturbances, alcohol or drug abuse).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Type 2 diabetes mellitus</keyword>
</DOC>