<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02226627</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study aims to make a proper scientific assessment on the dietary intake and physical activity levels of a representative sample of the urban population of 8 Latin American countries (Argentina, Brazil, Chile, Colombia, Costa Rica, Ecuador, Perú and Venezuela). The study was based on complex, multistage sample design, stratified by conglomerates, being all regions of each country represented, and random selection of main cities within each region according to probability proportional to size method. Sample will be stratified by gender, age (15 to 65 years old), and socioeconomic level. Socioeconomic levels will be balanced and divided in three strata (high, medium and low) based on national indexes used in each country. All the study sites are university-based and will adhere to a common study protocol for training, implementation of fieldwork, data collection and management, and quality control procedures to be performed simultaneously. All participants will be required to provide a written informed consent. A pilot study at small scale will be performed in each country in order to test procedures and tools involved in ELANS. Anthropometric variables, including body weight, height, waist, hip and neck circumferences will be measured according to a standardized protocol. Nutritional intake evaluation will be performed using two 24-hour dietary recalls, with 'multiple pass' procedure and a food frequency questionnaire. Nutritional data will be entered in Nutrition Data System for Research (NDS-R, Minnesota University) after a harmonization process between local foods and NDSR database. Physical activity and energy expenditure will be assessed by IPAQ-long version questionnaire and 7-day accelerometry.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Latin American Survey of Nutrition and Health / Estudio Latinoamericano de Nutrición y Salud</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
	<criteria>males and females 15 to 65 years old Adolescents without assent and parent´s or legal guardian´s permission will be excluded Any adolescent or adult with mental and/or physical disability will be excluded. Any adolescent or adult with a chronic or acute illness that may affect normal eating behavior or energy expenditure will be excluded. Pregnant and nursing women of a child younger than 6 months will be excluded. Any adolescent or adult who is not able to read will be excluded. Any adolescent or adult who is not present at or refuses to accept the second visit will be excluded. Any adolescent or adult living in any residential settings different from a household (hospitals, regiments, homes, such as oldage homes, etc.) and mobile homes or trailers are excluded.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>