<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02946879</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is a longer-term follow-up study for patients who have been administered AAV2/5-OPTIRPE65 in the Phase I/II, open label, non-randomised, two-centre, dose escalation trial in adults and children with retinal dystrophy associated with defects in RPE65. The study is designed to collect data on longer-term safety and efficacy at 9-, 12-, 18-, 24-, 36-, 48- and 60-month time-points following AAV2/5-OPTIRPE65 administration.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Long-Term Follow-Up Gene Therapy Study for Leber Congenital Amaurosis OPTIRPE65 (Retinal Dystrophy Associated With Defects in RPE65)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The follow up study is designed to collect data on longer-term safety and efficacy at 9, 12, 18, 24, 36, 48 and 60 month time-points following AAV2/5-OPTIRPE65 administration in the OPTIRPE65 trial. Safety and efficacy is being assessed by clinical examination and investigations according to a pre-defined schedule of follow up visits. The OPTIRPE65 trial is an on-going open-label, Phase I/II dose-escalation study to determine the safety and efficacy of a subretinal administration of the Advanced Therapy Investigational Medicinal Product in participants with RPE65-related retinal dystrophy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Eye Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Retinal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leber Congenital Amaurosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Blindness</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Retinal Dystrophies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Genetic Diseases, Inborn</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eye Diseases, Hereditary</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Are able to give informed consent or assent, with or without the guidance of their parent/guardian where appropriate. Were enrolled and treated in the prior openlabel, Phase I/II, dose escalation study involving intraocular administration of AAV2/5OPTIRPE65 Are willing to adhere to the protocol and longterm follow up Individuals will be excluded if they are unwilling or unable to meet with the requirements of the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>