<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02946138</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this research project is to assess the efficacy and toxicity of hypofractionated carbon-ion radiotherapy with concurrent granulocyte-macrophage colony-stimulating factor for the treatment of hepatocellular carcinoma</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase II Trial of Carbon-ion Radiotherapy Combined With GM-CSF for the Treatment of Hepatocellular Carcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Golden E.B. et al.in 2015 reported that localized radiotherapy granulocyte-macrophage colony-stimulating factor (GM-CSF) produced objective abscopal responses in solid tumor with metastasises. We hypothesize that hypofractionated carbon-ion radiotherapy combining granulocyte-macrophage colony-stimulating factor (GM-CSF) might improve the clinical response rate and progression-free survival (PFS) in hepatocellular carcinoma. The primary endpoint of the current phase II trial is progression-free survival rate at 2 years, secondary endpoints are overall survival, safety and toxicity.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. histologically confirmed hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) or clinical diagnosis of HCC according to American association for the study of liver diseases （AASLD）guidelines or clinical diagnosis criteria based on Alpha Fetoprotein （AFP), and radiological images proposed by Liver Cancer Society, Chinese AntiCancer Association; 2. no clinically distant metastasis; 3. the tumor is away from gastrointestinal (GI) tract (&gt;1cm); 4. Child Push score A,technically unresectable, or medically inoperable; maximal tumor size is less than 10 cm; 5. age ≥ 18 and &lt;80 years of age; 6. Karnofsky Performance Score ≥ 70; 7. No previous invasive cancer (within 5 years before the HCC diagnosis)except for skin nonmelanoma cancer or non muscle invasive bladder cancer; Ability to understand character and individual consequences of the clinical trial; 8. Willing to sign the written informed consent; Informed consent must be signed before the enrollment in the trial; 1. Distant metastasis (M1); 2. maximal tumor size is more than 10 cm; 3. tumor invading adjacent gastrointestine (T4); 4. Child push score B or C; 5. Previous hepatic radiotherapy; 6. Severe systemic disorders; 7. Previous malignancy (within 5 years) except for skin nonmelanoma cancer or 3year disease free interval from previous malignancy like in situ cervix cancer or non muscle invasive bladder cancer; 8. Non conformity of the radiotherapy dose distribution when compared to the dose constraints; 9. Psychiatric disorders or any other condition that can make unreliable the informed consent;</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hepatocellular Carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>carbon-ion radiotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>GM-CSF</keyword>
	<keyword>immunotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>