<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02821650</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to find out the impact of a locally designed and manufactured improved stove intervention on the level of household air pollution and the impact on associated respiratory health indicators and predictors of women and children.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Test the Impact of an Improved Chulha on Respiratory Health of Women and Children in Indian Slums</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Solid fuels used for cooking are a major cause of household air pollution. . Recent data from India suggests that the use of solid fuels was responsible for 20% of the total deaths among children in the age group, 1-4 years. Women, on the other hand, are three times more likely to develop COPD (Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease). A particular vulnerable group are slum dwelling communities, where not only financial constraints and poor living conditions contribute to the use of solid fuels, but the lack of proper infrastructure forces households to use solid fuels for indoor cooking Also, slum dwelling communities are extremely crowded and open space is virtually non-existent which forces household to cook inside their house, even during dry-season, resulting in an even more increased exposure. Noting the significant health impact of the use of solid fuels and traditional cooking systems on (public) health indicators, it is imperative to find clean cooking solutions for urban slum dwelling communities. While several efforts have been made to reduce indoor air pollution in India, most efforts focused on "enhancing stove energy efficiency, and not reducing emissions." Also, use of a strict top-down approach in the community was responsible for many unsuccessful projects. The current project is based on principles of co-creation, involving the local community in designing and producing clean cook stoves; a more scalable and sustainable solution than fully subsidized efforts. The aim is to find out the impact of a locally designed and manufactured improved stove intervention on the level of household air pollution and the impact on associated respiratory health indicators and predictors of women and children. The specific objectives are: 1. To test if PDSA-cycles (Plan-Do-Study-Act) improve local design, development and implementation of cooking stoves based on co-creation. 2. To know the impact of an improved cooking stove on the levels of household air pollution 3. To know the impact of an improved cooking stove on the respiratory health of women and children? 4. To know and monitor if there are any changes in behavioural and environmental practices of slum dwellers following introduction of improved cook stoves (ICSs)? 5. To know the compliance towards the ICS? 6. To know the perceived barriers and facilitators for the adoption of improved cookstove in the slum dwellers? The study will be conducted in two urban slums in Bangalore, India: Peenya and Ashrayanagar slum. The study design will be a randomised controlled intervention trial. The investigators plan to do a pilot study to test the stove prototype before implementing it on a larger scale. This pilot study will be done using a PDSA (Plan-Do-Study-Act) approach. The study will comprise of two phases- Phase 1: PDSA phase and Phase 2: RCT (Randomised Controlled Trial) Phase 1 consists of an iterative process which will assess the impact of a finalized model of an improved cook stove on the health and household air pollution of the participating households from a test slum in Bangalore. This phase will take into account the inputs from the participants and the location itself, and accordingly the cook stove will undergo modification. Phase 1 is planned for 6 months during which it may have 2-3 PDSA cycles. Following the analysis of Phase 1, a larger longitudinal RCT will be conducted (Phase 2) in a larger slum with similar characteristics as the test slum. Block randomization will be performed during the RCT to establish two groups: one intervention group receiving a new improved cook stove and the other acting as a control group. A field team will actively recruit households, assessing eligibility for the RCT and collecting baseline survey data. For Phase 1, the investigators would randomly select 20 households to participate in the PDSA-trials. For Phase 2, a randomized sample of 250 households will be selected. At the onset of both Phase 1 and Phase 2, a baseline household survey study will be conducted among the eligible households to obtain data of the respiratory health indicators/predictors (FEV1, FVC, symptoms of respiratory morbidity) and Household Air Pollution [indoor/ambient Carbon monoxide (CO), Particulate Matter (PM2.5)] of the sample population. It will also provide socio-demographic data , possible confounders and effect modifiers, symptoms of exposure to air pollutants such as burning eyes and headaches. All other symptoms or conditions considered to be relevant by participants will be recorded. Spirometry would be done twice, once at the beginning (before the intervention) as part of the baseline data, and another at the end of the intervention. Data collection will be performed during the baseline survey, and every 2 months after introduction of the cook stove during Phase 1 and at 0, 2, 4, 6, 12 months during Phase 2. Data entry and analysis will be done side by side. An intention-to-treat analysis will be conducted in order to ensure external validity of the study and minimize bias. For missing observations, "last value carried forward " method will be used. Personal, household and community characteristics will be controlled for.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Signs and Symptoms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Signs and Symptoms, Respiratory</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women (&gt;18years) and children (018 years) in the two specified slums (Ashrayanagar slum and Peenya slum)[All eligible women and children in a household will be included] Pregnant women Women/mothers who are capable of being interviewed and understanding/answering questions Will not migrate in the upcoming 2 months as far as the participants can predict Households cooking/heating solely with traditional stoves and solid fuels Households without children Households with cooking area inside house Households with cooking area outside house Pregnant women &lt;18 years of age (because of legal and ethical considerations)</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>