<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02821065</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Modern technology like computers, smartphones and the Internet enable patients to measure certain health indicators, like blood pressure and body weight, from the comfort of their own homes. This information can also be shared electronically with doctors and other healthcare providers to monitor remotely. This is called home health monitoring. In TEC4Home, we are developing a home monitoring solution for patients with heart failure to support their care and recovery at home after a visit to the emergency department. We hope to show that this solution decreases revisits to the emergency department and increases quality of life for patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Telehealth for Emergency-Community Continuity of Care Connectivity Via Home-Telemonitoring</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Emergencies</mesh_term>
	<criteria>PATIENT PARTICIPANTS: Have one or more typical symptoms of Heart Failure (i.e. dyspnoea at rest or minimal exertion (includes orthopnoea, reduced exercise tolerance)) AND Have one or more typical signs of Heart Failure (i.e. elevated jugular venous pressure, pulmonary crepitations, pleural effusions, peripheral oedema) AND Have one or more objective measures of heart failure: Radiological congestion. Elevated BNP ≥ 400 pg/mL or NTproBNP ≥ 1000 pg/mL. Reduced left ventricular ejection fraction &lt;40% (or &lt;45%) in previous 12 months. Diastolic dysfunction including tissue Doppler E/e' ratio &gt; 15 in previous 12 months. Pulmonary capillary wedge pressure &gt;20 mmHg. Diuretic therapy. The additional value of diuretic therapy (IV or oral) is debatable, as presumably unlikely (or unsafe) that patient with genuine HF will be discharged without diuretic. CLINICIAN PARTICIPANTS: To be eligible to participate, clinician participants (i.e. ED physicians, family physicians and monitoring nurse(s)) must have referred or have a patient enrolled in the TEC4Home monitoring service. PATIENT PARTICIPANTS: Physical barriers e.g. unable to stand on scales. Cognitive impairment (e.g. MMSE &lt;20), unless suitable caregiver support. Language (must be able to read and understand English), unless suitable caregiver support. Documented history of current and active substance misuse (within 3 months). Lack digital connectivity or landline phone connection. No regular care provider e.g. GP, or at least regular walkin clinic. Existing intensive system of care: LVAD, transplant, dialysis. Anticipated improvement due to revascularization (PCI/CABG) or valve intervention during index hospitalization. Anticipated survival &lt;90 days. Active palliative care, lessthan level III care, disseminated malignancy. CLINICIAN PARTICIPANTS: Clinicians who do not have patients enrolled in the TEC4Home service or who themselves are not involved in the implementation or operation of the TEC4Home monitoring service will not be eligible to participate.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>