<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02852616</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Narrative Exposure Therapy (NET) has been proven to be effective in the treatment of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD) and trauma-related depression in more than a dozen controlled clinical trials. Symptom reduction was greatest during long-term follow-ups after the completion of the therapy. In the current study, we will investigate the progression of PTSD symptoms and emotional stress before, during and after therapy. After a semi-structured interview all participants will be asked to report in monthly telephone interviews their core symptoms. Structured interviews after 6 and 12 months are used to validate the outcome. A convenience sample of individuals with a PTSD will be offered participation in the study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Trajectories of Psychopathology in Response to NET</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Participants will be recruited through the Center of Excellence for Psychotraumatology, University of Konstanz, with focus on refugees. All of them (approx. 100) will receive a structured interview and a detailed diagnosis. The interview includes questions about sociodemography, traumatic events, PTSD and depression symptomatology. Individuals with a PTSD diagnosis (up to 30) will be offered a Narrative Exposure Therapy (NET). Irrespective of treatment and diagnosis, respondents are asked to participate in monthly telephone interviews assessing trauma-related and emotional distress and changes in life. Interviews assessing PTSD, depression symptoms and emotional distress will be conducted 6 and 12 months after the initial interview. In addition, participants receiving NET will rate their PTSD symptoms and functionality prior to each therapy session.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>For treatment group: PTSD diagnosis (DSMIV or V) For nontreatment group: none Acute psychosis Cerebroorganic disease Acute drug or alcohol intoxication Already receiving another psychotherapy Antiepileptic drugs at baseline</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Course</keyword>
	<keyword>Posttraumatic Stress Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Narrative Exposure Therapy</keyword>
</DOC>