<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="150415">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01142089</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>C2009-0201</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01142089</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study to Evaluate Safety and Efficacy of Rifamycin SV Multi-Matrix System (MMX) for the Treatment of Traveler's Diarrhea (TD)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 3, Multicenter, Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Study to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of Rifamycin SV MMX for the Treatment of Traveler's Diarrhea</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Valeant Pharmaceuticals International, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Valeant Pharmaceuticals International, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine whether Rifamycin SV MMX is a safe and effective
      treatment for Traveler's Diarrhea.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a multicenter, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled efficacy and safety
      study conducted in patients traveling to developing regions with a known high incidence of
      TD. Eligibility will be based on a symptom complex that is highly indicative of enteric
      acute bacterial infection without indication of systemic infection.

      Approximately 262 patients will be enrolled in the study and randomized at a 3:1 ratio to
      receive Rifamycin SV MMX® 400 mg or placebo orally twice daily for 3 days (72 hours).
      Treatment will be initiated on the day of Screening (Visit 1, Day 1), within 72 hours of
      onset of diarrhea. Daily doses of study drug will be taken at breakfast time and dinner time
      with a glass of liquid.

      Safety and efficacy will be assessed.

      Blood samples for routine safety tests (chemistry and hematology) will be collected at Visit
      1 and at Visit 3 and sent to a local laboratory for analysis and reporting to the
      Investigator for safety monitoring. Urine samples for routine urinalysis (dipstick only)
      will be collected at Visits 1 and 3, and the results will be used by the Investigator for
      safety monitoring.

      If a patient's diarrhea and/or signs or symptoms of enteric infection worsen in a 24 hour
      interval of time during the treatment period or if the enteric illness fails to improve
      after 24 hours or more of therapy, the patient may receive Rescue Therapy. Rescue Therapy
      will be prescribed by the Investigator using local standard empiric therapy and/or guided by
      pathogen identification.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>May 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 2012</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 2012</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double Blind (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to Last Unformed Stool (TLUS)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>The primary endpoint is TLUS defined as the interval in hours between the first dose of study drug and the last unformed stool passed just before the start of Clinical Cure. An unformed stool is defined as either a soft or watery stool. TLUS will be calculated for each patient in the following manner:
Step 1: Identify when the patient achieves Clinical Cure.
Step 2: Moving backwards from this time, identify the time of the last unformed stool.
Step 3: The TLUS equals the time from the first dose of study drug to the time of the last unformed stool identified in Step 2.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Cure</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Cure is defined as either of the following:
Passage of two or fewer soft stools and no watery stools, no fever (&gt;100.4 ºF or 38 ºC), and no signs or symptoms of enteric infection (other than mild excess gas/flatulence) during a 24 hour interval in the 120-hr data collection period after the first dose of study drug
Passage of no stools or only formed stools and no fever during a 48-hour interval in the 120-hr data collection period after the first dose of study drug, with or without other signs or symptoms of enteric infection</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">264</enrollment>
  <condition>Traveler's Diarrhea</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo (two matching tablets) orally twice daily for 3 days (72 hours)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Rifamycin SV MMX</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Rifamycin SV MMX® 400 mg (two 200 mg tablets) orally twice daily for 3 days (72 hours).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo (two matching tablets) orally twice daily for 3 days (72 hours).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Rifamycin SV MMX</intervention_name>
    <description>Rifamycin SV MMX® 400 mg (two 200 mg tablets) orally twice daily for 3 days (72 hours).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Rifamycin SV MMX</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Male and female patients 18 years of age or older.

          -  Female and male patients of child-bearing potential must agree to use an effective
             method of birth control (this method must be approved by the investigator and may
             include total abstinence from sexual intercourse) during the treatment and follow-up
             study periods; female patients of child-bearing potential must have a negative
             pregnancy test in the 72 hours before randomization; female patients who abstain
             totally from sexual intercourse are not required to take the pregnancy test.

          -  Recent travel (i.e., must be within 30 days of randomization) from an industrialized
             country.

          -  Experiencing signs or symptoms indicative of acute bacterial diarrhea (travelers'
             diarrhea), defined as at least three unformed, watery or soft, stools within the 24
             hours preceding randomization and the duration of illness ≤ 72 hours before
             randomization, and able to provide an unformed stool sample during Screening (the
             latter can be the third unformed stool passed by the patient within the 24 hours
             preceding randomization); the bacterial cause of diarrhea will be confirmed by
             microbiology analysis of the stool sample.

          -  Experiencing one or more signs or symptoms of enteric infection (moderate to severe
             gas/flatulence, nausea, vomiting, abdominal cramps or pain, rectal tenesmus, or
             defecation urgency)

          -  Capable of and willing to give informed consent.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Fever (&gt; 100.4ºF or 38ºC) or presence of signs and symptoms of systemic infection
             Note: antipyretic medication should not be administered in the 6 hours before this
             assessment.

          -  Known or suspected infection with non-bacterial pathogen before randomization.

          -  Presence of diarrhea for &gt;72 hours duration.

          -  Presence of grossly bloody stool.

          -  Presence of moderate to severe dehydration (i.e., presence of orthostatic hypotension
             and/or dehydration requiring treatment with intravenous fluids).

          -  History of ulcerative colitis, diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome, Crohn's
             disease, celiac sprue (gluten-enteropathy), chronic pancreatitis, malabsorption, or
             any other gastrointestinal disease associated with diarrhea. Note: lactose
             intolerance treated with lactase supplements or a lactose-free diet are not excluded
             if these regimens are maintained during the study.

          -  Receiving more than two doses of an antidiarrheal medication (e.g., antimotility,
             absorbent, adsorbent, antisecretory, or probiotics) within 24 hours before
             randomization.

          -  Receiving one or more of the following antibiotics within 7 days before
             randomization, which are active against gram negative bacteria -
             trimethoprim/sulfamethoxazole, fluoroquinolone, azithromycin or rifaximin.

          -  Females pregnant or breast feeding or not using adequate birth control.

          -  Known intolerance/hypersensitivity/resistance to rifamycin or rifamycin-related
             antibiotics or to any excipient included in the study medications.

          -  Patients unable or unwilling to comply with study protocol (e.g., alcoholism, mental
             illness, travel schedule).

          -  Participation in a clinical study with another investigational drug in the 30 days
             prior to randomization or while participating in this study.

          -  Previous participation in this study.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mark Totoritis, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Valeant Pharmaceuticals International, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Santarus Investigational Site 03</name>
      <address>
        <city>Antigua</city>
        <zip>03001</zip>
        <country>Guatemala</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Santarus Investigational Site 14</name>
      <address>
        <city>Antigua</city>
        <country>Guatemala</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Santarus Investigational Site 04</name>
      <address>
        <city>Quetzaltenango</city>
        <zip>09001</zip>
        <country>Guatemala</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Santarus Investigational Site 05</name>
      <address>
        <city>Guadalajara</city>
        <state>Jalisco</state>
        <zip>42670</zip>
        <country>Mexico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Santarus Investigational Site 06</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cuernavaca</city>
        <state>Morelos</state>
        <zip>62240</zip>
        <country>Mexico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Santarus Investigational Site 12</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cabo San Lucas</city>
        <zip>23440</zip>
        <country>Mexico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Santarus Investigational Site 10</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cancun</city>
        <zip>77500</zip>
        <country>Mexico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Santarus Investigational Site 07</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oaxaca</city>
        <zip>6800</zip>
        <country>Mexico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Santarus Investigational Site 08</name>
      <address>
        <city>Puebla</city>
        <zip>72197</zip>
        <country>Mexico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Santarus Investigational Site 09</name>
      <address>
        <city>Puerto Escondido</city>
        <zip>71980</zip>
        <country>Mexico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Santarus Investigational Site 11</name>
      <address>
        <city>Puerto Vallarta</city>
        <zip>48330</zip>
        <country>Mexico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Santarus Investigational Site 13</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tulum</city>
        <zip>77760</zip>
        <country>Mexico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Guatemala</country>
    <country>Mexico</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2013</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 27, 2014</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>June 9, 2010</firstreceived_date>
  <firstreceived_results_disposition_date>April 5, 2013</firstreceived_results_disposition_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>traveler's</keyword>
  <keyword>diarrhea</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Diarrhea</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dysentery</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Rifamycins</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rifamycin SV</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted, but a results disposition has been submitted -->
</clinical_study>
