<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02242201</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Total hip arthroplasty is a one of the most commonly performed surgical procedures with increasing numbers anticipated over the next several decades. Differences in the analgesia outcomes between these three intervention groups would provide for an evidenced-based clinical pathway that will emerge as a result of this study. Hypothesis: Patients undergoing total hip arthroplasty within a clinical pathway utilizing preemptive low-dose opioid and non-opioid medications for multimodal analgesia randomized to peripheral nerve blockade will report less pain with movement on an NRS scale POD #1 compared to randomization to periarticular injection with ropivacaine mixture or periarticular injection with liposomal bupivacaine (Exparel&amp;#174;).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>THA Lumbar Plexus Verses Periarticular</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Bupivacaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ropivacaine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion: 1. Adult patients with an American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) physiological status IIII 2. Patients presenting for unilateral primary total hip arthroplasty. 3. Patients 18 years of age and older Exclusion: 1. Chronic pain syndromes such as fibromyalgia or complex regional pain syndrome 2. History of long term use of daily opioids (&gt;1 months) with OME &gt;5mg/day. 3. Body mass index (BMI) &gt; 40 kg/m2 4. Allergies to medications used in this study such as: fentanyl, hydromorphone, ketorolac, ibuprofen, acetaminophen, local anesthetics, oxycodone, tramadol, ondansetron, droperidol, dexamethasone, celecoxib and OxyContin. 5. Major systemic medical problems such as: 1. severe renal disorder defined as glomerular filtration rate (GFR) &lt;50 units/m2 2. cardiovascular disorders defined as CHF NYHA class IIIIV 3. severe hepatic disorder defined as current or past diagnosis of acute/subacute necrosis of liver, acute hepatic failure, chronic liver disease, cirrhosis (primary biliary cirrhosis), fatty liver, chronic hepatitis/toxic hepatitis, liver abscess, hepatic coma, hepatorenal syndrome, other disorders of liver 6. Impaired cognitive function or inability to understand the study protocol 7. Contraindication to a regional anesthesia technique (e.g., preexisting neuropathy in the operative extremity, coagulopathy [platelets &lt; 100,000, INR &gt;1.5], refusal, etc.). 8. Previous contralateral hip replacement managed with regional or periarticular injection 9. Unable to followup at the 3 month interval at Mayo Clinic in Rochester, MN 10. Pregnancy or breastfeeding (women of childbearing potential will require a negative pregnancy test)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>