<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02242136</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Soldiers deployed in peace-keeping missions as well as ex-combatants in conflict or former conflict regions were and are often exposed to multiple traumatic events and situations in which they are forced to engage in violent behavior. The treatment program Formation, Orientation and Rehabilitation by means of Narrative Exposure Therapy (FORNET) is a short-term, culturally sensitive treatment approach that aims to reduce Posttraumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD) symptoms as well as the risk to engage in uncontrolled violent behavior. Addressing trauma-related mental disorders as well as emotions related to aggression by means of FORNET is expected to facilitate reintegration in civil life and reduce uncontrolled violence. The investigators want to provide evidence, that FORNET is an effective and efficient module to assist soldiers after deployment in Somalia and/or male and female ex-combatants who fought in the civil war in Burundi. In addition the investigators aim to explore how traumatic incidences and maltreatment during childhood may influence treatment outcomes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Treatment of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder and Aggressive Behavior in Soldiers and Ex-combatants</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aggression</mesh_term>
	<criteria>High degree of symptoms of posttraumatic stress disorder according to the Posttraumatic Symptom Scale, High degree of appetitive aggression, Violent behavior during the past three months Current use of mind altering drugs, Psychotic symptoms</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Posttraumatic Stress Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Aggressive Behavior</keyword>
	<keyword>Appetitive Aggression</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>FORNET</keyword>
</DOC>