<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00780299</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Rationale: Despite spontaneous cardiac activity recovery, a shock occurs in more than half of patients after resuscitation for cardiac arrest. This acute circulatory insufficiency presents similar characteristics with septic shock and is responsible of most early deaths. Most frequently, usual treatments are unable to control this shock and to avoid the appearance of multiple organ failure. Aim of the study: In addition to conventional therapeutics, an early plasma epuration of inflammatory mediators (HDHP) could be able to improve hemodynamic parameters and to reduce the shock duration. This improvement could have an impact on multiple organ dysfunctions and also on early mortality.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Hemodynamic Efficiency of an Hemodialysis Treatment With High Permeability in Post-resuscitation Shock</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>HDHP (plasma epuration of inflammatory mediators) will be used in addition to the current clinical practice. The experimental arm will be treated by HDHP device. The high permeability membrane SepteX is a membrane polyarylethersulfone sold by Gambro that allows the purification of molecules of average size to near 50 kd molecular weight. We can thus purify molecules larger molecular weight than hemofiltration can with the usual membranes (30 kd). Furthermore, this increase in permeability allows a significant treatment medium-sized molecules in diffusion (hemodialysis), that the usual membranes do not allow. Finally, it is possible to purify certain molecules that hemofiltration including high volume does not allow (TNFalpha for example). Use of this membrane requires the use of specific set dedicated machine Prismaflex itself with a specific software (Exceed) to ensure the control and security of processing. 2 sessions of HDHP will be performed in the first 48 hours following ICU admission (with inclusion in the first 8 hours).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Shock</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Arrest</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Death</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Death, Sudden, Cardiac</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria Comatous patients admitted to the ICU for a sudden cardiac death apparently related to heart disease and requiring catecholamine infusion to treat a shock Cardiac arrest in front of witnesses Written informed consent obtained from the family or by emergency procedure Exclusion criteria Age under 18 years Response to verbal commands (Glasgow score &gt;7) Terminal illness present before the cardiac arrest Acquired or innate immune deficit Anticoagulation not recommended or high hemorrhagic risk pregnancy weight &gt; 100 kg without social security another clinical trial ongoing cardiac arrest from non cardiac etiology</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Plasma epuration</keyword>
	<keyword>Hemofiltration</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiac arrest</keyword>
	<keyword>Shock</keyword>
	<keyword>Inflammatory mediators</keyword>
</DOC>