<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02249507</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Aerobic exercise has the potential to diminish blood pressure values. The aim of this study is to determine whether this potential is also applicable for those with resistant hypertension and whether exercise intensity plays a role in this context. We hypothesize that performing an aerobic exercise session reduces blood pressure values in resistant hypertensive patients in a dose-response relation with exercise intensity.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Aerobic Exercise in Postexercise Cardiovascular Responses in Resistant Hypertension: a Cross-over Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Exercise prescription is gathering great importance in preventive health. Several organizations endorse the performance of at least 150min/wk of moderate intensity or 75min/wk of higher intensities in order to achieve better health parameters in different contexts. Aerobic exercise is known to be an effective way to diminish BP levels post-session. These responses are widely applicable in hypertensive subjects, acting in aid of BP management treatment. Although these benefits of aerobic exercise are well known, few studies explore the potential of this intervention in resistant-to-treatment patients. Moreover, the effects different intensities of aerobic exercise in this population is scarce. Thus, the aim of this study is to determine the magnitude of BP responses, if there is any, of resistant hypertensive subjects to two different intensities of aerobic exercise, compared with a control session. For that, subjects will be enrolled for one pre-intervention cardiopulmonary exercise testing and three randomized intervention sessions: control, 50%HRmax and 75%HRmax. Prior and immediately after all intervention sessions (during 1h), forearm blood flow and reactive hyperemia will be assessed by venous occlusion plethysmography. After the sessions, 24h blood pressure will be assessed with an ambulatory blood pressure monitoring system.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<criteria>resistanttotreatment hypertensive subjects (24h ambulatory BP above 130/80, or daytime ambulatory BP above 135/85, or nighttime ambulatory BP above 120/70 in spite use of 3 antihypertensive medications of different classes, being one diuretic; or use of 4 or more antihypertensive medications). Muscle or skeletal abnormalities that preclude effort, abnormal exercise stress test, major illnesses that would preclude exercise effort or could influence in the outcome variables (pulmonary disease, valve disease, renal insufficiency, etc.)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Resistant Hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>Aerobic Exercise</keyword>
</DOC>