<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02249013</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a phase II open label, single arm clinical trial on safety and efficacy exploring an short-course regimen of intra-operative Hyperthermic Intraperitoneal Chemotherapy (HIPEC) as upfront therapy for patients with advanced Epithelial Ovarian Cancer (EOC) undergoing Cytoreductive Surgery (CRS).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cytoreductive Surgery and Hyperthermic Intraperitoneal Chemotherapy for Ovarian Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of our protocol under the hypothesis that it may improve patient survival with low rates of morbidity and mortality. In these settings, CRS will be followed by an short-course regimen of intra-operative HIPEC as upfront therapy for patients with stage III-IV EOC. Advanced CRS will be performed with standard peritonectomy procedures and visceral resections directed towards complete elimination of tumors from the abdominopelvic cavity. HIPEC will be performed according to the closed-abdomen technique using cisplatin (25 mg/L of perfusate/m2, total limit of 240mg) for 30 minutes, with an intra-abdominal target temperature of 41-43°C. Perfusate (2L/m2, ranging from 4L to 6L) will be circulated using an extracorporeal circulation device (Performer HT; RAND, Medolla, Italy) at a flow rate of 700 ml/min. Systemic chemotherapy will include the standard combination of carboplatin and paclitaxel as adjuvant or neo-adjuvant plus adjuvant regimens.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fever</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with no previous treatment and candidates for elective surgery with histological diagnosis of epithelial ovarian carcinoma; clinical stage IIIB to IV, without suspicion of extraabdominal metastasis; aged between 18 and 70 years; performance status 02 (ECOG, Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group) and / or greater than 70 points by the Karnofsky scale; appropriated cardiorespiratory, hepatorenal and hematological reserves; and signing of the Consent Form. Evidence of extensive retroperitoneal lymph node disease; limiting obesity; apparent or confirmed uncontrolled infections; limiting comorbidities; other malignancies in activity; previous radiation or chemotherapy treatment (except neoadjuvant chemotherapy in the study protocol) or major abdominal surgery; neuropsychiatric disorders; history of drug allergies; and pregnancy or breast feeding. Still, it will not be considered for the HIPEC protocol those patients with unresectable disease (presence of invasive peritoneal implants inoperable or at high risk for resection in critical locations such as hepatic hilum, the mesenteric root, trunk celiac, mesentery, and several small implants the serosa of the small intestine) and / or with residual disease after cytoreduction greater than or equal to 2.5 mm (CC2 and CC3).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Ovarian Cancer</keyword>
</DOC>