<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03089125</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This research study is evaluating a behavioral intervention designed to help people with advanced lung cancer manage dyspnea (i.e., breathlessness or shortness-of-breath).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Brief Behavioral Intervention for Dyspnea in Patients With Advanced Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Many individuals with advanced lung cancer experience debilitating breathlessness at some point during the course of their illness. Unfortunately, few interventions exist to treat this distressing symptom of cancer. The purpose of this study is to test the efficacy of a brief behavioral intervention may help relieve breathlessness in individuals with advanced lung cancer. Participants will have a 50/50 chance of receiving the behavioral intervention or standard care. The principal investigator of the study, Dr. Joseph Greer, is a licensed clinical psychologist who has trained oncology nurses in how to deliver the behavioral intervention. The oncology nurses will meet with participants during their outpatient oncology appointments, such as chemotherapy infusions, to review the behavioral skills that may help with breathlessness. This intervention involves no medications but rather teaches patients skills for breathing control and relaxation of the body.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dyspnea</mesh_term>
	<criteria>A diagnosis of stage IV NSCLC or extensive stage SCLC Selfreported shortness of breath (a score of 2 or greater on the Modified Medical Research Council Dyspnea Scale) Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status from 0 (asymptomatic) to 2 (symptomatic and in bed &lt;50% of day) The ability to read and respond to questions English Primary cancer care at the Massachusetts General Hospital (MGH) Cancer Center or DanaFarber Cancer Institute (DFCI) Age &gt;18 years Cognitive or psychiatric conditions prohibiting study consent or participation. A treating clinician who reports that the patient is inappropriate for the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lung Cancer</keyword>
</DOC>