<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03089216</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this clinical study is to evaluate the efficacy and dental sensitivity associated with Combined Bleaching Technique (in-office + at-home) varying in-office bleaching application under two different time protocols, and dentifrice containing arginine 8% and carbonate calcium use. One hundred eight participants who meet the study inclusion criteria will be selected. The desensitizing agent used will be a dentifrice containing 8% arginine and calcium carbonate. In each evaluation will be determined: tooth sensitivity and color. The data collected will be submitted to the factorial statistical analysis for evaluation of color and chi-square test for tooth sensitivity (α = 5%).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Combined Bleaching Technique: Efficacy and Tooth Sensitivity</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will be conducted under the CONSORT recommendations. After approval by the Ethics Committee for Research duly registered, the trial will be conducted in the clinic of dental school at the Federal University of Goias located in Goiania. One hundred eight participants 108 volunteers will be selected on the criteria that qualify inclusion and exclusion from the study will be reported all volunteers were examined not qualify under the criteria for inclusion as part of the initial according to CONSORT recommendations . After signing the signed an informed consent form all volunteer participants will receive a dental prophylaxis with pumice and water in a rubber cups for the removal of extrinsic stains two weeks before the beginning of tooth whitening.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dentin Sensitivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium, Dietary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium Carbonate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydrogen Peroxide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Upper and lower anterior teeth without restorations; Upper and lower anterior teeth that have never undergone a bleaching procedure and are A2 or darker in color compared to the Vita Classical). Presence of primary and/or secondary carious lesion (s) on upper and lower anterior teeth; Presence of noncarious lesions, such as abfraction, erosion and abrasion; Presence of clinically visible cracks or defects of dental enamel on the dental surfaces of the upper and lower anterior teeth; Use of fixed orthodontic appliances; Presence of tooth sensitivity classified as equal to or greater than mild; Presence of severe dental dimming; Presence of parafunctional habits; Presence of any oral pathology; Smokers; pregnant and lactating women</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>