<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01572896</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to demonstrate the effectiveness of the "Taking Charge: Managing JIA Online" Internet intervention, when compared with an attention (static education only websites) control group in improving pain and HRQL as well as other health outcomes (anxiety, depression, treatment adherence, pain coping, knowledge, and self-efficacy) in adolescents with JIA. The proposed study will enroll and randomize 294 adolescents with JIA attending 10 pediatric rheumatology hospital clinics in the Canada to either the experimental or control groups.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An Internet-based Self-management Program for Adolescents With Arthritis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In summary, no rigorous Internet self-management intervention has been undertaken to improve HRQL, symptoms, treatment adherence, knowledge, and self-efficacy in youth with JIA. The proposed "Managing JIA Online" Trial will rigorously examine the effects of this Internet intervention on HRQL and other health outcomes thereby filling a significant gap in our knowledge related to promotion of self-management care for adolescents with JIA.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Juvenile</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥12 and ≤ 18 years. Diagnosed with JIA (using International League of Associations for Rheumatology classification criteria)83 by their rheumatologist. Adolescents and parent/ primary caregiver are able to speak and read either English or French. Participants are willing and able to complete online measures. There will be no restrictions on medication use for this study. Cognitive impairments (as assessed by reviewing medical chart and consultation with the patient's rheumatologist) Major comorbid illnesses which may mitigate HRQL assessment Excluded medical illnesses: inflammatory bowel disease, fibromyalgia, cancer, genetic disorders, diabetes Excluded psychiatric conditions: posttraumatic stress disorder, panic disorder, bipolar disorder, psychosis, depression and major mood disorders. Adolescents currently on medications for major depression, bipolar disorder or psychosis would also be excluded. Adolescents that are currently participating in other CBT interventions.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>adoloescent</keyword>
	<keyword>internet self-management</keyword>
	<keyword>managing JIA</keyword>
</DOC>