<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02479581</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study evaluates the enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) concept over conventional postoperative care in patients with heart valve disease undergoing cardiac surgery with cardiopulmonary bypass. Half of participants will adherence to the ERAS, while the other half will under the conventional postoperative care.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Safety and Efficacy of the Enhanced Recovery After Surgery(ERAS)Applied on Cardiac Surgery With Cardiopulmonary Bypass</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) or fast-track surgery is a perioperative and postoperative care concept initiated in the early 1990s aiming to reduce the length of hospital stays following elective abdominal surgery. The success of ERAS depends highly on multidisciplinary teamwork and patient compliance. This study intends to compare the Enhanced Recovery After Surgery (ERAS) concept applied to patients with heart valve disease undergoing cardiac surgery with cardiopulmonary bypass under traditional perioperative management of patients, committed to reducing patient's physical and psychological stress by surgical trauma, achieve the purpose of fast recovery, in order to establish an effective perioperative management during cardiopulmonary bypass surgery, improve patients' satisfaction and to accelerate postoperative rehabilitation safely.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Valve Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Morphine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epoetin Alfa</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Scopolamine Hydrobromide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Butylscopolammonium Bromide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Floxacillin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Heart function grade II III (Using the cardiac function classification method formulated by American Heart Disease Institute) The in hospital was treated with extracorporeal circulation operation and general anesthesia. Had a good cognition, and signed the informed consent. Aged between 18 and 70. The age, clinical examination and other generally situation of the two groups of patients had no statistical significance. Combined with other blood coagulation dysfunction, serious brain, liver and kidney dysfunction, endocrine system diseases and serious infectious disease. Patients with severe mental disorders cannot cooperate with the treatment. Emergency operation Have taboo of Echocardiography and pulmonary catheterization by echocardiography. Patients have been fitted with a pacemaker. Allergic to erythropoietin. Suspected or had alcohol, drug abuse history. Spinal deformity or paravertebral lesions.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Enhanced Recovery after Surgery</keyword>
</DOC>