<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02479321</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Crude incidence rate in Spain of hip fracture in people over 65 years was 511 cases per 100,000 in 2002. About 30% of patients die in the first year. Cardiocirculatory complications during and after surgery partly explain this high morbidity and mortality. Most patients are frail and with multicomorbidity. Perioperative Goal-Directed Hemodynamic Therapy (PGDT) based on noninvasive continuous monitoring of blood pressure, heart rate, oxygen saturation, cardiac output, cardiac index, stroke volume and stroke volume index can reduce perioperative complications and improve survival. The objective of our study is to assess the efficacy of a goal-directed hemodynamic therapy during the perioperative period in reducing intraoperative complications, especially hemodynamic instability, postoperative complications and 1-year survival. Patients and Methods: non-randomized intervention study with a historical control and 1-year follow-up. Patients older than 64 years with non-traumatic hip fracture requiring surgical intervention. In the control group blood pressure, heart rate, oxygen saturation and clinical situation besides respiratory parameters were recorded at intervals of 15 minutes. In the intervention group PGDT based on noninvasive monitoring will be performed. The main outcome will be the percentage of patients with hemodynamic instability complications and the average of complications per patient. Secondary outcomes: intraoperative complications, postoperative complications and survival at 12 months of surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Perioperative Goal Directed Hemodynamic Therapy Based on Noninvasive Monitoring in Patients With Hip Fracture</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hip Fractures</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Hip fracture that require surgical treatment Agree to participate and sign informed consent Pathological fracture Highimpact trauma fracture Anesthetic contraindication for surgery</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Perioperative Goal-Directed Hemodynamic Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Fluid therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Aged</keyword>
	<keyword>Perioperative complications</keyword>
	<keyword>Survival</keyword>
</DOC>