<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01509547</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a placebo-controlled smoking cessation treatment study for adolescents ages 14-21. After assessment and inclusion into the study, participants will be randomized to receive a 12-week double blind course of varenicline or placebo.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Varenicline for Adolescent Smoking Cessation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The objective of this protocol is to examine the efficacy and safety of varenicline for smoking cessation in adolescents. The guiding design philosophy was to model the adult smoking cessation literature (allowing for indirect comparisons of efficacy in different populations) while fine-tuning some elements specifically geared for adolescents. After assessment and inclusion into the study, participants will be randomized to receive a 12-week double blind course of varenicline or placebo. Participants will provide smoking self-report (cigarettes per day) throughout the study. Biological confirmation with carbon monoxide breathalyzer will occur at all visits, and urine cotinine measurement will occur at key time points (baseline, end of treatment and final post-treatment follow-up). Psychiatric/medical visits will occur weekly throughout active treatment to systematically monitor safety and tolerability. After the 12-week treatment course, participants will return for 3 post-treatment follow-up visits (Week 13, Week 18, and Week 26).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tobacco Use Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Varenicline</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 1421 Daily smoker for ≥6 months Desire to quit smoking, with at least one prior failed quit attempt and willingness to participate in a treatment study If under age 18, parent(s) or guardian(s) able to participate in informed consent and initial assessment (unless the participant provides evidence of emancipated status) If female, agreement to use birth control (any form of hormonal contraception such as DepoProvera, daily oral contraception, transdermal patch, or Nuvaring; intrauterine device; sterilization; or double barrier contraception, which is a combination of any two of the following methods: condoms, spermicide, diaphragm) to avoid pregnancy Lifetime history of any DSMIVTR mood or psychotic disorder (e.g., major depressive disorder, bipolar disorder, schizophrenia) Lifetime history of suicidality, homicidality, or clinically significant hostility/aggression Current substance dependence, other than nicotine Current unstable major medical disorder Current pregnancy or breastfeeding Current use of medications with smoking cessation efficacy Known hypersensitivity to varenicline</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>14 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>