<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01951963</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The proposed trial is a prospective, double blinded, randomized control trial with the primary aim of determining whether a single, sub-dissociative dose of ketamine will decrease the total narcotic requirements of pediatric patients requiring intravenous analgesia in an urban emergency department (ED) compared to a group of patients who receive morphine alone for pain management. Patients are randomized to receive either a single bolus of ketamine (0.3 mg/kg) or a single bolus of morphine (0.05mg/kg). All subsequent pain management will be accomplished using morphine. Patient, family member, and research staff pain scores will be recorded, until 3 hours post study medication administration. Family members are contacted via telephone 24 hours post-ED discharge, and again at 7 days post-hospital discharge, for evaluation via Post Hospitalization Behavior Questionnaire. Narcotic equivalents will be calculated for up to 3 hours post study medication administration and compared between the ketamine and morphine groups.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sub-dissociative Ketamine for the Management of Acute Pediatric Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Morphine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ketamine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age: 317 years old Condition (medical or trauma) requiring opioid pain management per standard of care Need to establish an IV per standard of care Treating physician agrees to manage the patient's pain with morphine following randomization. Trauma Team Activation Known allergy to ketamine Family member unable/unavailable to provide informed consent When appropriate, patient unwilling to provide assent High suspicion of injury related to child abuse Patient and/or family member is nonEnglish speaking Patient is incarcerated</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>pain management</keyword>
	<keyword>ketamine</keyword>
	<keyword>morphine</keyword>
	<keyword>pediatrics</keyword>
	<keyword>emergency medicine</keyword>
</DOC>