<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01951586</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This randomized phase 2 trial is studying the effect of adding denosumab to standard chemotherapy in the treatment of advanced lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Denosumab in Combination With Chemotherapy as First-line Treatment of Metastatic Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a global phase 2 randomized double-blind placebo-controlled study in subjects with Stage IV untreated NSCLC with or without bone metastasis. Eligible subjects are to receive 4 to 6 cycles of a standard of care platinum-doublet chemotherapy regimen. Approximately 216 subjects will be randomized in a 2:1 ratio to receive denosumab or matching placebo with the first investigational product dose coinciding with subject's first cycle of chemotherapy and continuing until the primary analysis, unacceptable toxicity, withdrawal of consent, death, or lost to follow-up. Subjects will be offered open label denosumab if study results show a positive benefit:risk profile, or be followed long-term, for up to 2 years. All subjects are to receive daily dietary supplements of at least 500 mg of calcium and 400 IU of vitamin D.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Zoledronic acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Denosumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically or cytologically confirmed stage IV nonsmall cell lung carcinoma (NSCLC), according to 7th TNM classification (cytological specimens obtained by bronchial washing or brushing, or fineneedle aspiration are acceptable) Subject has available and has provided consent to release to the sponsor (or designee) a tumor block with confirmed tumor content (or approximately 20 unstained charged slides [a minimum of 7 slides is mandatory]) and the corresponding pathology report Planned to receive 4 to 6 cycles of pemetrexed or gemcitabine in combination with cisplatin or carboplatin • For subjects to receive pemetrexed, planned to receive vitamin B12 and folate per pemetrexed approved labeling Radiographically evaluable (measurable or nonmeasurable) disease (according to modified RECIST 1.1 criteria Other inclusion criteria may apply Known presence of documented sensitizing epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) activating mutation or EML4ALK translocation (screening following local standards, but strongly encouraged in nonsquamous histology) Known brain metastases (systematic screening of patients not mandatory) Any prior systemic therapy (before randomisation) for the treatment of NSCLC (including chemoradiation), except if for nonmetastatic disease and was completed at least 6 months prior to randomization Planned to receive bevacizumab Significant dental/oral disease, including prior history or current evidence of osteonecrosis/ osteomyelitis of the jaw, or with the following: Active dental or jaw condition which requires oral surgery Nonhealed dental/oral surgery Planned invasive dental procedures for the course of the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>