<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00695942</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Venous thromboembolic (VTE) disease is the first cause of maternal mortality in the world. Some other pregnancy pathologies called Placental Vascular Pathologies (PVP) are linked to VTE by biological thrombophilia and are the principal cause of perinatal mortality. the identification of predictive factors of risk of occurrence or recurrence of two pathologies could enable us to propose an appropriate monitoring of patients at risk.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prediction of the Risk of Placental Vascular Pathology and Venous Thromboembolic Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Main aim: To evaluate echographic, doppler and biological markers in a prospective manner as a potential predictive factor of risk of PVP and VTE.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Thromboembolism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Venous Thromboembolism</mesh_term>
	<criteria>previous history of one or more PVC episodes (preeclampsia, HELLPs, retroplacental hematoma, vascular IUGR&lt;10th percentile, recurrence miscarriage &gt;2, unexplained IUFD or IUFD after abruption placentae, eclampsia. Previous history of personal VTE Diabete (treated with diet or insulin) chronic hypertension chronic renal pathology lupus obesity Antihopholipids syndrome early and late pregnancy (&lt;18 years, &gt;38 years) family history of cardiovascular disease of VTE known biological thrombophilia without any personal past history of PVC or VTE Multiple pregnancy past history of in utero fetal death due to congenital malformations, rhesus incompatibility or an infection previous history of IUGR which etiology was a chromosomal, genic or infectious anomaly</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>preeclampsia</keyword>
	<keyword>eclampsia</keyword>
	<keyword>retroplacental hematoma</keyword>
	<keyword>vascular IUGR</keyword>
	<keyword>IUFD</keyword>
	<keyword>VTE</keyword>
</DOC>