<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02901743</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main aim and objective of this study was to evaluate the effects of Non- surgical periodontal therapy on the subgingival microbiota and biochemical parameters in patients with chronic kidney disease and chronic periodontitis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect on Teeth and Gum Cleaning in Patients With Gum and Kidney Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study was designed as a Non randomized prospective, interventional clinical trial. The sample size for the study was 40 individuals aged between 35-75 years, equally divided into two groups. Group I--- Patients with Chronic kidney disease and chronic periodontitis (Test) Group II--- Patients with Chronic periodontitis only (Controls) At baseline both the groups were analyzed for clinical, microbiological and also biochemical parameters and underwent Non-surgical Periodontal treatment (i.e. scaling and root planning). All parameters were reassessed again after 3 months. A total of 20 patients attending the outpatient wing of Hyderabad Kidney Centre , Malakpet,Hyderabad who were diagnosed clinically with Chronic Kidney disease and willing to participate in the study were included in the study. Another 20 patients attending the outpatient wing of Department of periodontics, Panineeya Mahavidyalaya Institute of Dental Sciences &amp; Hospital, Hyderabad, diagnosed with Chronic Periodontitis and willing to participate in the study were taken. Biochemical parameters considered included -serum creatin &amp; urinary albumin: creatin ratio. Microbiological assay was done by Polymerase chain reaction test (PCR) i.e., pooled plaque samples were taken from both predialysis as well as chronic periodontitis patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>A total of 20 patients diagnosed with Chronic kidney disease, (having abnormal Glomerular filtration rate(GFR) and serum Creatinine levels.) and chronic periodontitis (with at least 15 teeth remaining, and with the presence of ≥4 sites in 3 different teeth having clinical attachment loss (CAL) of ≥ 4mm and bleeding on probing). (Group I) 20 patients diagnosed with chronic periodontitis only. (GroupII) Patients with HIV infection, pregnancy, lupus erythematosus, rheumatoid arthritis, any systemic disorder, periodontal therapy in the preceding 6 months, or on any course of antibiotic prophylaxis for periodontal procedures were excluded from the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>