<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02901184</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Heart failure with preserved ejection fraction (HFPEF) is common and deadly but without therapy. Inconclusive studies such as TOPCAT (Treatment of Preserved Cardiac Function Heart Failure With an Aldosterone Antagonist) suggest spironolactone may be effective in HFPEF, but it is generic and will not be studied by industry. SPIRRIT is a unique Registry-Randomized Clinical Trial (RRCT) that will test the hypothesis that spironolactone reduces all-cause mortality in HFPEF and is summarized by PICO (Patient Intervention Comparison Outcome) as follows: Population: HFPEF patients in the Swedish Heart Failure Registry. HFPEF defined as symptoms/signs of HF, elevated NTproBNP (B-type Natriuretic Peptide; N-terminal pro b-type Natriuretic Peptide) and EF&gt;=40%. Intervention and control: Randomized 1:1 to intervention: spironolactone + usual care vs. control: usual care alone. Outcome: Primary outcome all-cause mortality. Secondary outcomes include hospitalization for various causes, adverse events and treatment adherence. Outcomes are obtained automatically by linking with the Population, Patient and Drug Dispensed Registries. The trial is event-driven with enrollment 3 years and study duration 5 years. Based on actual patients meeting eligibility 2008-2010, the control death rate is 0.141 / year. Based on TOPCAT and accounting for dropouts, the investigators conservatively assume hazard ratio 0.85, or a clinically meaningful 15% reduction in death, yielding a required number of events of 1208 and a sample size of 3335, conservatively rounded to 3500. A detailed feasibility assessment shows that there will be &gt; 8197 eligible patients to meet the required enrollment of 3500.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Spironolactone Initiation Registry Randomized Interventional Trial in Heart Failure With Preserved Ejection Fraction</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spironolactone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written informed consent Age ≥50 years Stable heart failure defined by symptoms and signs of heart failure as judged by local Investigator Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) ≥40% recorded in last 12 months (stratified to max 2/3rd in either 4049% or ≥50% group) NTproBNP (the Nterminal prohormone of brain natriuretic peptide) &gt;300 ng/L in sinus rhythm or &gt;750 ng/L in atrial fibrillation as an outpatient or prior to hospital discharge Previously enrolled in this study Known Ejection Fraction &lt; 40% ever Current absolute indication or contraindication for MRA (mineral receptor antagonist) in judgement of Investigator Any condition other than heart failure with a life expectancy &lt; 3 years Known chronic liver disease Probable alternative explanations for symptoms: Known primary cardiomyopathy (hypertrophic, constrictive, restrictive, infiltrative, congenital) Primary hemodynamically significant valve disease Rightsided HF not due to leftsided HF Significant chronic pulmonary disease defined by Investigator or by requirement for home O2 or oral steroids, Hemoglobin &lt; 10 g/dL (100 g/L ) BMI (body mass index) &gt; 40 Heart rate &gt; 105 bpm Any other condition judged by Investigator to be responsible for symptoms and/or signs Heart transplant or LVAD (left ventricular assist device) recipient Systolic blood pressure &lt;90 or &gt;160 K (potassium) &gt;5.0 mmol/L eGFR (estimated glomerular filtration rate) by MDRD (Modification of Diet in Renal Disease) &lt; 30 ml/min/1.73m2 or creatinine &gt; 2.5 mg/dL (221 µmol/L ) Current lithium use Actual or potential for pregnancy Participation in another clinical trial where treatment for HF is studied Any condition that in the opinion of the Investigator may interfere with adherence to trial protocol</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>