<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02901041</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Alcoholism is the third leading cause of preventable death in the US, accounting for 80,000 deaths annually. Almost 18 million US adults have alcohol use disorder (AUD); however, approved medications for the treatment of AUD has shown limited effectiveness. Zonisamide (ZON), a broad spectrum anticonvulsant, has proven to be more effective than a placebo in reducing alcohol intake in individuals with alcohol dependence. ZON's mechanism of action seems to be quite distinct from currently approved anti-alcoholism medications, which holds promise for treatment of individuals who are not responsive to conventional medications. However, much remains unknown about ZON's therapeutic mechanisms and ZON's efficacy in treating patients with a diagnosis of AUD. To fill in these gaps, the investigators will conduct a double-blind randomized controlled study that assesses ZON's treatment mechanisms and effectiveness in reducing alcohol consumption in patients with AUD. Participants will be randomized to one of two conditions: 1) treatment with ZON and a computerized psychotherapy platform called Take Control (TC); 2) treatment with a placebo (PLC) and TC. To understand the neurobiology behind ZON's potential therapeutic effects on AUD, fMRI will be used to compare the brain activity of the ZON+TC versus PLC+TC group while participants perform an alcohol and emotional-word Stroop task, as well as an alcohol related cues task.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Interdisciplinary Study of A Novel Anticonvulsant in Alcoholism</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Alcoholism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Zonisamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anticonvulsants</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Salicylic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DSM5 diagnosis of an Alcohol Use Disorder (AUD) Adults ages 21 to 65 years old Expressed desire to stop drinking alcohol completely or to reduce alcohol consumption Reported drinking an average of at least 35 standard drinks per week for males, or 28 for females occurring over a 28 consecutive day period during the 90 daylong time window that preceded the screening session Must be willing to discontinue psychotherapy for substance use disorder (except A.A.) Bipolar disorder, schizophrenia, current bulimia/anorexia, dementia, or other substance use disorder, with the exception of nicotine, marijuana, and caffeine Clear and current suicidal risk Significant medical problem (e.g. uncontrolled diabetes) Medical contraindication to the use of ZON (e.g. history of significant renal disease, kidney stones, liver problems, metabolic acidosis, etc), as indicated by the FDA Zonisamide medication guide History of anticonvulsantinduced rash Currently taking: 1. acamprosate, naltrexone, topiramate, disulfiram, or benzodiazepines 2. a medication that is a moderate or major inhibitor or inducer of cytochrome P450 3A4 enzymes 3. an amphetamine or other psychomotor stimulant 4. opioids or have been treated chronically with opioids 5. antipsychotic agents, anticonvulsants, or sedative hypnotics 6. drugs with "sulfa" moiety (e.g. sulfonamides, sulfonylureas, carbonic anhydrase inhibitors, thiazides, and loop diuretics), except ethacrynic acid 7. anxiolytics or antidepressants Previously received ZON for the treatment of an AUD Known allergy to sulfonamides Implantation of anything containing magnetically sensitive material including metal plates, aneurysm clips, and cardiac pacemakers, stents NonEnglish speakers Pregnant women or women who are lactating (breastfeeding) Exclusion from Screening: Reduction in the mean number of drinks consumed per week for the prescreening period by 50% or more during the screening period or report of average drinks per day fall within safe levels of alcohol consumption (i.e. 2 drinks/day for males and 1 drink/day for females by the HHS standard) two weeks prior to screening Women of child bearing potential (not postmenopausal for at least one year) will not be admitted into this study unless they are found to have a negative HCG test during screening. If they pass the HCG screening, they will be asked to maintain the use of an effective means of contraception during the course of the study Blood test shows lower than average red or white blood cell count or higher than average level of acid in blood</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>