<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="197295">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00522548</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CERL080A-US49</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00522548</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of Gastrointestinal Side Effects in African American Kidney Transplant Recipients Treated With CellCept or Myfortic</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase IV Randomized, Open Label, Comparative, Single Center Study to Assess Gastrointestinal Adverse Effect Outcomes of De Novo African American Kidney Transplant Recipients Treated With Prograf (Tacrolimus) or Its Generic Equivalent/CellCept (Mycophenolate Mofetil) or Its Generic Equivalent/Corticosteroids Versus Prograf (Tacrolimus) or Its Generic Equivalent/Myfortic (Enteric Coated Mycophenolate Sodium)/Corticosteroids</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Pennsylvania</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Pennsylvania</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Myfortic (enteric-coated mycophenolate sodium) has been shown to have similar effectiveness
      to CellCept (mycophenolate mofetil) in preventing rejection in kidney transplant recipients.
      However, Myfortic has been thought to possibly be associated with fewer gastrointestinal
      side effects. CellCept and Myfortic pharmacokinetics (how the drug is absorbed and broken
      down) have not been well-studied in African American kidney transplant recipients. The
      investigators are interested in studying Myfortic and CellCept pharmacokinetics and
      gastrointestinal side effects in African American kidney transplant recipients.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      African American patients often experience more gastrointestinal complications after kidney
      transplant than Caucasian patients. In addition, African American kidney transplant
      recipients also experience a higher incidence of acute rejection and have worse outcomes
      compared with all other ethnic groups. Reasons accounting for these differences are not well
      understood.

      In light of the increased risk of GI complications in African American patients, we will
      compare in a pilot study, different regimens (described below) that we commonly use in our
      clinical practice in this population. As part of this study, patients will also fill out a
      GSRS survey at specified time points to help describe gastrointestinal side effects after
      transplant.

      Pharmacokinetic studies (studies looking at how the drugs are absorbed and broken down) for
      Cellcept or Myfortic have largely been performed in Caucasian populations. There is little
      information available in African-American patients. This is particularly concerning in the
      face of the worst clinical outcomes observed after transplantation in African American
      kidney transplant recipients.

      Comparisons: Patients will be randomized to one of two groups

        -  Group 1: Myfortic (enteric-coated mycophenolate sodium) in combination with Prograf
           (tacrolimus) or its generic equivalent and corticosteroids

        -  Group 2: CellCept (mycophenolate mofetil) or its generic equivalent in combination with
           Prograf (tacrolimus) or its generic equivalent and corticosteroids

      Since toxicity of Cellcept and Myfortic may be influenced by pharmacokinetics (studies that
      look at how the drugs are absorbed and broken down) of these respective drugs, we will
      compare the pharmacokinetics of Myfortic and CellCept in a subset of patients. This
      pharmacokinetic data may have the additional valuable benefit of helping to optimize dosing
      parameters for Cellcept and Myfortic in African American kidney transplant patients in the
      future.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    enrollment halted in order to have all patients complete follow-up by Jan 2011
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>March 2007</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 2011</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate gastrointestinal toxicity defined as requirement of permanent dose decrease or discontinuation of Myfortic or CellCept related to gastrointestinal toxicity</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the pharmacokinetics of CellCept or Myfortic in a sub-set of patients</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the incidence of the requirement of full dose proton pump inhibitors</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the incidence of intolerance (defined as transient dose reduction or transient discontinuation of Myfortic or CellCept therapy)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Compare Gastrointestinal Symptom Rating Scale (GSRS) score changes from baseline to 24 weeks post-transplant</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the incidence of the occurrence of upper and lower gastrointestinal symptoms (further details of definitions are provided by research center)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the incidence of rejection</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Compare changes from baseline serum creatinine and Modification of Diet and Renal Disease (MDRD) measured glomerular filtration rates to 24 weeks post-transplant</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">37</enrollment>
  <condition>Kidney Transplantation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Myfortic Comparator Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in this group will receive Thymoglobulin (rabbit anti-thymocyte globulin) induction immunosuppression in combination with Myfortic (enteric-coated mycophenolate sodium), Prograf (tacrolimus) or its generic equivalent and corticosteroid immunosuppression</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CellCept Comparator group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in this group will receive Thymoglobulin (rabbit anti-thymocyte globulin) induction immunosuppression in combination with CellCept (mycophenolate mofetil) or its generic equivalent, Prograf (tacrolimus) or its generic equivalent and corticosteroid immunosuppression.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Myfortic (enteric coated mycophenolate sodium)</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients in this group will receive Thymoglobulin (rabbit Anti-thymocyte globulin) induction immunosuppression, in combination with Myfortic (enteric-coated mycophenolate sodium, Prograf (tacrolimus) or its generic equivalent and corticosteroid immunosuppression.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Myfortic Comparator Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CellCept (Mycophenolate mofetil)</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients in this group will receive Thymoglobulin (rabbit Anti-thymocyte globulin) induction immunosuppression, in combination with CellCept (mycophenolate mofetil) or its generic equivalent, Prograf (tacrolimus) or its generic equivalent and corticosteroid immunosuppression.</description>
    <arm_group_label>CellCept Comparator group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Recipients of a deceased donor or living donor kidney transplant

          -  Recipients of age greater than 18 years but less than 76 years

          -  African Americans (self-reported patients of Black African descent who live in the
             United States)

          -  Willingness to participate in a randomized, clinical trial, as indicated by signed
             informed consent

          -  Patients with a history of gastrointestinal complications including any of the
             following: a history of diarrhea, constipation, acid reflux, or abdominal pain as
             reported by the patient

          -  For women of childbearing age, effective contraception must be used before beginning
             CellCept or Myfortic, during therapy and 6 weeks after therapy has been discontinued
             (childbearing women should have a negative serum or urine pregnancy test within 1
             week prior to starting CellCept or Myfortic therapy)

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Recipients with any prior solid organ transplant (including kidney)

          -  Recipients receiving a concurrent solid organ (heart, liver, pancreas) or cell
             (islet, bone marrow, stem cell) transplant

          -  Recipient age is less than 18 years old or greater than 75 years old

          -  Recipients who are not African American (self-reported patients of Black African
             descent who live in the United States)

          -  Recipients on proton pump inhibitor therapy at the time of initial screening
             (pre-transplant to 2 days post-transplant)

          -  Recipients with a gastrointestinal bleed within the past three months

          -  Recipients who are pregnant or breast feeding

          -  Recipients with known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection

          -  Allergy to any of the immunosuppressant medications

          -  Concurrent investigational medication

          -  Any medical or psychosocial condition, which, in the opinion of the investigators,
             would hinder compliance with the study requirements

          -  Inability or unwillingness of patient to provide informed consent
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Roy Bloom, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Pennsylvania-Renal Electrolyte and Hypertension Division</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital of the University of Pennsylvania</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104-4322</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2011</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>February 18, 2011</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>August 27, 2007</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Roy Bloom</name_title>
    <organization>University of Pennsylvania</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>African American</keyword>
  <keyword>Kidney Transplant</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Tacrolimus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mycophenolate mofetil</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Antilymphocyte Serum</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mycophenolic Acid</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
