<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01197027</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the acceptability and feasibility of an enhanced, individual-level counseling intervention for individuals in the acute and early phase of HIV infection aimed at reducing risk behaviors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Feasibility and Acceptability Study of an Individual-Level Behavioral Intervention for Individuals With Acute and Early HIV-Infection</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Be enrolled in CHAVI 001 Note: The inclusion and exclusion criteria for CHAVI 001 are provided below. The criteria will not be reassessed prior to enrollment in HPTN 062. Inclusion Criteria from CHAVI 001 Men and women aged ≥ 18 years at the time of screening. Able and willing to provide adequate information for locator purposes. Hemoglobin &gt; 10.0 g/dL. Willing to receive HIV test results. Not intending to relocate out of the area for the duration of study participation and does not have a job or other obligations that may require long absences from the area. Has acute HIV infection. (See Section 2.3 for definition). Any prior or current use of antiretroviral therapy (ART). This does not apply to individuals screening for Group 1A. ART use for the prevention of perinatal transmission may be waived after prior consultation with the protocol team. Previous or current participation in a HIV vaccine study. HPTN 062 Version 3.0 Final 03 August 2010 Any condition that, in the opinion of the Investigator of Record, would make participation in the study unsafe, complicate interpretation of study outcome data, or otherwise interfere with achieving the study objectives.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>