<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01197443</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The overall intent of this study is to explore a promising mode for delivering treatment for childhood obesity via parent education only, and to evaluate the cost effectiveness compared to the current gold standard treatment of parent-and-child dual education.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Parents as the Agent of Change for Childhood Obesity</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is a randomized clinical trial in which 150 overweight 8-12 year old children and their parent will be randomly assigned by the gender of the child to one of two conditions; a parent-only intervention or a parent + child intervention. Both treatment arms will provide behavioral treatment for childhood obesity for 5 months, and participants will be followed for 18-months post-treatment. Assessments will occur at baseline, immediately post-treatment, 6-12- and 18-months post-treatment. The overall intent of this study is to explore a promising mode for delivering treatment for childhood obesity (parent-only), and to evaluate the cost effectiveness compared to the current gold standard treatment of parent + child. Results of these studies will be utilized as evidence to recommend changes in the standard treatment for childhood obesity. This program of research is critical for exploring and developing interventions that mobilize parents to intervene with their overweight and obese children. The timing of this research is optimal given the increase in childhood obesity in the United States, and the need for disseminative intervention and prevention programs.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pediatric Obesity</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Overweight child 812 years of age and above the 95th% for age and gender An overweight (BMI &gt; 25) parent willing to participate and attend all treatment meetings Eligible parent who can read at a minimum of an 8th grade level Family willing to commit to 5 months of treatment attendance, and followup for 18 months posttreatment. Major child psychiatric disorder diagnoses Child diagnoses of a serious current physical disease (such as diabetes) for which physician supervision of diet and exercise prescription are needed (selfreport) Family with restrictions on types of food, such as food allergies, religious, or ethnic practices that limit the foods available in the home Child with physical difficulties that limit the ability to exercise Child with an active eating disorder (based on EDE interview) Families where children or parents are involved in swimming or weight training more than 5 hours per week Major parent psychiatric disorder</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>8 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>overweight</keyword>
	<keyword>overweight children</keyword>
	<keyword>overweight parents</keyword>
	<keyword>families with overweight child</keyword>
	<keyword>body mass index</keyword>
	<keyword>BMI</keyword>
	<keyword>weight</keyword>
	<keyword>childhood obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>diet</keyword>
	<keyword>treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>parent modeling</keyword>
	<keyword>traffic light diet</keyword>
	<keyword>stop light diet</keyword>
</DOC>