<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01094145</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In the study at hand, six patients with light to moderate Alzheimer's disease will be enrolled and implanted with bilateral electrodes in the nucleus basalis Meynert.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Deep Brain Stimulation (DBS) of the Nucleus Basalis Meynert (NBM) to Treat Cognitive Deficits in Light to Moderate Alzheimer's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In the study at hand, six patients with light to moderate Alzheimer's disease will be enrolled and implanted with bilateral electrodes in the nucleus basalis Meynert. The stereotactic implantation of the electrodes will be guided by computerized tomography (CT) and magnetic resonance tomography (MRT). Basically, even though deep brain stimulation is an invasive method, there are only few side effects. Surgical risks correspond with the risk of DBS in morbus Parkinson or other movement disorders (0,4-6%). After the baseline examination, the patients will be implanted with the electrodes; accordingly all follow-ups are accomplished postoperative. From the second week after the operation, the conventional stimulation takes place as a doubleblind, randomized change between ON and OFF periods. Modifications of the stimulation parameter to obtain the best possible result are possible. Throughout the one-year observation-period, the patients will be followed closely to monitor the effects of DBS on their cognitive abilities, psychopathological well being, the quality of life, praxie and nutritional condition using standardized neurological and psychiatric rating scales.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>German speaking male/female subjects age:6080 AD assessed by DSMIV, ICD10 and NINCDSADRDAScale no LewyBodydementia or other form of dementia MMST &gt;18 and &lt;26 stable psychopharmacological medication no psychotic symptoms, no suicidal tendency education for at least 8 years written informed consent of the patient consent of at least two family members no contraindication regarding PETexamination no contraindication regarding anesthesia or stereotactic operation legal accommodation clinical comorbidity contraindication of MRT examination psychotic symptoms last six months aggressive behavior or suicidal tendency verbal IQ &lt;85 stereotactic operation in previous history neoplastic neurological diseases serious organic disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>(light to moderate)</keyword>
</DOC>