<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00531427</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is to determine the analgesic efficacy and safety of Buprenorphine Transdermal System (BTDS) 10 and 20 compared to placebo in opioid-naïve subjects with moderate to severe chronic pain due to osteoarthritis (OA) of the knee. The double-blind treatment intervention duration is 12 weeks, during which time supplemental analgesic medication (immediate-release oxycodone for the first 6 days postrandomization and acetaminophen or ibuprofen for the remainder of the double-blind phase) will be provided to all subjects in addition to study drug.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Buprenorphine Transdermal System (BTDS) in Subjects w/Mod-sev Osteoarthritis (OA) Chronic Pain of Knee</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Buprenorphine is a synthetic opioid analgesic with over 25 years of international clinical experience indicating it to be safe and effective in a variety of therapeutic settings for the relief of moderate to severe pain. BTDS is a transdermal system formulation that is designed to deliver a consistent and a steady dose of buprenorphine over a 7-day period with limited blood concentration fluctuation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis, Knee</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Buprenorphine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>subjects with moderate to severe chronic osteoarthritis (OA) pain of the knee (lasting several hours daily) as their predominant pain condition, clinical diagnosis of OA of the knee 1 year or longer, subjects treated within the 14 days prior to screening with nonopioid therapy only, or with therapy including opioids at a dose of &lt; 5 mg oxycodone (or equivalent) per day, subjects whose OA knee pain is not adequately controlled with nonopioid analgesic medication and who the investigator feels are appropriate candidates for aroundtheclock opioid therapy. subjects who have had arthroscopy on either knee or hip within 6 months of entering the study or open surgery on either knee or hip within 9 months of entering the study, subjects who are allergic to buprenorphine or who have a history of allergies to other opioids, subjects who have allergies or other contraindications to transdermal delivery systems or patch adhesives. Other protocolspecific inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic pain,</keyword>
	<keyword>OA of the knee,</keyword>
	<keyword>opioid,</keyword>
	<keyword>transdermal</keyword>
</DOC>