<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02870179</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to conduct a SpO2 hypoxia evaluation of the Oxitone Medical Oxitone 1000 pulse oximeter. The Oxitone 1000 pulse oximeter will be evaluated during non-motion conditions over the range of 70-100% SpO2 in comparison to a Reference Pulse Oximeter. The study is observational in nature which quantifies device performance and accuracy in compassion to a Reference Pulse Oximeter.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Oxitone Sp02 Hypoxia Test Versus Reference Pulse Oximetry</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to conduct a SpO2 hypoxia evaluation of the Oxitone Medical Oxitone 1000 pulse oximeter. The Oxitone 1000 pulse oximeter will be evaluated during non-motion conditions over the range of 70-100% SpO2 in comparison to a Reference Pulse Oximeter. The end goal is to show the SpO2 accuracy performance of the Oxitone 1000 and if needed, use the data to make improvements prior to an arterial blood hypoxia study. A Clinimark 3900 Reference Pulse Oximeter or Nellcor N-600x will be used for the SpO2 calibration. There are no risks or adverse device effects to be assessed. There are no contraindications for use in the proposed study / study population The Control Pulse Oximeter, GE Healthcare (Datex-Ohmeda) 3900, an FDA cleared device, is used to monitor the oxygen saturation levels real time throughout the study for subject safety and to target stable plateaus. This device is used to assess the stability of the data.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anoxia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy individuals between the age of 1850 Clotting disorders, diabetes, currently taking psychotropic medications</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pulse Oximetry</keyword>
	<keyword>Temperature</keyword>
	<keyword>Respiratory Rate</keyword>
	<keyword>Respiratory Gases</keyword>
	<keyword>This study determines the measurement accuracy of the physiological parameters</keyword>
</DOC>