<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02870218</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Three hundred-twenty (320) adult smokers of menthol or non-menthol combustible cigarettes will be recruited and randomly assigned to one of five groups (n=64/group), who will be asked to switch for 12 weeks to ad libitum use of combustible cigarettes (matched to subjects' menthol preference) containing either 0.4, 1.4, 2.5, 5.6 or 16.9 mg nicotine (standardized nicotine yields ranging from 0.02-0.80 mg/cigarette), respectively. Each group will include 32 heavy, long-time smokers (≥ 10 cigarettes/day for ≥ 10 years), and 32 light smokers with a shorter smoking history (&lt;10 cigarettes/day for &lt;10 years), who are hypothesized to be more sensitive to nicotine's reinforcing effects. Participants will also have free access to nicotine-containing e-cigarettes (15 mg/ml) throughout the 12-week period. Abuse liability of combustible cigarettes will be assessed by behavioral (cigarettes/day, time to first cigarettes), self-report (rewarding effects, withdrawal symptoms) and biochemical indices (expired air carbon monoxide, cotinine blood sampling).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Abuse Liability of Reduced Nicotine Content Cigarettes in the Context of Concurrent E-Cigarette Use</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Nicotine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Subject is healthy as judged by the Investigator based on all available assessments from the Screening Period (e.g., safety laboratory, vital signs, physical examination, ECG, concomitant medications and medical history). 2. Subject smokes on average four days a week for the last 12 months. 3. Subject has no intention of quitting smoking within the next 90 days. 4. Owns a smart phone with text message and data capabilities. 5. Willingness to use and ability to operate ecigarettes. 6. Willingness to smoke Research Cigarettes. 1. Any medical or psychiatric condition (or associated symptoms or medications) determined by a medical professional to be severe enough to be disruptive to the study. 2. Severe or uncontrolled psychiatric disease with the exception of anxiety disorders, obsessivecompulsive disorder (OCD) and attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD); 3. Pregnant or nursing (by selfreport) or positive pregnancy test; 4. Daily use of: 1. Experimental (investigational) drugs that are unknown to subject; 2. Smokeless tobacco (chewing tobacco, snuff), cigars, pipes and hookah; 3. ecigarettes; 5. Use in the past 30 days of nicotine replacement therapy or other smoking cessation product 6. Positive drug screen for cocaine</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>