<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02660476</DOC>
	<brief_summary>QUDOS is a cross-sectional population study aiming to answer key questions about diabetes and its complications in Qatar as well as identify factors associated with the development and progression of diabetes complications.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Qatar Universal Diabetes Outcomes (QUDOS) Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>QUDOS aims to gain a better understanding of diabetes in primary and secondary care over a period of 24 months. A range of patients with diabetes will be sampled (including those with Type 1 diabetes as this group is under-studied in Qatar). This will be important in designing appropriate intervention plans that will improve diabetic patients' health conditions to prevent or delay the onset of complications and will provide a strong foundation for longitudinal study. The broad objectives of the study are: QUDOS 1: Aims to recruit 1,700 diabetic patients (including 200 with type 1 diabetes mellitus (independent of healthcare setting)) attending the hospitals and primary care and to collect the following data: - Demographics: age, sex, ethnicity, socio-economic background, smoking status; - Anthropometrics: vital signs, height, weight, body fat percentage, fat mass, neck and waist circumference; - Medical History: medications, complications, comorbidities, latest HbA1c and lipid profiles and family medical history; - Routine laboratory data; - Lifestyle: diet, physical activity,; - Sleep: quality and daytime sleepiness; - Cognition and Mental Health: depression, anxiety, stress and memory; - Diabetes microvascular complications: diabetic neuropathy, urine albumin/creatinine ratio; routine retinal screening data. - Gut microbiome from a stool sample QUDOS 2: To further characterise 500 patients, from the total 1500 patients with T2DM recruited in QUDOS 1, who accept to continue with QUDOS 2 (a more detailed study and assessment). This phase aims to concentrate on the following aspects: - Obstructive sleep apnoea; - Sleep duration and quality; - Diet; - Objective physical activity; - Stress; - Quality of Life; - Depression and anxiety; - Perceived control of health; - Detailed neuropathy screening; - Cardiovascular function; - Cognitive function; - Biological samples.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Type 1 and Type 2 diabetes mellitus; 2. Male or Female; 3. Resident in Qatar; 4. MENA birthplace and family origin; 5. 1870 years old; 6. Capable to give informed consent and complete the study. 1. Known pregnancy or planning pregnancy during the duration of study; 2. Congenital disorders; 3. Terminal illness; 4. Enrolled in a clinical trial involving medication; 5. Uncontrolled mental illness preventing participation; 6. Those who have already experienced a definitive microvascular complication: i. Endstage renal disease; ii. Major amputation; iii. Blindness.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diet</keyword>
	<keyword>Middle East and North Africa country</keyword>
	<keyword>Health</keyword>
	<keyword>Complication</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiovascular disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>Stress</keyword>
	<keyword>Obstructive Sleep Apnoea (OSA)</keyword>
</DOC>