<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02869321</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Patients with Head &amp; Neck Squamous Cell Carcinoma often need a gastrostomy. It can be performed with a radiological approach. This procedure is usually not performed under general anesthesia, but local anesthesia is not sufficient to counteract pain due to gastric insufflation and incision of the abdominal wall. Standard analgesic treatments are usually not well-fitted due to onset of action or route of administration. An alternative solution could be fentanyl nasal spray, a treatment with a fast onset of action and with easy use allowing repetition if needed, during the procedure. The purpose of this study is to compare analgesic efficacy of nasal instillation of PECFENT速 to usually administered morphinic analgesic treatment with fast onset of action (ORAMORPH速), in radiologic percutaneous gastrostomy tube placement: - during the procedure - following the procedure (measured by Visual Analog Scale (VAS) for Pain at 15 min, 30 min, 1 hour, 2 hours, 3 hours, 4 hours, 6 hours and 12 hours after procedure). Secondary purposes are to compare easiness of 2 treatments and their adverse effects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Analgesic Efficacy of Transmucosal Fentanyl for Breakthrough Pain Caused by Interventional Gastrostomy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Breakthrough Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Morphine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fentanyl</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Analgesics</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient care for cancer of the upper aerodigestive tract (except sinonasal) &gt; 18, all weights, all sexes Under balanced background opioid treatment since longer than 7 days (VAS &lt; 5) Needing a radiologic gastrostomy under local anesthesia Informed consent Affiliation to social security plan Preliminary medical examination Non balanced morphinic treatment : modification of analgesic treatment during 7 previous days Radiotherapy of nasal fossae/sinus Technical impossibility or contraindication to PECFENT速, ORAMORPH速 and associated drugs Impossibility of pain evaluation by patient Belonging to protected class: pregnant or breastfeeding woman, person deprived of liberty for judiciary or administrative decision, under18, person under legal protection or incapable of giving consent, person in lifeanddeath emergency incapable of giving a preliminary consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>