<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00834626</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Ileal interposition shifts a segment of ileum proximally to achieve maximal meal stimulated Glucagon-Like Peptide-1 secretion and coupled with a limited/complete sleeve gastrectomy (depending on the Body Mass Index), for Ghrelin reduction, helps in achieving good glycemic control in Type 2 Diabetes patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ileal Interposition With Sleeve Gastrectomy for Control of Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Laparoscopically, using 6 ports, the ileum is tarnsected at 30 cms proximal to ileo-caecal junction and at 200 cms proximal to Ileo-Caecal junction;this ileal segment of 170 cms is interposed into proximal jejunum between 20-50 cms distal to Ligament of Treitz. Endo-GIA staplers and hand-sown closure was used for the 3 anastomoses. The mesenteric gaps defects were closed with 3/0 prolene sutures. Sleeve gastrectomy was done starting from antrum/body upto angle of His with a sizing bougie ranging from size 32--58 Fr.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Type 2 Diabetes (as defined by American Diabetes Association criteria)of more than 1 year duration Body Mass Index 21 55 kg/m^2 Poor glycemic control (HbA1c &gt; 8%) despite maximal use of Oral Hypoglycemic Agents and Insulin; or good control(lower HbA1c) but requiring progressively higher drug doses. Gives Informed Consent for the surgery Postmeal C peptide &gt; 1.0 ng/mL Age 25 75 years Stable weight for more than 3 months Type 1 Diabetes Postmeal C peptide &lt; 1 ng/mL Pregnancy Significant nephropathy requiring dialysis Coexisting systemic disease Previous gastric or intestinal resection surgery Obesity due to organic illness</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Ileal Interposition</keyword>
	<keyword>Sleeve Gastrectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>Type-2 Diabetes</keyword>
</DOC>