<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01265173</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Spontaneous bacterial peritonitis (SBP) is one of the most serious complications of liver cirrhosis. Mainstay of treatment for SBP is use of proper antibiotics. Although, several antibiotics including cefotaxime, ceftriaxone, or ciprofloxacin are being used, it is unclear which drug is most effective. Our aim of study is to compare the efficacy of the three current antibiotics for the treatment of SBP in patients with liver cirrhosis. The primary hypothesis is that the efficacy of all the antibiotics will not significantly different. This is non-inferiority trial.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of Efficacy of Cefotaxime, Ceftriaxone, and Ciprofloxacin for the Treatment of Spontaneous Bacterial Peritonitis in Patients With Liver Cirrhosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Spontaneous bacterial peritonitis (SBP) is one of the most serious complications of liver cirrhosis. Mainstay of treatment for SBP is use of proper antibiotics. Although, several antibiotics including cefotaxime, ceftriaxone, or ciprofloxacin are being used, it is unclear which drug is most effective. Our aim of study is to compare the efficacy of the three current antibiotics for the treatment of SBP in patients with liver cirrhosis. The primary hypothesis is that the efficacy of all the antibiotics will not significantly different. The expected success rates (infection resolution rates) are 83%, 87%, and 78% for cefotaxime, ceftriaxone, and ciprofloxacin. This is non-inferiority trial. The level of significance is 5%. The power of this stuy is 80%. Non-inferiority margin is 15%. Therefore 87 patients for each group are needed.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Cirrhosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peritonitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ceftriaxone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ciprofloxacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cefotaxime</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cefoxitin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Liver cirrhosis patients with ascites 2. Ascitic fluid PMN cell count &gt;250/mm3 3. Age: 16~70 years old 1. Allergic to 3rd generation cephalosporin or quinolone 2. Antibiotics within 2 weeks 3. Open abdominal surgery within 4 weeks 4. Evidence of 2ndary peritonitis, intrabdominal hemorrhage, pancreatitis, Tb peritonitis, or peritoneal carcinomatosis 5. HCC with portal vein thrombosis 6. Pregnant woman 7. HIV positive</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>SBP</keyword>
	<keyword>liver cirrhosis</keyword>
	<keyword>antibiotics</keyword>
</DOC>