<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01265472</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Translocator protein (TSPO) is a intracellular protein that is found primarily in the outer membrane of the mitochondria that is encoded by the TSPO gene. It has been found that TSPO expression in the skin correlates with cell proliferation and differentiation. Many studies have shown that TSPO overexpression in solid malignancies such as in ovarian cancer, colon cancer, and others, was also found to correlate with more aggressive cancer behavior. Working Hypothesis and Aims: Previous studies described an aberrant expression of TSPO levels in solid malignancies as compared to normal tissues. It is assumed that this aberration can be found in cuntaneous malignancies as well. The occurrence of this aberration may lead to the understanding of the mechanism of TSPO involment in the cutaneous malignancy, and in malignancies in general. Methods: The study will be carried out on surgically resected skin lesions suspected to SCC or BCC, which will be removed as part of the surgical routine treatment. The excision will be made in elliptic shape including the lesion and a part of normal skin surrounding it. A sample will be taken from the central part of the lesion and from the external extremity of the normal tissue. Western Blot will be conducted to detect the expression of TSPO. Binding activity with the TSPO specific ligandwill also be determined. Expected Results: We expect to observe either (a) a higher level of TSPO expression and a lower binding activity in malignant tissue compared with healthy control tissue or (b) a higher level of TSPO expression and a lower binding activity in malignant tissue compared with healthy control tissue. Importance: Until today, only a very small number of studies have examined TSPO in cutaneous malignancies, and these only examined TSPO expression. Our study will also measure the binding activity of TSPO in cutaneous malignant tissues compared to normal tissues</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of Translocator Protein Expression and Binding Activity in Normal Tissue Versus Non Melanotic Malignancy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Basal Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clinical diagnosis of Basal Cell Carcinoma or Squamous Cell Carcinoma Noncompliance with inclusion criteria</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Translocator Protein</keyword>
	<keyword>Basal Cell Carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Squamous Cell Carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Malignancy</keyword>
</DOC>