<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00401661</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary objective: - End-point improvement from baseline in Male Sexual Health Questionnaire Ejaculation domain (MSHQ-EjD)in men with lower urinary tract symptoms (LUTS)suggestive of benign prostatic hyperplasia (BPH) treated for 6 months with XATRAL 10mg once daily OD. Secondary objectives: - MSHQ-EjD improvement by visit - Improvement in International Prostate Symptom Score (IPSS) total score, voiding and filling subscores, nocturia and bother score at end-point and by visit - Onset of action of XATRAL 10mg OD - Tolerability of XATRAL 10mg OD including occurrence of acute urinary retention.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sexuality And Management of Benign Prostatic Hyperplasia With Alfuzosin</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hyperplasia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Hyperplasia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alfuzosin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Patients suffering from moderate to severe LUTS suggestive of BPH IPSS total score ≥ 8 Patients sexually active Exclusion criteria: Known history of hepatic or severe renal insufficiency, unstable angina pectoris, concomitant lifethreatening condition Previous prostate surgery, minimally invasive procedure within 6 months prior to inclusion. Planned prostate biopsy, prostate surgery or minimally invasive procedure during the whole study period Active urinary tract infection or prostatitis, neuropathic bladder, a diagnosed prostate cancer Treatment with 5alphareductase inhibitors or phytotherapy within 6 months prior to inclusion, or alpha1blockers within 30 days prior to inclusion Patients receiving any treatment for erectile dysfunction (i.e. phosphodiesterase5 inhibitors) at inclusion History of postural hypotension or syncope Known hypersensitivity to alfuzosin The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2009</verification_date>
</DOC>