<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02415517</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The daily routine in clinical settings often showed cognitive impairments in patients with congestive heart failure, particularly in terms of executive functions, episodic memory, perceptual speed and attention. It is assumed that cognitive impairments in patients with congestive heart failure may lead to deficits in medication-adherence and self-care abilities, resulting in increased healthcare costs. Recent studies reported performance improvements after cognitive training that transferred to new, untrained tasks and abilities in healthy subjects across a wide range of ages. This study investigates the effects of cognitive training in patients with congestive heart failure.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cognitive Training in Heart Failure Study (CogTrain-HF)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Cognitive functions of patients with congestive heart failure (NYHA II-III) before (pretest) and after (posttest) cognitive-training intervention are investigated. Changes in cognitive functions are compared to changes in two control groups: 1) age and gender matched active control group 2) age and gender matched passive waiting list control group. The neuropsychological test battery applied at pretest and posttest includes measures of episodic memory, working memory, short-term memory, executive functions, perceptual speed and intelligence. In addition, the investigators apply standardized questionnaires of self-assessed quality of life, cognitive functioning in daily life, selfcare, and psychological well-being (depression, anxiety and personality). Relevant physiological data such as ejection fraction, heartrate, N-terminal pro brain natriuretic peptide (NT-pro-BNP) as well as drug blood level are recorded.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Congestive heart failure NYHA IIIII Psychosis Dementia Major depression Reanimation (&lt;3month) Patients with assist device system</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cognitive training</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive impairment</keyword>
	<keyword>Heart failure</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognition</keyword>
</DOC>