<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="53529">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02409329</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>140562</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>1R01DK100694-01A1</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02409329</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Improving Medication Adherence Among Underserved Patients With Type 2 Diabetes</brief_title>
  <official_title>Improving Medication Adherence Among Underserved Patients With Type 2 Diabetes</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases (NIDDK)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Approximately one in three persons with diabetes are nonadherent to their medications.
      Nonadherence is more common among low income, racial/ethnic minorities with type 2 diabetes
      (T2DM), and is a strong, independent predictor of having poor glycemic control, being
      hospitalized, pre-mature mortality, and higher healthcare costs. Theory-based adherence
      promotion interventions are more effective than atheoretical, adhoc approaches, and are
      needed for patients at highest risk of nonadherence. A well-validated theoretical model, the
      Information—Motivation—Behavioral Skills (IMB) model, has informed effective medication
      adherence promotion interventions for patients with HIV and hypertension, and should inform
      adherence interventions in diabetes. Moreover, widely available technologies, such as mobile
      phones, offer a means to deliver adherence interventions to a broad range of patients,
      including low income, racial/ethnic minorities at high risk of nonadherence.

      The goal of this research is to use the IMB model to inform the content and functionality of
      a mobile phone-delivered medication adherence promotion intervention, ensure intervention
      content is clearly communicated (i.e., uses simplified text and plain language), and
      evaluate intervention effects on adherence and glycemic control among low-income adults with
      T2DM receiving primary care at Federally Qualified Health Centers (FQHCs).

      This interdisciplinary research will greatly enhance our understanding of how to address
      social-cognitive barriers to adherence among high-risk patients with diabetes, how to
      leverage mobile devices to support high-risk patient populations in general; and how to
      better design interventions to improve services for low-income, diverse patients, as well as
      other high-risk groups. Knowledge gained form this work may also inform interventions to
      reduce disparities in adherence, glycemic control, and other diabetes outcomes.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Investigator</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Glycemic Control, as indicated by hemoglobin A1c (HbA1c)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 months, 6, months, 12 months, 15 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in self-reported medication adherence as measured by scores on the Adherence to Refills and Medication Scale (ARMS-D) and Summary of Diabetes Self-Care Activities (SDSCA) Medications subscale</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 months, 6, months, 12 months, 15 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">500</enrollment>
  <condition>Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</condition>
  <condition>Medication Adherence</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Text Message Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants assigned to the intervention group will complete measures at each time point and receive tailored short message service (SMS) text messaging aimed to improve their medication adherence.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants assigned to the control group will complete measures at each time point and maintain care as usual (i.e., medical treatment and physician monitoring), and receive a text message at each time point when A1c results are ready with instructions on how to access their results. Participants also have access to the REACH Helpline for research-, technical-, and/or medication-related questions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Text Messaging</intervention_name>
    <description>The intervention consists of daily, tailored text messaging addressing and assessing medication adherence, as well as a weekly text message that provides adherence feedback. Participants will receive a text message at each time point when A1c results are ready with instructions on how to access their results. Participants also have access to the REACH Helpline for research-, technical-, and/or medication-related questions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Text Message Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Adults aged 18 years and older

          -  Individuals who have received a diagnosis for type 2 diabetes mellitus

          -  Enrolled as a patient at a participating community health center

          -  Individuals currently being treated with oral and/or injectable diabetes medications

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Non-English speakers

          -  Individuals who report they do not have a cell phone

          -  Individuals unwilling and/or not able to provide written informed consent

          -  Individuals with unintelligible speech (e.g., dysarthria)

          -  Individuals with a severe hearing or visual impairment

          -  Individuals who report a caregiver administers their diabetes medications Individuals
             who fail the cognitive screener administered during the baseline survey

          -  Individuals who cannot receive, read, and respond to a text after instruction from a
             trained research assistant
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lindsay S Mayberry, PhD, MS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>January 25, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 9, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Lindsay Mayberry</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor of Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
