<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02636517</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Fecal Microbiota Transplant (FMT) in pediatric patients with recurrent C. Difficile with or without Inflammatory Bowel Disease (IBD) The aims of this study are to determine the safety and efficacy of FMT treatment in pediatric patients with recurrent or moderate to severe C. Difficile without (through an observational study) and with (through a clinical trial) Inflammatory Bowel Disease and to determine the effect of FMT on the gut microbiota through the use of 454 pyrosequencing before and after transplantation in these patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Fecal Microbiome Transplant</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Colitis, Ulcerative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Crohn Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Inflammatory Bowel Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Diagnosis of Inflammatory Bowel Disease by colonoscopy, radiographic and clinic measures, as per standard protocol. 2. Age ≥ 3 years old. 3. Recurrent C. difficile or Moderate to Severe C. difficile. 4. Satisfactory completion of the medical interview and physical exam conducted by a study team member 5. Participants must be between 3 and 21 years of age (inclusive) 6. Negative serologic testing to document baseline status within one month prior to FMT, to including, but not limited to: HIV 1 &amp; 2, Hepatitis A total, Hepatitis B surface Ag, surface Ab and core Ab, Hepatitis C Ab, rapid plasma reagin (RPR) 7. Signed informed consent form, and assent (if applicable) 1. Patients &lt;3 years old 2. Patients with other comorbid intestinal infectious processes 3. Patients will be excluded if on immunosuppressive therapy within 2 weeks of FMT. Clinical care will not be adjusted in order to meet criteria of this study. 4. Patients currently receiving chemotherapy 5. Recipients with a history of severe (anaphylactic) food allergy 6. If female, participants of childbearing potential (females aged 11 and older or those who have already begun menstruating) will be required to have a urine pregnancy test on the day of the FMT procedure. Patients who are pregnant will not be enrolled.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Fecal Microbiota transplant</keyword>
</DOC>