<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02539407</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Concentrations and effects of anti-infectives in critically ill children are unpredictable and the risk of under-exposure may be associated with poor clinical outcomes. In addition, between-subject variability (BSV) is known to be substantial in critically ill children. Rationalisation of anti-infectives in children is therefore desirable. The investigators aim to investigate, using a population approach, the pharmacokinetics (PK) and pharmacodynamics (PD) of anti-infectives including PK/PD targets (fT(%) &gt; minimal inhibitory concentration (MIC)) and PD endpoints (clinical outcomes) in critically ill children. Covariates The effects of covariates on anti-infectives PK and PK/PDs are investigated in order to better explain the BSV and to ultimately suggest individualized dosage regimens. It will be a prospective PK study including 11 anti-infectives antibiotics. Six blood samples were taken from each patient during dosing interval. The primary PK/ PD targets were anti-infectives concentrations above the MIC of the pathogen at both 50% (50% f T&gt;MIC) and 100% (100% f T&gt;MIC) of the dosing interval. The investigators used skewed logistic regression to describe the effect of anti-infectives exposure on patient outcome.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Population Pharmacokinetics of Anti-infectives in Critically Ill Children</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Background and aims of the study: Recent studies have suggested a risk of under-exposure to anti-infectives in critically ill adults. This under-exposure may be associated with poor clinical outcomes as well as a delay or incomplete clinical resolution of infection; The dosing regimen of anti-infectives in critically ill children is usually based on weight (i.e. mg per Kg). However, between-subject variability is known to be substantial in children and even more so in critical illness; As a result, concentrations and effects of anti-infectives are unpredictable and the risk of under- or over-exposure is thus genuine and considerable. Rationalisation of anti-infectives in children is therefore desirable. The purpose of the present study is to investigate, using a population approach, the pharmacokinetics (PK) and pharmacodynamics (PD) of intravenous anti-infectives including usual PK/PD targets (fT(%) &gt; minimal inhibitory concentration (MIC)) and PD endpoints (clinical outcomes) in critically ill children. The effects of developmental and other factors related to critical illness on anti-infectives PK and PK/PDs are investigated in order to better explain the observed between-subject variabilities and to ultimately suggest individualized dosage regimens. This prospective study will be conducted in six paediatric services of Public Hospitals in Paris, France Intervention: Patient selection will take place in the 6 paediatric services. The senior physician proposes the study to holders of parental authority whose child receives or will receive anti-infectives during its follow-up or hospitalization. The senior physician will give a briefing note to the holders of parental authority, and if the child is able to understand the information. The non-oral opposition for the retrieval and analysis of data will be collected. No intervention or no charge will be made for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Critical Illness</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Infective Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluoroquinolones</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Minor patient requiring the administration of an antiinfective belonging to the following classes : βlactam antibiotics; aminoglycosides, glycopeptides; fluoroquinolones; other antibiotics (daptomycin, rifampin, trimethoprim, sulfamethoxazole, clarithromycin); fungal; antivirals, during its followup or hospitalization Patient and parents having notified to the doctor that they refuse data recovery.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>β-lactam antibiotics</keyword>
	<keyword>Children</keyword>
	<keyword>Anti-infectives</keyword>
	<keyword>Aminoglycosides, glycopeptides</keyword>
	<keyword>Fluoroquinolone</keyword>
	<keyword>Fungal</keyword>
	<keyword>Antiviral</keyword>
</DOC>