<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02539329</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Sensory neuronopathies affect sensory neuron in the posterior spinal ganglion. They are responsible for pain, balance disorder (ataxia) and the use of hands. They depend on multiple etiologies. In a retrospective study, the investigators showed that the anti-FGFR3 antibody is a diagnostic marker of a subset of sensory neuronopathies. The investigators believe that other antibodies can be discovered in patients who remain seronegative changing. However, the study is retrospective and only a small number of patients could be identified. Several points therefore need to be clarified or confirmed in a second prospective study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Characterization of Anti-FGFR3 Antibodies</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In and out patients evaluated for a sensory neuropathy meeting the inclusion and non-inclusion criteria will be proposed to enter the study At inclusion the SSN diagnostic score is calculated and a blood sample is tested for anti-FGFR3 antibody. Follow up: Patients positive for anti-FGFR3 antibodies will be followed and evaluated clinically and electrophysiologically at 1, 6 and 12 months. A blood sample is taken at 6 and 12 months. A subgroup of patients negative for anti-FGFR3 antibodies will be randomly selected for evaluation at 1, 6 and 12 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Nervous System Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>A :Patients Male or female patient aged 18 years or more Patients with a clinically pure sensory peripheral neuropathy including : idiopathic or dysimmune sensory neuronopathies idiopathic or dysimmune distal axonal sensory neuropathy sensory chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyradiculoneuropathy idiopathic or dysimmune small fiber neuropathies idiopathic or dysimmune trigeminal nerve neuropathy positive to antibodies antiFGFR3 B :Controls Male or female patient aged 18 years or more Patients with a clinically pure sensory peripheral neuropathy including : idiopathic or dysimmune sensory neuronopathies idiopathic or dysimmune distal axonal sensory neuropathy sensory chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyradiculoneuropathy idiopathic or dysimmune small fiber neuropathies idiopathic or dysimmune trigeminal nerve neuropathy negative to antibodies antiFGFR3 Motor or sensorymotor neuropathies Genetic, toxic, paraneoplasic neuropathies Diabetic Neuropathy. Neuropathy with AntiMAG or antiganglioside IgM. Pregnant or breastfeeding woman</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>neuropathy</keyword>
	<keyword>antibodies antiFGFR3</keyword>
	<keyword>Biological diagnostic criteria</keyword>
</DOC>