<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03086330</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial is conducted in Asia, Europe and North America. The aim of the trial is to compare the effect of semaglutide s.c. 1.0 mg once-weekly versus placebo as add-on to sodium glucose co-transporter-2 inhibitor (SGLT-2i) monotherapy or in combination with either metformin or sulfonylurea on glycaemic control after 30 weeks of treatment in subjects with type 2 diabetes. Subjects will remain on their pre-trial medication.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Semaglutide Once-weekly Versus Placebo as add-on to SGLT-2i in Subjects With Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Informed consent obtained before any trialrelated activities. Trialrelated activities are any procedures that are carried out as part of the trial, including activities to determine suitability for the trial Male or female, above or equal to 18 years at the time of signing informed consent. For Japan only: Male or female, age equal to or above 20 years at the time of signing informed consent Diagnosed with type 2 diabetes mellitus HbA1c of 7.010.0% (5386 mmol/mol) (both inclusive) Stable dose of an SGLT2 inhibitor as monotherapy or in combination (including fixeddose drug combination) with a stable dose of metformin (equal to or above 1500 mg or maximum tolerated dose) or a SU for at least 90 days prior to the day of screening. All medications in compliance with current local label Female who is pregnant, breastfeeding or intends to become pregnant or is of childbearing potential and not using an adequate contraceptive method (adequate contraceptive measure as required by local regulation or practice) Any disorder which in the investigator's opinion might jeopardise subject's safety or compliance with the protocol Treatment with any medication for the indication of diabetes or obesity other than stated in the inclusion criteria within the past 90 days prior to the day of screening. However, short term insulin treatment for a maximum of 14 days prior to the day of screening is allowed Subjects with alanine aminotransferase above 2.5 x upper normal limit Family or personal history of multiple endocrine neoplasia type 2 or medullary thyroid carcinoma. Family is defined as a first degree relative History or presence of pancreatitis (acute or chronic) History of diabetic ketoacidosis Any of the following: myocardial infarction, stroke, hospitalization for unstable angina or transient ischaemic attack within the past 180 days prior to the day of screening Subjects presently classified as being in New York Heart Association Class IV Planned coronary, carotid or peripheral artery revascularisation known on the day of screening Renal impairment measured as estimated Glomerular Filtration Rate value of eGFR below 60 ml/min/1.73 m^2 as defined by KDIGO 2012 classification using isotope dilution mass spectrometry for serum creatinine measured at screening Proliferative retinopathy or maculopathy requiring acute treatment. Verified by fundus photography or dilated fundoscopy performed within the past 90 days prior to randomisation Presence or history of malignant neoplasms within the past 5 years prior to the day of screening. Basal and squamous cell skin cancer and any carcinoma insitu is allowed</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>