<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01349036</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is to evaluate the response of subjects with recurrent glioblastoma to continuous therapy of PLX3397.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase 2 Study of PLX3397 in Patients With Recurrent Glioblastoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female patients ≥18 years old with a life expectancy of at least 8 weeks Radiographically proven recurrent (≥ first relapse), intracranial GBM For all patients, availability of at least 10 unstained slides (or archival tumor block sufficient to generate at least 10 unstained slides) from any previous GBM surgery Previous treatment with external beam radiation and temozolomide chemotherapy Before the first dose of PLX3397,adequate recovery from toxicity of prior therapy as follows: &gt;28 days for cytotoxic therapy &gt;42 days for nitrosoureas &gt;28 days for bevacizumab &gt;7 days for non cytotoxic therapy such as interferon, tamoxifen, thalidomide, cisretinoic acid, or erlotinib Women of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test within 7 days of initiation of dosing and must agree to use an acceptable method of birth control while on study drug and for 3 months after the last dose. Women of nonchildbearing potential may be included if they are either surgically sterile or have been postmenopausal for ≥1 year. Men of childbearing potential must also agree to use an acceptable method of birth control while on study drug. Karnofsky performance status of ≥60 Adequate hematologic, hepatic, and renal function (absolute neutrophil count ≥1.0 x 109/L, Hgb &gt;9 g/dL, platelet count ≥50 x 109/L, AST/ALT ≤2.5x ULN, creatinine ≤1.5x ULN) Willing and able to provide written informed consent prior to any study related procedures and to comply with all study requirements Investigational drug use within 28 days of the first dose of PLX3397 GBM progression within 3 months of previous radiation by RANO criteria History of Grade 2 (CTCAE v4) or greater acute intracranial hemorrhage Previous failure of bevacizumab or other VEGF therapy except in a first line setting History of malignant glioma with codeletion of 1p/19q A concurrent active cancer that requires nonsurgical therapy (e.g. chemotherapy, radiation, adjuvant therapy). Prior history of other cancer is allowed, as long as there was no active disease within the prior 3 years. Refractory nausea and vomiting, malabsorption, biliary shunt, or significant bowel resection that would preclude adequate absorption Patients with serious illnesses, uncontrolled infection, medical conditions, or other medical history including abnormal laboratory results, which in the investigator's opinion would be likely to interfere with a patient's participation in the study, or with the interpretation of the results Women of childbearing potential who are pregnant or breast feeding QTc ≥450 msec at Screening</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>GBM</keyword>
	<keyword>Glioblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>brain cancer</keyword>
</DOC>