<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00269893</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effectiveness and safety of abciximab (an anti-platelet therapy) versus placebo in patients undergoing high risk coronary angioplasty.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study Evaluating the Efficacy and Safety of Abciximab, an Anti-platelet Therapy, in Patients Undergoing High-risk Coronary Angioplasty</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicenter study evaluating the efficacy and safety of abciximab, an anti-platelet therapy, in patients undergoing high risk coronary angioplasty. The primary outcomes of the study include any of the following: the number of deaths from any cause, or myocardial infarctions and recurrent ischemic events requiring urgent intervention (e.g., repeat angioplasty, coronary artery bypass surgery, intracoronary stent placement, or intra-aortic balloon pump). Patients receive an abciximab bolus, abciximab bolus plus infusion, or placebo.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Angina, Unstable</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Abciximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulin Fab Fragments</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients referred for elective or urgent coronary balloon angioplasty or atherectomy with an FDAapproved device in one of the following settings: unstable angina or nonQ wave myocardial infarction, acute Qwave myocardial infarction, or highrisk clinical/morphological characteristics Patients with a history of hemorrhagic diathesis Having had major surgery or clinically significant gastrointestinal or genitourinary bleeding within 6 weeks of study enrollment Having had a stroke within 2 years prior to enrollment or any stroke with significant residual neurological deficit Having occlusion of the left main coronary artery greater than 50% or a history of vasculitis Treated with oral anticoagulants within 7 days (unless prothrombin time is =&lt; 1.2 times control) or intravenous dextran (before or planned for during the treatment angioplasty)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Abciximab</keyword>
	<keyword>Angina, unstable</keyword>
	<keyword>Angioplasty, transluminal, Percutaneous coronary</keyword>
</DOC>