<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01653353</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Residents of nursing homes are endangered by malnutrition and vitamin D deficiency. Our study checks compliance with Swiss federal recommendations on vitamin D and calcium supplementation among residents of a Swiss nursing home. A peer physician-applied recommendation on compliance with the federal recommendations with individual evaluation of the residents will be sent to the physicians in care. After one year, data will be collected again.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Swiss Study on Vitamin D and Calcium in Nursing Homes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigators plan to get a complete sample of all inhabitants, so the only inclusion criterion is to get an informed consent either from the residents or from their relatives. The following data will be recorded: Year of birth, gender, height, weight, blood pressure and heart rate, daily calcium intake from diet, nursing home scales on pain, depression, dementia and activities of daily life, date of entry to the home, diagnosis and medication lists. From a venous blood sample the investigators get: calcium, phosphate, albumin, creatinin, 25-hydroxyvitamin D, parathormone (intact). Primary endpoint: Proportion of medication lists of residents complying with federal recommendation on vitamin D and calcium supplementation. Secondary endpoints: 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels, effect of an intervention with a nursing home-applied recommendation to the physicians.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Avitaminosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium, Dietary</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Resident of nursing home on qualifying date Written informed consent by residents or their relatives Refusion of participation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>nursing home</keyword>
	<keyword>vitamin D supplements</keyword>
	<keyword>calcium supplements</keyword>
	<keyword>guideline adherence</keyword>
</DOC>