<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01653652</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the current study is to evaluate the efficacy of administering a probiotic in adult human subjects suffering from allergic rhinitis during seasonal grass pollen exposure.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of a Probiotic on Seasonal Allergic Rhinitis Symptoms</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Adult subjects with documented seasonal allergic rhinitis (SAR) to grass pollen will be assigned to placebo or probiotic groups and take either placebo or probiotic dietary intervention for 8 weeks during the grass pollen allergy season. Total nasal symptom score (TNSS) will be compared over 8 weeks between the two treatment groups.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic, Seasonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adults aged 18 to 65 years of age at the time of enrolment. Established seasonal allergic rhinitis (clinical history of rhinorrhea, congestion, sneezing, pruritis &gt;2 years) Positive Skin Prick Test (SPT)to Grass Pollen (GP). Presence of specific IgE to Grass Pollen (GP) Have a Body Mass Index in the range 1932 kg/m2 Have signed the consent form Have been instructed during screening and agreed to not take any probiotic containing products outside the study for the study period Subjects currently under treatment with antibiotics or undergoing allergen immunotherapy at the time of enrolment Pregnancy Vasomotor rhinitis, nasal cavity disorders (nasal polyps), ear infections otitis media). Other chronic diseases (e.g. gastrointestinal, cardiovascular, infections) Subjects diagnosed with asthma Subjects currently participating in another interventional clinical trial or having participated in another clinical trial in the last 2 months Subjects on chronic use of systemic corticosteroids prior to randomization</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>grass pollen</keyword>
	<keyword>allergic rhinitis</keyword>
	<keyword>TNSS</keyword>
	<keyword>miniRQLQ</keyword>
</DOC>