<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01653275</DOC>
	<brief_summary>We propose a 24 week clinical research trial (12 week observational period followed by 12 week MedSD intervention) with feasibility of diet adoption and markers of bone turnover as the primary outcomes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mediterranean Diet for Post-menopausal Women: Effects on Bone Turnover</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Postmenopausal women are at increased risk of osteoporosis and fracture. Components of a Mediterranean style diet (MedSD) are associated with reduced bone loss and fracture risk; however, the MedSD has not been tested in this population in the U.S. Therefore, we propose a 24 week clinical research trial (12 week observational period followed by 12 week MedSD intervention) with feasibility of diet adoption and markers of bone turnover as the primary outcomes. The 12 week intervention will include provision of olive oil, walnuts and high n-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids (PUFA) fish to replace other fats and oils, processed snacks and red meat, respectively; accompanied with fruit, vegetable, whole grain and legumes intake recommendations. We hypothesize the MedSD intervention will increase serum n-3 PUFA and decrease saturated fatty acids and n-6 PUFA and this will result in an improvement in bone turnover markers. The outcomes of the proposed intervention trial will promote further study of the benefits of a MedSD in the US. We envision the research team to expand to other systems such as cardiovascular, metabolic, and inflammatory mechanisms in which less risk of disease is associated with a MedSD.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Osteoporosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoporosis, Postmenopausal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. postmenopausal women &gt; 65 years; 2) BMI&lt;30 kg/m2; 3) able to travel to clinical sites for followup visits; 4) willing to make no changes to habitual physical activity or calcium and vitamin D intake for the study duration 1) any disease that may affect bone metabolism, (i.e Paget's disease, primary hyperparathyroidism); 2) cancers of any kind (except basal or squamous cell of skin) in past 5 years; 3) use of medication known to affect bone metabolism; 6) extreme dietary behaviors or supplementation in excess of DRI upper limits; 7) following a medically prescribed diet or dietary pattern similar to the MedSD; 9) history of chronic renal or liver disease; 10) history of hip fracture or known vertebral fracture within the past year; 11) persons with an allergy to fish or nuts.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Mediterranean Diet</keyword>
	<keyword>Bone turnover</keyword>
	<keyword>postmenopausal women</keyword>
</DOC>