<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00835562</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Displaced four-part fractures are among the most severe injuries of the proximal humerus. The optimal treatment is disputed and published data are inadequate for evidence-based decision making. The investigators aim to: 1) compare the effect of angle-stable plate osteosynthesis and non-surgical management, 2) compare the effect of primary hemiarthroplasty with both osteosynthesis and non-surgical management, 3) study prognostic differences between 'valgus impacted' and 'classical' four-part fracture patterns. The investigators will conduct a randomised, multi-centre, clinical trial including patients from ten national shoulder units within a two year period. Patients will be randomised to non-surgical treatment, hemiarthroplasty or angle-stable plate osteosynthesis. All patients will receive a standardised three-month rehabilitation program of supervised physiotherapy. Patients will be followed at least one year and will be assessed blindly according to a standardised evaluation protocol including Constant Disability Scale, Oxford Shoulder Score, and Short Form-36.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Osteosynthesis, Primary Hemi-arthroplasty, and Non-surgical Management for Fractures of the Proximal Humerus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Humeral Fractures</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Shoulder Fractures</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Displaced fourpart fracture of the proximal humerus Mentally alert Physically fit for surgery and rehabilitation (ASAgroup 13) Informed written consent Operation can be conducted within 2 weeks of injury Fracturedislocations Headsplitting fractures Previous shoulder surgery on injured side Chronic shoulder pain Abuse problems Patients unable to understand instructions in Danish</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Shoulder fractures</keyword>
	<keyword>Proximal humeral fractures</keyword>
	<keyword>Randomised clinical trial</keyword>
	<keyword>elderly</keyword>
	<keyword>Displaced four-part fractures of the proximal humerus</keyword>
</DOC>