<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02577341</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This Phase II randomized study is to determine the efficacy and toxicity of Nimotuzumab in combined with chemoradiotherapy for unresectable,local advanced squamous cell lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Nimotuzumab Combined With Chemoradiotherapy for Unresectable Locally Advanced Squamous Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This Phase II randomized study is to determine the efficacy and toxicity of Nimotuzumab in combined with chemoradiotherapy for unresectable,local advanced squamous cell lung cancer. All patients received five cycles of weekly docetaxel and cisplatin, each of 1 day's duration. Thoracic RT includes the delivery of 65 Gy in 25 fractions on weekdays for a total of five weeks. Nimotuzumab group was treated with five doses of weekly nimotuzumab (200mg, IV) combined with chemoradiotherapy, while placebo group was treated with five doses of placebos. 150 patients are needed to be enrolled for an 80% power to detect an improvement in overall survival from 15 months to 25 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>histologically confirmed squamous cell lung cancer patients have measurable or evaluable lesions based on the Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) criteria unresectable phase IIIA(N2) and IIIB lung cancer confirmed by CT or MRI ECOG performance status 01 Previously treated with chemotherapy or treatmentnaive no previous chest radiotherapy, immunotherapy or biotherapy. hemoglobin≥10 mg/dL, platelet≥100000/μL,absolute neutrophil count ≥1500/μL serum creatinine ≤1.25 times the upper normal limit(UNL), or creatinine clearance≥60 ml/min bilirubin ≤1.5 times UNL, AST（SGOT）≤2.5 times UNL ,ALT（SGPT）≤2.5 times UNL,alkaline phosphatase ≤5 times UNL FEV1 &gt;0.8 L CB6 within normal limits patients and their family signed the informed consents adenosquamous carcinoma previous or recent another malignancy, except for nonmelanoma skin cancer or cervical cancer in situ contraindication for chemotherapy women in pregnancy, lactation period, or no pregnancy test 14 days before the first dose women who has the probability of pregnancy without contraception tendency of hemorrhage in other clinical trials within 30 days addicted in drugs or alcohol, AIDS patients uncontrollable seizure or psychotic patients without selfcontrol ability severe allergy or idiosyncrasy not suitable for this study judged by researchers</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Nimotuzumab, Chemoradiotherapy,Squamous Cell Lung Cancer</keyword>
</DOC>