<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02628574</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will be conducted in 2 parts (Part A and Part B). Subjects ≥18 years with advanced solid tumors will be enrolled in the study. Dose escalation will be performed in Part A. Cycle 1 data from each cohort will be evaluated for safety and dose-limiting toxicities (DLTs) prior to dose escalation. Subjects will be assigned to a cohort in the order screening is completed. Dose will depend upon the cohort in which a patient is enrolled and cohorts will be dosed consecutively by ascending dose. Once the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) or maximum administered dose (MAD) has been identified, an expanded cohort will be enrolled (Part B).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dose Escalation Study of TRX518 in Adults With Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Advanced Solid Malignancies with at least 1 measurable lesion, who have failed to respond to or relapsed following standard treatment or who have declined to pursue standard treatment, in otherwise stable health (as confirmed by medical history, physical examination, ECG, and screening laboratory tests). Expected survival of at least 12 weeks after dosing. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status score of 0 or 1 Evidence of adequate organ function by standard laboratory tests. All female subjects of child bearing age must be either surgically sterile, postmenopausal for at least 1 year, or using an acceptable method of contraception. Adequate contraception for both male and female subjects must be used from the beginning of the screening period until at least 8 weeks after the last dose of TRX518. Hematologic malignancies or multiple myeloma. Known, clinically important cardiac or respiratory disease Any concomitant serious physical illness other than cancer (e.g., immune deficiency disease, bleeding disorder, etc.) within 1 year prior to dosing. No history of autoimmune disease. Active, uncontrolled infections within 7 days of study entry requiring systemic therapy. Evidence of progression of central nervous system (CNS) metastases or symptomatic CNS metastases within 30 days prior to dosing.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Metastatic</keyword>
	<keyword>Stage III or IV</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent</keyword>
	<keyword>refractory</keyword>
	<keyword>solid tumors</keyword>
</DOC>