<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02927184</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will investigate the efficacy, safety, and tolerability of VK2809 in lowering LDL-C and liver fat content in patients with primary hypercholesterolemia and fatty liver disease. The primary efficacy endpoint is percent change from baseline LDL-C at the end of the treatment period (Week 12). Secondary endpoints include effects on liver fat content and other liver and lipid markers, as well as effects on safety and tolerability, and pharmacokinetic (PK) measurements.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Tolerability of VK2809 in Patients With Primary Hypercholesterolemia and Non-Alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypercholesterolemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fatty Liver</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperlipidemias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Non-alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Minimum of 10% liver fat as assessed by MRI Proton Density Fat Fraction 2. Fasting serum LDLC &gt;130 mg/dL at screening, &gt;110 mg/dL on lipid lowering medications 3. Any one of the following: 1. Triglycerides ≥150 mg/dL or receiving prescription medication for elevated triglycerides. 2. Systolic blood pressure &gt;130 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure ≥85 mmHg or receiving prescription medication for hypertension. 3. Waist circumference &gt;40 inches (men) or &gt;35 inches (women) 4. Body mass index (BMI) 18.50 40.00 kg/m2 inclusive at screening 5. Provide a personallysigned and dated informed consent document 1. Females of childbearing potential and males unwilling to use barrier birth control method (condom) throughout the study 2. Resting 12lead ECG showing QTc &gt;450 msec, any tachyarrhythmia or morphology change, or any other clinically significant abnormality 3. Cardiovascular event requiring hospitalization in the past year 4. History or presence of thyroid disorder 5. History of malignancy in past 5 years 6. LDLC ≥190 mg/dL or familial hypercholesterolemia 7. Significant hepatic or renal function test abnormalities</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>