<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01266148</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A controlled, randomized, open-label, multicenter study evaluating if early initiation of everolimus and early elimination of cyclosporine in de novo heart transplant recipients can improve long-term renal function and slow down the progression of chronic allograft vasculopathy</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>SCHEDULE - Scandinavian Heart Transplant Everolimus de Novo Study With Early Calcineurin Inhibitor (CNI) Avoidance</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This was a prospective, multi-center, randomized, controlled, parallel group, open label study in de novo heart transplant recipients. Patients eligibility for randomization was assessed 5 days after heart transplant.. Patients fulfilling the inclusion and exclusion criteria were randomized to one of two treatment groups: either conventional treatment with Cyclosporine A (CsA), Mycophenolate mofetil (MMF), and corticosteroids (Group A), or low-dose CsA and everolimus, reduced dose MMF, and corticosteroids (Group B). After 7 to 11 weeks, CsA was discontinued in Group B, while the standard triple-drug immunosuppressive regimen was maintained in Group A.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antilymphocyte Serum</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolate mofetil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcineurin Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>De novo heart transplant recipients who had received induction therapy with antithomocyte globulin (ATG) were eligible for inclusion. Recipients of multiorgan transplants or a previous transplant were excluded, as were those with a donor aged &gt; 70 years, cold ischemia time &gt;6 hours, patients with severe systemic infection, recipients of ABO incompatible transplants, patients with severe hypercholesterolemia (&gt;350mg/dL) or hypertriglyceridemia (&gt;750 mg/dL), patients with past (&lt;5 years). In order to continue in the study after week 711 (period 1), patients had to complete first 711 weeks on randomized immunosuppression and none of the following criteria should be present: Ongoing rejection treatment or experience of one grade 3R rejection or two or more grade 2R rejections during first 711 weeks.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>