<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01348139</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of single doses of three different dry powder inhalation formulations of AZD3199 administered via Single Inhalation Device (SID) compared to AZD3199 administered via Turbuhaler™ Inhaler and compared to placebo in patients with persistent asthma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Pharmacokinetics and the Pharmacodynamics of Different Dry Powder Inhalation Formulations of AZD3199 in Patients With Asthma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>AZD-3199</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Provision of signed and dated written informed consent prior to any study specific procedures Men or women, age ≥ 18 years. Women must be of nonchildbearing potential or stable on a highly effective contraceptive method for at least 3 months prior to Visit 1 and be willing to continue on the chosen contraceptive method throughout the study. Be a nonsmoker or exsmoker who has stopped smoking for &gt;6 months prior to study start A history of asthma for at least 6 months. Body Mass Index (BMI) 1930 kg/m2 Significant disease or disorder which, in the opinion of the Investigator, may either put the patient at risk because of participation in the study, or influence the result of the study, or the patient's ability to participate in the study History of severe allergy/hypersensitivity or ongoing allergy/hypersensitivity, as judged by the Investigator or history of hypersensitivity to β2agonists in general or to AZD3199 and/or excipients Prolonged QTcF &gt; 450 msec or shortened QTcF &lt;340 msec History of alcohol/drug abuse or excessive intake of alcohol as judged by the Investigator Pregnancy or lactation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Asthma</keyword>
	<keyword>patients</keyword>
	<keyword>lung function</keyword>
</DOC>