<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01348789</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To measure the safety of hair removal device when used frequently.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety for Frequent Use Conditions of Hair Removal Device</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary endpoint of this study is to measure the safety of the Hair2Go device when used frequently. The secondary endpoints include the kinetics of the hair clearance up to 8 weeks after the last treatment, and gathering information about the pain associated with the procedure</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Healthy males and females, between 18 and 65 years of age. Willing to sign informed consent. Willing to follow the treatment schedule and post treatment followup. Willingness to have photographs of the treated area taken that may be used for marketing and educational presentation and/or publications Willingness to avoid excessive sun exposure two weeks prior treatments A history of keloidal scarring (hypertrophic scars or keloids). Active dermatologic lesion or infection in the treatment site. Subject has permanent tattoos or makeup in the treatment area. Recently tanned in the area to be treated and/or unable or unlikely to refrain from tanning during the study. Subject has disease related to photosensitivity, such as porphyria, polymorphic light eruption, solar urticaria, lupus, etc Subject has a history of herpes outbreak in the area of treatment, unless receiving preventative treatment from physician Pregnant, planning to become pregnant, hormone fluctuations and/or breast feeding during the experiment. Subjects with Diabetes (Type I or II) or other systemic or metabolic condition Subject has an active electrical implant anywhere in the body, such as a pacemaker, an internal defibrillator, insulin pump, incontinence device, etc. Subject suffers from epilepsy. Subject has active cancer, or has a history of skin cancer or any other cancer in the area to be treated, including presence of malignant or premalignant pigmented lesions. Subject received radiation therapy or chemotherapy treatments with the past 3 months. Subject has known anticoagulative or thromboembolic condition or is on any form of anticoagulation treatment. Subject has a history of immunosuppressant/immune deficiency disorders (including HIV infection or AIDS) or currently using immunosuppressive medications. Subject has any other condition which in the physician's opinion would make it unsafe for the subject to be treated. Subject had rotating type tweezer epilator treatment, or waxing within the last 3 months Subject had electrolysis treatment within the last 6 months over the treatment area. Subject had any type of professional intense pulsed light (IPL), laser or RF hair removal in the treatment site within the last 6 months. Participation in a study of another device or drug within 1 month prior to enrollment or during this study. Subject is taking medication known to induce photosensitivity, including nonsteroidal antiinflammatory agents, tetracyclines, phenothiazines, thiazide diuretics, sulfonylureas, sulfonamides, Dacarbazine (DTIC), fluorouracil, vinblastine, and griseofulvin within 4 weeks of therapy. Subject has been taking Accutane® within 6 months of therapy. Subject has been on steroid regimen during the last three months. Subject is on Gold therapy (for arthritis treatment).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hair removal</keyword>
	<keyword>Hair Clearance</keyword>
	<keyword>Epilation</keyword>
</DOC>