<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01703065</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This pilot clinical trial studies cabozantinib in treating men with castration-resistant prostate cancer. Cabozantinib may stop the growth of tumor cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cabozantinib in Treating Men With Castration-Resistant Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To assess the impact of cabozantinib on markers of bone turnover and microenvironment in men with non-metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer and to compare the findings in men with metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer. SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To describe the associated changes in dynamic histomorphometry at baseline and after 6 weeks of cabozantinib therapy in men with non-metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer. II. To characterize, describe, and compare the effects of cabozantinib in men with non-metastatic and metastatic bone disease with respect to the following measurements at baseline and on therapy: markers of bone metabolism in blood including bone specific alkaline phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, lactate dehydrogenase (LDH); changes in markers of apoptosis, proliferation, and angiogenesis in biopsy specimens from both bone and soft tissue during therapy with cabozantinib. TERTIARY OBJECTIVES: I. Radiographic disease responses and toxicities will be monitored for all patients. OUTLINE: Patients receive cabozantinib orally (PO) once daily (QD) in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up for 4 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key Inclusion Criteria The subject has a proven histologic diagnosis of prostate adenocarcinoma, but may have undergone prior surgery and/or radiation The subject must currently have castration resistant prostate cancer defined as 2 serial rising prostatespecific antigens (PSAs) with a castrate level of testosterone (&lt; 50 ng/dL) A subject with nonmetastatic castrationresistant prostate cancer (CRPC) may not have received prior chemotherapy unless in the neoadjuvant or adjuvant setting &gt; 24 months ago and may not have received prior zoledronic acid or denosumab A subject with metastatic CRPC must have bone metastases accessible for biopsy by computed tomography (CT) guidance The subject must be willing to undergo sequential biopsy of bone or bone metastases Adequate organ and bone marrow function. The subject is capable of understanding and complying with the protocol requirements and has signed the informed consent document Key Exclusion Criteria Prior treatment with cabozantinib and other met inhibitors Cytotoxic chemotherapy or biologic agents within 3 weeks of study treatment Recent radiation therapy (3 months for thoracic cavity, 14 days for bone or brain metastasis, 28 days for other sites) or radionuclide treatment within 6 weeks of starting study drug. The subject has received any other type of investigational agent within 28 days before the first dose of study treatment The subject has not recovered from toxicities due to all prior therapies except alopecia and other nonclinically significant adverse events (AEs) The subject has primary brain tumor or active brain metastases or epidural Coagulation tests need to be adequate for the study The subject requires concomitant treatment, in therapeutic doses, with anticoagulants such as warfarin or warfarinrelated agents, heparin, thrombin or Factor Xa inhibitors, or antiplatelet agents (eg, clopidogrel); low dose aspirin (=&lt; 81 mg/day), lowdose warfarin (=&lt; 1 mg/day), and prophylactic low molecular weight heparin (LMWH) are permitted The subject requires chronic concomitant treatment of strong cytochrome P450, family 3, subfamily A, polypeptide 4 (CYP3A4) inducers (e.g., dexamethasone, phenytoin, carbamazepine, rifampin, rifabutin, rifapentine, phenobarbital, and St. John's Wort) History of clinically significant gastrointestinal bleeding The subject has uncontrolled, significant intercurrent or recent illness The subject is unable to swallow tablets The subject has a corrected QT interval (QTcF) &gt; 500 ms within 28 days before day 1 of cycle 1 The subject has a previously identified allergy or hypersensitivity to components of the study treatment formulation or to tetracycline</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Bone metastases</keyword>
</DOC>