<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01703156</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A large number of patients are diagnosed with low risk ACS, and these individuals are at significant cardiovascular risk. Though guidelines recommend stress testing to manage low risk ACS patients, evidence supporting this recommendation is not based on trials examining this population. A well-designed, randomized trial is warranted to determine if stress testing is useful in managing low risk ACS. If medical therapy alone is equivalent as the investigators hypothesize, healthcare expenditures could be reduced and patients may not be exposed to the harms associated with more invasive cardiac testing such as coronary angiography.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Low Risk Acute Coronary Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Coronary Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium Channel Blockers</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. TIMI score &lt; or = to 2(12) 2. TIMI risk score of 3 with no known CAD, greater than 50% in one or more vessels 3. Normal cardiac biomarkers (3 sets over 1288 hours) 4. No evidence of acute ischemia on electrocardiograms 5. Normal ejection fraction (&gt;40%) on echocardiography 6. Age 3075 7. Ability to complete noninvasive stress test 8. Ability to provide informed consent 1. Presence of another medical condition to explain chest pain or noncardiac chest pain (i.e. pneumonia, costochondritis) 2. Any patient who is initially classified as low risk but whom develops recurrent symptoms of ischemia, hemodynamic instability, or arrhythmias attributable to ischemia 3. Evidence of ischemia on electrocardiogram 4. Abnormal cardiac biomarkers 5. History of medical noncompliance or social circumstances preventing compliance 6. Life span estimated at &lt;1 year 7. Pregnancy 8. Refusal to sign consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Low Risk ACS, Acute Coronary Syndrome, Stress Testing, Non-Stress Testing</keyword>
</DOC>