<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01703117</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Cognitive aging is a major source of disability in an increasingly aging population. The paucity of effective treatments for cognitive aging disorders, and most importantly in Alzheimer's disease instigates a need for further research into novel therapeutic possibilities. Alzheimer's disease is the most common neurodegenerative disorder and its prevalence steeply increases. Glutamate-mediated excitotoxicity in neuropsychiatric disorders and in particular in Alzheimer's disease has been shown to cause significant cerebral damage. Early effective therapeutic intervention in Alzheimer's disease is critical in order to prevent or at least retard neuropathological progression that will lead to widespread irreversible neuronal loss and significant cognitive dysfunction. Riluzole, a glutamate modulator agent that is a proven safe medication and has not yet been used in cognitive aging disorders, will be tested in mild Alzheimer's disease patients. Cognitive functional changes along with two established in vivo biomarkers, namely, Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopy (MRS) and Fluorodeoxyglucose (18F) positron emission tomography (FDG-PET) will be evaluated.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Riluzole in Mild Alzheimer's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A double-blinded, randomized, placebo-controlled study will be performed. Forty-eight individuals with a diagnosis of mild Alzheimer's disease between 60-85 years old will complete the study. There will be two cohorts of 60-75 and 75-85 years old that will be age-matched. All forty-eight individuals will have been on donepezil, which is FDA approved for the treatment of Alzheimer's disease, at a dose of 5mg or 10mg per day for at least 3 months prior to consenting and will remain on the drug throughout this study. Twenty-four mild Alzheimer's disease patients will receive riluzole and another 24 will receive a placebo (the placebo tablets will be generated at the Rockefeller University's pharmacy by the research pharmacist). All patients will have a neurological evaluation and neuropsychological tests performed to confirm that they meet criteria for probable Alzheimer's disease set out by the National Institute on Aging - Alzheimer's disease Association that recently revisited the NINCDS-ADRDA criteria and to have mild Alzheimer's disease.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Riluzole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female; 60 85 years old with mild Alzheimer's disease determined after neurological and neuropsychological evaluation following the National Institute on Aging Alzheimer's disease Association criteria that recently revisited the NINCDSADRDA criteria. For mild Alzheimer's disease, Clinical Dementia Ratings Scale (CDR) should be 0.5 or 1 and Mini Mental State Examination (MMSS) between 19 and 27. Must be on donepezil (Aricept速) or rivastigmine (Exelon速) or galantamine (Razadyne速) at a consistent dose for at least 2 months. Must be fluent in English The subject will appoint or have previously appointed a health care proxy specifically designated for research consent and that this be documented. ModerateSevere Alzheimer's disease and other dementias as determined by neuropsychological testing and neurological evaluation. Previous riluzole treatment. MRI contraindication (severe claustrophobia, metal implants, shunts, pacemaker, joint implants, metal valves). Currently taking medications that either have evidence of glutamatergic activity or has previous MRS evidence of effects on brain glutamate levels at the discretion of the PI such as memantine, lamotrigine, lithium, opiates, bupropion, psychostimulants such as amphetamines and methylphenidate, tricyclic antidepressants, benzodiazepines and any other drug that the investigators judge might interfere with the study. (subjects on those medications may still be included in the study however only the values of NAA from MRS will be utilized and not the glutamate measurements). Currently a user of the following illicit drugs: cocaine, methylenedioxymethamphetamine (MDMA) ("ecstasy"), heroin and other opioids (as verified by urine drug test) or has a history of drug or alcohol abuse within the past 5 years. Serum creatinine &gt;1.5 times the upper limit of normal. Abnormal liver function test (greater than 2 times the upper limit of normal for alanine aminotransferase (ALT) or aspartate aminotransferase (AST); or bilirubin &gt;1.5 times the upper limit of normal. History of brain disease including Parkinson's Disease, severe brain trauma, seizures, history of stroke,clinically significant lacunar infarct in a region important for cognition or multiple lacunes or a cortical infarct or focal lesions of clinical significance, multiple sclerosis, mental retardation, normal pressure hydrocephalus, central nervous system (CNS) tumor, Huntington's disease, subdural hematoma or other serious neurological disorder. Uncontrolled diabetes mellitus (Hba1c higher than 7) or chronically uncontrolled hypertension. Subject must not be taking Namenda速 (memantine) for at least 2 months. Currently taking any concomitant hepatotoxic drugs such as allopurinol, methyldopa and sulfasalazine. Any unstable serious coexisting medical condition(s) including but not limited to myocardial infarction, coronary artery disease requiring coronary bypass surgery, unstable angina, clinically evident congestive heart failure within 6 months prior to the screening visit. Current smoker or user of nicotinecontaining products, such as chewing tobacco, nicotine patch or gum for the past 2 months. Current major depression defined by Hamilton Psychiatric Rating Scale &gt;18. Participation in any investigational or marketed drug or device trial within 30 days prior to the screening visit. Significant neuropsychiatric illnesses such as bipolar disorder, schizophrenia, moderatesevere anxiety, vascular dementia, CreutzfeldtJakob dementia, HIV dementia, and dementia in other specified diseases. Subjects who have been on donepezil for longer than 5 years. Weight&gt; 300 pounds. Lactose intolerance. Any medical or social condition that, in the opinion of the Investigator, might pose additional risk to the participant or confound the results of the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Alzheimer's Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Dementia</keyword>
</DOC>