<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00421109</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of the study is to evaluate the efficacy and tolerability of Bilastine 20 mg Q.D., compared to Levocetirizine 5 mg Q.D. and placebo for the treatment of Chronic Idiopathic Urticaria.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy Study for the Symptomatic Treatment of Chronic Idiopathic Urticaria</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A total of 540 patients with CIU will be enrolled in this pivotal, randomised, multicentre, international, double-blind, placebo and active-comparator controlled, parallel study . Patients will be selected from both public and private clinical practices. The study population includes males and females between 18 and 70 years of age, suffering from CIU for at least 6 weeks prior to entry in the study with no identifiable cause.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Urticaria</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levocetirizine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cetirizine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>18 to 70 years old. Documented history of CIU for at least 6 weeks prior to entry in the study. Dermatological pathology other than chronic idiopathic urticaria. History of autoimmune disorders, Hodgkin's disease, lymphoma, leukemia and generalized cancer. Pregnant or breastfeeding women. Patients who will be operating heavy machinery or need to drive motor vehicles as an essential part of their profession. Patients who have a recent history (within previous 12 months) of drug addiction or alcohol abuse. Patients who are currently participating in or have participated in another clinical trial within the last 3 months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Urticaria</keyword>
	<keyword>Hives</keyword>
	<keyword>Wheals</keyword>
	<keyword>Flare</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic</keyword>
	<keyword>Idiopathic</keyword>
	<keyword>Erythema</keyword>
	<keyword>Skin diseases, vascular</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypersensitivity, Immediate</keyword>
	<keyword>Allergic</keyword>
	<keyword>Cutaneous</keyword>
</DOC>