<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01581177</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main objective of this study is to evaluate the efficacy, dose-ranging and initial safety profiles of A006, an Albuterol dry powder inhaler (DPI), in the dose range of 25 to 180 mcg per dosing in comparison to a DPI Placebo Control and an Albuterol metered dose inhaler (MDI) Active Control. This study will be conducted in male and female adult patients who have mild-to-moderate persistent asthma for at least 6 months, but are otherwise generally healthy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Albuterol DPI (A006) Clinical Study-B2: Efficacy, Dose-Ranging and Initial Safety Evaluation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The main objective of this study is to evaluate the efficacy, dose-ranging and initial safety profiles of A006, an Albuterol dry powder inhaler (DPI), in the dose range of 25 to 180 mcg per dose in comparison to the DPI Placebo Control and the Active (Reference) Control. The study results of this study together with that of A006-B study will be utilized to determine the optimum final dose range of A006 for further clinical studies. The study will be conducted in male and female adult patients who have mild-to-moderate persistent asthma but are otherwise generally healthy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albuterol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Generally healthy, male and female adults, 1855 years of age at screening With mildtomoderate persistent asthma for at least 6 months prior to screening and having used a betaagonist(s) inhaler Demonstrate a Forced Expiratory Volume (FEV1) at 5085 percent of predicted normal during screening baseline measurement Demonstrate an airway reversibility of greater than or equal to 15 percent within 30 minutes of inhaling 2 inhalations of Proventil MDI during screening visit Demonstrate Peak Inspiratory Flow Rate (PIF) within 80150 L/min (after training), at least 2 times consecutively Demonstrate ability to use a DPI and MDI inhaler properly after training Females must be not pregnant, not lactating, and using a clinically acceptable form of birth control Properly agree to participate in the trial A smoking history of more than or equal to 10 years or having smoked within 6 months of screening visit Upper respiratory tract infections within 2 weeks or lower respiratory tract infection within 4 weeks prior to screening visit Asthma exacerbations that required emergency care or a hospital stay within 4 weeks prior to screening visit Any current or recent respiratory tract infections that might affect the response to the study drug as determined by the investigator, including cystic fibrosis, bronchiectasis, tuberculosis, emphysema and other significant respiratory diseases besides asthma Current clinically significant cardiovascular, hematological, renal, neurologic, hepatic, endocrine, psychiatric, malignant or other illnesses that could impact the study as determined by the investigator Known intolerance or hypersensitivity to any ingredients of the study drug DPI or Proventil MDI (i.e.: Albuterol, sulfate, lactose, milk protein, HFA134a, oleic acid and ethanol)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>asthma</keyword>
	<keyword>mild-to-moderate persistent asthma</keyword>
	<keyword>mild asthma</keyword>
	<keyword>moderate asthma</keyword>
	<keyword>persistent asthma</keyword>
</DOC>