<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01464983</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the efficacy and tolerability of 500 mg and 1000 mg Aspirin® (study medication) by comparing it to placebo (the control group without active substance) or 200 mg or 400 mg Ibuprofen (study medication) in treating the symptoms of episodic tension-type headache. The study is designed to develop a treatment method against episodic tension-type headache which will have more advantages for patients than the methods that are currently available.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Placebo and Active Controlled, Double Dummy Study to Compare Efficacy of Aspirin and Ibuprofen in Treatment of Episodic Tension-type Headache</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Headache</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tension-Type Headache</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aspirin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ibuprofen</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Ambulatory male or female, 18 to 65 years of age Normal blood pressure Patients suffering from episodic tensiontype headache Headache lasting from 30 minutes to 7 days Headache had at least two of the following characteristics: Bilateral location. Pressing/tightening (nonpulsating). Mild or moderate intensity. Not aggravated by routine physical activity such as walking or climbing stairs. Both of the following: No nausea or vomiting. No more than one of photophobia or phonophobia. Other headaches, including migraine, that required medical treatment Hypersensitivity to acetylsalicylic acid, salicylates, ibuprofen or other nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) Serious physical illness especially uncontrolled disorders of kidney, liver, lung, heart or brain function, neurological disorders or severe chronic or terminal disease Mental illness, including depression Needed or were using or likely to need or use any of the prohibited concomitant medications: antidepressants, oxicams Pregnant or lactating women, or sexually active women of childbearing potential unless using effective contraception Participating in any other clinical study or had done within the previous 4 weeks Had been previously enrolled in this study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>