<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03046173</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To investigate the effects of concentrated growth factors applied in maxillary sinus floor elevation via a lateral window approach with simultaneous implant placement on repair of bone defects and new bone formation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Concentrated Growth Factors Applied in Maxillary Sinus Floor Elevation Via a Lateral Window Approach</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Maxillary sinus floor elevation via a lateral window approach is the most effective method of overcoming the shortage of bone mass deficiency in atrophic maxillary posterior region. Bone transplantation is considered to be a prerequisite for the success of maxillary sinus floor elevation. Platelet-rich plasma and platelet-rich fibrin have been used to accelerate bone formation, regeneration, and repair. However, few in-depth studies are reported on the effects of concentrated growth factors on new bone formation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Mitogens</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Loss of one or more maxillary molars in the posterior maxillary region Occlusogingival distance of &gt; 4 mm Residual bone height of 25 mm in the posterior maxillary region, no obvious maxillary sinus separation No problems with the lungs, heart, or brain Normal liver and kidney function Normal coagulation function Adequate prosthetic space No history of bruxism or temporomandibular joint disorders No tumors, cysts and polyps in maxillary sinus No acute or chronic maxillary sinusitis No acute periodontitis No oral mucosal disease Age 2045 years Able to tolerate the stress of anesthesia and surgery Residual bone height of &lt; 1 mm in the posterior maxillary region or presence of maxillary sinus mucosa rupture Poor control of complex periodontal disease Local inflammation or poor oral hygiene Poorly treated maxillary disease With severe bruxism With temporomandibular joint disorders Alcohol consumption and cigarette smoking (20 cigarettes/d) Have a history of chemotherapy and radiation therapy in face and neck Pregnant With coagulation disorders With autoimmune disease With severe osteoporosis With acute maxillary sinusitis Unable to tolerate simple surgery because of systemic diseases including severe diabetes mellitus and heart disease Unable to provide informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>