<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03046550</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study evaluates the safety and pharmacokinetics of NTM-1634 in healthy subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Evaluate Safety and PK of NTM-1634 vs Placebo Administered Intravenously in Healthy Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>NTM-1634 drug product is a mixture of four human monoclonal IgG1 antibodies (XC41, XC42, XC44, and XC84) which bind to non-overlapping epitopes on BoNT/C/D. This study is a randomized, double-blind, placebo controlled dose escalation study of three dose cohorts. Cohort A: 0.33mg/kg; B: 0.66mg/kg; and C: 1 mg/kg.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>1. Informed consent understood and signed 2. Healthy male or healthy, nonpregnant, nonlactating female 3. Willingness to comply and be available for all protocol procedures including inpatient confinement for 36 48 hours 4. Age between 18 and 45 years, inclusive on the day of infusion 5. Body Mass Index (BMI) of ≥18.5 and ≤30 kg/m2 6. If the subject is female and of childbearing potential, she has a negative urine pregnancy test at screening and negative serum test within 24 hours prior to infusion Note: A woman is considered of childbearing potential unless postmenopausal (≥ 1 year without menses) or surgically sterilized via bilateral oophorectomy, or hysterectomy or bilateral tubal ligation or successful Essure placement with documented confirmation test at least 3 months after the procedure. 7. If the subject is female and of childbearing potential, she agrees to practice abstinence from sexual intercourse with men or use acceptable contraception up to visit 12 of the study Note: Acceptable contraception methods are restricted to effective devices (Intrauterine Contraceptive Devices , NuvaRing®) 8. The hemoglobin, platelet count, white blood cell count and absolute neutrophil count are within normal limits 9. The urine dipstick results on protein, glucose and blood are negative or trace Note: Menstruating females failing inclusion criteria due to a positive blood on urine dipstick may be retested following cessation of menses. 10. Chemistry screening laboratory tests as outlined in Section 7.5.1.4 are in the normal reference range Note: The following exceptions to laboratory normal reference ranges are allowed: Creatinine, Blood Urea Nitrogen (BUN), total bilirubin, AST, ALT, lipase, amylase, Prothrombin Time (PT), Partial Thromboplastin Time (PTT) below the lower limit of normal (LLN); CK less than 400mg/ml; Glucose, potassium, total protein, and alkaline phosphatase with a toxicity grade of 1 is allowable; albumin above the upper limit of normal (ULN). Laboratory values that are outside the range of eligibility but are thought to be due to an acute condition or due to laboratory error may be repeated once. Abnormalities in mean corpuscular volume (MCV), mean corpuscular hemoglobin (MCH), mean corpuscular hemoglobin concentration (MCHC), red cell distribution width (RDW), mean platelet volume (MPV), and nucleated red blood cell count (NRBC CT), which are included in a complete blood count with differential, will not be exclusions. 11. Has adequate venous access for the infusion 12. The urine drug screen is negative 13. Breathalyzer test is negative 14. Available for followup for the duration of the study 15. Agrees not to participate in vigorous activity 72 hours prior to dosing through day 15 post dosing 1. History of a chronic medical condition that would either interfere with the accurate assessment of the objectives of the study or increase the risk profile of the subject. Note: Chronic medical conditions include diabetes; Asthma requiring use of medication in the year before screening; Autoimmune disorder such as lupus, Wegener's, rheumatoid arthritis, thyroid disease; Coronary artery disease; Chronic hypertension; History of malignancy except lowgrade (squamous and basal cell) skin cancer thought to be cured; chronic renal, hepatic, pulmonary, or endocrine disease (except previous asthma which has required no treatment for the past year); 2. History of severe allergic reaction of any type to medications, bee stings, food, or environmental factors or hypersensitivity or reaction to immunoglobulins. Note: Severe allergic reaction is defined as any of the following: anaphylaxis, urticaria, or angioedema 3. A marked baseline prolongation of QT/QTc interval (e.g., repeated demonstration of a QTc interval &gt;450 milliseconds) 4. Clinically significant abnormal electrocardiogram at screening. Note: Clinically significant abnormal ECG results include: complete left or right bundle branch block; other ventricular conduction block; 2nd degree or 3rd degree atrioventricular (AV) block; sustained ventricular arrhythmia; sustained atrial arrhythmia; two Premature Ventricular Contractions in a row; pattern of ST elevation felt consistent with cardiac ischemia; or any condition deemed clinically significant by a study investigator 5. Positive serology results for HIV, HBsAg, or HCV antibodies 6. Febrile illness with temperature ≥38°C within 7 days of dosing 7. Pregnant or breastfeeding 8. Donated blood within 56 days of enrollment 9. Known allergic reactions to any of the study product components present in the formulation or in the processing, as listed in the Investigator Brochure 10. Treatment with another investigational drug within 28 days of dosing 11. Treatment with a monoclonal antibody at any time 12. Receipt of antibody (e.g. TIG, VZIG, IVIG, IM gamma globulin) or blood transfusion within 6 months or within 5 halflives of the specific product given 13. Active drug or alcohol use or dependence that, in the opinion of the investigator, would interfere with adherence to study requirements 14. Use of H1 antihistamines or betablockers within 5 days of dosing 15. Use of any prohibited medication within 28 days prior to study entry or planned use during the study period Note: Prohibited medications include immunosuppressives (except Nonsteroidal AntiInflammatory Drugs [NSAIDS]); immune modulators; oral corticosteroids (topical/intranasal steroids are acceptable); antineoplastic agents; any vaccine (licensed or investigational) 16. Previous exposure to botulinum toxin, receipt of antibodies against botulinum toxin, or previous treatment with equine antitoxin 17. Any previous injection or planned injection within 4 months after enrollment of botulinum toxin for cosmetic reasons, spastic dysphonia, torticollis, or any other reason 18. Any specific condition that in the judgment of the investigator precludes participation because it could affect subject safety 19. Plans to enroll or is already enrolled in another clinical trial* that could interfere with safety assessment of the investigational product at any time during the study period Note: Includes trials that have a study intervention such as a drug, biologic, or device 20. Is a study site employee or staff Note: Site employees or staff include the PIs and subinvestigators or staff who are supervised by the PI or SubInvestigators 21. Systolic blood pressure &gt;140mm Hg or diastolic blood pressure &gt;90 mm Hg 22. Resting hear rate &lt;50 or &gt;100 beats per minute 23. Oral temperature ≥ 38°C (100.4°F)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>48 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>