<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02691507</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this 1 week trial is to evaluate the efficacy of an over-the-counter (OTC) 1% colloidal oatmeal skin protectant cream in adults and children with mild to moderate AD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Trial to Determine the Therapeutic Benefit of an OTC Cream on Dry, Itchy Skin of Adults and Children With Eczema</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Approximately 60 subjects will be enrolled to ensure 52 subjects complete the study (39 subjects: active treatment and 13 subjects: positive control). Adults and children (ages 12 and over) will receive either a marketed or not yet marketed investigational product for the treatment of eczema. Subjects will be asked to stop use of prescription and all eczema treatments 2 days before the start of the study and during the study. Subjects will apply study product as indicated for 7 days to affected areas. Subjects will record treatment use in a daily diary and complete questionnaires. A dermatologist will examine and score the eczema and symptoms. Skin moisture levels will also be tested.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dermatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dermatitis, Atopic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eczema</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pruritus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Decanoic acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Able to comprehend and follow the requirements of the study (including availability on scheduled visit dates) 2. Male or female of any race or ethnicity, ages 12 and older 3. Diagnosed as having eczema 4. Willing to stop use of all nonassigned moisturizers and/or creams for the entire duration of the study 1. Known sensitivity to any investigational product ingredient 2. Females who are pregnant , breastfeeding , or planning on becoming pregnant during the study 3. Individuals with a history of skin cancer 4. Use of a therapeutic (overthecounter or prescription) body wash that contains an active ingredient for eczema 5. Participation in any clinical study within 30 days of Visit 1 6. Active infection of any type at the start of the study 7. Diagnosed as having severe eczema 8. Has a compromised immune system 9. Individuals with any planned surgeries and/or invasive medical procedures during the course of the study 10. Requires greater than 2.0mg/day inhaled or intranasal corticosteroids</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Eczema, Itchy Skin</keyword>
</DOC>