<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00478699</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Randomized Study of Customized Adjuvant Chemotherapy based on BRCA1 mRNA Levels in Completely Resected stages II-IIIA Non-Small-Cell Lung Cancer Patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Randomized Customized Adjuvant Chemotherapy (GECP-SCAT)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Randomized, phase III, predictive pharmacogenomic, open, prospective, international, multicenter study in patients with non-small-cell lung carcinoma (NSCLC) after complete resection and with N1 or N2 involvement</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with histological confirmation of nonsmallcell lung carcinoma. Complete surgical resection of the disease. Tumoral tissue available for molecular analysis. N1 (stage II) or N2 (stage IIIA) lymph node involvement in the study of the operative piece. Men or women age 18 years or older. Patients with a performance status of 2 or less according to the ECOG classification. Patients with the following laboratory results: ANC &lt; 1500/L, Hb &lt; 10 g/dL, platelets &lt;100,000/L, bilirubin &lt; 1.0 mg/dL, AST and ALT &lt; 1.5 upper limit of normality, creatinine clearance &lt; 60 mL/min. Complete recovery from surgery within 6 weeks. Patients who have given written informed consent before initiating any specific study screening procedure. Patients who have received previously chemotherapy or radiotherapy for the study disease. Impossibility of complying with chemotherapy treatment due to cultural or geographic circumstances. Patients with active infection, heart disease, or any other serious disease, in the judgment of the investigator. Women who are pregnant or in the period of lactation. Patients with a previous diagnosis of malignant disease in the last five years except for carcinoma in situ of the uterine cervix or skin cancer other than melanoma. Patients under treatment with investigational agents.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>SCAT</keyword>
	<keyword>BRCA1</keyword>
	<keyword>BRCA1 mRNA Levels</keyword>
	<keyword>ADJUVANT</keyword>
	<keyword>LUNG</keyword>
	<keyword>GECP-SCAT</keyword>
</DOC>