<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01472016</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase 1/1b open-label study evaluating the safety, pharmacokinetics (PK), and preliminary efficacy of ABT-700 in subjects with advanced solid tumors that may have MET amplification or c-Met overexpression. ABT-700, previously known as h224G11 in publications, is an anti-c-Met antibody. The early clinical development plan for ABT-700 is based on the activity demonstrated in preclinical models. Up to 124 subjects will be enrolled.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of ABT-700 in Subjects With Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cetuximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erlotinib Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject with advanced solid tumors; Doseexpansion: evidence for MET gene amplification. Subject must have disease: a) that is not amenable to surgical resection, or b) that has progressed or recurred despite standard therapy, or c) that has failed to respond to standard therapy, or d) for which no effective therapy exists. Subject cannot tolerate or must not be eligible for other approved therapeutic options with known survival advantage. Subjects enrolled on the combination therapy phase must satisfy the above inclusion criteria and also the following: Subjects must have inoperable, locally advanced or metastatic cancer and be eligible to receive docetaxel or FOLFIRI/cetuximab or erlotinib in combination with ABT700. Subject has received anticancer therapy including chemotherapy, immunotherapy, radiation therapy, immunotherapy, biologic, or any investigational therapy within a period of 21 days, or herbal therapy within 7 days prior to the first dose of ABT700. Subjects with uncontrolled metastases of the central nervous system. Subjects with brain metastases are eligible provided they have shown clinical and radiographic stable disease after definitive therapy and have not used steroids for at least 1 month prior to first dose of ABT700. Subject has unresolved adverse events &gt; Grade 1 from prior anticancer therapy except for alopecia or anemia. Subject has had major surgery within 21 days prior to the first dose of ABT700. Subjects enrolled on the combination therapy phase must not meet the above exclusion criteria and must be eligible to receive docetaxel or FOLFIRI/cetuximab or erlotinib per most current prescribing information, or at the discretion of the Investigator. Subjects with KRas mutationpositive colorectal cancer will be excluded from receiving FOLFIRI/cetuximab.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>c-Met overexpression</keyword>
	<keyword>MET amplification</keyword>
	<keyword>Neoplasms</keyword>
	<keyword>h224G11</keyword>
</DOC>