<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01472003</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an open label study designed to evaluate the biodistribution and imaging characteristics of ABT-806i (111In-ABT-806) in subjects with advanced solid tumor types.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An Evaluation of the Biodistribution and Imaging Characteristics of ABT-806i (111In-ABT-806) in Subjects With Advanced Solid Tumor Types</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Subject has a solid tumor of a type likely or known to either overexpress wildtype Epidermal Growth Factor Receptor (EGFR) or to express variant III mutant EGFR (e.g., head and neck squamous cell carcinoma, Nonsmall Cell Lung Carcinoma (NSCLC), and colorectal carcinoma). Subject must have disease that is not amenable to surgical resection or other approved therapeutic options with curative intent. Subject cannot tolerate or must not be eligible for other approved therapeutic options with known survival advantage. Subject has an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status of 0 to 2. Subject must have measurable disease as defined by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) version 1.1 with at least 1 extrahepatic 2 cm lesion. Subject has received anticancer therapy including chemotherapy, immunotherapy, radiotherapy, hormonal, biologic, or any investigational therapy within a period of 14 days prior to the first dose of ABT806i. Subject has received a prior EGFRdirected monoclonal antibody within a period of 4 weeks prior to the first dose of ABT806i. Subject has unresolved clinically significant toxicities from prior anticancer therapy, defined as any Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) Grade 2 or higher. Subject has had major surgery within 21 days prior to the first dose of ABT806i. Subject has a clinically significant uncontrolled condition(s) including but not limited to the following: Active uncontrolled infection Symptomatic congestive heart failure Unstable angina pectoris or cardiac arrhythmia Psychiatric illness/social situation that would limit compliance with the study requirements</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>