<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02642354</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will investigate performance criteria over one week of daily wear to determine if the Study Test contact lens performs equivalently to the comfilcon A contact lenses in terms of measurement and subjective ratings of visual performance.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>One Week Assessment of a Lens With a Novel Optical Profile</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is a prospective, single site, daily wear, double masked, randomized bilateral cross over dispensing study of binocular wear of Study Test Lens and comfilcon A sphere contact lenses over 1 week of daily wear. Assessments will be obtained upon dispensing each lens pair and following 1 week of daily lens use.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>A person is eligible for inclusion in the study if he/she: Oculovisual examination in the last two years Between 18 and 35 years of age and has full legal capacity to volunteer Has read and understood the informed consent letter Is willing and able to follow instructions and maintain the appointment schedule Is correctable to a visual acuity of 20/25 or better (in each eye) with their habitual correction or 20/20 best corrected Currently wears, or has previously successfully worn, soft contact lenses between 1.00D (Diopter) and 4.00D Spherical Contact Lens Rx between 1.00 and 4.00 and spectacle cylinder &lt;0.75 Has not worn lenses for at least 12 hours before the initial visit Has a subjective response at baseline, which indicates suitability for this study Currently spends a minimum of 4 hours a day; 5 days a week on digital devices and can replicate this time during the study period Is willing and able to wear the study contact lenses a minimum of 10 hours per day; 5 days a week. A person will be excluded from the study if he/she: Has never worn contact lenses before Any systemic disease affecting ocular health Is using any systemic or topical medications that will affect ocular health Has known sensitivity to the diagnostic pharmaceuticals or study products used in this study. Has any ocular pathology or anomaly that would affect the wearing of the lenses Has persistent, clinically significant corneal or conjunctival staining using sodium fluorescein dye Is aphakic Has anisometropia of &gt;1.00 Has undergone corneal refractive surgery Has strabismus Has any ocular amblyopia &gt;= 1 line of HC (High Contrast) Visual Acuity Is participating in any other type of eye related clinical or research study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>