<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02642107</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Currently, most protocols of nasopharyngeal carcinoma(NPC) of various research bodies such as the Radiation Therapy Oncology Group require routine elective irradiation to the retropharyngeal area and to levels II-V, and also to the supraclavicular lymph nodal areas regardless of the status of nodal metastasis. Previous studies had confirmed that the pattern of cervical lymph node metastasis in NPC followed an orderly manner. Retropharyngeal lymph nodes (RLNs) and Level II LNs were the most commonly involved, followed by Level III and Level V LNs, Level IV LNs, and SCF LNs, and the incidence of LN skip metastasis is rare, ranging from 0.5% to 7.9%. It was rare for NPC patients without neck lymph node metastases to experience neck failure after elective irradiation to levels II, III and VA. It also confirmed that with unilateral LN metastases of higher-level LNs usually spread down ipsilateral LNs.Thus, the investigators conduct the non-inferior randomized trial to determine the value of elective neck irradiation in NPC with N0-N1.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Individualized Elective Neck Irradiation Based on MRI in NPC Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Currently, most protocols of nasopharyngeal carcinoma(NPC) of various research bodies such as the Radiation Therapy Oncology Group require routine elective irradiation to the retropharyngeal area and to levels II-V, and also to the supraclavicular lymph nodal areas regardless of the status of nodal metastasis. Previous studies had confirmed that the pattern of cervical lymph node metastasis in NPC followed an orderly manner. Retropharyngeal lymph nodes (RLNs) and Level II LNs were the most commonly involved, followed by Level III and Level V LNs, Level IV LNs, and SCF LNs, and the incidence of LN skip metastasis is rare, ranging from 0.5% to 7.9%. It was rare for NPC patients without neck lymph node metastases to experience neck failure after elective irradiation to levels II, III and VA. It also confirmed that with unilateral LN metastases of higher-level LNs usually spread down ipsilateral LNs.Thus, the investigators conduct the non-inferior randomized trial to determine the value of elective neck irradiation in NPC with N0-N1.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nasopharyngeal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with newly histologically confirmed nonkeratinizing carcinoma (according to WHO histological type) Tumor staged as T14N0/N1(according to the 7th AJCC edition staging system) No evidence of distant metastasis (M0) Performance status: KPS &gt; 70 Written informed consent Age &gt; 65 or &lt; 18 Treatment with palliative intent Prior malignancy (except adequately treated carcinoma insitu of the cervix or basal/squamous cell carcinoma of the skin) Pregnancy or lactation (consider pregnancy test in women of childbearing age and emphasize effective contraception during the treatment period) History of previous RT (except for nonmelanomatous skin cancers outside intended RT treatment volume) Prior chemotherapy or surgery (except diagnostic) to primary tumor or nodes Any severe intercurrent disease, which may bring unacceptable risk or affect the compliance of the trial, for example, unstable cardiac disease requiring treatment, renal disease, chronic hepatitis, diabetes with poor control (fasting plasma glucose &gt; 1.5×ULN), and emotional disturbance</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>nasopharyngeal carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>elective neck irradiation</keyword>
</DOC>