<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00001991</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To facilitate provision of atovaquone (566C80) to patients who have mild to moderate Pneumocystis carinii pneumonia (PCP) and are intolerant and/or unresponsive to trimethoprim / sulfamethoxazole (TMP / SMX ); to monitor serious adverse events attributable to 566C80.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Treatment IND for 566C80 Therapy of Pneumocystis Carinii Pneumonia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia, Pneumocystis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atovaquone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trimethoprim, Sulfamethoxazole Drug Combination</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Patients must have the following: Clinical diagnosis of acute mild to moderate Pneumocystis carinii pneumonia. Doselimiting intolerance to TMP / SMX or inadequate response to TMP / SMX. Willingness and ability to give informed consent. The clinical condition of the patient and appropriate physiologic criteria should be used in evaluating patients for therapy with 566C80. Patients who are rapidly progressing in disease severity or have severe disease as evidenced by sustained tachypnea (e.g., sustained respiratory rate &gt; 30 breaths/minute), rapid deterioration in (Aa)DO2 and chest radiograph may not be appropriate candidates for oral therapy, including 566C80. Therapy with parenteral pentamidine should be undertaken in these cases. Treatment with IV trimetrexate or primaquine / clindamycin should be considered for these patients unless the patient is known to have doselimiting intolerance to these agents. Patients with severe PCP who are intolerant and/or unresponsive to therapy with TMP / SMX and parenteral pentamidine may enroll in the 566C80 openlabel compassionate plea protocol. Exclusion Criteria Patients with the following prior conditions are excluded: History of serious or doselimiting adverse experience during previous 566C80 therapy, thought to be attributable to the drug.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2003</verification_date>
	<keyword>Trimethoprim-Sulfamethoxazole Combination</keyword>
	<keyword>Pneumonia, Pneumocystis carinii</keyword>
	<keyword>Antifungal Agents</keyword>
	<keyword>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>atovaquone</keyword>
</DOC>