<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00001040</DOC>
	<brief_summary>PRIMARY: To determine the efficacy and toxicity of three treatment regimens: saquinavir mesylate (Ro 31-8959) plus zidovudine (AZT) vs. AZT plus zalcitabine (dideoxycytidine; ddC) vs. Ro 31-8959 plus AZT plus ddC. SECONDARY: To investigate the pharmacokinetics and effects on various clinical parameters of the three regimens.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of Ro 31-8959 Plus Zidovudine (AZT) Versus AZT Plus Zalcitabine (ddC) Versus Ro 31-8959 Plus AZT Plus ddC</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Zidovudine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Zalcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Saquinavir</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Prior Medication: Required: At least 4 months total of AZT at some point in the past, alone or in combination with other antiretroviral therapy. Patients must have: HIV seropositivity. Diagnosis of AIDS, ARC, PGL, or asymptomatic infection. CD4 count &gt; 50 to &lt;= 300 cells/mm3. Life expectancy of at least 6 months. Prior AZT therapy. Exclusion Criteria Coexisting Condition: Patients with the following symptoms or conditions are excluded: Acute serious opportunistic infections requiring immediate treatment, including (but not limited to) tuberculosis, CMV, cryptococcal meningitis, disseminated MAC, cerebral toxoplasmosis, and Pneumocystis carinii pneumonia. Known intolerance to Ro 318959, AZT, or ddC. Symptoms suggestive of pancreatitis. Moderate or severe peripheral neuropathy as evidenced by discomfort from numbness, tingling, burning or pain of the extremities or any related symptoms that are accompanied by an objective finding. Visceral Kaposi's sarcoma. Lymphoma that will require therapy within the next 6 months. Transfusion dependence. Concurrent Medication: Excluded: Investigational or antineoplastic agents. Concurrent Treatment: Excluded: Radiotherapy (other than local skin radiotherapy). Transfusions. Prior Medication: Excluded: Any antiretroviral agent (other than AZT) or immunomodulatory therapy within 14 days prior to study entry. Prior treatment with an HIV proteinase inhibitor.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Zalcitabine</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug Therapy, Combination</keyword>
	<keyword>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>AIDS-Related Complex</keyword>
	<keyword>Zidovudine</keyword>
	<keyword>Saquinavir</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV Protease Inhibitors</keyword>
</DOC>