<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00001631</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Blood flows to areas of the heart providing oxygen and fuel to the pumping muscle. Occasionally the arteries providing the fuel can become blocked. This occurs in coronary artery disease. Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) can be used to evaluate the blood flow to different areas of the heart muscle. In this study magnetic resonance imaging will be compared to other diagnostic tests (radionucleotide perfusion studies) capable of measuring blood flow to heart muscle.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Blood Flow in Heart Muscle</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In this pilot study, magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) of myocardial enhancement during first passage of intravenously injected gadolinium contrast will be used to evaluate regional myocardial perfusion in patients with known or suspected coronary artery disease and hypertrophic cardiomyopathy. The MRI results will be compared with conventional radionuclide perfusion studies (ex. dipyridamole thallium). A clinically defined normal group will also be studied without radionuclide correlation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cardiomyopathies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypertrophy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cardiomyopathy, Hypertrophic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>INCLUSION CRITERIA: Ages 18 to 80. Either sex. Capable of giving informed consent. Group 1: Outpatients with known or suspected coronary artery disease with clinical indication for radionuclide perfusion imaging. Group 2: Patients with nonobstructive hypertrophic cardiomyopathy with clinical indication for radionuclide perfusion imaging. Group 3: Normal volunteers. Positive stress thallium or stress sestamibi (i.e., exercise, adenosine, dobutamine or dypiridamole) at the NIH. EXCLUSION CRITERIA: Pregnancy. Unstable angina. Uncontrolled hypertension (SBP greater than 185, DBP greater than 105). Recent myocardial infarction (less than 5 days). 2nd or 3rd degree heart block by ECG. Asthma, emphysema, renal failure, acute medical illness (fever, pneumonia, etc.) or anemia (hct less than 30). Cardiac pacemaker or implantable defibrillator, aneurysm clip, neural stimulator, any type of ear implant, metal in your eye, any implanted device (i.e. insulin pump, drug infusion device) or any metallic foreign body, shrapnel, or bullet.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2003</verification_date>
	<keyword>Gadolinium</keyword>
	<keyword>Ischemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Coronary Artery Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypertrophic Cardiomyopathy</keyword>
	<keyword>Dipyridamole</keyword>
</DOC>