<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00001495</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study examines a 96 hour infusion schedule of irinotecan alternating with 72 hour drug-free intervals in patients with solid tumors in order to determine the maximum tolerated dose of this regimen.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase I Study of Irinotecan (CPT-11) Administered as a Prolonged Infusion in Adult Patients With Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Irinotecan (CPT-11) is a promising camptothecin analogue with activity in solid tumors. In Phase I studies using short intravenous infusion schedules, the predominant drug toxicities have been gastrointestinal, such as diarrhea, and myelosuppression. In animal studies, prolonged infusion schedules followed by short drug-free intervals have resulted in preservation of antitumor activity and decreased drug toxicity. Therefore, we propose to examine a 96 hour infusion schedule of irinotecan alternating with 72 hour drug-free intervals in patients with solid tumors in order to determine the maximum tolerated dose of this regimen. The duration of these treatments will be escalated in our Phase I study until patients are receiving therapy for 2 out of every 3 weeks. Standard Phase I drug toxicity and tumor response information will be monitored and the pharmacokinetics of irinotecan and its active metabolite, SN-38 will also be examined. We will also attempt to monitor the intracellular molecular effects of SN-38 therapy in blood, bone marrow, and, whenever possible, tumor tissue.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Irinotecan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Camptothecin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Recurrent or metastatic cancer, including lymphoma. No leukemia. No active CNS disease. Refractory to all effective therapy OR No effective therapy exists. Measurable disease not required. PRIOR/CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic Therapy: Greater than 4 weeks and recovered from immunotherapy. Chemotherapy: Greater than 4 weeks and recovered from chemotherapy. Previous therapy with irinotecan is permitted. Endocrine Therapy: Not specified. Radiotherapy: Greater than 4 weeks since radiotherapy. Surgery: Recovered from prior surgery. PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 18 and over. Performance status: ECOG 02. Hematopoietic: AGC greater than 1,500. Platelets greater than 100,000. Hepatic: Bilirubin no greater than 1.5 mg/dL. AST no greater than 2 times normal. Renal: Creatinine no greater than 1.5 mg/dL. OTHER: HIV negative. No active infection requiring antibiotics. No concurrent medical illness that would interfere with chemotherapy. No pregnant or nursing women. Adequate contraception required of fertile patients. Imaging/exams for tumor measurement within 28 days prior to registration.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 1999</verification_date>
	<keyword>Camptothecin</keyword>
	<keyword>Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Chemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Natural Products</keyword>
	<keyword>Neoplasms</keyword>
</DOC>