<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00001993</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to determine the preliminary efficacy and tolerability of combining a selected dose of SC-48334 with low-dose AZT in the treatment of symptomatic HIV+ patients with 200 to 500 CD4+ cells/mm3. The secondary objective is to determine the pharmacokinetics and bioavailability of both SC-48334 and AZT, when administered together, in symptomatic HIV+ patients with 200 - 500 CD4+ cells/mm3.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Initial Phase II Efficacy and Safety Study of SC-48334 Administered in Combination With Low-Dose Zidovudine (AZT) to Symptomatic HIV-1 Infected Patients With = or &gt; 200 to = or &lt; 500 CD4+ Cells/mm3</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Zidovudine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Miglustat</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Concurrent Medication: Allowed: Medications for the prophylaxis of opportunistic infections, such as: Aerosolized pentamidine. Trimethoprim/sulfamethoxazole. Nystatin. Clotrimazole. Antimycobacterial agents. Ganciclovir. Topical acyclovir. Patients must have the following: CD4+ cells counts = or &gt; 200 &lt; 500 /cell mm3. For purposes of inclusion the absolute CD4+ cell count must be = or &gt; 200 &lt; 500 cells/mm3 on the first sample and = or &gt; 190 &lt; 510 cells/mm3 on the second sample. Have at least one of the following: Oral candidiasis. Herpes zoster during the last 3 years. Oral hairy leukoplakia during the past three years. Chronic ( &gt; 30 day period), recurrent seborrheic dermatitis, or topical, pruritic folliculitis (itchy bumps). Unintentional weight loss in excess of 10 pounds or 10 percent of usual body weight. Chronic fatigue present for the past 6 months, which has interfered with normal activity at least 1 to 2 times per week. HIV antibody positive as determined by federally licensed Enzymelinked Immunosorbent Assay (ELISA). Documented, written informed consent must be obtained prior to admission to the study. Prior Medication: Allowed for no more than 12 weeks prior to study entry: Zidovudine (AZT). Exclusion Criteria Coexisting Condition: Patients with the following conditions or symptoms are excluded: Malignancies, with the exception of basal cell carcinoma. Significant organ dysfunction. Concurrent Medication: Excluded: All antiretroviral drugs with the exception of Zidovudine. Cancer chemotherapeutic agents. Antimetabolites and alkylating agents. All investigational nonFDA approved drugs. Patients with the following are excluded: Clinically significant diarrhea (&gt; 3 liquid stools per day for &gt; 7 days) without definable cause, within 6 months prior to enrollment). Diarrhea, as above, with known, nonHIV related cause occurring within one month prior to enrollment. Meets CDC criteria for AIDS classification. Chronic fever (&gt; 38.5 C persisting for more than 14 consecutive days, or for more than 15 days in any 30day interval prior to study entry). Malignancies, with the exception of basal cell carcinoma. Significant organ dysfunction. Known hypersensitivity to SC48334 or related compounds. History of lactose intolerance. Prior Medication: Excluded within 30 days of study entry: Any investigational medication. Treatment with a drug (other than Zidovudine) with antiHIV activity. Excluded for &gt; 12 weeks prior to study entry: Zidovudine (AZT). Excluded within 90 days of study entry: Ribavirin. Excluded within 6 months of study entry: Cancer chemotherapy. Excluded: Treatment with SC48334. Prior Treatment: Excluded within 30 days of study entry: Electron beam radiation. Excluded within 6 months prior to study entry: Required HIVrelated blood transfusions. Whole body radiation. Current use of illicit substances; or current abuse of alcohol, the use of which would limit compliance with the protocol.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 1992</verification_date>
	<keyword>Drug Therapy, Combination</keyword>
	<keyword>Zidovudine</keyword>
</DOC>