<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00001627</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is designed to provide bone marrow and/or blood cells for other research studies. Patients participating in this study will be asked to provide small amounts of medical information and undergo a limited physical examination designed to detect the presence of any obvious blood disease. A blood and bone marrow sample will be obtained to verify that the patient has normal blood cell production. Researchers plan to obtain bone marrow samples to be used in laboratory studies directed toward understanding the formation of blood cells. Bone marrow samples will be taken from the hip bone of patients and healthy volunteers. These samples are valuable to many research studies within the Hematology Branch of the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, including studies of normal and abnormal production of blood cells, the viral causes of blood diseases, and the role of the immune system in bone marrow failure and related conditions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Collection of Blood and Bone Marrow From Healthy Volunteers and Patients for Research Purposes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This protocol defines in general terms the purposes for which blood and bone marrow specimens will be collected by members of the Hematology Branch and the conditions under which the sampling will be performed. Samples of blood and bone marrow from healthy volunteers and from patients are indispensable for many research projects, including studies of normal and abnormal hematopoiesis, the viral etiology of blood diseases, and the role of the immune system in marrow failure and related conditions.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myelodysplastic Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Preleukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anemia, Aplastic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hematologic Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fanconi Anemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fanconi Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>INCLUSION CRITERIA: Healthy volunteers age greater than or equal to 18 years. Subjects with hematologic disease age greater than or equal to 2 (for subjects less than 18, blood and bone marrow specimens will be obtained concurrently with clinically indicated sampling). EXCLUSION CRITERIA: History of a significant bleeding disorder. Abnormal hostdefense mechanisms.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 16, 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Bone Marrow</keyword>
	<keyword>Hematopoiesis</keyword>
	<keyword>DNA</keyword>
	<keyword>RNA</keyword>
	<keyword>Viruses</keyword>
	<keyword>Normal Volunteer</keyword>
	<keyword>Aplastic Anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Myelodysplasia</keyword>
	<keyword>Fanconi's Anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Single Lineage Cytopenia</keyword>
</DOC>