<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00001788</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate patients with primary immunodeficiency disorders to identify patients with mutations of the genes for the following proteins: Jak3, STAT1, STAT4, interleukin-7, interleukin-7 receptor, interleukin-12 receptor subunits, and others. Patients will undergo screening history, physical examination, and clinical laboratory evaluation at referring institutions and tissue samples, or cell lines will be sent to the NIH. We will establish cell lines if necessary, prepare DNA and RNA for molecular genetic analysis and study cytokine signal transduction in patient cell lines.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Genetic Basis of Primary Immunodeficiencies</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to evaluate patients with primary immunodeficiency disorders to identify patients with mutations of the genes for the following proteins: Jak3, STAT1, STAT4, interleukin-7, interleukin-7 receptor, interleukin-12 receptor subunits, and others. Patients will undergo screening history, physical examination, and clinical laboratory evaluation at referring institutions and tissue samples, or cell lines will be sent to the NIH. We will establish cell lines if necessary, prepare DNA and RNA for molecular genetic analysis and study cytokine signal transduction in patient cell lines.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<criteria>INCLUSION CRITERIA: Samples from patients with known or suspected primary immunodeficiencies, including those treated with stem cell transplants or gene correction therapy, and their families will be accepted worldwide primarily from tertiary care centers that treat patients with such immunodeficiencies. Such patients will have documented evidence of either opportunistic infection, recurrent infection, or unusually severe responses to infectious agents that cause mild illness in unaffected individuals. Either patientderived B cell lines or primary blood samples will be accepted although in some cases buccal swabs will also be accepted. Blood samples may be obtained from unaffected children. Infants with SCID or other primary immunodeficiency will not be seen; their physicians will care them for and only clinical material will be sent on such patients. Medically stable patients with mild to moderate immunodeficiency may be seen at the NIH. EXCLUSION CRITERIA: Inability to provide informed consent. A presence of any medical condition that would, in the opinion of the investigators, confuse the interpretation of the study (e.g., HIV infection).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 28, 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cytokine</keyword>
	<keyword>Stat</keyword>
	<keyword>Jak</keyword>
	<keyword>IL-12</keyword>
	<keyword>Mutation</keyword>
	<keyword>Immunodeficiency</keyword>
</DOC>