<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00001174</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study looks to identify genes that may affect a person's chances of developing bipolar disorder (BP) and related conditions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Genetics of Bipolar Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Bipolar affective disorder is a severe, heritable condition affecting about one percent of the population. The mode of inheritance is poorly understood and probably involves multiple loci of small to moderate effect. In this project, we use genetic mapping and sequencing methods to identify genetic markers and variations that contribute to the risk of bipolar disorder. Individuals diagnosed with bipolar disorder are studied, along with their relatives. Phenotypic information obtained from clinical interviews and family history is correlated with genotypic information obtained from genetic marker and sequencing methods. The goal is to identify genes involved in bipolar disorder and related conditions so that better methods of diagnosis, treatment, and prevention can be developed.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bipolar Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mood Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>INCLUSION CRITERIA: Age &gt; 18 yr Able to provide informed consent Diagnosed with bipolar disorder not attributable to substance abuse, neurological disease; or a 1st or 2nd degree relative of an enrolled participant Able to safely provide a blood or saliva sample EXCLUSION CRITERIA: Active alcohol or substance abuse. NIMH employees/staff and their immediate family members will be excluded from the study per NIMH policy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 10, 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Bipolar Manic-Depressive Illness</keyword>
	<keyword>Affective Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Depression</keyword>
	<keyword>Genetic</keyword>
	<keyword>DNA</keyword>
	<keyword>Mania</keyword>
	<keyword>Affected Sibling Pairs</keyword>
	<keyword>Family Study</keyword>
	<keyword>Genome-Wide Scan</keyword>
	<keyword>Lymphoblastoid Cell Lines</keyword>
	<keyword>Diagnostic Interview for Genetic Studies (DIGS)</keyword>
	<keyword>Panic Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Bipolar Disorder</keyword>
</DOC>