<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="70248">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02191267</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2014P000035</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02191267</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Tau Imaging of Chronic Traumatic Encephalopathy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Tau Imaging of Chronic Traumatic Encephalopathy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Marcelo F. Di Carli, MD, FACC</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>U.S. Army Medical Research and Materiel Command</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Boston University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Brigham and Women's Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Chronic traumatic encephalopathy (CTE) is a progressive degenerative brain disease with
      symptoms that include memory loss, problems with impulse control, and depression that can
      lead to suicide. As the disease progresses, it can lead to dementia. Currently CTE can only
      be diagnosed postmortem where an over-accumulation of a protein called tau is observed.
      There is now a new experimental measure that makes it possible, for the first time, to
      measure tau protein in the living human brain using a novel positron emission tomography
      (PET) ligand, [F-18] AV-1451 (aka, [18F]-T807).

      The main objective of this study is to use a novel PET approach to measure tau accumulation
      in the brain. The presence of CTE at autopsy in deceased National Football League (NFL)
      players has been well documented. Accordingly, we will conduct this study in a group of
      retired NFL players who have clinical symptoms of CTE and are suspected of having CTE based
      on high levels of tau in their spinal fluid and abnormalities seen on research brain scans.
      We will compare them with a control group of former elite level athletes who have not
      experienced any brain trauma, deny any clinical symptoms, and who have completely normal
      spinal fluid tau and amyloid levels, and brain scans. We will also include a group of
      subjects with AD. All participants will be recruited from ongoing studies, headed by the
      Partnering PI of this proposal, Dr. Robert Stern, at the Boston University Center for the
      Study of Traumatic Encephalopathy and the Alzheimer's Disease Center. We will use both a
      beta amyloid PET scan ([18F]-florbetapir) and a tau PET scan ([18F]-T807) on consecutive
      days. With the beta amyloid scan we expect little or no evidence of amyloid in the NFL
      players with presumed CTE, and no evidence of amyloid in the control group of athletes with
      no history of repetitive brain trauma. In contrast we expect to see beta amyloid
      accumulation in the AD patient brains. With the new tau ligand, we expect that the NFL
      players with presumed CTE will show elevated levels of tau protein in the brain, which will
      not be observed in athletes without a history of brain trauma, but which will be seen in the
      AD patients' brains.

      Another goal is to use the latest MRI technologies to develop specific tau imaging
      biomarkers that correlate with the PET and spinal fluid tau measures but without the
      radiation of PET or invasiveness of spinal taps. The development of these surrogate imaging
      markers of tau, is critically important to diagnosing CTE. This in turn will lead to studies
      relevant to treatment and prevention of this devastating disease. Finally, as an exploratory
      method of examining possible genetic risk for CTE, we will also use cutting edge genetic
      analysis of blood samples from subjects in this proposal and compare tau load, measured by
      PET tau ligand uptake and cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) p-tau level, with a measure of genetic
      susceptibility to tau load, referred to as the genetic risk score for tau.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date>January 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>No masking</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Tau Protein Uptake..</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Evidence of differences in tau protein uptake as measured by the [18F]-T807 PET ligand will be assessed in our 3 subject groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Beta-Amyloid (Aβ) Protein Uptake.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years.</time_frame>
    <description>Evidence of differences in Aβ protein uptake as measured by the [18F]-florbetapir PET ligand will be assessed in our 3 subject groups.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>MR Biomarkers of Chronic Traumatic Encephalopathy (CTE).</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years.</time_frame>
    <description>MR (Magnetic Resonance) biomarkers for CTE derived from svMRI, DTI and MRS that are associated with brain tau findings measured by PET and previously acquired CSF p-tau levels will be developed.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Genetic Risk Score for Tau.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years.</time_frame>
    <description>We will compare tau load (measured by PET tau ligand uptake and CSF p-tau level) with a measure of genetic susceptibility to tau load, referred to as the genetic risk score for tau.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Traumatic Encephalopathy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Presumed CTE Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Interventions administered to the Presumed CTE Group include: [F-18]-T807 PET Scan, [F18]-Florbetapir PET Scan, MRI/MRS Scans, and Genetic Analysis for Genetic Risk Score for Tau.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Interventions administered to the Control Group include: [F-18]-T807 PET Scan, [F18]-Florbetapir PET Scan, and MRI/MRS Scans.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>AD Dementia Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Interventions administered to the AD Dementia Group include: [F-18]-T807 PET Scan, [F18]-Florbetapir PET Scan, MRI/MRS Scans</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>[F18]-T807</intervention_name>
    <description>[F18]-T807 PET Scan to measure tau deposition in the brain.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Presumed CTE Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>AD Dementia Group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>[F-18] AV-1451</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>[F18]-Florbetapir</intervention_name>
    <description>[F18]-Florbetapir PET scan to measure Beta-amyloid deposition in the brain.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Presumed CTE Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>AD Dementia Group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Amyvid</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MRI/MRS</intervention_name>
    <description>Two scans (structural, diffusion tensor imaging, and susceptibility weighted imaging scanned as part of one MR protocol, and a one-dimensional and two-dimensional spectroscopy examination as part of the other MR protocol.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Presumed CTE Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>AD Dementia Group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Magnetic Resonance Imaging</other_name>
    <other_name>Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopy</other_name>
    <other_name>Diffusion Tensor Imaging</other_name>
    <other_name>Susceptibility Weighted Imgaging</other_name>
    <other_name>One-dimensional Spectroscopy</other_name>
    <other_name>Two-dimensional Spectroscopy</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Genetic</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Genetic Analysis for Genetic Risk Score for Tau.</intervention_name>
    <description>DNA will be extracted from previously acquired and de-identified frozen blood specimens using a standard protocol (Gentra Puregene Kit, Qiagen 158422). Genotyping will be performed using the iPLEX Sequenom MassARRAY platform and samples will be genotyped for single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) associated with the deposition of neurofibrillary tangles.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Presumed CTE Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        1. Presumed CTE Group (includes 20 former NFL players who will have already participated
             in the NIH-funded R01 &quot;DETECT&quot; (Diagnosis and Evaluation of Traumatic Encephalopathy
             with Clinical Tests) study (Stern, PI; Shenton, Neuroimaging Site PI). Eligibility
             criteria for presumed CTE group and the control group are based on findings from the
             DETECT study.

             Inclusion Criteria:

               -  significant cognitive impairment (and impairment in at least one of the
                  following):

               -  behavioral (e.g., impulsivity, aggression),

               -  mood (e.g., elevated depression measures, elevated suicidality),

               -  and/or motor (e.g., impairments evidenced in neurological examination;

               -  demonstrated abnormalities on svMRI, DTI, or MRS

             Exclusion Criteria:

               -  weight &gt; 350 lbs

               -  known metallic implants preventing MRI

               -  history of stroke

               -  non-English speaking

               -  significant vision or hearing impairment

               -  unable to provide written informed consent

          2. Control Group (comprised of 5 male participants selected from 50 control subjects in
             the DETECT study).

             Inclusion Criteria:

               -  no history of mTBI or exposure to repetitive brain trauma

               -  normal functioning on DETECT clinical measures

               -  no abnormalities on svMRI, DTI, or MRS

             Exclusion Criteria:

               -  weight &gt; 350 lbs

               -  known metallic implants preventing MRI

               -  history of stroke or other neurological disease

               -  non-English speaking

               -  significant vision or hearing impairment

          3. AD Dementia Group (comprised of 5 male participants recruited from the BU Alzheimer's
             Disease Center (ADC) Clinical Core Registry (Dr. Stern, PI).

        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  diagnosis of Dementia due to AD using the NIA-AA (National Institute on
             Aging-Alzheimer's Association) criteria

          -  Clinical Dementia Rating Global Score of 1.0,

          -  a positive florbetapir PET study,

          -  CSF p-tau/Aβ consistent with AD.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  history of TBI, mTBI or or exposure to repetitive brain trauma

          -  weight &gt; 350 lbs

          -  known metallic implants preventing MRI

          -  history of stroke or other neurological disease

          -  non-English speaking

          -  significant vision or hearing impairment
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>69 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Martha E. Shenton, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Brigham and Women's Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Boston University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02118</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Brigham and Women's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhang W, Arteaga J, Cashion DK, Chen G, Gangadharmath U, Gomez LF, Kasi D, Lam C, Liang Q, Liu C, Mocharla VP, Mu F, Sinha A, Szardenings AK, Wang E, Walsh JC, Xia C, Yu C, Zhao T, Kolb HC. A highly selective and specific PET tracer for imaging of tau pathologies. J Alzheimers Dis. 2012;31(3):601-12. doi: 10.3233/JAD-2012-120712.</citation>
    <PMID>22683529</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chien DT, Bahri S, Szardenings AK, Walsh JC, Mu F, Su MY, Shankle WR, Elizarov A, Kolb HC. Early clinical PET imaging results with the novel PHF-tau radioligand [F-18]-T807. J Alzheimers Dis. 2013;34(2):457-68. doi: 10.3233/JAD-122059.</citation>
    <PMID>23234879</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>February 2, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>July 15, 2014</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Brigham and Women's Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Marcelo F. Di Carli, MD, FACC</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Chief, Division of Nuclear Medicine and Molecular Imaging</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>CTE</keyword>
  <keyword>Positron Emission Topography</keyword>
  <keyword>Tau</keyword>
  <keyword>Beta-amyloid</keyword>
  <keyword>Magnetic Resonance Imaging</keyword>
  <keyword>Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopy</keyword>
  <keyword>Diffusion Tensor Imaging</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Brain Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dementia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Brain Injury, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
