<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00298779</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an open-label, randomized, multiple-dose, multicenter Pharmacokinetics drug-drug interaction study in patients with advanced solid tumors, including non-Hodgkin's lymphoma, who are in need of anti-tumor therapy. In addition, the impact of omeprazole on the pharmacodynamics of VELCADE will also be evaluated.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Open-Label Study to Assess the Effect of Omeprazole on the Pharmacokinetics of VELCADE in Patients With Either Advanced Solid Tumors or Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bortezomib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Omeprazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1) Male or female at least 18 y/o 2)Weigh &gt;/= 50 kg (110lbs) and a BMI of &lt;/= 28kg/m2;3)life expectancy &gt;/= 3 mos; 4)Karnofsky Performance Status &gt;/=70%; 5)Women must be menopausal. 3)Men must agree to use an acceptable method of contraception for the duration of the study.4)Must sign an informed consent document indicating understanding of the purpose and procedures required for the study;5)informed consent for genetic testing 6)Subjects have advanced solid tumor (including nonHodgkin's lymphoma).7)resolution of reversible toxicities considered related to any prior antineoplastic therapies before entry; 8)must be able to swallow capsules whole; 1)Prior exposure to VELCADE.2)Has known hypersensitivity or intolerance to omeprazole, boron, mannitol or heparin. 3)Medical history of of liver or renal insufficiency; significant cardiac, vascular, pulmonary, GI, endocrine, neurologic, rheumatologic, pyschiatric or metabolic disturbances. 4)Uncontrolled diabetes. 5)history of hypotension or decreased blood pressure;6)Uncontrolled or severe cardiovascular disease incl. myocardial infarction within 6 mos of enrollment; 7)History of alcohol/drug abuse. 8)Presence of HIV antibodies, hepatitis C antibodies or hepatitis B. 9)active systemic infection requiring treatment; 10)Pregnant or breastfeeding' 11)neuropathy &gt;/= Gr.1; 12)transfusion dependence; 12)preplanned surgeries or procedures that would interfere with conduct of study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>patients with advanced solid tumors or Non-Hodgkins's Lymphoma</keyword>
</DOC>