<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01765920</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is: - to assess safety of the liquid dosage form of Ergoferon for treatment of acute upper respiratory tract infections in adult patients. - to assess clinical efficiency of the liquid dosage form of Ergoferon for treatment of acute upper respiratory tract infections in adult patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Trial of Safety and Clinical Efficiency of Ergoferon in Liquid Dosage Form in Treatment of Acute Upper Respiratory Tract Infections in Adult Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Tract Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients of both sexes aged from 18 to 60 inclusively. 2. Patients who consulted a doctor during the increase of seasonal incidence within 24 hours after the onset of acute upper respiratory tract infection. 3. Body temperature at least 37.8 °С at the moment of examination by the doctor. 4. Presence of two or more moderate level symptoms or three or more mild level symptoms according to the CCQ scale. 5. The possibility to start therapy within 24 hours after the onset of the first symptoms of acute upper respiratory tract infection. 6. Usage of contraceptive methods by the patients of both the sexes during the trial and within 30 days after ending of the participation in the trial. 7. Availability of information sheet (informed consent form for taking part in the clinical trial) signed by the patient. 1. Suspected invasive bacterial infection or presence of severe disease requiring use of antibacterial drugs (including sulfanilamides). 2. Suspected initial manifestations of diseases that have symptoms similar to ARI (other infectious diseases, flulike symptoms at the onset of systemic connective tissue disorders, oncohematological and other pathologies). 3. Exacerbation or decompensation of chronic diseases affecting the patient's ability to participate in a clinical trial. 4. Oncological diseases. 5. Medical history of polyvalent allergy. 6. Allergy / intolerance to any of the components of medications used in the treatment. 7. Impaired glucose tolerance, diabetes mellitus type 1 and 2. 8. Hereditary fructose intolerance (due to the presence of maltitol in the examined medicine). 9. Intake of medicines listed in the section "Prohibited concomitant treatment" for 1 month prior to participation in the trial. 10. Pregnancy, breast feeding. 11. Drugs usage, alcohol usage in the amount over 2 units of alcohol per day. 12. Patients with mental disorders. 13. Patients, who from investigator's point of view will fail to comply with the observation requirements of the trial or with the intake regimen of the investigated medicines. 14. Participation in other clinical trials in the course of 3 months prior to inclusion into the present trial. 15. Other factors, which hinder the patient's participation in the trial (for example, planned trips or business trips). 16. The patient is related to the research personnel of the centre who are directly involved in the trial or are the immediate family of the researcher. The immediate family includes husband / wife, parents, children or brothers / sisters, regardless of whether they are natural or adopted. 17. The patient works for OOO "NPF "Materia Medica Holding", i.e. s/he is the company's employee, temporary contract worker, and designated official responsible for carrying out the research or their immediate family.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>