<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02313415</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Study of the treatment of infertility caused by severe intrauterine adhesions or endometrial dysplasia by collagen scaffold loaded with umbilical cord blood-derived mesenchymal stem cells, and to provide clinical evidence for the treatment of uterine infertility.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Treatment of Infertility by Collagen Scaffold Loaded With Umbilical Cord Blood-derived Mesenchyma Stem Cells</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Infertility is defined as a women fails to become pregnant after having a normal sex life for two years without contraception. There is no effective treatment to the infertility caused by severe intrauterine adhesions or endometrial dysplasia which affects embryos implantation. The existing drugs, physical or surgical treatments had no significant effects to severe intrauterine adhesions.Collagen is the main component of the extracellular matrix with good biocompatibility, and it has been approved for the reparation of skin and oral mucosa by State Food and Drug Administration. umbilical cord blood-derived mesenchymal stem cells have been used in the clinical treatment of diseases, and achieved good results. In this study, collagen scaffold and umbilical cord blood-derived mesenchymal stem cells are combined, and they showed good biological safety</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infertility</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tissue Adhesions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Infertility caused by severe intrauterine adhesions or endometrial dysplasia Hysteroscopy examination confirmed intrauterine adhesions or endometrial dysplasia Monitoring of endometrial cycle Sign a consent form Follow the test plan and followup process Chromosome karyotype abnormalities Congenital uterine malformations Severe endometriosis Severe adenomyosis Contraindications to pregnancy Contraindications to bone marrow collection Contraindications to hormone replacement therapy Medical history of pelvic tumors or receiving pelvic radiotherapy Unable to adhere to the hospital examination and followup, or carrying on other treatment during followup period</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>