<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02629289</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is for healthy participants. This study tests single dose of the research drug HSP-130 against two existing approved drugs United States - approved Neulasta and European Union-approved Neulasta.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Comparative Study to Evaluate the Effect of HSP-130, US-approved Neulasta and EU-approved Neulasta in Healthy Participants</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>There will be 25 healthy participants in each of the six sequence groups. A total of 150 participants will be studied in one site in Australia. In addition to the 150 participants included, alternate subjects will be asked to come to the site on the day prior to when dosing is scheduled to begin. There will be 3 treatment options with 3 study dosing periods (1, 2 and 3) and at least 56 days between each treatment. The subject once asked to take part in the study will be assigned by chance (randomized) to one of the sequence groups as mentioned above (1, 2, 3, 4, 5, or 6).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neutropenia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Provides written informed consent approved by an Independent Ethics Committee (IEC) prior to any study related activities 2. Healthy male or female volunteers between 18 and 65 years of age (both inclusive) 3. Body mass index (BMI) between 19 and 30 kg/m^2, inclusive, and body weight of not &lt;50 kg or &gt;100 kg 4. Nonsmoker (defined as a subject who has not smoked and has not used nicotine containing products for at least 3 months prior to study drug administration and has a negative urine screen for cotinine) at Screening 5. Female subjects of childbearing potential and male subjects and their partners of childbearing potential, agree to pregnancy prevention throughout the duration of the study (through the Followup Visit). Subjects and their partners must agree to use of an effective method of contraception, to avoid impregnation of females throughout the course of the study. Subjects using oral contraceptives must be on a stable regimen for at least 3 months prior to Screening. Adequate forms of contraception to be used include hormonal contraceptives (oral, patch, depot), intrauterine devices (IUD), barrier contraceptive methods, such as diaphragm, cervical cap/shield, male condoms and female condoms.Sexually active subjects must use contraception while on study drug from admission to the Followup Visit. Male subjects must also refrain from donating sperm from admission to the Followup visit 6. Willing and able to comply with the requirements of the protocol and available for the planned duration of the study 1. Any active systemic or immunologic disease or condition, including but not limited to the following general categories: cardiovascular/pulmonary, hepatorenal, or systemic infection, or lactation 2. History of, or current, malignancy with the exception of adequately treated squamous or basal cell carcinoma of the skin or cervical carcinoma in situ within 5 years 3. Any disease or condition that might interfere with the absorption, distribution, metabolism, or excretion of the study drug or would place the subject at increased risk 4. Hematologic laboratory abnormalities including leukocytosis (defined as total leukocytes &gt;11,000/μL), leukopenia (defined as total leukocytes &lt;4000/μL), neutropenia (defined as ANC &lt;1500/μL) or thrombocytopenia (defined as platelet count of &lt;150/μL) 5. Clinically significant, as judged by the investigator, vital sign or 12lead ECG abnormality 6. History of biological growth factor exposure, including but not limited to filgrastim and other granulocytecolony stimulating factors in the context of treatment, prophylaxis, peripheral blood stem cell mobilization, or previous investigational study setting. This also includes exclusion for history of interferon, epoetin, and intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIG) exposure 7. Receipt of live vaccination, or exposure to communicable viral diseases such as, varicella, mumps, or measles within the 4 weeks prior to Screening 8. Surgery within the 4 months prior to Screening 9. Use of any prescription medicine (with the exception of contraceptives) within 7 days or at least 5 halflives, whichever is longer. Use of oral or parenteral anticoagulant or antiplatelet agents and corticosteroids should be specifically queried 10. Administration of a drug by depot injection (with exception of depot contraception) within 30 days prior to Randomization or 5 halflives of that drug, whichever is longer 11. Use of over the counter medications, including aspirin and nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs, or natural preparations (dietary supplement or herbal product) within 7 days or at least 5 halflives, whichever is longer. Vitamins and calcium are allowed (not to exceed 100% Daily Value) 12. History of drug or alcohol abuse within 2 years prior to Randomization, as determined by the investigator or a positive urine screen for drugs of abuse (UDS) at Screening. Screening for drugs of abuse will minimally include cannabinoids, opiates, barbiturates, amphetamines, cocaine, benzodiazepines, and alcohol 13. Drug sensitivity, allergic reaction to, or known hypersensitivity/idiosyncratic reaction to Escherichia coliderived proteins, filgrastim, other granulocytecolony stimulating factors, or pegylated agents 14. History of splenic rupture (or subject who is asplenic), pulmonary infiltrate or pneumonia, sickle cell disease, chronic neutropenia, thrombocytopenia, or vasculitis 15. Any clinically significant, as determined by the investigator, abnormal laboratory evaluations, including human immunodeficiency virus antibody (HIVAb), hepatitis B virus surface antigen (HBsAg), hepatitis C virus antibody (HCVAb), and liver function including alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and aspartate aminotransferase (AST) &lt; 1.5 the upper limit of normal taken at Screening. Negative HIVAb status will be confirmed at Screening and the results will be maintained confidentially by the study site 16. Donated or lost 475 mL or more blood volume (including plasmapheresis) or had a transfusion of any blood product within 3 months prior to Screening 17. Participated in another clinical research study with administration of investigational drug within 30 days prior to Randomization 18. Potentially not be able to comply with the requirements of this clinical trial, to communicate effectively with study personnel, or is considered by the Investigator, for any reason, to be an unsuitable candidate for the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>HSP-130</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacodynamic and Pharmacokinetic equivalence</keyword>
	<keyword>Pegfilgrastim</keyword>
</DOC>