<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01135134</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multicenter, randomized, parallel design, double-blind study of mometasone furoate (MF) in pediatric subjects with perennial allergic rhinitis. The subjects 5 to 15 years of age with perennial allergic rhinitis will enter a no-treatment observation period of 7 days at minimum and eligibility for inclusion in this study will be assessed. Following the observation period, eligible subjects will be randomized to MF or MF placebo for a 2-week double-blind treatment. At each clinic visit (at the start of treatment and after 1 and 2 weeks of treatment or at discontinuation), nasal symptom scores, nasal findings, and adverse events (AEs), will be evaluated. A 30-day follow-up visit will take place after the completion (or discontinuation) of the 2-week treatment period, to confirm presence or absence of serious adverse events (SAEs) and trial procedure-related AEs.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multicenter, Double-blind, Randomized, Placebo-controlled Study of Mometasone Furoate Nasal Spray in Pediatric Subjects With Perennial Allergic Rhinitis (Study P06332)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic, Perennial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mometasone Furoate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pediatric subjects with perennial allergic rhinitis who satisfy all of the following main criteria: Subjects having symptoms of perennial allergic rhinitis of moderate to severe degree, after the pretreatment observation period. Subjects confirmed to be allergic to nonseasonal environmental antigens (e.g., house dustmite antigen). Male or female outpatients aged 5 to 15 years at the time of providing informed consent. Subjects for whom any of the main exclusion criteria below is applicable will not be registered in this study. Subjects with coexisting tuberculous disease or lower respiratory tract infection and subjects who have a nasopharyngolaryngeal infection (acute upper respiratory tract infection, acute pharyngolaryngitis, or acute tonsillitis, etc.) requiring treatment at the time of registration Subjects with coexisting infections or systemic mycosis for which there are no effective antibiotics Subjects with repeated epistaxis Subjects who have nasal septum ulcers, nasal surgery, or nasal trauma, which have not healed Subjects with severe hepatic, renal, cardiac, hematological disease, diabetes mellitus, hypertension, or other serious coexisting diseases and whose general condition is poor Subjects with complication of vasomotor rhinitis or eosinophilic rhinitis. Subjects with nasal conditions (infectious sinusitis, hypertrophic rhinitis, acute or chronic rhinitis, nasal polyps, septal deviation, etc.) which may interfere with the evaluation of the efficacy of the study drug.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>15 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>