<DOC>
	<DOCNO>NCT01618669</DOCNO>
	<brief_summary>The purpose study demonstrate strength agreement single photon emission compute tomography ( SPECT ) image regadenoson follow inadequate exercise stress test SPECT image regadenoson alone inferior strength agreement two sequential regadenoson SPECT image without exercise .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study Assess Regadenoson Administration Following Inadequate Exercise Stress Test Compared Regadenoson Alone Myocardial Perfusion Imaging ( MPI ) Using Single Photon Emission Computed Tomography ( SPECT )</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Regadenoson</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects refer exercise pharmacologic stress test SPECT MPI procedure evaluation coronary artery disease ( CAD ) eligible study participation . Subjects refer pharmacologic stress reasonable potential attempt exercise stress . Subject must one following : . Past ischemia prior image stress test without invasive intervention artery subtend territory b . Subject know CAD symptom similar previous ischemic symptom , recent onset symptom recently worsen symptom suggestive ischemia c. Diamond Forrester estimate pretest probability CAD ≥ 50 % d. History recent coronary artery bypass surgery recent percutaneous coronary intervention ( PCI ) &gt; 10 year ( patient &gt; 30 day less 10 year post coronary artery bypass graft ( CABG ) PCI include meet criterion , b , e ) e. Previously demonstrate 100 % occlusion invasive coronary compute tomography ( CT ) angiography without successful intervene revascularization food may alter regadenoson effect Subject clinically significant illness , medical condition , laboratory abnormality Female subject pregnant lactating Subject dialysis end stage renal disease history glomerular filtration rate ( GFR ) &lt; 15 mL/min ( calculate use MDRD [ Modification Diet Renal Disease ] formula ) Subject history coronary revascularization either PCI CABG within 1 month prior rest myocardial perfusion imaging ( MPI ) Subject pacemaker implantable cardioverter defibrillator ( ICD ) Subject history acute myocardial infarction ( MI ) high risk unstable angina within 30 day prior rest MPI cardiac transplantation Subject uncontrolled hypertension point Visit 2 prior exercise testing ( i.e. , systolic blood pressure ( SBP ) ≥ 180 diastolic blood pressure ( DBP ) ≥ 95 mmHg two consecutive measurement rest ) . Subject severe aortic stenosis hypertrophic cardiomyopathy obstruction decompensated congestive heart failure Subject history severe respiratory disease include : asthma , chronic obstructive pulmonary disease ( COPD ) bronchospastic reactive airway disease 24hour continuous oxygen</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Coronary Artery Disease ( CAD )</keyword>
	<keyword>regadenoson</keyword>
	<keyword>pharmacologic stress</keyword>
</DOC>