<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02623673</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Retrospective cases series is a non-randomized, open-label, single-center investigation (Retina Clinic, São Paulo, Brazil) of patients diagnosed with macular edema secondary to diabetic retinopathy (DME) and retinal vein occlusions who underwent to simultaneous treatment with intravitreal injection of bevacizumab 1.25mg and implant of dexamethasone 0.7mg.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Simultaneous Therapy With Intravitreal Dexamethasone Implant and Bevacizumab for the Treatment of Macular Edema</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This retrospective cases series is a non-randomized, open-label, single-center investigation (Retina Clinic, São Paulo, Brazil) approved by the Institutional Review Board of Hospital Oftalmológico de Sorocaba/SP, and adhered to the tenets of the Declaration of Helsinki. Were included patients older than 18 years, treated between April 2014 and July 2015, diagnosed with macular edema secondary to diabetic retinopathy (DME) and retinal vein occlusions who underwent to simultaneous treatment with intravitreal injection of bevacizumab 1.25mg (Avastin; Genentech, South San Francisco, CA) and intravitreal implant of dexamethasone 0.7mg (Ozurdex; Allergan, Inc, Irvine, CA).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Macular Edema</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Edema</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<criteria>central macular thickness &gt; 300 µm on optical coherence tomography (OCT) macular edema secondary to diabetic retinopathy (DME) and retinal vein occlusions intravitreal antiVEGF within 6 weeks treatment with laser or intravitreal corticosteroids within 3 months of study entry.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>