<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02623114</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study was to identify genetic, brain morphologic, and environmental biomarkers that contribute to the pathophysiology of attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Attention-deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder Translational Center for Identifying Biomarkers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigators planned to recruit ADHD and healthy controls from the age of 6 to 17. Genetic data including dopamine, norepinephrine, serotonin, neurotropic factors, glutamate-related genes will be genotyped. Environmental disruptors including phthalate and cotinine will be analyzed. Brain MRI data including T1, diffusion tensor imaging (DTI), resting state functional MRI (rsfMRI) will be obtained. Neuropsychological tests including continuous performance test, Stroop test, Children's color trail test, Wisconsin card sorting test will be conducted. The investigators plan to identify biomarkers of ADHD using an integrative approach of genetic, environmental, neuroimaging and clinical data.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperkinesis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atomoxetine Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylphenidate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>A diagnosis of attentiondeficit/hyperactivity disorder confirmed using the KiddieSchedule for Affective Disorders and Schizophrenia Present and Lifetime Version Korean Version (KSADSPLK). IQ over 70 Intelligence quotient (IQ) &lt; 70 A hereditary genetic disorder A current/past history of brain trauma, organic brain disorder, seizure, or any neurological disorder Autism spectrum disorder, communication disorder, or learning disorder Schizophrenia or any other childhoodonset psychotic disorder Major depressive disorder or bipolar disorder Tourette's syndrome or chronic motor/vocal tic disorder obsessivecompulsive disorder A history of methylphenidate treatment lasting more than 1 year or received within the previous 4 weeks</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>