<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02276196</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Based on preclinical and small-sized studies in non-diabetic individuals, incretin-based therapies, i.e. glucagon-like peptide (GLP)-1 receptor agonists and dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitors, may hold promise in preventing the onset and progression of diabetic kidney disease. However, the potential renoprotective effects of these agents, that are believed to be effectuated "beyond glucose control", have not been sufficiently detailed in human diabetes. Therefore, the present study aims to explore the mechanistic and clinical effects of GLP-1 receptor agonists on renal physiology and biomarkers in patients with type 2 diabetes. Forty patients with insulin-treated type 2 diabetes will undergo an eight week intervention with lixisenatide or insulin glulisine in order to assess changes in the outcome parameters.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of LIXIsenatide on the Renal System</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetic Nephropathies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin glulisine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glucagon-Like Peptide 1</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with type 2 diabetes (HbA1c: 6.510.0% or 4886 mmol/mol) Stable treatment with basal insulin glargine (dose ±20%) and metformin or basal insulin glargine (dose ±20%) alone for at least 3 months Fasting plasma glucose &lt;10 mmol/L or the use of &gt;50 units of basal insulin glargine Females must be postmenopausal Caucasian Age: 35 75 years Body Mass Index: &gt;25 kg/m2 Hypertension should be under control, i.e. &lt;140/90 mmHg, and treated with an angiotensinconverting enzyme inhibitor or angiotensinIIreceptor blocker for at least 3 months. Albuminuria should be treated with an angiotensinconverting enzyme inhibitor (ACEI) or angiotensinIIreceptor blocker (ARB) for at least 3 months. Current/chronic use of the following medication: thiazolidinediones, sulfonylurea derivatives, GLP1 receptor agonists, dipeptidyl peptidase (DPP)4 inhibitors, glucocorticoids, immune suppressants, antimicrobial agents, chemotherapeutics, antipsychotics, tricyclic antidepressants and monoamine oxidase inhibitors. Subjects on diuretics, will only be excluded when these drugs cannot be stopped for the duration of the study. Chronic use of nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs will not be allowed, unless used as incidental medication (12 tablets) for nonchronic indications (i.e. sports injury, headache or back ache). However, no such drugs can be taken within a timeframe of 2 weeks prior to renaltesting Hypoglycemia unawareness based on investigator judgment History of severe hypoglycemia that required emergency hospital treatment within 3 months prior to screening Estimated GFR &lt;60 mL/min/1.73m2 (determined by the Modification of Diet in Renal Disease (MDRD) study equation) Pregnancy Current urinary tract infection and active nephritis Recent (&lt;6 months) history of cardiovascular disease, including: acute coronary syndrome, chronic heart failure (New York Heart Association grade IIIV), stroke or transient ischemic neurologic disorder Complaints compatible with or established gastroparesis, neurogenic bladder and/or incomplete bladder emptying (as determined by ultrasonic bladder scan) Active liver disease or a 3fold elevation of liver enzymes (aspartate aminotransferase/alanine aminotransferase) at screening History of or actual pancreatic disease History of or actual malignancy (except basal cell carcinoma) History of or actual severe mental disease Substance abuse (alcohol: defined as &gt;4 units/day) Allergy to any of the agents used in the study Individuals who are investigator site personnel, directly affiliated with the study, or are immediate (spouse, parent, child, or sibling, whether biological or legally adopted) family of investigator site personnel directly affiliated with the study Inability to understand the study protocol or give informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>