<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02276079</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study is a "proof-of-principle" project to examine the safety and feasibility of implementing a 1-week aerobic exercise program in the post-acute phase after mild traumatic brain injury (mTBI). The study will define the extent to which the exercise program improves recovery from mTBI in terms of relevant functional outcomes (cognition, mood, and physical status) and biomarkers (peripheral brain-derived neurotrophic factor [BDNF] concentration).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Exercise on Neurorecovery Following Mild Traumatic Brain Injury</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a "proof-of-principle" project for human subjects to examine the safety and feasibility of implementing a 1-week aerobic exercise program in the post-acute phase after mild traumatic brain injury (mTBI). This study will define the extent to which the exercise program improves recovery from mTBI in terms of relevant functional outcomes (cognition, mood, and physical status) and biomarkers (peripheral brain-derived neurotrophic factor [BDNF] concentration). This project will also lay the foundation for understanding the relationship between exercise and BDNF in the area of mTBI neurorecovery, thereby allowing future studies to develop best-practice methods for implementing exercise interventions as a treatment option for brain injuries.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Concussion</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Mild traumatic brain injury (mTBI) group: Meet criteria for mTBI as set forth by the American Congress of Rehabilitation Medicine mTBI was sustained 1425 days before beginning the exercise intervention comorbid orthopaedic injury that inhibits movement history of serious psychiatric disturbance with hospitalization, prior history of neurologic disease, current or past history of substance abuse disorder, diabetes previous history of moderate or severe head injury, neurological disorder unrelated to TBI (e.g., seizure disorder) physician recommendations against exercise nonEnglish speakers Noninjured Group: Gainesville, Florida community member History of mTBI or other brain injury in the past year comorbid orthopaedic injury that inhibits movement history of serious psychiatric disturbance with hospitalization, prior history of neurologic disease, current or past history of substance abuse disorder, diabetes previous history of moderate or severe head injury, neurological disorder unrelated to TBI (e.g., seizure disorder) physician recommendations against exercise nonEnglish speakers</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Mild Traumatic Brain Injury</keyword>
	<keyword>Aerobic Exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>Brain-Derived Neurotrophic Factor</keyword>
</DOC>