<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01619540</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Left ventricular failure (LVF) is a common cause of acute exacerbation of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (AECOPD). This association is frequently underestimated with regard to the difficulty of clinical diagnosis . The investigators expect that Valsalva Maneuver (VM) could be useful in this issue.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Valsalva Manœuvre in the Diagnosis of Left Ventricular Failure in Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease Exacerbation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria We included in this group, patients with a history (previous history) of COPD who consulted the emergency room for an exacerbation of COPD defined by a respiratory rate&gt; 25c/min and a pH &lt;7.35 and a PaCO2 &gt;6 KPa. This group is also divided into two groups according to clinical expert assessment and the BNP value: Group1 : BNP&gt; 400pg/ml, Group2 : BNP &lt;400PG / ml We excluded from this study patients with Prominent cardiac arrest Rhythm disorders including severe tachycardia arrhythmia Auricular fibrillation Hemodynamic instability requiring the use of vasoactive drugs and a contre indications of non invasive ventilation such us consciousness disorders with a Glasgow score &lt;12/15,a swallowing disorder A significant bronchial obstruction ,the upper airway obstruction , in upper gastrointestinal bleeding in progress, an extreme obesity and Cirrhosis or cancer. We are also excluded patients who did not cooperate and those who refused the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>COPD</keyword>
	<keyword>Left Ventricular Failure</keyword>
	<keyword>Valsalva Manoeuver</keyword>
</DOC>