<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01619501</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The overall goal of this research is to enhance the investigators understanding of the pathways involved in lung cancer, and to identify new biomarkers and/or therapeutic targets. By comparing gene expression between normal lung tissue and tumors growing in lung-specific C/EBPa KO mice, the investigators have identified the Bmi-1 proto-oncogene as being abnormally upregulated in C/EBPa-deleted tumors. Subsequently, the investigators have validated this observation in human lung cancer, implicating the investigators KO mice are an effective discovery tool for lung cancer research. Through similar approaches, the investigators have already identified (Sonic Hedgehog, SHH), and plan to identify other pathways which are abnormally regulated in C/EBPa-/- tumors. In parallel, the investigators will proceed to define the clinical relevance of the SHH pathway and the other newly-discovered molecular aberrations, by analyzing their expression and correlate it to C/EBPa expression on the samples of patients with NSCLC at NUHS. If the investigators preliminary data on Bmi-1 will be confirmed, this proto-oncogene may generate useful correlates that could be used in diagnosis and treatment of lung cancer, as well as identify new prognostic/predictive markers in lung cancer. Similarly, SHH pathway-components may behave as potential biomarkers and therapeutic tools for C/EBPa-related lung cancers. This proposal seeks to test the hypothesis that pathways which are dysregulated in lung tumors growing in a lung-specific C/EBPa KO model can be utilized as discovery tools to identify genes involved in human lung cancer pathogenesis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dysregulation of the C/EBPa Pathway in Human Lung Cancer and Search for New Biomarkers and/or Therapeutic Targets</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with lung cancer</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>