<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00379210</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to examine behavioral and neural changes resulting from Mindfulness Meditation Training (MMT), and to use this knowledge in advancing our understanding of the mechanisms of attention.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Neural Effects of Mindfulness Training on Attention</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Mindfulness Meditation Training (MMT) has been used successfully to decrease stress, pain, and adverse health symptoms in a varied subject population. MMT has been described as "paying attention in a particular way." Although attention is a key component of meditation, little is known about the cognitive and neural changes within the human attention system that result from MMT. In this study, we examine the effects of MMT on the human attention system using neurobehavioral measures. Here MMT comprises participation in a Mindfulness-Based-Stress-Reduction (MBSR) course, while the comparison group participates in a nutrition education course, both 8 weeks long. We compare the performance and neural activity of these groups both before and after participation in the course.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Men and women (all races and ethnicities) between 18 and 40 years old Women of childbearing age with a negative pregnancy test within 48 hours of scanning In good health Righthanded Normal or correctedtonormal vision English as a first language Able to understand and provide signed informed consent No history of metal in their body or other reasons why they could not undergo an Magnetic Resonance Imaging No history of ischemic or hemorrhagic stroke, encephalopathy or encephalitis, minimalcognitive impairment or dementia, movement disorder such as Parkinson's disease, head trauma causing loss of consciousness, cancer involving the central nervous system Pregnant or breastfeeding women Individuals with implanted metal or electronic devices that would prevent them from MRI scanning. Individuals with a history of neurologic dysfunction that would prevent performance on attentional tasks including: history of transient ischemic attacks, history of cerebral infarction, history of Binswanger's disease (or a history of hypertensive encephalopathy), history of intracranial hemorrhage, history of head trauma with loss of consciousness, history of encephalitis, history of extended exposure to any known neurotoxin, history of acquired cognitive impairment, history of normal pressure hydrocephalus, history of a cancer metastatic to the central nervous system, history of Parkinson's or other basal ganglia disease, history of GuillainBarré syndrome or chronic or relapsing polyneuropathy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>Attention</keyword>
	<keyword>ERP</keyword>
	<keyword>event-related potentials</keyword>
	<keyword>fMRI</keyword>
	<keyword>functional magnetic resonance imaging</keyword>
	<keyword>MBSR</keyword>
	<keyword>Mindfulness Based Stress Reduction</keyword>
	<keyword>Mindfulness Meditation Training</keyword>
	<keyword>MMT</keyword>
</DOC>