<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02373033</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study evaluates the effects of folate-rich foods regarding improvement of folate status compared with folic acid supplement. A randomized, parallel intervention trial with two active groups (folate-rich foods or folic acid supplement) and one control group (apple juice - 0 µg/d folate) was executed over 12 weeks.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Folate-Rich Foods Improve Folate Status</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Sixty-two women in reproductive age, apparently healthy, non-smokers, not consuming special diets (vegetarian), not pregnant, not planning conception or not lactating. A randomized, controlled, parallel intervention trial with two active groups and one blinded control group was carried out for 12 weeks (March to June, 2013). The active food group (n = 21) consumed folate-rich foods (germinated canned faba beans, cookies, orange juice, providing additional 250 μg/d folate); the active folic acid supplement group consumed a supplement (n = 19, providing 500 μg/d folic acid); and the control group (n = 22) received apple juice containing no folate or folic acid) in addition to the freely chosen diet. Fasted venous blood samples were collected at baseline, two months and three months for quantification of folate in plasma and erythrocytes and of homocysteine in plasma.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Folic Acid Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Folic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin B Complex</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Normal biochemical range for: Fasted plasma glucose Iron status (haemoglobin, serum ferritin) Liver status (aspartate transaminase, alanine transaminase, and γglutamyl transferase activities) Lipid profile (triglycerides, LDL, HDL) Folate status (plasma and erythrocyte folate) Plasma total homocysteine (tHcy) Vitamin B12 History of acute or chronic disease Use of vitamin or mineral supplements or folic acid fortified foods (within the past one month) A body mass index (BMI, in kg/m2) &gt;18 and &lt;30 Any medication interfering with folate metabolism (e.g., antiepileptic drugs, antibiotics, methotrexate, sulfasalazine, or anticonvulsants), smokers, consuming special diets (vegetarian), pregnancy, planned conception or lactation</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>32 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Folate</keyword>
	<keyword>folic acid</keyword>
	<keyword>intervention trial</keyword>
	<keyword>folate status</keyword>
	<keyword>women in childbearing age</keyword>
	<keyword>food folate</keyword>
</DOC>