<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02373163</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial is designed to: 1. Assess the response to montherapy with : a thiazide diuretic (HCTZ), a calcium-channel blocker (CCB, amlodipine) and an angiotensin-receptor blocker (telmisartan), among hypertensive subjects who live at sea level, at medium altitude above sea level and at high altitude above sea level. 2. To test whether diferentes exist in the response to therapy among subjects who live at different altitude above sea level 3. To assess the hemodynamic characteristics of hypertension in populations that live at sea level, at medium altitude above sea level, and at high altitude above sea level.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>INTERVENCION Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Telmisartan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydrochlorothiazide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amlodipine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angiotensin Receptor Antagonists</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium Channel Blockers</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age 4575 years. Enrollment will be stratified by age group (5065 and 6680 years), gender and altitude above sea level 2. Leaving in the enrollment cities for at least 2 years 3. Untreated hypertension for at least 2 weeks 4. Systolic BP between 140 and 160 mmHg and/or diastolic BP between 90 and 99 mmHg, in the absence of therapy. 1. Diabetes mellitus. 2. Chronic kidney disease (estimated glomerular filtration rate &lt;60 ml / minute / 1.73 m2 of body surface area. 3. Smoking. 4. Lung disease, liver disease or active cancer 5. Any factor that, in the opinion of the investigator, decreases shortterm survival 6. Psychiatric illness 7. Inability to provide informed consent 8. Established heart disease (previous myocardial infarction, heart failure, valvular heart disease, cardiomyopathy, atrial fibrillation or any significant cardiac arrhythmia) 9. History of cerebrovascular disease 10. History of orthostatic hypotension. 11. History of syncope. 12. History of allergy of adverse effects to study medications or drugs of the same pharmacologic classes.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>