<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01784900</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Treatment by association of complete surgical excision of the lesions and intraperitoneal immunotherapy using Catumaxomab for patients with gastric peritoneal carcinomatosis</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Treatment of Gastric Peritoneal Carcinomatosis by Association of Complete Surgical Resection of the Lesions and Intraperitoneal Immunotherapy Using Catumaxomab</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Bispecific</mesh_term>
	<criteria>consent form signed Age &gt;= 18 Carcinomatosis pre operative known or discivered in intraoperative Patients uin good general condition who may have extent surgery associated to specific inflammatory syndrom of immunotherapy Patients in good general condition Patient insured to social care Inclusion Criteria (intraoperative): Gastric adenocarcinoma with macroscopic peritoneal carcinomatosis (PC) confirmed by extemporaneous histological examination CP extension minimal or moderate (peritoneal index ≤ 12). Resection of the entire macroscopic lesions detectable (primary tumor, lymph nodes and CP). cleaning D2 lymph node (or D1.5). Presence of metastasis in reach Previous treatment with a nonhumanized monoclonal AC (mice or rat) Hypersensitivity to any type of antibody. History of cancer within 5 years preceding the entry in the trial other than basal cell skin carcinoma or in situ of the cervix, Patients already included in another clinical trial with experimental molecule Pregnant, or likely to be or breastfeeding, (Women of childbearing potential should have a pregnancy test (blood) negative 15 days before the date of the surgery) Using of a suitable method of contraception for patients of childbearing age during treatment. adequate contraception Methods includeare: an intrauterine device, hormonal contraception, condom use combined with a spermicide Persons deprived of liberty or Trust (including curatorship) Unable to undergo medical test for geographical, social or psychological. Exclusion Criteria (intraoperative): Persistent peritoneal lesions visible to the end of the surgery Resection of the tail of the pancreas or pancreatic break (because no drainage postop); break pleural (for K cardia) Presence of metastasis in reach during surgery (except for ovarian metastasis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>