<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00274651</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Open-label, non-randomized trial to assess the effectiveness of PXD101 in patients with recurrent or refractory cutaneous or peripheral and other types of T-cell lymphomas. PXD101 is a new, potent histone deacetylase (HDAC) inhibitor. Patients are treated with belinostat(PXD101) 1000 mg/m2 on days 1-5 of a 21 day cycle.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase II Clinical Trial of PXD101 in Patients With Recurrent or Refractory Cutaneous and Peripheral T-Cell Lymphomas</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell, Peripheral</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell, Cutaneous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Belinostat</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female with age &gt; or = 18 years. Histologically confirmed diagnosis of cutaneous Tcell lymphoma (CTCL) or peripheral Tcell lymphoma (PTCL) or other Tcell nonHodgkin's lymphoma (NHL). Must have failed at least one line of prior systemic therapy. No limitation in number of prior therapies. CTCL patients who are refractory or intolerant to oral Targretin are also eligible. The presence of measurable disease (defined as &gt; or = 1 cm with radiographic imaging) for PTCL or stage 1B or greater disease for CTCL and assessable by the severityweighted assessment tool (SWAT). Adequate bone marrow and hepatic function including the following: Absolute neutrophil count &gt; or = 1,000 cells/mm3, platelets &gt; or = 40,000/mm3 Total bilirubin &lt; or = 1.5 x upper normal limit or &lt; or = 3 x upper normal limit if hepatic involvement AST (SGOT) (aspartate aminotransferase), ALT (SGPT) (alanine aminotransferase) &lt; or = 2.5 x upper normal limit (&lt; or = 5 x upper normal limit if hepatic involvement) Hemoglobin &gt; or = 9.0 g/dL. Serum potassium within normal range. Karnofsky performance status &gt; or = 70%. Estimated life expectancy &gt; 3 months. Signed informed consent approved by the Institutional Review Board (IRB). Anticancer therapies within 4 weeks of first PXD101 administration should be excluded unless toxicity from prior anticancer therapy has resolved or returned to baseline and cancer disease status warrants. Any use of investigational drugs within 4 weeks prior to study registration. Major surgery within 4 weeks of study drug administration. Prior allogeneic bone marrow transplant. A diagnosis of adult Tcell lymphoma/leukemia (ATLL) or precursor Tlymphoblastic lymphoma. Coexisting active infection or any coexisting medical condition likely to interfere with trial procedures. However, patients with progressing CTCL whose open skin lesions are frequently infected may not be excluded from this trial at the discretion of Investigators. Clinically significant cardiovascular disease including unstable angina pectoris, uncontrolled hypertension, and congestive heart failure related to primary cardiac disease, a condition requiring antiarrhythmic therapy, history of sustained ventricular tachycardia, history of ventricular fibrillation or Torsade de Pointes, bradycardia (HR&lt;50bpm) with or without a pacemaker, bifascicular block with a right bundle branch block and a left anterior block, ischemic or severe valvular heart disease, a myocardial infarction within 6 months or a left ventricular ejection fraction &lt; 40% (by echocardiogram [ECHO] or multigated acquisition scan [MUGA]) within 3 months of study enrolment. A marked baseline prolongation of QT/QTc ((corrected) QT) interval, e.g., repeated demonstration of a QTc interval &gt; 450 milliseconds (msec). Long QT Syndrome; the required use of concomitant medication on belinostat infusion days that may cause Torsade de Pointes. Renal insufficiency defined as a calculated creatinine clearance of &lt; 45 mL/min/1.73 m2. A history of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biological composition to PXD101 and Larginine. Clinically significant central nervous system disorders with altered mental status or psychiatric disorders precluding understanding of the informed consent process and/or completion of the necessary studies. Patients requiring treatment for other malignant diseases or less than 5 years posttreatment completion for an invasive malignant disease (excluding nonmelanotic skin cancers or cervical cancer insitu). Patients with any history of melanoma should be excluded. Pregnant or breastfeeding women, and women of childbearing age and potential, who are not willing to use effective contraception. Male patients and/or their fertile female partners who are not willing to use contraceptives during the trial. Known infection with HIV, human Tcell leukemia virus type1 (HTLV1), hepatitis B or hepatitis C.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>CTCL</keyword>
	<keyword>PTCL</keyword>
	<keyword>lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Cutaneous T-Cell Lymphomas (CTCL)</keyword>
	<keyword>Peripheral T-Cell Lymphomas (PTCL)</keyword>
	<keyword>Other Types of Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>belinostat</keyword>
</DOC>