<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00274768</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as capecitabine, work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing. PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying how well capecitabine works in treating patients with metastatic breast cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Capecitabine in Treating Patients With Metastatic Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Determine the response rate in patients with metastatic breast cancer treated with a fixed-dose of capecitabine. Secondary - Determine the clinical benefit, time to treatment failure (TTF), safety, and toxicity profile of this regimen in these patients. - Determine the pharmacokinetics (PK) and pharmacogenetics in these patients. - Correlate pharmacodynamic effects of this drug with toxicity and response in these patients. - Determine compliance and adherence to this regimen and correlate with PK parameters in these patients. OUTLINE: This is an open-label study. Patients receive a fixed-dose of oral capecitabine twice daily on days 1-14. Courses repeat every 21 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed periodically. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 45 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically or cytologically confirmed diagnosis of adenocarcinoma of the breast Evidence of metastatic involvement (stage IV disease) Patients must have measurable disease At least one measurable lesion as defined by the Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) Treated brain metastases (surgery or radiation therapy) allowed if clinically stable Patients with leptomeningeal disease are ineligible Hormone receptor status: Not specified PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: ECOG (Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group) performance status 02 Male or female Menopausal status not specified Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1,500/mm^3 Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm^3 Creatinine clearance &gt; 50 mL/min Fertile patients must use effective contraception No history of another severe and/or lifethreatening medical disease No other active primary malignancy Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Patients with asymptomatic HIV infection are eligible Liver dysfunction score ≤ 9 No preexisting liver disease (i.e., cirrhosis or active viral hepatitis) No active gastrointestinal malabsorption illness No clinically significant cardiac disease, including the following: Congestive heart failure, symptomatic coronary artery disease, and cardiac arrhythmias not well controlled with medication, or myocardial infarction within the past six months No prior unanticipated severe reaction to fluoropyrimidine therapy, known hypersensitivity to fluorouracil, or known dihydropyrimidine dehydrogenase deficiency No history of uncontrolled seizures or central nervous system disorders No significant history of noncompliance to medical regimens No clinically significant psychiatric disability that would preclude study compliance PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: No previous capecitabine Up to 3 prior cytotoxic regimens allowed for metastatic disease Prior noncytotoxic therapy allowed (e.g., hormonal treatment or trastuzumab) No other concurrent therapies intended to treat the primary condition including chemotherapy, biologic agents, or immunotherapy No concurrent antiestrogen therapy, radiation therapy, or investigational systemic therapy No other concurrent investigational drugs No concurrent use of the following drugs: warfarin for full anticoagulation, cimetidine, or azidothymidine (AZT) Minidose warfarin for prophylaxis of central venous catheter thrombosis allowed At least 4 weeks since prior sorivudine or brivudine Concurrent use of bisphosphonates allowed if initiated before beginning study therapy Concurrent use of megestrol acetate suspension as an appetite stimulant allowed</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage IV breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>male breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent breast cancer</keyword>
</DOC>