<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03070925</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The PuraPly AM case series is a prospective, observational study for patients who have received PuraPly AM which consists of a collagen sheet coated with polyhexamethylene biguanide hydrochloride (PHMB) and is intended for the management of wounds; no experimental intervention is involved.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prospective PuraPly™ AM Case Series Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of the case series is to assess the ability of PuraPly AM to meet wound specific treatment goals including management of bioburden, support of granulation tissue formation, and support of wound closure. Patients will undergo clinical assessments and receive the standard of care as determined by the treating physician. The case series is being undertaken to better understand PuraPly AM utilization and subsequent healing outcomes as well as to evaluate the effects of concomitant wound therapy on healing. Patient's participation may involve follow-up for up to 12 weeks following application of PuraPly AM.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pressure Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Varicose Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Infective Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Participant is at least 18 years of age 2. Participant has read, understood and signed and Institutional Review Board (IRB) approved Informed Consent Form (ICF). 3. Participant has at least 1 wound appropriate for receiving PuraPly AM, including Partial and fullthickness wounds Pressure ulcers Venous ulcers Diabetic ulcers Chronic vascular ulcers Tunneled/undermined wounds Surgical wounds (donor sites/grafts, postMohs' surgery, postlaser surgery, podiatric, wound dehiscence) Trauma wounds (abrasions, lacerations, seconddegree burns, skin tears) Draining wounds 1. Participant has a known sensitivity to porcine materials 2. Participant has a thirddegree burn 3. Participant has a known sensitivity to polyhexamethylene biguanide hydrochloride (PHMB) 4. Participants receiving concurrent treatment with other topical antimicrobials or skin substitute products</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Antimicrobial</keyword>
	<keyword>Collagen</keyword>
	<keyword>Bioburden</keyword>
	<keyword>Biofilm</keyword>
	<keyword>PHMB</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic wounds</keyword>
	<keyword>Acute wounds</keyword>
</DOC>