<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00919958</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The The purpose of this study is to determine the safety of PLX-PAD single dose, Intra-muscular injection for the treatment of CLI patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety of Intramuscular Injection of Allogeneic PLX-PAD Cells for the Treatment of Critical Limb Ischemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PLX-PAD are mesenchymal-like stromal cells derived from a full term placenta, termed PLX-PAD, and intended for the treatment of Critical Limb Ischemia</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Arterial Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Diagnosis of critical limb ischemia defined as persistent, recurring ischemic rest pain for at least two (2) weeks, and/or ulceration or gangrene of the foot or toe, with ABI &lt; 0.4 or/and TBI &lt; 0.4 or transcutaneous partial pressure of oxygen ≤ 30 mmHg pO2 at the foot. 2. Rutherford category 45 3. No acceptable options for revascularisation as confirmed by angiographic imaging results or by color flow duplex ultrasound obtained within 6 months prior screening visit and signed approval of vascular surgeon. 4. In the opinion of the investigator, major amputation is not anticipated over a period of three (3) months. 1. Uncontrolled hypertension (defined as diastolic blood pressure &gt; 110 mmHg or systolic blood pressure &gt; 180 mmHg during screening). 2. Poorly controlled diabetes mellitus (HbA1c &gt; 9%) 3. Wounds with severity greater than Grade 2 on the Wagner Scale 4. Lifethreatening ventricular arrhythmia except if an ICD is implanted or unstable angina pectoris characterized by increasingly frequent episodes with modest exertion or at rest, worsening severity, and prolonged 5. ST segment elevation myocardial infarction and/or TIA/CVA within six (6) months prior to enrollment. Patients with severe congestive heart failure (i.e. NYHA Stage IV) 6. In the opinion of the investigator, the patient is unsuitable for cellular therapy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>81 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Peripheral Artery Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Peripheral Vascular Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Critical limb ischemia</keyword>
</DOC>