<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01148225</DOC>
	<brief_summary>There is an unmet medical need in non-infectious intermediate-, posterior- and pan uveitis. These types of uveitis are at a higher risk for vision loss compared to anterior uveitis. Patients with these types of uveitis are often treated with chronic corticosteroids. The use of chronic corticosteroids is linked with predictable long-term side effects. The objective of this study is to evaluate the long term efficacy and safety of adalimumab subjects with non-infectious intermediate-, posterior- or pan-uveitis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of the Long-term Safety and Efficacy of Adalimumab in Subjects With Intermediate-, Posterior-, or Pan-uveitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Uveitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Panuveitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adalimumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject must have successfully enrolled in either study M10877 or M10880 and either met the endpoint of "Treatment Failure" or completed the study A subject will be excluded from this study if the patient discontinued from study M10877 or M10880 for any reasons other than having a Treatment Failure event Subject with corneal or lens opacity that precludes visualization of the fundus or that likely requires cataract surgery during the duration of the trial Subjects with intraocular pressure of &gt;= 25 mmHg and on &gt;= 2 glaucoma medications or evidence of glaucomatous optic nerve injury Subject with proliferative or severe nonproliferative diabetic retinopathy or clinically significant macular edema due to diabetic retinopathy Subject with neovascular/wet agerelated macular degeneration Subject with abnormality of vitreoretinal interface (i.e., vitreomacular traction, epiretinal membranes, etc.) with the potential for macular structural damage independent of the inflammatory process Subject with a systemic inflammatory disease that requires therapy with a prohibited immunosuppressive agent at the time of study entry</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Non-infectious Uveitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Active Uveitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Posterior-Uveitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Uveitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Pan-uveitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Intermediate-Uveitis</keyword>
</DOC>