<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02039700</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will assess the absolute bioavailability of a single oral dose of lesinurad and evaluate the pharmacokinetic (PK) parameters of lesinurad and [14C]lesinurad in healthy adult male subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bioavailability of Lesinurad and Intravenous [14C]Lesinurad</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In this study a single dose of lesinurad will be administered after an overnight fast followed by a single 15-minute infusion of a radiolabeled intravenous micro tracer dose of [14C]lesinurad to assess the in vivo performance of lesinurad.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lesinurad</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject has a body weight ≥ 50 kg (110 lbs) and body mass index ≥ 18 and ≤ 30 kg/m2. Subject is free of any clinically significant disease or medical condition, per the Investigator's judgment Subject has a history or suspicion of kidney stones. Subject has undergone major surgery within 3 months prior to Screening. Subject donated blood or experienced significant blood loss (&gt;450 mL) within 12 weeks prior to Screening or gave a plasma donation within 4 weeks prior to Screening. Subject has inadequate venous access or unsuitable veins for repeated venipuncture. Subject does not have a normal or clinically acceptable physical examination, per the Investigator's judgment. Subject has clinically relevant abnormalities in blood pressure, heart rate, or body temperature, per the Investigator's judgment. Subject has Screening clinical safety laboratory parameters (serum chemistry, hematology, or urinalysis) that are outside the normal limits and are considered clinically significant by the Investigator. Subject has clinically relevant abnormalities in 12lead electrocardiogram, per the Investigator's judgment. Subject has a Screening serum urate level &gt; 7 mg/dL. Subject had radiation exposure that exceeds 5 mSv in the last 12 months or 10 mSv in the last 5 years. This includes radiation exposure from the present study or other clinical studies, including diagnostic Xrays and other medical exposures but excluding exposure to background radiation. No occupationally exposed worker, as defined in the Ionising Radiation Regulations 1999, shall participate in the study.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>