<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02039115</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Complete endoscopic resection of early neoplastic BE is a curative procedure. However, a significant proportion of patients develop symptomatic esophageal strictures following CBE, and this limits the technique, particularly for circumferential and longer segment disease. Oral steroid therapy may reduce stricture formation; thereby allowing CBE to be performed with minimal associated morbidity.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Reduction in Symptomatic Esophageal Stricture Formation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The main objective of the proposed randomized trial is to compare the rate of symptomatic oesophageal strictures in patients receiving placebo versus oral prednisone.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Constriction, Pathologic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Esophageal Stenosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Histologically confirmed Barretts mucosa with high grade dysplasia or early esophageal adenocarcinoma (T1a, intramucosal adenocarcinoma). 2. Barretts segment ≥ 30% circumference, ≤C3 and ≤M5. 3. The general health condition of the patient permits anesthesia for endoscopy. 4. Patient is 18 years of age or older. 5. Informed consent is obtained 1. Previous (referral) biopsies show low grade dysplasia only, or invasive adenocarcinoma. 2. Barretts segment &lt;30% circumference, &gt;C3 or &gt;M5. 3. During initial gastroscopy there are highly suspicious areas for submucosal invasive cancer (Kudo pit pattern type V; excavated/depressed type morphology; large smooth or ulcerated nodule). In cases of significant doubt, initial resection is of the highly suspicious area only, and urgent histology processing requested. If submucosal invasion is excluded, the patient is rebooked for 1st stage complete barrett's excision (60% circumferential resection) and randomization after a 46 weeks interval. 4. Presence of a tight peptic oesophageal stricture that impedes safe and effective endoscopic mucosal resection using a cap (Cook Medical). 5. Active malignancy, uncontrolled Diabetes Mellitus, active or untreated major psychiatric disorder, uncontrolled infection, uncontrolled hypertension, uncontrolled or severe congestive cardiac failure, noncorrectable coagulopathy (INR&gt;2, or platelet count &lt;60 x 109/L), osteoporosis, recent peptic ulcer disease, moderatetosevere glaucoma or untreated glaucoma, or pregnancy. 6. Unable to provide informed consent 7. Allergy to compound used in tablet formulation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>89 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>