<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00149890</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Systemic infection is still a major concern in young children with liver transplantation. The approach of this study is to reduce the risk of systemic infections by avoiding intraoperative steroids (another class of immunosuppressive drugs) given in combination with basiliximab, cyclosporine and steroids in pediatric de novo liver transplant recipients. The treatment is compared to the same treatment regimen including intraoperative steroids with respect to rejection episodes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Basiliximab, Cyclosporine/Cyclosporine Microemulsion, and Steroids in Pediatric de Novo Liver Transplant Recipients Avoiding Intraoperative Steroids</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Basiliximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pediatric patients undergoing primary orthotopic liver transplantation (whole organ or split liver or reduced size) Cadaveric or living donor (related or unrelated) Patients who are recipients of multiple solid organ transplants and/or who have previously received transplanted organs If cold ischemia time of the transplanted organ is &gt;12 hours Auxiliary liver transplant recipients Fulminant hepatic failure Autoimmune hepatitis Primary sclerosing cholangitis Severe acute systemic infections Hepatitis B surface antigen/HCV/HIV positive Known contraindication to intravenous (i.v.) or per os (orally) (p.o.) cyclosporine or corticoids Nonability to comply with the protocol Relevant abnormal physical or laboratory findings within 2 weeks of inclusion Relevant severe allergy, hypersensitivity to basiliximab or similar drugs History/presence of relevant malignancy Pregnancy/breastfeeding Use of any investigational or immunomodulatory/immunosuppressive drug within 4 weeks prior to transplantation.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>16 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>pediatric</keyword>
	<keyword>liver transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>Simulect</keyword>
	<keyword>Basiliximab</keyword>
	<keyword>ciclosporin microemulsion</keyword>
	<keyword>steroid reduction</keyword>
	<keyword>pediatric liver transplantation</keyword>
</DOC>