<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00196742</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Fabry Registry is an ongoing, international multi-center, strictly observational program that tracks the routine clinical outcomes for patients with Fabry disease, irrespective of treatment status. No experimental intervention is involved; patients in the Registry undergo clinical assessments and receive care as determined by the patient's treating physician. The objectives of the Registry are: - To enhance the understanding of the variability, progression, and natural history of Fabry disease, including heterozygous females with the disease; - To assist the Fabry medical community with the development of recommendations for monitoring patients and reports on patient outcomes to help optimize patient care; - To characterize and describe the Fabry population as a whole; and - To evaluate the long-term safety and effectiveness of Fabrazyme®</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Fabry Disease Registry</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The Fabry Registry is an international program; in addition to the central contact information provided under the "Location" heading, patients may contact: - In Asia-Pacific - Vivian Liu, +65-6431-2548, Vivian.liu@genzyme.com - In Europe - +31-35-699-1232, europe@FabryRegistry.com - In Latin America - +617-591-5500, help@FabryRegistry.com - In North America - +617-591-5500, help@FabryRegistry.com</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fabry Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria All patients with a confirmed diagnosis of Fabry disease who have signed the informed consent and patient authorization form(s) are eligible for inclusion. Confirmed diagnosis is defined as a documented deficiency in plasma or leukocyte αGAL (alphagalactosidase) enzyme activity and/or mutation(s) in the gene coding for αGAL. Exclusion Criteria There are no exclusion criteria in this Registry. Patients are allowed to participate in other clinical studies and may be receiving different therapies to treat their disease; however, enrollment in other clinical studies should be noted on the Registry case report forms (CRFs).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>alpha Galactosidase A</keyword>
	<keyword>aGAL (alpha-galactosidase)</keyword>
	<keyword>Fabry</keyword>
	<keyword>GL3 (globotriaosylceramide)</keyword>
	<keyword>Anderson-Fabry Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>angiokeratomas</keyword>
	<keyword>GLA deficiency (gene deficiency)</keyword>
	<keyword>errors in metabolism</keyword>
</DOC>