<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02504060</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is a randomized double-blind placebo-controlled clinical trail to evaluate the clinical efficacy and safety of 1.1 chemical drugs N-acetyl-D-glucosamine on Chinese IBS-D patients coming from thirty- six centers in Chinese. 720 IBS-D patients (360 for treatment group, 360 for placebo group) in this research are accord with the Rome III diagnostic criteria, screening/import period pain intensity scores of the NRS(numerical rating scale) week mean value are 3.0 plus and the days which at least more than one time a stool type are 6 or 7 type over 2 days/week. Test cycle includes screening/import period (2 weeks), open treatment period (12 weeks), follow-up period (2 weeks). The main outcome measures are pain intensity (NRS score 11 point scale) and stool type ( Bristol type), and secondary endpoints included overall symptoms sensory scores, defecation frequency, abdominal distension, defecation urgency and quality of life parameters (IBS-QOL scale).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Trials of N-acetyl Glucosamine Capsule for IBS-D Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Irritable Bowel Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Voluntarily signed the informed consent form. Man or woman, aged 18 to 65 years, inclusive. Based on the Roman III diagnostic criteria for diagnosis of IBSD subjects, recurrent abdominal pain accompanied with abdominal discomfort or not, monthly attack within the past 3months at least 3 days. With two or more of the following three kinds of symptoms: At least a portion of the time abdominal pain or defecate increase when discomfort. At least a portion of the time abdominal pain or the row of loose stools when discomfort. At least a portion of the time abdominal pain or discomfort improved after defecation. Symptoms for at least 6 months before diagnosis. Screening/import period pain intensity scores of the NRS week mean value are 3.0 plus and the days which at least more than one time a stool type are 6 or 7 type over 2 days per week. During the screening period，patients should answer the questions of electronic log completely following the requirements for 10days or more. Patients are willing to stop drugs for abdominal symptoms or diarrhea which are in violation of the scheme, and take medicine prescribed in the scheme. Patients agree to not change the lifestyle significantly that may affect the symptoms of IBSD from signing up the Informed Consent Form to the last experiment. The illness recured after a normal colonoscopy report within one year that was provided by this hospital or a grade first class teaching hospital, include polyp of colon (less than 3mm,the number of less than 5) patients who taked therapeutic endoscopy and recurrenced within one year; or those that get a normal colonoscopy report in this hospital or a grade first class teaching hospital before screening but have a history of bowel preparation, should be chosen when next attack. History of organic gastrointestinal diseases: Chronic pancreatitis (cp), inflammatory bowel disease, intestinal tuberculosis, malabsorption syndrome, celiac disease, gastrointestinal tumor, or other organic diseases etc. History of abdominal and pelvic surgery ( not including appendectomy and intestinal polyposis (&lt;3mm) after treatment within one year ). The nonintestinal disease of digestive system such as Peptic ulcer, tuberculous peritonitis, cirrhosis etc. Heart, lung, kidney and other important organs have severe lesions, immune regulatory disease, metabolic disease (diabetes, thyroid disease) or malignant tumor, reproductive system diseases such as ovarian cysts, endometriosis, etc. Laboratory tests or Electrocardiogram were significantly abnormal, and judging by the researchers may damage the patient safety or successful completion of the clinical research: Male hemoglobin &lt;120g/L, female hemoglobin &lt;100g/L; Male serum creatinine≥133umol/L, female serum creatinine≥124umol/L; or creatinine clearance rate≤60ml/min; Chronic liver disease and/or abnormal liver function, defined as AST (aspartate aminotransferase) &gt; 1.5 x ULN (Upper Limit Of Normal) and/or ALT (alanine aminotransferase) &gt; 1.5 x ULN and/or total bilirubin &gt; 1.5x ULN; Serious psychiatric patients( Hamilton Depression Scale scores&gt;20). History of drug abuse or alcohol abuse. Allergic to this study drug. Concomitant medication is unable to stop or use continuously for more than a week but affect the gastrointestinal movement and function in the experiment, such as antibiotic drugs, the drugs of regulating the intestinal microecology, parasympathetic inhibitors, muscle relaxants, antidiarrheal, opiates, etc. Do not fill in the electronic log of one week before entering the group (1 week) completely. Pregnant or lactating women Is participating in clinical trials or have finished it less than 3 months. Other researchers think not suitable for the list.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>diarrhea</keyword>
	<keyword>abdominal pain</keyword>
</DOC>