<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01641471</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A prospective, randomized postmarket trial to assess the efficacy of the Select TENS™ Pain Management System, a transcutaneous electrical nerve stimulation (TENS) device, for reducing pain and narcotics requirement in patients managed with a total knee arthroplasty (TKA). This will be a placebo-controlled study involving 116 patients undergoing primary unilateral TKA procedures; 58 patients will be randomly selected to be treated postoperatively with an active TENS unit and the other 58 patients will be randomly selected to be treated with the placebo TENS unit (control group). Patients will be enrolled at two sites within the Cleveland Clinic Health System (Main Campus and Lutheran Hospital). Both treatment and control groups will receive a femoral nerve catheter, standard during a primary TKA. It is hypothesized that TENS (in combination with a femoral nerve catheter) can reduce narcotic usage, reduce pain, and allow for a quicker return to function following TKA.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Electrical Nerve Stimulation (TENS) Therapy for Pain Relief Following Total Knee Arthroplasty (TKA)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis, Knee</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Polystyrene sulfonic acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients undergoing unilateral primary total knee arthroplasty Patients who are between the ages of 1885 years Patient has signed informed consent Patients who live &gt;100 miles from the Cleveland Clinic main campus (9500 Euclid Ave., Cleveland, OH 44195) Patients who will not receive a femoral nerve catheter for surgery Patients who are not planned to be discharged directly home following surgery Patients who have used a TENS device in the past Preoperative daily use of narcotics (i.e., high tolerance) Already enrolled in another research study, including the present study for contralateral knee Patients with a history of epilepsy Patients with a cardiac pacemaker Patients who are a risk for poor compliance or have a poor understanding of the use of the TENS device Condition deemed by physician or medical staff to be nonconducive to patient's ability to complete the study, or a potential risk to the patient's health and wellbeing.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Total Knee Arthroplasty (TKA)</keyword>
	<keyword>Transcutaneous Electrical Nerve Stimulation (TENS)</keyword>
	<keyword>Pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Function</keyword>
	<keyword>Knee Osteoarthritis</keyword>
</DOC>