<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02864875</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objetive of this study is to compare the treatment of two groups of politrauma patients that have fibrinogen deficiency (Fibtem &lt; 9) diagnose by thromboelastography (ROTEM) but do not have clinical or laboratorial signs of coagulopathy at emergency room admission. One group will receive fibrinogen concentrate (Haemocomplettan) and the control group will be clinically followed. If any of the groups show clinical signs of coagulopathy it will be treated by anesthesiologist decision.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Treatment of Coagulopathy Trauma-induced Guided by Thromboelastography in Politrauma Patients.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Coagulation defects related to severe trauma, trauma-induced coagulopathy (TIC) has several related factors, including: the blood loss with extensive consumption of coagulation and platelet factors, dilutional coagulopathy after administration of crystalloids and colloids to maintain blood pressure, in addition to the main cause pathophysiological indicated that the activation of the fibrinolytic system or secondary hyperfibrinolysis activation of protein C. The presence of TIC reflects the extent and severity of the injury and is directly correlated with mortality; The fibrinogen plays an important role in coagulation. The concentration of fibrinogen in the plasma is the highest of all coagulation factors, and as acute phase protein undergoes elevation of plasma level during inflammation. In the final phase of coagulation, large amount of fibrinogen is captured by activated platelets by glycoprotein IIb / IIIa receptor. Especially the maximum value of the thrombus firmness is influenced by the number of platelets and plasma fibrinogen levels. Recent studies suggest that thromboelastography would be more appropriate to monitor hemostasis earlier than traditional laboratory methods (prothrombin time, activated partial thromboplastin time, serum fibrinogen). This method is able to provide information about the polymerization of fibrin in the presence of platelet activity, fibrinogen deficiency evaluation, factor XIII deficiency and hemofilia. Fibrinogen can be found in human plasma, cryoprecipitate and fibrinogen concentrate (Heamocompletan® ); The amount of fibrinogen cryoprecipitate per milliliter in cryoprecipitate is much higher than the plasma, which justifies the use of cryoprecipitate in place of the plasma when the goal is to offer the patient Fibrinogen. However, studies deserves to be performed to compare the use of cryoprecipitate with fibrinogen concentrate. This study aims to compare the classical approach in which we await signs of clinical coaguloplatia with a proactive approach in which the fibrinogen replacement is performed early using concentrated fibrinogen. Objective is to evaluate a possible decrease in the amount of concentrates transfused RBCs when the anticipatory approach. This study shows is important because being original, prospective, since there is a shortage in world literature comparative studies in this regard.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Blood Coagulation Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemostatic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Trauma patients with ISS (Injury Severity Score) over than 15 Not eligible for massive transfusion protocol Hypofibrimogenemia diagnosed by Fibtem &lt; 9 Do not show clinical or laboratorial signs of coagulopathy Not signed consent term Pregnats Previous coaglupathy disorders Use of anticoagulants drugs and/or platelet anti aggregation drugs (exception of aspirin) Previous thromboembolic disorders Cardiopulmonary arrest at trauma Patient coming from another hospital More than 6 hours from trauma to hospital admission Patients with only traumatic brain injury</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Fibrinogen</keyword>
	<keyword>Tromboelastography</keyword>
</DOC>