<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02864342</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A randomized clinical study to assess the impact of Symbicort® pMDI medication reminders on adherence in COPD patients</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Adherence Study in COPD Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) is a common disease with substantial associated morbidity and mortality. COPD is the third leading cause of death in the US and claimed 133,965 US lives in 2009. In 2011 12.7 million US adults were estimated to have COPD. However, approximately 24 million US adults have evidence of impaired lung function, indicating an under diagnosis of COPD. COPD also has a potentially harmful economic impact. In 2010, COPD resulted in over 10 million office visits, nearly 1.5 million emergency department visits, 700,000 hospitalizations, and 133,575 deaths in the US. In 2010, US total medical treatment costs attributed solely to COPD (i.e., excluding comorbidities) were estimated to be $32.1 billion with an additional $3.9 billion in COPD costs resulting from worker absenteeism. Even in industrialized countries such as the US, where anti-smoking initiatives have been relatively successful, the legacy of past smoking behavior in aging populations ensures that the COPD burden will unavoidably continue to climb over the next 20 to 30 years. Adherence rates for inhaled combination therapy is poor (average 3.9 refills per year). COPD patients with lower adherence tend to have higher overall healthcare costs, as demonstrated in a 24 month study of 33,816 patients in the US, which found: Patients continuing therapy had lower costs of care by $3764 compared with patients who had ceased to take their maintenance therapy. COPD patients with higher adherence to prescribed regimens experienced fewer hospitalizations and lower Medicare costs (-$2185) than those who exhibited lower adherence behaviors. Given the poor adherence with inhaled combination therapy seen in patients with COPD, and associated morbidity/mortality and economic costs, the present study is being conducted to see if medication reminders can be used to improve adherence in this population.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Budesonide, Formoterol Fumarate Drug Combination</mesh_term>
	<criteria>For inclusion in the study subjects should fulfil the following criteria: Signed informed consent at Visit 1 prior to any study specific procedures Outpatient adults 40 years and older A diagnosis of COPD confirmed by a postbronchodilator Forced Expiratory Volume in 1 second/Forced Vital Capacity (FEV1/FVC) &lt;0.70 at some point in the past 3 years. Moderate to Very Severe COPD as defined by a postbronchodilator FEV1 &lt;80% of predicted on most recent spirometry. Had been on an ICS/LABA combination therapy of a brand and dose approved forCOPD, for at least 3 months prior to screening. Current or previous smoker with a smoking history equivalent to 10 or more pack years (1 pack year = 20 cigarettes smoked per day for 1 year). Willing to discontinue all medications containing both a LABA and an ICS and to begin Symbicort 160/4.5 μg, 2 inhalations bid. Must be willing to make a return visit, and complete all study assessments for the duration of study. Life expectancy &gt;12 months. Must be willing to comply with all study procedures including being able to remove and attach device to the inhaler. Must be able and willing to read and write/respond using the electronic device provided. Patients should not enter the study if any of the following exclusion criteria are fulfilled: Involvement in the planning and/or conduct of the study (applies to both AstraZeneca staff and/or staff at the study site). Previous randomization in the present study. Patients who have been randomized in a clinical study and received an investigational product within 30 days of Visit 1 (participation is defined as the completion of a treatment related visit). Current diagnosis of asthma. Known history of drug or alcohol abuse which, in the opinion of the Investigator, may interfere with subject's ability to participate or comply with the study. An acute exacerbation of COPD that required hospitalization or emergency room visit or treatment with systemic steroids and/or antibiotics during the 28 days before Visit 1. Patients who had a COPD exacerbation within 28 days of Visit 1 can be rescreened once. Rescreening can occur no earlier than 28 days from the last dose of systemic steroids and/or antibiotics and/or hospitalization, whichever is later. Enrolled patients that have a COPD exacerbation during the runin period, defined as worsening symptoms which in the judgment of the Investigator requires treatment with systemic steroids and/or antibiotics and/or hospitalization. Patients who had a COPD exacerbation during the runin period can be rescreened once. Rescreening can occur no earlier than 28 days from the last dose of systemic steroid and/or antibiotics and/or hospitalization, whichever is later. Any hospital admissions due to ischemic heart disease or heart failure within 3 months of study enrollment. Any significant disease or disorder (e.g., gastrointestinal, liver, renal, neurologic, musculoskeletal, endocrine, metabolic, infectious, psychiatric, major physical impairment) which, in the opinion of the Investigator, may either put the patient at risk because of participation in the study, or may influence the results of the study, or the patient's ability to participate in the study. History of lung or upper airway cancer and any other malignancy not in remission for 5 years or more, except for patients who have had basal cell carcinoma, or in situ carcinoma of the cervix provided that the patient is in remission and curative therapy was completed at least 12 months prior to the date informed consent was obtained. Use or planned use of systemic corticosteroids as a maintenance treatment (defined as daily or every other day treatment for 21 or more days) for inflammatory or immunologic conditions unrelated to their COPD. Planned hospitalization or surgical procedure requiring inpatient stay during the study. Pregnancy, breastfeeding or planned pregnancy during the study; fertile women not using acceptable contraceptive measures, as judged by the Investigator. Female subjects who are not postmenopausal or surgically sterile must have a negative urine pregnancy test (urine dipstick test only) prior to randomization and must comply with contraceptive methods. Any clinically relevant abnormal findings in physical examination or vital signs, which in the opinion of the Investigator, may put the patient at risk because of his/her participation in the study. Known or suspected hypersensitivity to the study therapy (Symbicort). Patients who are unable or unwilling to use mobile communication devices, or patients who plan to be away from home for a significant part of the study without access to cellular connectivity are excluded because of the challenges of collecting data and providing information to these patients who are unable to use the service. Patients with thoracic surgery within 6 months of Visit 1. Patients who have received a lung transplant or are currently active on the lung transplant waiting list.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>130 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>chronic obstructive pulmonary disease</keyword>
	<keyword>COPD</keyword>
	<keyword>Respiratory</keyword>
	<keyword>adherence</keyword>
	<keyword>medication reminders</keyword>
</DOC>