<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="166377">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00931879</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LVZ111903</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00931879</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Lovaza® and Microvascular Function in Type 2 Diabetes</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Role of Lovaza® on Microvascular Function and Lipoprotein Profile in Type 2 Diabetes</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Eastern Virginia Medical School</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>GlaxoSmithKline</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Eastern Virginia Medical School</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The objective of this study is to determine the efficacy of 6 months of 4 g/day oral Lovaza®
      on endothelial-dependent and heat-induced vasodilation in type 2 diabetics with neuropathy
      and elevated triglyceride levels. Omega-3 fatty acids appear to exert beneficial effects on
      vascular function that are independent of the changes in serum triglycerides. The efficacy
      will be compared with a placebo given at the same duration. Efficacy of the drug will be
      evaluated after 3 and 6 months of treatment. This timeline should be adequate for evaluation
      of the primary neurophysiological endpoints. Previously, the investigators have demonstrated
      that it is feasible to pharmacologically alter nerve fiber density in as little as 18 weeks
      and that this correlates with subjective and objective measures of neurovascular function.
      The investigators are predicting an enhancement of post-ischemic hyperemia of the foot
      dorsum, where the dilative mechanism is primarily endothelium-dependent and a similar
      improvement in heat-induced hyperemia.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This pilot study is a within-subject repeated measures design. This study will compare the
      neurophysiological and vascular responses to placebo and treatment with Lovaza®
      (omega-3-acid ethyl esters, Reliant Pharmaceuticals, Inc.) in subjects with type 2 diabetes,
      neuropathy, and dyslipidemia.

      Lovaza's potential mechanism of action is the inhibition of acyl CoA:1, 2-diacylglycerol
      acyltransferase and increased peroxisomal β-oxidation in the liver.

      Subjects will be recruited and a baseline of physiological, neurological and hematological
      profile established for each patient. Forty-four subjects (20 in the active arm, 20 in the
      placebo arm, and 2 replacements for each arm) will receive 4 g/day Lovaza® tablets or
      placebo for a period of 6 months. All subjects will receive a physical and neurological exam
      as well as neurovascular function testing. This includes nerve conduction studies,
      quantitative sensory testing, quantitative autonomic testing, and skin blood flow testing,
      which includes, ischemia reperfusion. Lab tests include an insulin resistance profile,
      hepatic and renal function profiles, lipid profile, C-reactive protein, thyroid stimulating
      hormone, and fatty acids. Other tests include inflammatory markers such as adiponectin and
      TNF-α. The study is powered to detect differences in microvascular function after 6 months
      of Lovaza® and differences in ethnic responses.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 2012</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 2012</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double Blind (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy measures are nerve conduction studies, specifically increases in conduction velocity and increased vascular response to ischemic block and to local warming at the dorsum of the foot.</measure>
    <time_frame>One year</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measurements of indices of large and small fiber nerve function include: vibration and thermal thresholds, heart rate variation, markers of inflammation, oxidative stress, dyslipidemia and diabetes control</measure>
    <time_frame>One year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">44</enrollment>
  <condition>Hypertriglyceridemia</condition>
  <condition>Diabetic Neuropathy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects are males or non-pregnant, non-lactating females age 18-80 years. All subjects must have been diagnosed with type 2 diabetes mellitus a minimum of two years according to the current ADA criteria and triglyceride levels above 149 mg/dL. Subjects in this arm will be taking placebo for 6 months.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lovaza</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects are males or non-pregnant, non-lactating females age 18-80 years. All subjects must have been diagnosed with type 2 diabetes mellitus a minimum of two years according to the current ADA criteria and triglyceride levels above 149 mg/dL. Subjects in this arm will be taking 4 g of Lovaza per day for 6 months.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>omega-3-acie ethyl esters</intervention_name>
    <description>Lovaza (TM) (omega-3-ethyl esters) 1 gram Capsules are indicated as an adjunct to diet to reduce very high (&gt;500 mg/dL) triglyceride (TG) levels in adult patients.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Lovaza</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Lovaza</other_name>
    <other_name>omega-3-ethyl esters</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Subjects may be males or non-pregnant, non-lactating females age 18-80 years.

          2. Subjects must have been diagnosed with type 2 diabetes mellitus according to the
             current ADA criteria.

          3. Triglyceride levels above 149 mg/dL

          4. Minimum of 2 years after diagnosis of type 2 diabetes

          5. Prior to participation in this study, each subject must sign an informed consent
             document.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Presence of type 1 diabetes mellitus (defined as C-peptide &lt; 1 ng/ml or diabetes
             onset at &lt; 35 years of age in a non-obese patient).

          2. Presence of diabetic retinopathy that is more severe than &quot;background&quot; level.

          3. Presence of diabetic nephropathy, defined by urine dipstick results greater than 300
             mg/100 mL for protein (proteinuria).

          4. Presence of clinically significant neuropathy that is clearly of non-diabetic origin,
             e.g. alcoholic or autoimmune.

          5. Bilateral amputation of lower extremities or foot ulcers involving the great toes.
             Presence of neuroarthropathy (Charcot deformity) is allowable.

          6. History of major macrovascular events such as myocardial infarction or stroke.

          7. Participation in another clinical trial concurrently or within 30 days prior to entry
             into this study.

          8. The use of ACE-inhibiting agents or angiotensin receptor blockade therapy (ARB) is
             allowed but must have been stable for at least 30 days prior to study entry and may
             not change during the course of the study. This is prudent due to their potential
             effects on blood flow.

          9. Patients with moderate or severe hepatic insufficiency or abnormalities of liver
             function defined as any liver enzymes (AST, ALT, alkaline phosphatase) greater than 3
             times the upper limit of normal.

         10. Presence of pedal edema.

         11. Presence or history of heart failure NYHA Class II or greater.

         12. Other serious medical conditions that in the opinion of the investigator, would
             compromise the subject's participation in the study.

         13. Concomitant use of medications known to exacerbate triglyceride levels, such as
             estrogens.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Aaron I Vinik, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Eastern Virginia Medical School</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Henri K Parson, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Eastern Virgina Medical School</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Strelitz Diabetes Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Norfolk</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>23510</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2012</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>August 14, 2012</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>June 17, 2009</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Eastern Virginia Medical School</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Aaron I. Vinik, MD, PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetic Neuropathies</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypertriglyceridemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
