<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00659633</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to study if lidocaine, given intravenously, reduces pain.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Intravenous Lidocaine on Allodynia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Clinicians use lidocaine intravenously in a fashion that suggests that it might have analgesic effects. Therefore, we test the hypothesis that lidocaine reduces pain intensity in response to experimental pain.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hyperalgesia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lidocaine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Chronic Regional Pain Syndrome diagnostic criteria by the Work Safe BC. vi History of Substance abuse Other Medications: CRPS patients are expected to be treated for chronic pain, whether the current treatment regimen interferes with sensory motor testing will be determined on a case by case basis. Coronary Artery Disease (CAD): unstable Congestive Heart Failure (CHF): unstable Heart Arrhythmia: symptomatic Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) Lidocaine Allergy Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (Rev IV): Axis I: Common Axis I disorders include depression, anxiety disorders, bipolar disorder, ADHD, and schizophrenia. Axis II: borderline personality disorder, schizotypal personality disorder, antisocial personality disorder, and mild mental retardation. Presence of Contraindications for MRI Presence of electronically, magnetically, and mechanically activated implants Electronically, magnetically, and mechanically activated implants Ferromagnetic or electronically operated active devices like automatic cardioverter defibrillators Cardiac pacemakers Metallic splinters in the eye Ferromagnetic haemostatic clips in the central nervous system (CNS) Claustrophobia Pregnancy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>lidocaine</keyword>
	<keyword>allodynia</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic regional pain syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>pain</keyword>
</DOC>