<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00659711</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Sitagliptin is a new oral hypoglycemic anti-diabetic drug used either alone or in combination with metformin or a thiazolidinedione for control of type 2 diabetes mellitus. Sitagliptin has been shown to have fewer side effects in the control of blood glucose values. Obesity and diabetes are states of increased inflammation and can influence the free radicals and inflammatory markers (chemicals in the blood which increase due to inflammation in the body) and are also major risk factors for atherosclerotic disease. In this study we want to see the effect of sitagliptin on these markers. We believe that Sitagliptin may exert an anti-inflammatory effect in the human. The purpose of this study is to determine if the addition of sitagliptin to diabetic patients will provide added benefit. We believe that sitagliptin provides these added benefits by suppressing free radicals (charged substances that cause damage to the body) and inflammation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Januvia (Sitagliptin) on Oxidative Stress in Obese Type 2 Diabetic Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Sitagliptin Phosphate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males or females with age 2075 years inclusive. Type 2 diabetes Males and Females BMI &gt; 30 Subjects on statins, ACE inhibitors, thiazolidenediones and antioxidants will be allowed as long as they are on stable doses of these compounds and the dosage in not changed during the course of study. BP under control No change required to BP medications HbA1c &gt; 7% Coronary event or procedure (myocardial infarction, unstable angina, coronary artery bypass, surgery or coronary angioplasty) in the previous four weeks Pregnancy Hepatic disease (abnormal LFT's),Renal impairment (serum creatinine &gt; 1.5), Participation in any other concurrent clinical trial Any other lifethreatening, noncardiac disease, Uncontrolled hypertension (BP &gt; 160/100 mm of Hg) Congestive Heart Failure Use of an investigational agent or therapeutic regimen within 30 days of study Subjects on Exenatide, incretin or insulin therapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>