<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00659360</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase II trial is studying how well AZD0530 works in treating patients with recurrent locally advanced, or metastatic soft tissue sarcoma. AZD0530 may stop the growth of tumor cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>AZD0530 in Treating Patients With Recurrent Locally Advanced or Metastatic Soft Tissue Sarcoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. To assess the efficacy of AZD0530, in terms of disease control rate (i.e., response rate and stable disease rate), in patients with recurrent locally advanced or metastatic soft tissue sarcoma. II. To assess the toxicity, time to progression, and response duration of AZD0530 in these patients. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Patients receive oral AZD0530 once daily in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study therapy, patients are followed every 8 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhabdomyosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leiomyosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liposarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mixed Tumor, Mullerian</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fibrosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Uterine Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Histiocytoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Histiocytoma, Benign Fibrous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Histiocytoma, Malignant Fibrous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dermatofibrosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoma, Endometrial Stromal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Saracatinib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Leukocytes &gt;= 3,000/mcL Histologically or cytologically confirmed soft tissue sarcoma including, but not limited to any of: Malignant fibrous histiocytoma Fibrosarcoma non infantile Leiomyosarcoma not uterine Liposarcoma Nonrhabdomyosarcoma soft tissue sarcoma Rhabdomyosarcoma, not otherwise specified Carcinosarcoma of the uterus Dermatofibrosarcoma Endometrial stromal sarcoma Leiomyosarcoma uterus Recurrent or locally advanced or metastatic disease No more than two prior lines of chemotherapy for metastatic disease (not including adjuvant chemotherapy) Measurable disease, defined as &gt;= 1 unidimensionally measurable lesion &gt;= 20 mm by conventional techniques or &gt;= 10 mm by spiral CT scan Target measurable lesion must not have been in previous radiation portal, unless progression of this lesion after radiotherapy has been documented ECOG performance status (PS) 02 or Karnofsky PS 60100% Life expectancy &gt; 12 weeks Recovered from all prior therapy Platelet count &gt;= 100,000/mcL Hemoglobin &gt; 9 g/dL Total bilirubin =&lt; 1.25 times upper limit of normal (ULN) AST and ALT =&lt; 3 times ULN Creatinine =&lt; 1.5 times ULN OR creatinine clearance &gt;= 50 mL/min Urine protein:creatinine ratio =&lt; 1.0 OR 24hour urine protein &lt; 1,000 mg ANC &gt;1,500/mcL Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception during and for 8 weeks after completion of study therapy No history of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biological composition to AZD0530 No QTc prolongation (defined as a QTc interval &gt;= to 460 msecs) or other significant ECG abnormalities No poorly controlled hypertension (i.e., systolic blood pressure (BP) &gt;= 140 mm Hg, or diastolic BP &gt;= 90 mm Hg) No condition that impairs a patient's ability to swallow AZD0530 tablets, including any of the following: Gastrointestinal tract disease resulting in an inability to take oral medication or a requirement for IV alimentation Prior surgical procedures affecting absorption Active peptic ulcer disease At least 4 weeks since prior chemotherapy (6 weeks for nitrosoureas or mitomycin C) No intercurrent cardiac dysfunction including, but not limited to, any of the following: Symptomatic congestive heart failure Unstable angina pectoris Cardiac arrhythmia No history of ischemic heart disease, including myocardial infarction No uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to ongoing or active infection or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements More than 4 weeks since prior radiotherapy More than 7 days since prior and no concurrent prohibited CYP3A4active agents or substances No other concurrent investigational agents or commercial agents or therapies No concurrent combination antiretroviral therapy for HIVpositive patients No known brain metastases</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>