<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03032874</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Patient age 45 year old and above who presented with rectal bleeding at three tertiary hospitals in South West Nigeria were invited for colonoscopy. The clinical information of the patients and the colonoscopy data were analyzed</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Community Based Screening for Colorectal Cancer in an Underserved High Risk Population in Nigeria</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patient age 45 year old and above who presented with rectal bleeding at Obafemi Awolowo University Teaching Hospitals Complex, Ile Ife, Nigeria, University College Hospital, Ibadan, Nigeria, and University of Ilorin Teaching Hospital, Ilorin Nigeria were invited for colonoscopy. Categorical variables were compared using χ2-test or Fisher's exact test while the Kruskal-Wallis test was used for quantitative variables. Multivariate analysis was performed using logistic regression model. All statistical tests were two-sided and p-values below 0.05 were considered statistically significant. Statistical analysis was carried out using SAS 9.4 and R 3.3.1.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>must be 45years of age or older has rectal bleeding lasting at least one week has had a complete colonoscopy performed Individuals with a personal history of inflammatory bowel disease, colorectal polyps, colorectal adenoma or CRC Individuals with a family history of familial adenomatous polyposis syndromes or other hereditary polyposis syndromes, hereditary nonpolyposis colorectal cancer Individuals with severe comorbidities that were contraindication to colonoscopy Individuals who had a previous history of colectomy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Colorectal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Polyps</keyword>
	<keyword>Colonoscopy</keyword>
	<keyword>Rectal bleeding</keyword>
	<keyword>Nigeria</keyword>
</DOC>