<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00574340</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Hypoglycemia (low blood glucose level) occurs frequently in intensively treated patients with diabetes. Although hypoglycemia was thought to occur almost exclusively in T1DM, with the advent of improved metabolic control in T2DM, the incidence of hypoglycemia is rising in these patients. Therefore in this application, we will test the novel hypothesis that prior hypoglycemia will result in (cardiovascular complications) during subsequent hypoglycemia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Metabolic Causes of Thrombosis in Type 2 Diabetes - Question 4</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will test the hypothesis that 1) hypoglycemia causes a prothrombotic state and defective endothelial function and 2) episodes of repeated hypoglycemia will result in greater impairments of endothelial function and an increased prothrombotic tendency. Preliminary data in healthy men demonstrates that hypoglycemia can dramatically increase PAI-1 levels and the PAI-1 to tPA ratio, thereby creating a prothrombotic state. Whether this also occurs in type 2 DM patients is unknown. Furthermore, the effects of hypoglycemia on endothelial function in T2DM are also unknown.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thrombosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypoglycemic Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria 14 (7 female/ 7 male) Type 2 diabetic patients age 1860 yrs 14 (7 female/ 7 male) Nondiabetic controls age and weight matched Body mass index &gt;20 kg/m2 Normal results of routine blood test to screen for hepatic, renal, and hematological abnormalities Female volunteers of childbearing potential: negative HCG pregnancy test Volunteers over 40 years old: normal baseline cardiac stress test For those with type 2 diabetes: HBA1C &gt;5.5% For those with type 2 diabetes: diabetes &lt; 20 years For those with type 2 diabetes: Cpeptide &gt;0.2 nmol (1.14.4 ng/ml). If cpeptide is abnormal or there is a clinical suspicion of type 1 diabetes, MODY, or LADA, AntiIslet cell (negative) and Glutamic Acid Decarboxylase (GAD) antibody negative (0.01.5 U/ml) will be performed Exclusion Criteria Uncontrolled hypertension History of cerebrovascular incidents Pregnancy Subjects unable to give voluntary informed consent Subjects with a recent medical illness Subjects on anticoagulant drugs, anemic, or with known bleeding diseases Tobacco Use Physical Exam Exclusion Criteria Blood Pressure greater than 150/95 Clinically significant Cardiac Abnormalities (e.g. Heart Failure, Arrhythmias, ischemic tachycardia, ST segment deviations, ect.) from history or from cardiac stress testing Pneumonia Hepatic Failure/Jaundice Renal Failure Acute Cerebrovascular/ Neurological deficit Fever greater than 38.0 C Screening blood tests exclusions according to protocol</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Type 2 Diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Endothelial Function</keyword>
	<keyword>Fibrinolytic Balance</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypoglycemia</keyword>
</DOC>