<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02007785</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study will be to determine the effects of the Cognitive Orientation to daily Occupational Performance (CO-OP) as a treatment program for individuals with Parkinson's disease-related cognitive impairment. The potential effects of the CO-OP on successful engagement in meaningful activities will be examined from participants' and live-in caregivers' perspectives. Effects of the CO-OP on participant-perceived health-related quality of life and caregiver burden will also be evaluated. Hypotheses: 1. Training with the CO-OP will have an effect or multiple effects on participation in meaningful activities and health-related quality of life for individuals with Parkinson's-related cognitive impairment. 2. Training with the CO-OP will have an effect or multiple effects on caregiver burden and health-related quality of life for caregivers of individuals with Parkinson's-related cognitive impairment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of the Effect of the Cognitive Orientation to Daily Occupational Performance (CO-OP) on Cognitive Impairment in Parkinson's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria for Participants with Parkinson's disease: Clinical diagnosis of Idiopathic Parkinson's Disease Presence of a livein caregiver or significant other who is willing to participate in the study Montreal Cognitive Assessment (MoCA) score above 16/30 and below 26/30 Schwab and England Activities of Daily Living Scale scores between 60% and 90% Hoehn and Yahr Scale scores between Stage 1 and Stage 3 Selfreported difficulty completing routine functional activities that may be related to new cognitive changes since PD diagnosis Exclusion Criteria for Participants with Parkinson's disease: Clinical diagnosis of atypical parkinsonism Clinical diagnosis of youngonset Parkinson's disease Comorbidities associated with cognitive impairment Poorly controlled depression Clinical diagnosis of dementia Residence outside boundaries of the city of Winnipeg, Manitoba, Canada Inclusion Criteria for Caregiver Participants: Live in the same residence as participant with Parkinson's Be willing to participate Exclusion Criteria for Caregiver Participants: Scores at or below 16/30 on Montreal Cognitive Assessment (MoCA)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cognitive Orientation to daily Occupational Performance</keyword>
	<keyword>CO-OP</keyword>
</DOC>