<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02007707</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goals of the study are to develop smoking cessation intervention using lay health worker (LHW) outreach and family involvement targeting Vietnamese Americans ages 18 and above in Santa Clara County, CA, to evaluate efficacy of the proposed intervention. The study is a two-arm randomized controlled trial targeting a total of 18 lay health workers (LHW) and 108 dyads of a smoker and a family member from the same household. The hypotheses are: H. At 6-month post initiation of the intervention, Vietnamese male daily smokers who receive the proposed ―Quit Smoking For a Healthy Family Intervention, a Family-based Intervention (FI), will be more likely to achieve biochemically verified 7-day point prevalence of smoking abstinence when compared to those receiving an attention control intervention (CI). H2. At 6-month, FI participants we be more likely to report making at least one 24-hour quit attempt than those in CI. H3. At 6-month, FI participants will be more likely to report using a recommended evidence-based smoking cessation resource (quitline, FDA-approved smoking cessation medications, advice from health professionals) than those in CI</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Family-Based Approach To Reduce Smoking in Vietnamese Men</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>selfidentified as Vietnamese, VietnameseAmerican, or VietnameseChinese; Vietnamese speaking; reside in the Santa Clara County, California plan to stay in the area (Santa Clara County, California) for the next 6 months for the smoker participants, they must be male and have smoked at least 1 cigarette daily in the past 7 days. for family member participants, the participant must live in the same household as the smoker participant to form a dyad. provide a valid contact telephone number for pre and postintervention assessments. For smoker participants, currently engaging in assisted smoking cessation efforts</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Asian American</keyword>
	<keyword>Vietnamese American</keyword>
	<keyword>Smoking cessation</keyword>
	<keyword>Community Health Worker</keyword>
	<keyword>Lay Health Worker Outreach</keyword>
	<keyword>Family Intervention</keyword>
</DOC>