<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02904239</DOC>
	<brief_summary>New technical developments make ultra-fast non-electrocardiogram (ECG) triggered scan acquisition with a high temporal resolution possible, which can be used for the evaluation of cardiac pathologies on a standard thoracic Computed Tomography (CT) scans. Current studies have shown that it is possible to assess the heart and it's coronary arteries on standard ultra-high pitch thoracic CT, which could result in incidental or new cardiac findings. However, to be able to perform a complete cardiopulmonary assessment on a thoracic CT scan, the injection protocol and bolus tracking settings could be optimised for both aortic and pulmonary vasculature (e.g. sufficient attenuation in pulmonary arteries, pulmonary trunk and ascending aorta). Therefore, the aim of the study is to evaluate the presence and extent of coronary artery disease, valvular morphology and calcification, pericardial abnormalities, and cardiac size on a standard ultra-high pitch thoracic CT-scan with individualised injection protocols.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Cardiac Pathologies on Thoracic CT</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Standard nonECG triggered thoracic CT scanning. Severe allergy against Iopromide or any of the ingredients, Previous severe CM reaction (according to current European Society of Urogenital Radiology (ESUR) guidelines), Renal insufficiency, pregnancy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Contrast Media</keyword>
	<keyword>Multidetector Computed Tomography</keyword>
	<keyword>Individualized Medicine</keyword>
	<keyword>Radiation Dosage</keyword>
	<keyword>Incidental cardiac findings</keyword>
	<keyword>Thoracic high-pitch Computed Tomography</keyword>
</DOC>