<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02951546</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Nonalcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) is frequently associated with obesity. NAFLD genetic susceptibility involves Patatin Like Phospholipase Domain Containing 3 (PNPLA3) rs738409 and Transmembrane 6 Superfamily Member 2 (TM6SF2) rs58542926 polymorphisms. To date, biochemical mechanisms that affect the "metabolic flexibility" in obese NAFLD subjects, in presence or absence of genetic susceptibility, need to be better clarified. Different studies demonstrated that a dietary intervention, accompanied by a physical personalized training, significantly reduce either the hepatic fat content either insulin resistance in overweight and obese subjects, independently of weight loss. On these bases, the aim of the study is to evaluate "metabolic flexibility" in obese NAFLD subjects taking in account their genetics (presence or absence of PNPLA3 and TM6SF2 polymorphisms) and the histopathological diagnosis of either simple steatosis or nonalcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH). In addition, the composition of gut microbiota will be evaluated. Finally, in this study, two distinct healthy dietary profiles accompanied by a personalized physical training, will be tested in order to comprehend whether and how "healthy diets" could be effective not only in the prevention, but also in the clinical treatment of NAFLD and other related conditions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study on Metabolic Flexibility and Gut Microbiota Composition in Obese Subjects With NAFLD, Taking Into Account PNPLA3 and TM6SF2 Polymorphisms. Effects of Nutritional Intervention Combined to Exercise</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fatty Liver</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Non-alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>body mass index (BMI) &gt; 30 Kg/m2 and &lt; 40 Kg/m2; Caucasian Italian subjects hepatic steatosis according with ultrasonographic Hamaguchi's criteria and/or hypertransaminasemia (ALT &gt;30 IU/L in men and &gt;20 IU/L in women) any malignant disease during the last 5 years; any inflammatory or autoimmune disease; corticosteroids for systemic use; renal failure (GFR&lt;90 ml/min); heart failure (NYHA classes IIIV); history of viral or autoimmune liver disease; any cause cirrhosis; excessive alcohol intake (&gt;140g/week for men and 70g/week for women); participation in a reducingweight program in the last 3 months; level of physical activity higher than 3 METs; therapy with antibiotics during the last 3 months; bile salts, cholestyramine during the last 6 months before enrollment; previous cholecystectomy; gallbladder disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>