<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02951078</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is to verify the short-term efficacy and long-term prognosis of thulium laser resection compared with conventional transurethral resection of non-muscular invasive bladder cancer. Half of participants will receive thulium laser resection of bladder cancer, while the other half will receive electrical transurethral resection of bladder cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Comparing Effects of Thulium Laser en Bloc Resection and Electrical Transurethral Resection of the Non-muscle Invasive Bladder Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Pathological or histological diagnosis of primary nonmuscle invasive bladder urothelial carcinoma (TaTisT1); 2. Imaging examinations showed the bladder muscle has not been affected, no lymph node metastasis or distant metastasis; 3. Patients who agree to TURBT surgery, and will be effected to the postoperative followup treatment such as conventional infusion after the operation; 4. Function of main organs (heart, liver, lung, kidney) should be normal, PS score 02; 5. Bladder capacity≥ 200ml. 1. Find distant metastasis ,infiltration of the surrounding organs or relapse before operation.Metastatic bladder cancer or other cancers involve the bladder; 2. Received chemotherapy or BCG perfusion therapy in the nearly 3 months; 3. Patients who can not tolerate the serious side effects during the bladder perfusion treatment process (bladder irritation and other symptoms); 4. Patients during pregnancy ,critical care patients and patients who have other cases of surgical contraindications.Such as serious cardiovascular disease,coagulation abnormalities,nontransitional epithelial tumors( such as adenocarcinoma and squamous cell carcinoma),acute cystitis,can not be supine because of spinal deformity,untreated urethral stricture.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>