<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02745470</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aims this study is to explore the effect of a GLP-1 receptor agonist on the degree of brain activation and connectivity obtained by functional magnetic resonance imaging in lean and obese type 2 diabetes</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of a GLP-1 Receptor Agonist on Functional Activation and Connectivity of the Brain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Fifteen lean [BMI(body mass index) less than 23 kg/m2] type 2 diabetes subjects and fifteen obese (BMI more than 26 kg/m2) subjects with type 2 diabetes treated by diet and/or metformin, SU(sulfonylurea), DPP4-inhibitors(Dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitor) will be recruited. Every subject will be studied on 2 separate days in random order with 1-2 week intervals. These participants will be injected either normal saline or 10 mcg of lixisenatide in a cross-over fashion. Neuroimaging composed with resting-12-min, visual stimulation task-12-min, T1-5-min, and diffusion tensor image-12-min will be proceeded. Ad lib buffet will be provided to every participant and the intake will be measured. Surveys about appetite and mood will be done before and after neuroimaging test and buffet eating.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glucagon-Like Peptide 1</mesh_term>
	<criteria>BMI ≤ 23kg/m2 or BMI ≥ 26kg/m2 participants with diabetes treated by diet or oral antidiabetic drug, HbA1c less than 8.5% Those who diagnosed by Type 1 diabetes History of insulin therapy Aspartate aminotransferase(AST) or Alanine transaminase(ALT) &gt;2.5 times of upper normal reference range Estimated Glomerular Filtration Rate(eGFR) &lt;30 mL/min/1.73m2 Those who can't be performed MRI</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>lean/obese diabetes mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>functional MRI</keyword>
	<keyword>GLP-1</keyword>
	<keyword>appetite</keyword>
	<keyword>activation of brain</keyword>
	<keyword>connectivity</keyword>
</DOC>