<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01586715</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the practicability of the autologous e-ASC (Autologous Stem Cells) for the treatment of extremely complex and treatment resistant perianal fistulae.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Stem Cells Treatment for Extremely Complex Fistulae (HULPCIR)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fistula</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rectal Fistula</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Signed informed consent Extremely Complex perianal fistulae Men and women over 18 years old. Good general state of health according to the findings of the clinical history and the physical examination Previous failure in at least one closing fistula standard treatment Presence of severe proctitis or dominant active luminal disease requiring immediate therapy Patients with an abscess unless a complete toilet of the area with drainage of the collections and the absence of abscess and other collections is confirmed prior to treatment start Patients with a history of abuse of alcohol or other addictive substances in the 6 months prior to inclusion Patients with malignant tumor, except for basal cell or cutaneous squamous cell carcinoma, or patients with a prior history of malignant tumors, unless the neoplastic disease has been in remission for the previous 5 years Patients with cardiopulmonary disease which, in opinion of the investigator, in unstable or sufficiently serious to exclude the patient from the study. Patients with any type of medical or psychiatric disease which, in the opinion of the investigator, could be grounds for exclusion from study Patients with congenital or acquired immunodeficiencies. HIV, HBV, HCV or treponema infection, whether active or latent Patients who have suffering major surgery or severe trauma in the prior 6 months Pregnant or breastfeeding women Patients currently receiving, or having received within 1 month prior to enrollment into this clinical trial, any investigational drug</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Extremely complex perianal fistula</keyword>
	<keyword>Adipose Derived Stem Cells</keyword>
</DOC>