<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01586819</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is being done to find out if the use of botulinum toxin prior to a medium strength combination chemical peel (Jessner's peel followed by 35% Trichloroacetic acid peel) will improve the appearance of crow's feet wrinkles when compared to a chemical peel alone. Botulinum toxin type A is a purified substance, derived from a bacteria that block muscular nerve signals. Jessner's Peel, a combination of resorcinol (14g), salicylic acid (14g), and lactic acid (85%) in ethanol (95%), is a superficial chemical peel. These two products/procedures have been FDA approved to improve the appearance of facial wrinkles.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Lateral Canthal Rhytides With Medium Depth Chemical Peel With or Without Pretreatment With Botulinum Toxin A</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Wrinkling in the skin is caused by habitual facial expressions, aging, sun damage, smoking, poor hydration, and various other factors. There are two major types of wrinkles—dynamic and static. Dynamic wrinkles, which are due to excessive muscle activity, usually of the face, tend to disappear when you relax your facial muscles. The most common of these dynamic wrinkles are frown lines, forehead wrinkles, and eye wrinkles (or crow's feet). However, if the excessive muscle activity is carried on for too long, these do not disappear completely on relaxation, and are thus called static wrinkles. Static wrinkles are formed either by chronic excessive muscle activity or are due to the effects of age and gravity, with a loss of subcutaneous fat. Examples of static wrinkles are the nasolabial folds, which are the deep grooves running from the sides of the nose to the corners of the mouth.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Botulinum Toxins, Type A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>incobotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>abobotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>onabotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Botulinum Toxins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 30 to 75 years old In good health Has static and dynamic lateral canthal wrinkles ("crow's feet") Has the willingness and the ability to understand and provide informed consent and communicate with the investigator Pregnant or lactating Has received the following treatments: botulinum toxin injections in the past 6 months ablative laser procedure in the past 6 months radiofrequency device treatment in the past 6 months ultrasound device treatment in the past 6 months medium to deep chemical peel in the past 6 months temporary soft tissue augmentation material in the past year semipermanent soft tissue augmentation material in the past 2 years permanent soft tissue augmentation material Is planning to receive within the next 3 months, any cosmetic procedure (such as any chemical peels, botulinum toxin injections, ablative or nonablative laser procedures, filler injections, radiofrequency procedures, dermabrasion, ultrasound and face lifting procedures) Has an active infection on their face (excluding mild acne Has a history of neuromuscular disorders Has an allergy to albumin Has an allergy to Aquaphor AND petroleum jelly Has a history of bleeding disorders Is unable to understand the protocol or to give informed consent Has a mental illness</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>