<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01586806</DOC>
	<brief_summary>For patients undergoing Anterior Cruciate Ligament reconstruction surgery, the postoperative period can be a painful experience without adequate pain management. Hence the investigators propose a randomized controlled clinical study, investigating prolonged saphenous nerve blocks. Patients will be randomized to receive saphenous nerve blocks with or without dexamethasone, a corticosteroid used to prolong analgesia. Depending on the randomized treatment assignment, patients may receive one of the following: 1. 13 ml of 0.5% bupivacaine, a local anesthetic (no dexamethasone); 2. 13 ml of 0.5% bupivacaine mixed with 1 mg of dexamethasone; 3. 13 ml of 0.5% bupivacaine mixed with 4 mg of dexamethasone. Patients will be followed postoperatively. Following admission to the recovery room, data collectors will ask patients to rate their pain on a scale of 0-10 until discharge. Data collectors will also record patient satisfaction, pain medication use and any side effects experienced (i.e. nausea and vomiting). Patients will then be contacted on postoperative days 1, 2 and 14 and asked questions about their general well-being.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparing Subsartorial Saphenous Nerve Blocks With and Without Dexamethasone for Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bupivacaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics, Local</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients undergoing ambulatory surgery for anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) reconstruction with a patella tendon autograft. ASA IIII [American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) Physical Status classification system] BMI &lt; 35 Smokers included Ages 1665 Patients on steroids or requiring stress dose steroids BMI &gt; 35 Patient refusal Allergy to study medications, NRS scores &gt; 3 with frequent opioid use (including tramadol) prior to surgery—daily for greater than 3 weeks Lower extremity neurological dysfunction Diabetic (NIDDM, insulindependent and/or oral hypoglycemic dependent) Not in included age range (under 16 or over 65 years of age) Contraindications to the use of dexamethasone NonEnglish speaking patients. We will be using the Short Form 8 Health Survey, as well as the ORSDS questionnaire (these are in English; any translations would have to be separately validated).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dexamethasone</keyword>
	<keyword>Glucocorticoids</keyword>
	<keyword>Physiological Effects of Drugs</keyword>
	<keyword>Therapeutic Uses</keyword>
	<keyword>Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction</keyword>
	<keyword>Regional Anesthesia, nerve block</keyword>
	<keyword>Ultrasonic Imaging</keyword>
	<keyword>Post-Operative Complications: muscle weakness, pain, nausea and vomiting</keyword>
	<keyword>Dexamethasone (as local anesthetic additive)</keyword>
</DOC>