<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01586260</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this research study is to evaluate a new investigational drug to prevent reoccurrence of neuroblastoma that is in remission. This study drug is called DFMO. The objectives of this study will be to monitor for safety and look at efficacy of DFMO. The safety of the proposed dosing regimen in this trial will be tested by an on-going risk/benefit assessment during the study. A patient benefiting from treatment, not progressing on therapy, and in the absence of any safety issues associated with DFMO may continue on treatment up to 27 cycles with the expectation that there will be an overall clinical benefit. The procedures involved in this study include Medical history, Physical exam, Vital signs (blood pressure, pulse, temperature), Blood tests, Urine tests, MRI or CT scan of the tumor(s), MIBG scans, and Bone marrow aspirations. All of these tests and procedures are considered standard of care for this population. Drug administration is also part of this protocol, including an investigational new drug called DFMO. The proposed dosing regimen is an oral dose of DFMO tablets two times a day for each day while on study. There will be 27 cycles. Each cycle will be 28 days in length.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Preventative Trial of DFMO in Patients With High Risk Neuroblastoma in Remission</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Neuroblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eflornithine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age: 021 years at the time of diagnosis. Diagnosis: histologic verification at either the time of original diagnosis or a previous relapse of high risk neuroblastoma. Disease Status: Neuroblastoma that is in remission Greater than 30 days from completion of cytotoxic and biologic therapy and less than 120 days from previous therapy. A negative urine pregnancy test is required for female subjects of child bearing potential (onset of menses or ≥13 years of age). Both male and female postpubertal study subjects need to agree to use one of the more effective birth control methods during treatment and for six months after treatment is stopped. These methods include total abstinence (no sex), oral contraceptives ("the pill"), an intrauterine device (IUD), levonorgestrol implants (Norplant), or medroxyprogesterone acetate injections (Depoprovera shots). If one of these cannot be used, contraceptive foam with a condom is recommended. ANC &gt; 500/μl and platelet count &gt;50,000/μl Organ Function Requirements: Subjects must have adequate liver function as defined by: AST and ALT &lt;10x upper limit of normal Serum bilirubin must be ≤ 2.0 mg/dl Serum creatinine based on age/gender Informed Consent: All subjects and/or legal guardians must sign informed written consent. Assent, when appropriate, will be obtained according to institutional guidelines Lansky score &lt; 60% BSA (m2) of &lt;0.25 Investigational Drugs: Subjects who are currently receiving another investigational drug are excluded from participation. Anticancer Agents: Subjects who are currently receiving other anticancer agents are not eligible. Subjects must have fully recovered from the effects of prior chemotherapy (hematological and bone marrow suppression effects). Infection: Subjects who have an uncontrolled infection are not eligible until the infection is judged to be well controlled in the opinion of the investigator. Subjects who, in the opinion of the investigator, may not be able to comply with the safety monitoring requirements of the study, or in whom compliance is likely to be suboptimal, should be excluded.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Neuroblastoma in remission</keyword>
	<keyword>Relapsed Neuroblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Refractory Neuroblastoma</keyword>
</DOC>