<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01448668</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Efficacy and safety of a supportive treatment with European mistletoe extract Iscador® Qu ("quercus", i.e. from oak tree) in patients with pancreatic cancer (Union for International Cancer Control, UICC stages II-IV), in addition to conventional oncological therapy (radio-, chemo-, targeted therapy) as compared to a parallel group with conventional therapy only. Primary Endpoints: Reduction of adverse effects of conventional therapy; reduction of therapy or disease induced symptoms (both are quality of life parameters and evaluated after 1 year); prolongation of disease free and/or overall survival (DFS, OS) after 3 years. Prospective observational confirmation study of previous retrospective cohort study. As this is a non-interventional cohort study, all therapies and measurements are performed on directive by the treating physician and/or request by the patient only.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Iscador Qu as Supportive Treatment in Pancreatic Cancer (Union for International Cancer Control, UICC Stages II-IV)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>see summary</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Viscum album peptide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Confirmed diagnosis of pancreatic cancer, adenocarcinoma, UICC stage IIIV Age between 18 (Austria: 19) and 85 years No previous malign tumor ECOG 02 Estimated life expectancy &gt; 3 months Surgical resection of the tumor (R0, R1) or determination of interoperability Conventional oncological therapy and measurements, or passive aftercare ("best care") Followup for several years feasible Patient gives written consent to use the anonymized date for evaluation Other Iscador® sorts than Qu in the test group Other mistletoe preparations in the test group Any mistletoe preparation in the control group Nononcological immunomodulating, stimulating or suppressive drugs (e.g. Echinacea, interferons, Polyerga®, BCG, azathioprine). Allowed are approved tumor inhibiting immuno or targeted therapies (e.g. bevacizumab, cetuximab) and tumor specific vaccines HIV infection, Aids, organ transplantation Contraindications for Iscador® Qu (allergy against mistletoe, acute inflammatory disease or fever &gt; 38.5°C, active tuberculosis, hyperthyreosis with notadjusted metabolism, primary brain or spinal tumor, brain metastases) Patients participating in another clinical study with nonapproved substances</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>pancreatic cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>mistletoe</keyword>
	<keyword>supportive treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>long-term study</keyword>
	<keyword>non-interventional cohort study</keyword>
	<keyword>controlled study with parallel groups</keyword>
</DOC>