<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02002000</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Non-systematized chronic musculoskeletal pains are a frequent reason for consulting in general practice. The possible causes are numerous and sometimes nonspecific. In some cases, the etiologic investigation of patients with non-systematized and chronic musculoskeletal pain can not highlight any organic cause. Several studies have shown a link between these symptoms and vitamin D deficiency, characterized by a blood level of 25 (OH) vitamin D &lt; 20.8ng/ml. This deficit is easy to identify and to correct through proper vitamin D supplementation with few side effects. Nevertheless, it remains unknown and vitamin D deficiency is rarely considered as a possible etiology in patients with chronic pain. We hypothesize that vitamin D supplementation in patients with non-systematized musculoskeletal pain and deficient in vitamin D could improve painful symptoms. We aim to perform a double-blind randomized controlled trial, vitamin D versus placebo, to assess the pain improvement after vitamin D supplementation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Chronic Pain and Vitamin D</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Musculoskeletal Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholecalciferol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women and men Aged 1850 years (included) Consulting their general practitioner With chronic and diffuse musculoskeletal pain, without known etiology, lasting for at least 3 months With a 25(OH)vitamin D deficiency &lt;20.8 ng/ml (52 nmol/l) at inclusion Who signed the consent form Identifiable source of pain requiring an appropriate specific management Disease or treatment that may interfere with the metabolism of vitamin D Current or previous hypercalcemia or hypercalciuria, treatment with digitalics and patients with history of nephrolithiasis Current treatment with vitamin D or at least one vitamin D vial taken over the previous 6 months Pregnancy or breastfeeding not affiliated to a social security system Refusal or inability to give consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Vitamin D deficiency</keyword>
	<keyword>Musculoskeletal pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Vitamin D supplementation</keyword>
</DOC>