<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02002299</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate the invasive front in growth mode (expanding or infiltrative) and dedifferentiation (tumor budding) and comparing these with the tumor surface (polypose or flat) + / - ulceration in surgical specimens at colorectal cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Does Surface Tell us About the Invasive Front in Colorectal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Timetable: From 1 August 2013 to 31 July 2014. Organisational arrangements: The project is deleted from the pathology department, Roskilde Hospital, and surgical department, Roskilde Hospital. inclusion criteria All colorectal surgical specimens having cancer were the patient did not receive neoadjuvant treatment received in the pathology department in accordance with current guidelines with the cutting of the tumor area in parallel slices and photographed, so there is macroscopic photo documentation. Microscopic tumors classified as adenocarcinoma of glandular type, mucinous adenocarcinoma, signet ring cell carcinoma. When the specimens is received at the department of pathology and is included in the study the pathologist report is registered in a local database.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All surgical preparations from patients with colorectal cancer that did not receive neoadjuvant treatment received in the pathology department in accordance with current guidelines with the cutting of the tumor area in parallel slices and photographed, so there is macroscopic photo documentation. Microscopic tumors classified as adenocarcinoma of glandular type, mucinous adenocarcinoma, signet ring cell carcinoma. All surgical preparations from patients with colorectal cancer where the patient received neoadjuvant therapy or when surgery preparation could not be received by current guidelines and all preparations where it is not possible to obtain macroscopic image of the parallel slices. Microscopic tumors that can not be classified as adenocarcinoma of the glandular type, mucinous adenocarcinoma or signet ring cell carcinoma excluded.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>colorectal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>surface</keyword>
	<keyword>invasive front</keyword>
	<keyword>tumor budding</keyword>
</DOC>