<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02002897</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study aims at evaluating the efficacy of the fractional carbon dioxide laser as a new modality for treatment of localized scleroderma and to compare its results with the well established method of UVA 1 phototherapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Fractional Carbon Dioxide Laser Versus UVA 1 in Treatment of Localized Scleroderma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study includes 20 Cases presenting with one or more lesions of morphea (plaque, linear and atrophic). Each case will be subjected to: 1. -Informed consent. 2-Detailed history 3- Clinical examination to assess type, site, extent. 4-Clinical evaluation before treatment, in the follow up period and after treatment ( 24 sessions of UVA1) (one month after last CO2 laser session) using a scoring system: - Skin thickness: 0-3, 0: normal; 1: thickened skin; 2: decreased ability to move the skin; 3: unable to pinch or move skin (according to the Modified Rodnan skin score) - Dermal atrophy: 0-3, 0: none, 1: shiny, 2: visible vessels, 3: obvious atrophy - Dyspigmentation (Hypo or hyper pigmentation): 0-3, 0: none, 1: mild, 2: moderate ,3: marked C- Digital Photography before, follow up and after treatment using the same digital camera , at fixed distance and constant settings for standardization . 5-Investigations: A- Punch biopsy: A punch biopsy will be taken before and after treatment to be stained with haematoxylin and eosin. B-Immunohistochemical assessment of - MMP1 (matrix metalloproteinase 1) in the pre and post treatment skin biopsies. - TGFß ( transforming growth factor beta)in the pre and post treatment skin biopsies. 6-Treatment intervention: Two lesions with identical scoring will be chosen for the treatment interventions. 1. Lesion number (1) will be subjected to: localized UVA1 phototherapy (340-400 nm), low dose irradiation, at a rate of 3 sessions per week , total of 24 sessions with full clinical evaluation and investigations before and after treatment and clinical follow up one month after treatment. 2. Lesion number (2) will be subjected to: Fractional carbon dioxide laser (10,600 nm), a session once per month, total of 3 sessions with full clinical evaluation and investigations before and one month after the last session of treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Scleroderma, Systemic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Scleroderma, Diffuse</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Scleroderma, Localized</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Types of morphea: plaque, linear and atrophic. 2. Patients are either new or discontinued systemic treatment for at least two months 1. Morphea profunda and systemic scleroderma (diagnosed by: Rayaund's Phenomenon and sclerodactyly +/ internal organ affection) 2. Contraindications to phototherapy: eg: photosensitivity, systemic lupus, melanoma, skin cancer, or porphyria. 3. Contraindications to laser: Use of systemic retinoids in the last 6 months.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Localized scleroderma UVA1 fractional carbon dioxide laser</keyword>
</DOC>