<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02846532</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Purpose of this study is to characterize the single and multiple-dose pharmacokinetic (PK) and pharmacokinetic/pharmacodynamic (PK/ PD) profiles after oral rivaroxaban therapy administered to pediatric participants 2 to 8 years of age with single ventricle physiology who have completed the Fontan procedure within 4 months prior to enrollment (Part A) and to evaluate the safety and efficacy of rivaroxaban, administered twice daily (exposure matched to rivaroxaban 10 milligram [mg] once daily in adults) compared to acetylsalicylic acid (ASA), given once daily (approximately 5 milligram per kilogram [mg/kg]) for thromboprophylaxis in pediatric participants 2 to 8 years of age with single ventricle physiology who have completed the Fontan procedure within 4 months prior to enrollment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacokinetic, Pharmacodynamic, Safety, and Efficacy Study of Rivaroxaban for Thromboprophylaxis in Pediatric Participants 2 to 8 Years of Age After the Fontan Procedure</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Part A: This part includes a 12-day Initial PK, PD, and Safety Assessment Period. Participants in Part A will not participate in Part B. Randomization in Part B of this study will begin once the cumulative data from the Initial PK, PD, and Safety Assessment Period in Part A are deemed acceptable by the Independent Data Monitoring Committee. Part A of the study will consist of an up to 21-day Screening Period, a 12-day Initial PK, PD, and Safety Assessment Period, a 12-month Open-Label Treatment Period, and a 30-day Follow-Up phone contact. Part B: Participants will be randomly assigned to two treatment groups and randomization ratio will be 2:1 for rivaroxaban and ASA. ASA will be used as control. There will be an up to a 21-day Screening Period, a 12 month Open-Label Treatment Period and a 30-day Follow-Up phone contact.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Thrombosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aspirin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rivaroxaban</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participant must be considered to be clinically stable by the investigator and able to tolerate oral or enteral administration of a suspension formulation and oral/enteral feedings Satisfactory initial postFontan transthoracic echocardiographic Screening as defined in the PostFontan Echocardiographic Examination Research Protocol Parent/legally acceptable representative must sign an informed consent form (ICF) and child assent will also be provided, if applicable, according to local requirements Evidence of thrombosis, including those that are asymptomatic confirmed by postFontan procedure transthoracic echocardiogram, or other imaging techniques, during the Screening period of the study History of gastrointestinal disease or surgery associated with clinically relevant impaired absorption History of or signs/symptoms suggestive of proteinlosing enteropathy Active bleeding or high risk for bleeding contraindicating antiplatelet or anticoagulant therapy, including a history of intracranial bleeding Platelet count less than (&lt;)50*10^9/Liters (L) at Screening Creatinine clearance (CrCl) &lt;30 milliliters per minute per 1.73 meter square (mL/min/1.73m^2) Known clinically significant liver disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>8 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Thromboembolism</keyword>
	<keyword>Fontan Procedure</keyword>
	<keyword>Children</keyword>
</DOC>