<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00680277</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this protocol is to determine the vitamin A value (equivalence) of spirulina. The investigation will use intrinsically deuterium labeled spirulina and an isotope vitamin A reference dose, 13C10- retinyl acetate (13C10 RAc), in males (n=20). Up to 45 blood samples (10 ml/sample) will be collected from each subject over a two-month period to evaluate the bioavailability and bioconversion of spirulina ß-carotene to vitamin A.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Vitamin A Value of Spirulina Carotenoids in Humans</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>By utilizing novel stable isotope dilution techniques recently developed in our laboratory, we will trace deuterium labeled ß-carotene in intrinsically labeled spirulina, which is harvested from a hydroponic system. In the mean time, we will track 13C10 labeled vitamin A in humans. In this way we will determine absorption of ß-carotene from spirulina matrix and the conversion of the spirulina ß-Carotene to retinol. This will enable us quantitatively determine the vitamin A equivalence of spirulina. The specific aims of this study are: 1. To determine labeled ß-C blood response kinetics following an acute dose of intrinsically labeled spirulina; 2. To determine labeled retinol blood response from the intrinsically labeled spirulina; 3. To determine 13C10 retinol blood response from the isotope reference material 13C10 retinyl acetate; 4. To determine s spirulina-vitamin A equivalence.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Retinol palmitate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carotenoids</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy volunteer Not has GI track problems Any medical condition that will affect the intestinal absorption</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>spirulina</keyword>
	<keyword>carotenoids</keyword>
</DOC>