<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00680719</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This project involves two studies focusing on the engagement and treatment of adolescents diagnosed with substance use disorders. Study 1 will evaluate a promising parent-based engagement intervention, Community Reinforcement Training, designed to facilitate the entry of resistant drug-abusing adolescents in treatment. The approach will be compared with an Engagement As Usual intervention condition. Study 2 involves a controlled clinical trial evaluating the efficacy of an HIV/AIDS prevention intervention embedded in family-based drug abuse treatment for reducing HIV/AIDS risk behaviors and substance use. Adolescents who are successfully engaged in treatment through Study 1 will be randomly assigned to receive either family therapy alone or family therapy with the integrated HIV/AIDS prevention intervention. Both studies are being conducted in Portland, Oregon.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Preventing HIV/Aids in Drug Abusing Youth</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Parents have an adolescent in the ages of 1520 years. Have had contact with the adolescent on at least 40% of the past 90 days. Have some knowledge or evidence that the adolescent would meet DSMIV diagnostic criteria for a substance abuse disorder. Adolescent has explicitly refused to attend any intake or therapy sessions. All parents' efforts to enter adolescent into treatment have failed, despite therapist's assistance. Residence in Portland vicinity. Sufficient residential stability to permit probable contact at followup. (e.g. not homeless at time of intake) Evidence of psychotic or organic state of sufficient severity to interfere with understanding of study instruments and procedures. Adolescent has received residential drug treatment longer than a 2week period in the past 90 days.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>20 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>substance abuse</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV risk</keyword>
	<keyword>Behavior and Mental Disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV Seronegativity</keyword>
</DOC>