<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00523367</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine which COPD patients have GERD and if COPD patients with GERD treated with high dose lansoprazole for 1 year decreases the frequency of COPD exacerbations compared to the previous year without treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>COPD Patients Diagnosed With GERD,COPD Exacerbations After Treatment With High Dose PPI</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Gastroesophageal reflux disease (GERD) is a common esophageal disorder with 40% of the US adult population experiencing symptoms monthly. Pulmonary diseases associated with GERD may include pneumonia, pulmonary fibrosis, asthma, or chronic bronchitis. The latter may be a manifestation of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), suggesting GERD as a risk factor for acute exacerbation of COPD. Acute exacerbations of COPD are a major cause of morbidity and mortality in patients with the disease. Recent work suggests that COPD patients with a minimum of weekly reflux symptoms have an increased number of COPD exacerbations that those who are either asymptomatic or have GERD symptoms less than once a week. On this basis, we theorized that in patients with COPD, who also have gastro esophageal reflux disease are at increase risk for acute exacerbations of COPD. To test this question, we will determine which COPD patients have GERD by 24 hour pH testing, treat their GERD with esomeprazole or lansoprazole for 1 year, and compare the number of COPD exacerbations during the treatment period to the previous year.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gastroesophageal Reflux</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Esomeprazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>diagnosis of COPD forced expiratory volume/forced vital capacity ratio (FEV1/FVC) of &lt; 70% on pulmonary function testing age &gt; 40 years &gt;20 pack year history of smoking presence of the following disorders: respiratory disorders other than COPD, known esophageal disease such as cancer, achalasia, stricture, active peptic ulcer disease, ZollingerEllison syndrome, mastocytosis, scleroderma, or current abuse of alcohol defined as greater than three alcoholic drinks per day.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Gastro Esophageal Reflux Disease (GERD)</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD)</keyword>
</DOC>