<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00523965</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Rationale The overall objective of this trial is to identify a safe and effective combination, (co-administration) short course treatment for the treatment of VL which could be easily deployed in a control programme. The hypothesis is that the combination treatment is as effective or better than the 5 mg/kg single dose of AmBisome and will reduce the risk of parasite resistance occurring. Safety and tolerability should be such that the combination can be easily deployed. Objective The specific primary and secondary objectives are as follows: Primary objective: To identify a short course combination treatment regimen which is at least as effective as a single dose of AmBisome 5mg/kg Secondary objective: To compare safety and tolerability of the various treatments measured by vital signs, blood biochemistry, (renal and liver function tests) haematology, spontaneous and elicited adverse event reporting Primary Endpoint: The primary efficacy endpoint variable is parasitological clearance 2 weeks after start of treatment with no relapse during follow up and no clinical signs or symptoms of VL at 6 months post treatment. Parasitology is only carried out at any time during follow-up or at six months post treatment if there are signs or symptoms of VL infection.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Combination Therapy in Indian Visceral Leishmaniasis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Leishmaniasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leishmaniasis, Visceral</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amphotericin B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paromomycin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liposomal amphotericin B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amphotericin B, deoxycholate drug combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Miltefosine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Deoxycholic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients &gt; 5 years old with symptoms and signs of kalaazar (fever, weight loss, splenomegaly) and parasites demonstrated by microscopy in splenic aspirate smear Pregnant or breastfeeding women Individuals seropositive to HIV or individuals with a serious concurrent infection such as tuberculosis or bacterial pneumonia. Women of childbearing age will be counseled about adequate birth control during and for three months after miltefosine treatment and provided with a satisfactory method of contraception. Granulocyte count &lt; 1,000/mm3, hemoglobin &lt; 5 g/dL or platelet count &lt; 40,000/mm3 Hepatic transaminases or total bilirubin greater than three times normal Serum creatinine &gt; 2.0 mg/dL Prothrombin time &gt; 5 seconds above control Inability of subject or guardian to provide written informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Kala-azar</keyword>
	<keyword>miltefosine</keyword>
	<keyword>liposomal amphotericin B</keyword>
</DOC>