<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02004366</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A total of 280 patients with type 2 diabetes (T2DM) who have undergone surgical procedure will be enrolled in the study. These patients could be on diet, oral hypoglycemia medication or low dose insulin prior to their admission. This study is a prospective, randomized, open label trial to compare the safety and efficacy of linagliptin (an oral anti diabetic medication) given orally once daily to an insulin regimen of glargine once daily plus rapid-acting insulin before meals. Both of these treatment groups will be given corrective doses of rapid-acting insulin analogs (aspart, lispro or glulisine) before meals if their blood sugars are &gt; 140 mg/dl. The patients will be monitored for their blood sugars while the hospital. If patients are agreeable to participate in the discharge part of the study, the investigators will randomized them to a treatment group based on their admission HbA1c. The investigators will follow these patients for 3 months with phone calls and clinic visits, and will monitor their blood sugars. This is to compare the efficacy of linagliptin and our discharge treatment algorithm in controlling blood sugars as out patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Linagliptin Inpatient Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Specific Aim 1: To determine whether in-hospital glycemic control, as measured by mean daily glucose concentration and frequency of hypoglycemic events, is different between treatment with linagliptin (Tradjenta®) plus correction doses with a rapid-acting insulin analog before meals and a basal bolus regimen with glargine once daily and rapid-acting insulin analog before meals in general surgery patients with T2D. Specific Aim 2: To determine the efficacy and safety of an A1C based discharge algorithm in controlling BG after discharge in patients with T2D. Patients who participate in the in-hospital arm (Aim 1) will be invited to enroll in this open label prospective outpatient study. The total duration of the study is 3 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Linagliptin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Glargine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Lispro</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Short-Acting</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypoglycemic Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Males or female surgical nonICU patients ages between18 and 80 years 2. A known history of T2D &gt; 1 month, receiving either diet alone, oral antidiabetic agents: sulfonylureas and metformin as monotherapy or in combination therapy (excluding DPP4 inhibitors) or lowdose (≤ 0.5 units/kg/day) insulin therapy. 3. Subjects with a BG &gt;140 mg and &lt; 400 mg/dL at time of randomization without laboratory evidence of diabetic ketoacidosis (serum bicarbonate &lt; 18 mEq/L or positive serum or urinary ketones) 1. Age &lt; 18 or &gt; 80 years. 2. Subjects with increased BG concentration, but without a history of diabetes (stress hyperglycemia). 3. Subjects with a history of type 1 diabetes (suggested by BMI &lt; 25 requiring insulin therapy or with a history of diabetic ketoacidosis and hyperosmolar hyperglycemic state, or ketonuria) (43). 4. Treatment with dipeptidyl peptidase4 (DPP4) inhibitor or Glucagonlike peptide1 (GLP1) analogs during the past 3 months prior to admission. 5. Acute critical illness or coronary artery bypass graft (CABG) surgery expected to require admission to a critical care unit. 6. Subjects with gastrointestinal obstruction or adynamic ileus or those expected to require gastrointestinal suction. 7. Patients with clinically relevant pancreatic or gallbladder disease. 8. Patients with previous history of pancreatitis 9. Patients with acute myocardial infarction, clinically significant hepatic disease or significantly impaired renal function (GFR &lt; 30 ml/min). 10. Chronic use of steroid with total daily dose (prednisone equivalent) &gt;5 mg/day 11. Mental condition rendering the subject unable to understand the nature, scope, and possible consequences of the study. 12. Pregnancy or breast feeding at time of enrollment into the study. 13. Patients who received supplemental sliding scale insulin &gt;72 hours prior to randomization 14. Patients who received basal insulin &gt; 48 hours prior to randomization</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Linagliptin</keyword>
	<keyword>hospital hyperglycemia</keyword>
	<keyword>inpatient diabetes</keyword>
</DOC>