<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00613808</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether nitric oxide (NO)gas is effective in the treatment of venous ulcers of the lower leg.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of Gaseous Nitric Oxide on Venous Stasis Leg Ulcers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>SUbjects were divided into two Groups - one receiving 200ppm NO gas delivered topically to the wound area for 8 hours a day for 6 weeks. The other Group (control arm) received Standard of Care (compression) for 22 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Varicose Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Postphlebitic Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Postthrombotic Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nitric Oxide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Must have given written informed consent and HIPAA authorization Must be ≥ 18 years of age Must have a venous ulcer for 60 days or greater ABPI &gt; 0.8 and ≤ 1.2 Must have ulcer between 3cm2 and 25cm2 in size Has an ulcer that is deemed by the Investigator to be caused primarily by a medical condition other than venous insufficiency BMI ≥ 35 Has evidence of clinical infection Suffers from diabetes mellitus with HbA1c ≥ 8% Suffers from clinically significant arterial disease Has a known allergy to any of the compounds / drugs that are part of this protocol Has evidence of the ulcer and / or infection extending to the underlying muscle, tendon or bone Has used any investigational drug(s) within 30 days preceding randomization Is unable to manage selftreatment Is pregnant, nursing mother or a woman of child bearing potential who is not using an adequate form of contraception (or abstinence) Suffers from a condition which in the opinion of the Investigator would compromise the safety of the subject and / or the quality of the data Is using any of the prohibited concomitant medications or treatments Has previously participated in this study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>venous</keyword>
	<keyword>leg</keyword>
	<keyword>ulcer</keyword>
</DOC>