<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00915486</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Although major improvements in the management and treatment of diabetic foot ulcers have been made, the clinical and financial burden of such long-term wounds is still high and is likely to increase as the general population ages. The large population affected by diabetic foot ulcers and the high rates of failure ending with amputation even with the best therapeutic regimens have resulted in the development of new therapies. I-020201 is a bioactive therapy intended for topical treatment of hard-to-heal diabetic foot ulcers, stimulating the granulation tissue formation. This study aims to evaluate the safety and efficacy of I-020201 in adjunct to good standard of care in patients with chronic diabetic foot ulcer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Dose Finding Study of Topically Applied I-020201 as an Adjunct to Good Standard-of-care in Patients With Chronic Diabetic Foot Ulcers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetic Foot</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Foot Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<criteria>male or female, aged ≥ 18 years given written informed consent female of childbearing potential with a negative result from the pregnancy test at screening who agrees to use an acceptable birth control method (hormonal or IUD) or abstinence throughout the trial Type 1 or Type 2 Diabetes mellitus with HbA1c =&lt; 12% with only one diabetic foot ulcer on the foot to be treated on or below the ankle pregnant or breastfeeding known or suspected allergies to any of the components of the I020201 uncontrolled anemia (Hb &lt; 9 g/dL in females and &lt; 10 g/dL in males) hypoalbuminemia (albumin &lt; 3 g/dL) overtly infected target ulcer (as judged by investigator) highly exuding wounds (wounds that require a daily dressing change) osteomyelitis systemic infections acute Charcot foot and severe chronic Charcot deformity ABPI &lt; 0.7 or ankle systolic pressure &lt; 70 mm Hg one of the following findings (only 1 out of 3 tests is required): on Doppler waveform analysis on the dorsalis pedis and posterior tibial arteries a monophasic or biphasic flow (with loss of reverse flow) in either foot artery, or a toe: brachial index &lt; 0.7, or transcutaneous oxygen pressure (TcpO2) &lt; 40 mm Hg suspicion, presence or history of systemic or local cancer or tumor of any kind</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetic</keyword>
	<keyword>ulcer</keyword>
	<keyword>topical</keyword>
	<keyword>PDGF</keyword>
	<keyword>GSoC</keyword>
</DOC>