<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00230152</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The synergistic value of the fusion of physiologic and anatomical data has been described using several co-registration techniques for various nuclear medicine procedures and morphologic imaging modalities (single photon emission computed tomography-computed tomography [SPECT-CT], SPECT-magnetic resonance imaging [MRI], camera-based positron emission tomography [PET]-CT and PET-CT). The researchers hypothesize that fusion of nuclear medicine (NM) and CT data acquired sequentially in a single imaging session on one device is clinically superior to side-by-side evaluation of separately performed imaging tests. They hypothesize that more accurate localization of increased radiotracer activity on NM procedures will improve the diagnostic accuracy for detection of infection and will subsequently have a significant impact on patient management. The purpose of the present study is to assess the clinical value of this new technology of fused imaging in patients undergoing diagnostic nuclear medicine evaluation for suspicion of an infection process.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Hybrid Imaging Modalities for the Evaluation of Infection</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The researchers hypothesize that fusion of nuclear medicine (NM) and CT data acquired sequentially in a single imaging session on one device is clinically superior to side-by-side evaluation of separately performed imaging tests. They hypothesize that more accurate localization of increased radiotracer activity on NM procedures will improve the diagnostic accuracy for detection of infection and will subsequently have a significant impact on patient management. The purpose of the present study is to assess the clinical value of this new technology of fused imaging in patients undergoing diagnostic nuclear medicine evaluation for suspicion of an infection process.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients referred for NM imaging procedures to assess the presence of infectious processes. Patients signed informed consent The study will not be performed in pregnant or lactating women. Patients unable or unwilling to tolerate the scan until its completion</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2005</verification_date>
</DOC>