<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00230451</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Surgery (esophagectomy or removal of the esophagus)has been the standard treatment for cancer of the esophagus. However, evidence suggests that preoperative chemotherapy and radiation therapy may add benefit. The purpose of this study is to determine if a treatment program of combined chemotherapy and radiation therapy prior to surgery and chemotherapy after surgery will delay or eliminate recurrence of the cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pre-operative Chemotherapy and Radiation Therapy for Esophageal Carcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Esophageal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient Eligibility: 1. Histologically confirmed squamous cell carcinoma, adenocarcinoma, or mixed adeno/squamous of the the esophagus or gastroesophageal junction. 2. Disease limited to the esophagus and regional lymph nodes. However, celiac node enlargement will be acceptable for tumors of the distal esophagus, because they will be included in the radiation field. 3. Disease must be able to be encompassed in a single radiation field. 4. No medical contraindication to surgery. 5. All treatment is to be administered at the University of Michigan Medical Center 6. Karnofsky Performance Status &gt; 60% 7. Ages 1875 8. Adequate renal function (BUN &lt;1.5 x N; creatinine &lt;1,5 mg/dl, or measured creatinine clearance&gt;60 ml/min.). 9. Adequate bone marrow reserve (WBC&gt;3500/ul; Platelets&gt;100,000/ul.). 10. Adequate hepatic function (Bilirubin&lt;1.5x N; AST &lt;2 x upper limit of normal). 11. Prior malignancy is acceptable if the patient is considered to be cured. In most cases this will mean a 5 year diseasefree period. 12. Ability to give informed consent. 1. Patients with active infection, pregnancy, lactating females, serious intercurrent medical conditions including congestive heart failure, cardiac arrhythmias, or symptomatic coronary artery diseases are ineligible. 2. No prior treatment allowed. No prior thoracic radiation.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2010</verification_date>
</DOC>