<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="32453">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02684188</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>177-15</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02684188</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Rural Options At Discharge Model of Active Planning</brief_title>
  <acronym>ROADMAP</acronym>
  <official_title>Rural Options At Discharge Model of Active Planning</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Montana</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Providence St. Patrick Hospital, Missoula Montana</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Montana</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Residents of rural and frontier counties experience significant disparities in health care
      access and outcomes when compared to their urban counterparts. The organization of health
      care delivery contributes significantly to these disparities. For rural residents with
      multiple chronic conditions, transitioning along the continuum of care, between systems of
      treatment and support, and between dispersed locations present significant challenges. One
      critical challenge involves hospitalization for treatment because it requires travel to
      locations at a significant distance from home and disrupts personal and family routines. The
      transition back home is also problematic because discharge planning does not adequately
      account for limited access to care in rural areas. Indeed, discharge planning has been
      recently described as a &quot;black hole;&quot; fragmented and uncoordinated, and contributing to poor
      outcomes and patient dissatisfaction. The specific aim of this research is to ascertain
      rural patients' actual experience of the discharge planning process and to involve patients
      and rural providers in designing and testing a contextually appropriate rural options
      discharge model (ROADMAP) that improves patient outcomes and reduces re-hospitalizations.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Residents of rural counties experience significant disparities in health care access and
      outcomes when compared to their urban counterparts. These disparities are structural; based
      in our market-based medical care delivery system. For rural residents with multiple chronic
      conditions, transitioning along the continuum of care, between systems of treatment and
      support, and between dispersed locations both expose and produce disparities. The transition
      home from hospitalization for treatment exposes the current urban bias. Indeed, discharge
      planning is fragmented and uncoordinated, and contributes to poor the disparities. The
      specific aims of this research is to ascertain rural patients' actual experience of
      discharge; then to involve patients and rural providers in using those data to design a
      contextually appropriate rural options at discharge model of active planning (ROADMAP) that
      improves patient outcomes and reduces disparities. Objectives include:

        1. Ascertain actual patient experience in the rural discharge process.

        2. Design the ROADMAP model to fit the emerging health services context.

        3. Test the ROADMAP's efficacy in enhancing patient defined outcomes.

        4. Design the components for rapid diffusion.

      Researchers will work in four counties of the Missoula Hospital Referral Region with a total
      population of 53,116 living on 12,342 square miles (4.3 persons per square mile).
      Researchers will recruit patients seeking treatment from St. Patrick Hospital. Patients and
      patient advocates will serve on an Innovations Design Team (IDT) to create the ROADMAP.
      Researchers will first interview patients (n = 40) who have been discharged to one of the
      rural counties. Researchers will compare their experiences to guidelines. Next, they will
      conduct a Design Survey (n=600) to verify goals important to patients. The IDT will use
      these findings to develop design requirements for ROADMAP. Finally, we will use a
      quasi-experimental research design to compare the patient designed rural ROADMAP to standard
      practice. The primary outcome measures are measures that reflect the patient's values for
      health-related quality of life and functional status, as well as hospital re-admissions. An
      independent statistician will use Hierarchical Linear Modeling to examine the complex
      relationships. This approach accounts for patients nested in four counties and the
      correlated errors inherent in within subject analysis. Health care reform sets the occasion
      for rapid diffusion of ROADMAP. This can provide an incremental reduction in rural
      disparities. Incorporating patient and provider input increases the likelihood it will fit
      within the emerging reimbursement model. Researchers expect that ROADMAP will reduce
      re-hospitalizations by as much as 30%, and improve patient recovery and return to
      participation in daily life.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single Blind (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change over baseline in Re-hospitalizations</measure>
    <time_frame>Within the first 90 days post discharge</time_frame>
    <description>Number of admissions to any hospital following discharge</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change over baseline in Medical Outcomes Study Short Form 12</measure>
    <time_frame>During the first 90 days post discharge</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported physical, functional, and emotional health</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change over baseline in Coleman Transitions Measure 3</measure>
    <time_frame>3 days after discharge</time_frame>
    <description>A three item rating of the discharge services and supports received</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change over baseline in Rural Transitions Assessment 12</measure>
    <time_frame>During the first 90 days post discharge</time_frame>
    <description>A 12 item rating of the Rural Transitional services and supports received</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">145</enrollment>
  <condition>All Causes Hospital Admissions</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Current Treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive that current discharge planning services and supports.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Enhanced Transitions Planning</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The intervention consists of a package of procedures that enhances supports during the transitions from the hospital to recovery at home, including a structured needs assessment that produces a plan that matches available rural community service providers to a patient's transitions needs and the provision of recovery supports to the patient.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Enhanced Transitions Planning</intervention_name>
    <description>While in the treating hospital, patients from small towns and rural communities are engaged in package of procedures designed to improve the transitions home, including a functional needs assessment that produces a plan that matches available rural community service providers to a patient's transitions needs and the provision of enhanced recovery supports to the patient.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Enhanced Transitions Planning</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Between 18 and 75 years of age

          -  Admitted to St. Patrick regional referral hospital for treatment

          -  Discharged home to one of four rural counties in Montana

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Primary diagnosis involves psychiatric condition or substance abuse

          -  Inmates of state prison

          -  Admitted under ongoing criminal investigation.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Tom W Seekins, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Montana</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>February 11, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>December 30, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Montana</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Tom Seekins</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Psychology and Director, RTC:Rural</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
