<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2627">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03072693</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CARDIAC_HF_1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03072693</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>RATIONALE AND DESIGN OF A DAILY AMBULATORY REMOTE MONITORING SYSTEM VS CONVENTIONAL THERAPY FOR THE POST-DISCHAGE MANAGEMENT OF ACUTE DECOMPENSATED HEART FAILURE</brief_title>
  <acronym>DAVID-HF</acronym>
  <official_title>RATIONALE AND DESIGN OF A DAILY AMBULATORY REMOTE MONITORING SYSTEM VS CONVENTIONAL THERAPY FOR THE POST-DISCHAGE MANAGEMENT OF ACUTE DECOMPENSATED HEART FAILURE</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The University of Hong Kong</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Chinese University of Hong Kong</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The University of Hong Kong</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background: Despite the advances in pharmacological management of heart failure (HF), the
      associated mortality and re-hospitalization for HF remain poor. This is at least partly due
      to suboptimal early discharge care, delayed detection of HF complications, and
      underutilization and under-dosing of evidence-based HF medications. Mobile technology has
      revolutionized inter-personal communication allowing instantaneous, multi-directional, and
      massive data transfer. Nonetheless the potential of these enhanced communications have not
      been fully explored in the management of patients with HF.

      Objective: To explore the potential of state-of-the-art mobile technology for home-based
      remote HF management in order to reduce HF mortality and HF re-hospitalization.

      Study Design: This will be a multicenter, randomized controlled clinical trial in patients
      with HF and reduced left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) who are discharged from
      hospital following an episode of acutely decompensated HF. The clinical effectiveness of a
      physician-directed patient self-management strategy based on remotely collected
      physiological data obtained from home-based and wearable devices will be compared with two
      control groups who will receive the home-based remote HF management system without
      activation or routine therapy. In the interventional arm, there will be three modes of
      home-based HF management: (1) Early discharge mode to optimize volume status; (2) Drug
      escalation mode to ensure the utilization of evidence-based medications at the maximum
      tolerated dose; and (3) Maintenance mode to ensure medication compliance and early detection
      of complications such as acutely decompensated HF and atrial fibrillation. The trial will
      enroll up to 876 patients with LVEF &lt;40% who are discharged from hospital after an episode
      of acutely decompensated HF. Randomization to the intervention group or control groups will
      be in a 1:1:1 ratio with follow-up for 1 year. The primary outcome will be a composite of
      cardiovascular death and HF hospitalization within 1 year.

      Summary: DAVID-HF will provide essential information about the role of home-based, remote
      heart failure monitoring that will incorporate instantaneous physician-directed patient-self
      management in the long-term management of HF patients.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Participant</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Composite Primary Endpoints</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>composite of re-hospitalization for acute decompensated HF and/or mortality</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>1-year mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>1-year mortality</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>1-year heart failure rehospitalization</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>1-year heart failure rehospitalization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual analog symptom score</measure>
    <time_frame>Continuously for 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Visual analog symptom score for heart failure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>6-minute walking distance</measure>
    <time_frame>intermittently for 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>6-minute walking distance</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Utilization of evidence-based anti-heart failure medications</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The number and percentage dosage of anti-heart failure medications</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Minnesota Living with Heart Failure questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">876</enrollment>
  <condition>Heart Failure With Reduced Ejection Fraction</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Home-based remote heart failure management with daily review of physiological parameters by clinicians. Three modes of interventions include (1) early discharge mode for fluid volume control, (2) drug escalation mode, and (3) maintenance mode.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Home-based physiological parameter recording without active remote intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will receive usual care.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Home-based remote heart failure management</intervention_name>
    <description>For patients randomized to Group 1, the home-based remote heart failure management system will be connected via the internet for active intervention. In Group 2 patients, the system will not be activated although all data will continue to be stored and reviewed at clinic visits. For patients in Group 1, clinically-assigned targets and alert thresholds of individual physiological parameters including blood pressure, pulse rate, and body weight will be decided before discharge and at entry into the three management modes. Site investigators will review individual patient physiological parameters upon clinic visits, and treatment can be initiated through instant communication (electronic communication and/or phone).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Home-based heart failure monitoring with no remote management</intervention_name>
    <description>For patients randomized to Group 2, the home-based remote heart failure management system will continuously record and store patients information to be reviewed at clinic visits but not connected to internet. Site investigators will review individual patient physiological parameters upon clinic visits, and no treatment will be initiated through instant communication.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Age ≥ 18 years

          -  Recently discharged from hospital for acutely decompensated HF (within 2 weeks)
             requiring intravenous diuretic therapy.

          -  Left ventricular ejection fraction &lt;40%

          -  Voluntarily agrees to participate by providing written informed consent

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Acute coronary syndrome within 4 weeks

          -  Complex congenital heart disease

          -  Significant valvular stenosis

          -  Left ventricular assist device

          -  Planned cardiac intervention including revascularization, cardiac resynchronization,
             and valvular surgery

          -  Listed for heart transplant

          -  Renal impairment with serum creatinine ≥250 μmol/L or on renal replacement therapy

          -  Inability or refusal to provide inform consent

          -  Lack of skills in operating simple electronic devices

          -  Unavailability of a mobile network service in the place of residence
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 2, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 2, 2017</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>The University of Hong Kong</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr. David Siu</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
