<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01450358</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is to evaluate the consumption of antimicrobial therapy in patients comparing a rapid molecular test (PCR in Real-Time Multiplex) with blood cultures to identify the etiological agents of sepsis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation in the Treatment of Nosocomial Sepsis Comparing Polymerase Chain Reaction With Conventional Blood Culture.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients staying more than 48 hours in hospital with clinical suspicion of sepsis could be included in the study. Blood samples for cultures and multiplex PCR will be collected immediately prior to initiation of antibiotic therapy. Patients will be randomly selected into two groups. In Group I, the PCR results will be immediately reported to the medical researcher (6-12 hours), which will change the antimicrobial regimen (De-escalation). In Group II, the Multiplex PCR results will not be informed, being focused care as a result of blood culture (at least after 72 hours). The initial empirical antimicrobial therapy will be the same in both groups, according to the standardization of the institution.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sepsis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Toxemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bacteremia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fungemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Bacterial Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibiotics, Antitubercular</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient 18 or more years old Patient staying more than 48 hours in hospital Patient with clinical suspicion of infection and presenting at leat two of the following criteria:temperature &gt; 38oC or &lt; 36oC, heart rate &gt; 90 beats/minute, respiratory rate &gt; 20 breaths/minute or PaCO2 &lt; 32 mmHg or leukocytosis &gt;12 000/μl or leukopenia &lt;4000/μl or normal white blood cell count with &gt;10% immature forms Patient or responsible able to provide informed consent Patient submitted to cardiovascular surgery in the last fifteen days Patient or responsible are not able to provide informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Sepsis</keyword>
	<keyword>Real time PCR</keyword>
	<keyword>Blood culture</keyword>
	<keyword>Bacteremia diagnosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Fungemia diagnosis</keyword>
</DOC>