<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01450423</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Epilepsy is a chronic neurologic disorder characterized by seizures. Beside seizures people suffering from epilepsy experience several challenges related to education, work and everyday life such as learning-, problem-solving-, memory-, concentration-, attention difficulties and fatigue. It is generally approved that physical activity (PA) has a positive effect on physical as well as mental factors. However, people with epilepsy are found to be less active and PA is rarely offered or recommended as supplement to anti-epileptic medical treatment. Few studies have investigated the effect of PA in subjects with epilepsy and additional studies of high methodical quality are needed to enable evidence-based information and counselling. This study is carried through as a randomized controlled trial which investigates the effect of participation in a 10-week cardio exercise program in people with Juvenile Myoclonic Epilepsy aged 15-50. The study hypothesis is that participation in a 10-week cardio exercise program will induce a positive change in cognitive function (concentration and attention) and possibly in brain-derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF). In addition it is expected that the intensity and duration of the 10-week cardio exercise program is sufficient to cause changes in physiological parameters related to a reduced risk of lifestyle diseases.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Physical Exercise in Subjects With Juvenile Myoclonic Epilepsy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Seizures</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epilepsy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epilepsies, Myoclonic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myoclonic Epilepsy, Juvenile</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age: 1550 Resident: Fyen, Denmark Epileptic syndrome: Juvenile Myoclonic Epilepsy Physical handicaps which complicate participation in physical activity</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Epilepsy</keyword>
	<keyword>Physical activity</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardio exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>Physical fitness</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive function</keyword>
</DOC>