<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="51674">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02433483</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MITREL</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2015-00691</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02433483</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Microtransplantation to Treat Refractory or Relapsed Hematologic Malignancies in Younger Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase II Study of Microtransplantation in Patients With Refractory or Relapsed Hematologic Malignancies</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>St. Jude Children's Research Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Cookies for Kids' Cancer</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>St. Jude Children's Research Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Allogeneic transplant can sometimes be an effective treatment for leukemia. In a traditional
      allogeneic transplant, patients receive very high doses of chemotherapy and/or radiation
      therapy, followed by an infusion of their donor's bone marrow or blood stem cells. The
      high-dose chemotherapy drugs and radiation are given to remove the leukemia cells in the
      body. The infusion of the donor's bone marrow or blood stem cells is given to replace the
      diseased bone marrow destroyed by the chemotherapy and/or radiation therapy. However, there
      are risks associated with allogeneic transplant. Many people have life-threatening or even
      fatal complications, like severe infections and a condition called graft-versus-host
      disease, which is caused when cells from the donor attack the normal tissue of the
      transplant patient.

      Recently, several hospitals around the world have been using a different type of allogeneic
      transplant called a microtransplant. In this type of transplant, the donor is usually a
      family member who is not an exact match. In a microtransplant, leukemia patients get lower
      doses of chemotherapy than are used in traditional allogeneic transplants. The chemotherapy
      is followed by an infusion of their donor's peripheral blood stem cells. The objective of
      the microtransplant is to suppress the bone marrow by giving just enough chemotherapy to
      allow the donor cells to temporarily engraft (implant), but only at very low levels. The
      hope is that the donor cells will cause the body to mount an immunologic attack against the
      leukemia, generating a response called the &quot;graft-versus-leukemia&quot; effect or
      &quot;graft-versus-cancer&quot; effect, without causing the potentially serious complication of
      graft-versus-host disease.

      With this research study, the investigators hope to find out whether or not
      microtransplantation will be a safe and effective treatment for children, adolescents and
      young adults with relapsed or refractory hematologic malignancies
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVES:

        -  To assess the safety and feasibility of standard chemotherapy plus GCSF-mobilized
           Hematopoietic Progenitor Cell, Apheresis (HPC-A) in pediatric patients with relapsed or
           refractory hematologic malignancies.

        -  To estimate the response rates to standard chemotherapy plus GCSF-mobilized HPC-A in
           pediatric patients with relapsed or refractory hematologic malignancies.

      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:

        -  To describe the event-free and overall survival of patients treated with standard
           chemotherapy plus GCSF-mobilized HPC-A.

        -  To estimate the time to neutrophil and platelet recovery after treatment with standard
           chemotherapy plus GCSF-mobilized HPC-A.

        -  To determine the cumulative incidence of acute and chronic graft-versus-host disease
           (GVHD).

      OTHER PRESPECIFIED OBJECTIVES:

        -  To characterize donor chimerism and microchimerism.

      Patients will receive standard chemotherapy followed by infusion of donor peripheral blood
      mononuclear cells 2 days after the completion of chemotherapy. Patients who have at least a
      partial response are eligible to receive a second cycle.

      Diagnostic lumbar puncture and intrathecal (IT) chemotherapy will be given prior to cycle 1.
      Patients without evidence of central nervous system (CNS) leukemia will receive no further
      IT therapy during cycle 1. Patients with CNS disease will receive weekly IT therapy
      (age-adjusted methotrexate, hydrocortisone, and cytarabine) until the cerebrospinal fluid
      (CSF) becomes free of leukemia (minimum of 4 doses).

      Bone marrow aspiration (BMA) and biopsy to assess response will be performed on
      approximately day 29 of therapy.

      For hematopoietic stem cell mobilization, donors will receive G-CSF (Filgrastim) (Neupogen®)
      each day for 5 days given subcutaneously (SQ) prior to HPC-A collected by leukapheresis on
      day 6.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 22, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>No masking</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants by stratum who complete 2 cycles of therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of therapy cycle 2 (approximately 2-3 months)</time_frame>
    <description>If two or more patients die from causes other than leukemia progression or experience ≥ Grade 3 GVHD that is associated with detectable donor chimerism due to this protocol, or demonstrate persistent engraftment defined as &gt;5% donor chimerism at the time of count recovery (ANC &gt; 0.3 x 10^9/L and platelet count &gt; 30 x 10^/L), then the cohort will close due to intolerability. Any subject who transfers to transplant prior to completion of two courses without experiencing an unacceptable toxicity is considered inevaluable for purposes of evaluating tolerability. Accrual will be halted for intolerability if there are two or more failures in tolerability among the first six subjects who are evaluable for tolerability.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of participants who experience therapeutic success</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of therapy cycle 2 (approximately 2-3 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Simon minimax two-stage phase II design will be used to evaluate efficacy. All patients will be counted towards this two-stage design. Therapeutic success for patients at time of enrollment is defined as:
Patients with fewer than 5% blasts, a ≥ 10-fold decrease in level of minimal residual disease after completion of 1 or 2 cycles of therapy.
Patients with greater than 5% in leukemic blasts in the marrow, achieving CR or CRi after completion of 1 or 2 cycles of therapy.
In terms of efficacy, patients who die before achieving therapeutic success will be counted as a failure, and all patients who receive ≥ 1 dose of protocol chemotherapy will be counted as a failure or success. Only subjects who withdraw or die prior to receiving the first dose of protocol chemotherapy will be considered inevaluable and replaced. The evaluation of tolerability and this phase II design will be performed concurrently, i.e., the first enrollees will be counted for both tolerability and efficacy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>3-year event free survival (EFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years after enrollment of the last participant</time_frame>
    <description>We will use the Kaplan-Meier method to describe the event-free. EFS will be defined as the time from enrollment to death, relapse, or refractory disease with event-free subjects' time censored at the date of last follow-up.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>3-year overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years after enrollment of the last participant</time_frame>
    <description>We will use the Kaplan-Meier method to describe overall survival. Overall survival will be defined as the time from enrollment to death, with living subjects' time censored at the date of last follow-up</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to neutrophil and platelet recovery</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of therapy to completion of therapy (approximately 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The time to neutrophil and platelet recovery will be summarized using descriptive statistics. If there are no deaths prior to recovery of neutrophils and platelets, nonparametric confidence intervals for the median time to recovery will be computed by inverting the sign test. Otherwise, we will compute cumulative incidence curves to describe the time to platelet and neutrophil recovery while adjusting for competing events.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>1-year cumulative incidence of acute and chronic graft versus host disease (GVHD)</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of therapy through completion of therapy (approximately 1 year)</time_frame>
    <description>All grades of GVHD will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Percent donor chimerism</measure>
    <time_frame>At weeks 1, 2, 3, and 4 after infusion of HPC-A</time_frame>
    <description>Percent donor chimerism in blood and bone marrow</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">38</enrollment>
  <condition>Acute Myeloid Leukemia (AML)</condition>
  <condition>Myelodysplastic Syndrome (MDS)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Myeloid Malignancies</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Includes participants with AML and MDS. Participants receive chemotherapy based on diagnosis followed by infusion of donor HPC-A.
Participants with CNS disease receive weekly age-adjusted intrathecal triples therapy until the cerebrospinal fluid becomes free of leukemia (minimum of 4 doses).
Interventions:
Cycle 1: cytarabine, HPC-A donor infusion
Cycle 2: Participants who have at least a partial response to Cycle 1 are eligible to receive Cycle 2: cytarabine, HPC-A infusion</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cytarabine</intervention_name>
    <description>Given by either intrathecal (IT) or intravenous (IV) route.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Myeloid Malignancies</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Cytosine arabinoside</other_name>
    <other_name>Ara-C</other_name>
    <other_name>Cytosar®</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Intrathecal Triples</intervention_name>
    <description>given IT.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Myeloid Malignancies</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>ITMHA</other_name>
    <other_name>Methotrexate/hydrocortisone/cytarabine</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>HPC-A</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Myeloid Malignancies</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Donor infusion</other_name>
    <other_name>Hematopoietic Progenitor Cell, Apheresis</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        INCLUSION CRITERIA - AML and MDS PARTICIPANTS

          -  Participants must have a diagnosis of AML or myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS), ALL, and
             must have disease that has relapsed or is refractory to chemotherapy, or that has
             relapsed after HSCT.

               -  Refractory disease is defined as persistent disease after at least two courses
                  of induction chemotherapy.

               -  Patients with AML must have ≥ 5% leukemic blasts in the bone marrow or have
                  converted from negative minimal residual disease (MRD) status to positive MRD
                  status in the bone marrow as assessed by flow cytometry. If an adequate bone
                  marrow sample cannot be obtained, patients may be enrolled if there is
                  unequivocal evidence of leukemia in the peripheral blood.

          -  Participant is ≤ 21 years of age (i.e., has not reached 22nd birthday).

          -  Adequate organ function defined as the following:

               -  Total bilirubin ≤ upper limit of normal (ULN) for age, or if total bilirubin is
                  &gt; ULN, direct bilirubin is ≤ 1.5 mg/dL

               -  AST (SGOT)/ALT (SGPT) &lt; 5 x ULN

               -  Calculated creatinine clearance &gt; 50 ml/min/1.73m^2 as calculated by the
                  Schwartz formula for estimated glomerular filtration rate &gt;

               -  Left ventricular ejection fraction ≥ 40% or shortening fraction ≥ 25%.

          -  Has an available HPC-A donor.

          -  Performance status: Lansky ≥ 50 for patients who are ≤ 16 years old and Karnofsky ≥
             50% for patients who are &gt; 16 years old.

          -  Does not have an uncontrolled infection requiring parenteral antibiotics, antivirals,
             or antifungals within one week prior to first dose. Infections controlled on
             concurrent anti-microbial agents are acceptable, and anti-microbial prophylaxis per
             institutional guidelines is acceptable.

          -  Patient has fully recovered from the acute effects of all prior therapy and must meet
             the following criteria.

               -  At least 14 days must have elapsed since the completion of myelosuppressive
                  therapy.

               -  At least 24 hours must have elapsed since the completion of hydroxyurea,
                  low-dose cytarabine (up to 200 mg/m^2/day), and intrathecal chemotherapy.

               -  At least 30 days must have elapsed since the use of investigational agents.

               -  For patients who have received prior HSCT, there can be no evidence of GVHD and
                  greater than 60 days must have elapsed since the HSCT. Patients cannot be
                  receiving therapy, including steroids, for GVHD.

          -  Post-menarchal female has had negative serum pregnancy test within 7 days prior to
             enrollment.

          -  Male or female of reproductive potential has agreed to use effective contraception
             for the duration of study participation.

          -  Not breastfeeding

        INCLUSION CRITERIA - HPC-A CELL DONOR

          -  At least 18 years of age.

          -  Family member (first degree relatives).

          -  Not pregnant as confirmed by negative serum or urine pregnancy test within 7 days
             prior to enrollment (if female).

          -  Not breast feeding.

          -  Meets donation eligibility requirements as outlined by 21 CFR 1271.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jeffrey E. Rubnitz, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>St. Jude Children's Research Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jeffrey E. Rubnitz, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>866-278-5833</phone>
    <email>info@stjude.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. Jude Children's Research Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Memphis</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>38105</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jeffrey E Rubnitz, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>866-278-5833</phone>
      <email>info@stjude.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jeffrey E Rubnitz, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.stjude.org</url>
    <description>St. Jude Children's Research Hospital</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.stjude.org/protocols</url>
    <description>Clinical Trials Open at St. Jude</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 30, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>April 29, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Adolescent</keyword>
  <keyword>Children</keyword>
  <keyword>Microtransplant</keyword>
  <keyword>Leukemia</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myelodysplastic Syndromes</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Preleukemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Cytarabine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hydrocortisone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
