<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01165684</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial is conducted in Europe, and North and South America. The aim of this clinical trial is to investigate if the two treatments are equally effective.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Basal-bolus Therapy, Comparing Stepwise Addition of Insulin Aspart Versus Complete Basal-bolus Regimen</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin degludec, insulin aspart drug combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Detemir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Aspart</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Long-Acting</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Type 2 diabetes (diagnosed clinically) for at least 12 months Basal insulin treatment (NPH once or twice daily, insulin glargine once daily or insulin detemir once daily) for at least 6 months HbA1c: 7.09.0 % (both inclusive) by central laboratory analysis (one retest analysed at the central laboratory within a week is permitted with the result of the last sample being conclusive) BMI (Body Mass Index) less than 40.0 kg/m^2 Previous use of premix or bolus insulin (allowed is previous use of bolus insulin only in case of a hospitalisation or a severe condition requiring intermittent use of bolus insulin for less than 14 consecutive days, but not during the last 6 months prior to screening visit (Visit 1) Use of GLP1 (Glucagonlike peptide1) receptor agonists or pramlintide within the last 6 months prior to prior to screening visit (Visit 1) Anticipated change in concomitant medication known to interfere significantly with glucose metabolism (e.g. systemic corticosteroids, betablockers, MAO (Monoamine oxidase) inhibitors, etc.) Cardiovascular disease, within the last 12 months prior to screening visit (Visit 1), defined as: stroke; decompensated heart failure New York Heart Association (NYHA) class III or IV; myocardial infarction; unstable angina pectoris; or coronary arterial bypass graft or angioplasty Uncontrolled treated/untreated severe hypertension (systolic blood pressure sitting at least 180 millimetre (mm) mercury (Hg) and/or diastolic blood pressure at least 100 mmHg). For Argentina: systolic blood pressure sitting at least 150 mmHg and/or diastolic blood pressure at least 90 mmHg Impaired liver function, defined as ALAT (Alanine aminotransferase) at least 2.5 times upper limit of normal (one retest analysed at the central laboratory within a week is permitted with the result of the last sample being conclusive) Impaired renal function defined as serum creatinine above 135 micromol/L (above 1.5 mg/dL) for males and above 110 micromol/L (above 1.2 mg/dL) for females; and, if required by the locally applicable metformin label, glomerular filtration rate below 60 ml/min, calculated by the Cockroft &amp; Gault formula). One retest within a week is permitted with the result of the last sample being conclusive Recurrent severe hypoglycaemia (more than 1 severe hypoglycaemic episode, during the last 12 months) or hypoglycaemic unawareness as judged by the Investigator or hospitalisation for diabetic ketoacidosis during the previous 6 months Proliferative retinopathy or maculopathy requiring treatment according to the Investigator Treatment with OADs (Oral antidiabetic drug) contraindicated or unapproved for combination treatment with insulin (according to local OAD label)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>