<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01165632</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: New imaging procedures, such as fluorine F 18 fluorodopa-labeled PET scan, may help in guiding surgery and radiation therapy and allow doctors to plan better treatment. PURPOSE: This clinical trial studies fluorine F 18 fluorodopa-labeled PET scan in planning surgery and radiation therapy in treating patients with newly diagnosed high- or low-grade malignant glioma</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Fluorine F 18 Fluorodopa-Labeled PET Scan in Planning Surgery and Radiation Therapy in Treating Patients With Newly Diagnosed High- or Low-Grade Malignant Glioma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To determine correlation between 18F-FDOPA PET activity, MRI contrast enhancement, and high- or low-grade glioma biopsies. II. To compare radiotherapy target volume delineation with and without 18F- FDOPA-PET metabolic imaging information to determine role of metabolic imaging in radiotherapy treatment planning. SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To determine correlation between concordance of 18F-FDOPA PET activity, MRI contrast enhancement, and high- or low-grade glioma biopsies and patient outcomes including overall survival and progression free survival. OUTLINE: Beginning at no more than 1 week before biopsy and resection, patients undergo fluorine F 18 fluorodopa-labeled PET/CT scan and pre-operative MRI. Patients then undergo stereotactic craniotomy. Some patients may also undergo radiation therapy. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up every year for 5 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Astrocytoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gliosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ependymoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oligodendroglioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glioma, Subependymal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dihydroxyphenylalanine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorides</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥18 years. MRI findings compatible with newly diagnosed high or lowgrade malignant glioma Planned craniotomy and resection or biopsy Willing to sign release of information for any radiation and/or followup records Negative pregnancy test done =&lt; 48 hours of injection of study drug, for women of childbearing potential only Provide informed written consent Patients with eGFR &lt; 60 mg/min/1.72m2 are eligible for the study; PLEASE NOTE: the patient is not eligible to receive the contrast for the pMRI at the study dose. Unable to undergo MRI scans with contrast (e.g. cardiac pacemaker, defibrillator, kidney failure) Unable to undergo an 18FFDOPA PET scan (e.g. Parkinson's Disease, taking antidopaminergic, or dopamine agonist medication or less than 6 halflives from discontinuance of dopamine agonists) Pregnant women; nursing women; men or women of childbearing potential who are unwilling to employ adequate contraception</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>