<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01886105</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary goal of this study will be to examine tumor response after radiation treatment via a combination of Samarium-153 EDTMP and external beam radiotherapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Combination of External Beam Radiotherapy With 153Sm-EDTMP to Treat High Risk Osteosarcoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>DAY 1 Tracer dose 153Sm-EDTMP administration (1 mCi/kg) SPECT/High-resolution CT at 4 hours. SPECT/CT (low resolution) at 24 and 48 hrs DAY 7 Individualized treatment dose 153Sm-EDTMP administration (max 30 mCi/kg) SPECT scans at 4, 24 and 48 hours DAY 21 (2 weeks following treatment dose administration) Auto-Stem cell infusion DAY 40 (approximately two weeks after stem cell rescue) Initiate external beam radiation therapy upon count recovery One month following completion of all therapy Response assessment with repeat imaging (CT/MRI, Tc-99m bone scan) 18F-MISO/FDG PET</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Osteosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Samarium ethylenediaminetetramethylenephosphonate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients must be between 13 and 65 years of age, inclusive Must have unresectable primary tumor or metastases Must have measurable disease that is demonstrated by positive Tc99m Bone Scan. Not all lesions must be positive on bone scan. Creatinine clearance &gt;70ml/min/1.73m2 ANC &gt;500/mm3 Platelets &gt;50,000/mm3 Life expectancy &gt; 8 weeks Karnofsky performance status &gt;50% Stem cell product collected prior to the infusion of Samarium must be available, either by peripheral stem cell mobilization or bone marrow harvest prior to trial entry. Patient may not be pregnant or breastfeeding. Patients who have received prior radiotherapy to all areas of current active disease are not eligible.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Osteosarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Osteogenic Sarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Sarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Bone Cancer</keyword>
</DOC>