<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01886508</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators designed this multicentre randomized study to investigate the clinical benefits of nerve-spring radical hysterectomy for cervical cancer. Patients with FIGO stage Ia2, Ib1, IIa1 and FIGO stage Ib2, IIa2 after neoadjuvant chemotherapy are randomized to either nerve-spring radical hysterectomy or radical hysterectomy. The primary endpoint are urodynamic outcome including maximum flow rate, residual volume, maximum vesical compliace, cystomctric capacity at first desire, and maximum cystomctric capacity. A total 240 patients (120 per treatment arm) are planned to accrue for this study within 7 years.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Multicentre Trial of Nerve-Spring Radical Hysterectomy vs. Radical Hysterectomy for Cervical Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Uterine Cervical Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. FIGO(2009) stage Ia2, Ib1, and IIa1 Untreated cervical cancer OR FIGO(2009) stage Ib2 and IIa2 cervical cancer that possible to surgery after neoadjuvant chemotherapy 2. Possible to radical hysterectomy or nervespring radical hysterectomy 3. Age: 17 to 60 years 4. No complication during operation 5. Written informed consent 1. patients who underwent radiotherapy 2. Pathologically diagnosed Pathologically diagnosed squamous carcinoma, Small Cell Carcinoma, Small Cell Carcinoma 3. Patients who have uncontrolled diabetes or uncontrolled hypertension 4. patients with neurogenic bladder dysfunction 5. patients with uterine prolapse 6. Patients with psychiatric illness 7. Patients who have active infection 8. Patients who have had heart failure, unstable angina, or myocardial infarction within the past 6 months 9. Patients who are unable to undergo radical hysterectomy for complication of excessive obesity, liver cirrhosis, or bleeding tendency</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>17 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>