<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00876031</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate whether the addition of oral maintenance chemotherapy with O-TIE (Etoposide, Idarubicin, Trofosfamide) for 6 months improves the event free survival (EFS) in patients with localised high-risk RMS and RMS-like Soft Tissue Sarcoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Trial for Localised High-risk Rhabdomyosarcoma and Rhabdomyosarcoma-like Soft Tissue Sarcoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhabdomyosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Idarubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trofosfamide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>written informed consent for registration, randomisation, data collection/transfer, and tumour material asservation available pathologically (including molecular pathology) proven diagnosis of rhabdomyosarcoma (RMS) or RMSlike soft tissue sarcoma (STS) and tumour material available for pathology review Rhabdomyosarcoma of the "High Risk" Group, i.e.: RME, N0, M0, IRS II&amp;III, &gt;5 cm or &gt;10 years in EXT, HNPM, OTH, UGBP RME, N1, M0, any IRSgroup, any size or age RMA, NO, M0, any IRSgroup, any size or age (exception: paratesticular RMA are not eligible) or Rhabdomyosarcoma of the "Very High Risk" Group, i.e.: RMA, N1, MO, IRS II&amp;III, any size or age or localised highrisk RMSlike Soft Tissue Sarcoma, i.e.: EES, pPNET, UDS: any N, M0, any IRSgroup, any size or age SySa, any N, M0, any size or age (exception: SySa IRSI&amp;II, not T2b, N0, M0 are not eligible) no preexisting illness preventing treatment (esp. those listed in the medicinal product information, e.g. cardiac, hepatic, metabolic, or renal dysfunction; hypersensitivity) no previous malignant tumours available for long term follow up through the treating centre in remission (according to the CWS2007HR definition (see X7.1.8X)) at the time of randomisation after standard multimodal therapy e.g. according to the CWSguidance pregnant or lactating women other medical condition precluding treatment with protocol therapy (e.g. HIV, psychiatric disorder, etc.) for sexually active females and males in Arm B (OTIE treatment): refusal to use effective contraception (e.g. oral, IUD)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>pediatric soft tissue sarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>rhabdomyosarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>extraosseous Ewing family tumours</keyword>
	<keyword>synovial sarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>undifferentiated sarcoma</keyword>
</DOC>