<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00193375</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this multicenter trial, we plan to evaluate the feasibility and toxicity of initial treatment with irinotecan/carboplatin/radiation therapy, followed by treatment with bevacizumab, in patients with limited stage small cell lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Irinotecan, Carboplatin and Radiation Therapy Followed by Bevacizumab in Limited Stage Small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Upon determination of eligibility, all patients will be receive: - Irinotecan + Carboplatin + Radiation Therapy + Bevacizumab Patients will receive 4 courses of irinotecan/carboplatin. Radiation therapy will begin concurrently with the third course of chemotherapy. The intervals between chemotherapy courses will be 21 days except for the interval between the third and fourth courses (during radiation therapy), which will be 28 days.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Irinotecan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Camptothecin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>To be included in this study, you must meet the following criteria: Small cell lung cancer, confirmed by biopsy. Limited stage disease after standard evaluation. Able to perform activities of daily living without assistance. No previous treatment with chemotherapy, radiation therapy, or biologics. Measurable or evaluable disease Adequate bone marrow, liver and kidney function Able to understand the nature of this study and give written consent. You cannot participate in this study if any of the following apply to you: Age &lt; 18 years History of previous malignancies Women pregnant or lactating History or physical exam evidence of central nervous system disease) Active infection requiring intravenous antibiotics Fulldose anticoagulation or thrombolytic therapy within 10 days Proteinuria. Serious nonhealing wound, ulcer, or bone fracture Evidence if bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy History of heart attack within 6 months. Uncontrolled cardiovascular disease PEG or Gtube History of other serious disease Please note: There are additional inclusion/exclusion criteria. The study center will determine if you meet all of the criteria. If you do not qualify for the trial, study personnel will explain the reasons. If you do qualify, study personnel will explain the trial in detail and answer any questions you may have.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>