<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02994953</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the safety, tolerability, and maximum tolerated dose (MTD) of NHS-IL12 when given in combination with a fixed avelumab dose in subjects with metastatic or locally advanced solid tumors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase Ib Study to Evaluate the Safety, Tolerability, and Pharmacokinetics of Avelumab in Combination With M9241(NHS-IL12)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Interleukin-12</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulin G</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects must have signed written informed consent. Male or female subjects age greater than equals to (&gt;=)18 years. Subjects must have histologically or cytologically proven metastatic or locally advanced solid tumors for which no standard therapy exists, standard therapy has failed, or subject is intolerant of established therapy known to provide clinical benefit for their condition. Subjects who have been treated previously with a checkpoint inhibitor may enroll. At least 1 unidimensional radiographically measurable lesion based on Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) version 1.1 (v1.1), except for subjects with metastatic castrationresistant prostate cancer (CRPC) or metastatic breast cancer who may be enrolled with objective evidence of disease without a measureable lesion. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 to 1 at Screening Estimated life expectancy of more than 12 weeks Adequate hematological function as defined below: White blood cells (WBC) count &gt;= 3.0 × 10^9 per liter (/L) Absolute neutrophil count &gt;= 1.5 × 10^9/L Lymphocyte count &gt;= 0.5 × 10^9/L Platelet count &gt;= 100 × 10^9/L Hemoglobin &gt;= 9 gram per deciliter (g/dL) (may have been transfused) Adequate hepatic function as defined below: A total bilirubin level &lt;= 1.5 × the upper limit of normal (ULN) range Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) levels &lt;= 2.5 × ULN Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) levels &lt;= 2.5 × ULN Subjects with documented Gilbert disease are allowed if total bilirubin &gt; 1.5 but less than 3 × ULN Adequate renal function as defined by an estimated creatinine clearance &gt;= 50 milliliter per minute (mL/min) according to the CockcroftGault formula Negative blood pregnancy test at Screening for women of childbearing potential. For the purposes of this trial, women of childbearing potential are defined as all female subjects after puberty unless they are postmenopausal for at least 1 year, are surgically sterile or are sexually inactive. Highly effective contraception (ie, methods with a failure rate of less than 1% per year) must be used before the start of treatment, for the duration of the trial treatment, and for at least 60 days after stopping trial participation for both men and women if the risk of conception exists. The effects of avelumab and NHSIL12 on the developing human fetus are unknown; thus, women of childbearing potential and men must agree to use effective contraception. Concurrent treatment with a nonpermitted drug/intervention (listed below) Anticancer treatment (eg, cytoreductive therapy, radiotherapy, immune therapy, cytokine therapy, monoclonal antibody, targeted small molecule therapy) or any investigational drug within 2 weeks prior to start of trial treatment, or not recovered from adverse event (AE) related to such therapies, with the following exceptions: Palliative bonedirected radiotherapy is permitted; Erythropoietin and darbepoetinα are permitted; Hormonal therapies acting on the hypothalamicpituitarygonadal axis are permitted (i.e. luteinizing hormonereleasing hormone agonist/antagonists). No other hormonal anticancer therapy is permitted. Major surgery (as deemed by Investigator) for any reason, except diagnostic biopsy, within 4 weeks prior to start of trial treatment, or not fully recovered from surgery within 4 weeks prior to start of trial treatment Subjects receiving immunosuppressive agents (such as steroids) for any reason should be tapered off these drugs before start of trial treatment, with the following exceptions: Subjects with adrenal insufficiency, may continue corticosteroids at physiologic replacement dose, equivalent to less than (&lt;) 10 mg prednisone daily; Administration of steroids through a route known to result in a minimal systemic exposure (topical, intranasal, introocular, or inhalation) is permitted; Previous or ongoing administration of systemic steroids for the management of an acute allergic phenomenon is acceptable as long as it is anticipated that the administration of steroids will be completed in 14 days, or that the dose after 14 days will be equivalent to &lt;= 10 mg prednisone daily. Any prior treatment with any form of interlukin12 (IL12) Intolerance to checkpoint inhibitor therapy, as defined by the occurrence of an AE requiring drug discontinuation. Active or history of primary or metastatic central nervous system tumors Prior organ transplantation, including allogeneic stemcell transplantation Previous malignant disease (other than the indication for this trial) within the last 5 years (except adequately treated nonmelanoma skin cancers, carcinoma in situ of skin, bladder, cervix, colon/rectum, breast, or prostate) unless a complete remission without further recurrence was achieved at least 2 years prior to trial entry and the subject was deemed to have been cured with no additional therapy required or anticipated to be required. Significant acute or chronic infections requiring systemic therapy including, among others: History of testing positive test for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or known acquired immunodeficiency syndrome Hepatitis B or C infection (HBV surface antigen positive and HBV core antibody positive with reflex to positive HBV deoxy ribonucleic acid (DNA) or HBV core antibody positive alone with reflex to positive HBV DNA or positive hepatitis C virus [HCV] antibody with reflex to positive HCV ribonucleic acid [RNA]). Subjects with history of infection must have polymerase chain reaction documentation that infection is cleared. Active tuberculosis (history of exposure or history of positive TB (tuberculosis) test with presence of clinical symptoms, physical, or radiographic finding Active or history of autoimmune disease that might deteriorate when receiving an immunostimulatory agent. Subjects with diabetes type I, vitiligo, psoriasis, hypo or hyperthyroid disease not requiring immunosuppressive treatment are eligible. Known severe hypersensitivity reactions to monoclonal antibodies (Grade&gt;= 3 National Cancer InstituteCommon Terminology Criteria for Adverse Event (NCICTCAE) v4.03, or uncontrolled asthma (ie, 3 or more features of partially controlled asthma) History of allergic reaction to methotrexate (trace methotrexate may be present in NHSIL12 as a part of the manufacturing process) Persisting toxicity related to prior therapy of Grade &gt; 1 NCICTCAE v4.03 with the following exceptions: Neuropathy Grade &lt;= 2 is acceptable. All grades of alopecia are acceptable. Endocrine dysfunction on replacement therapy is acceptable. Pregnancy or lactation Known alcohol or drug abuse as deemed by the Investigator Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to: Hypertension uncontrolled by standard therapies (not stabilized to 150/90 millimeter of mercury (mm Hg) or lower) Uncontrolled active infection Uncontrolled diabetes (eg, glycosylated hemoglobin [HgbA1c] &gt;= 8%) Clinically significant (or active) cardiovascular disease: cerebral vascular accident/stroke (&lt; 6 months prior to enrollment), myocardial infarction (&lt; 6 months prior to enrollment), unstable angina, congestive heart failure (New York Heart Association Classification Class &gt;= II), or serious cardiac arrhythmia requiring medication All other significant diseases (eg, inflammatory bowel disease, current severe acute or chronic colitis) or chronic medical conditions (including laboratory abnormalities) that in the opinion of the Investigator might impair the subject's tolerance of trial treatment or interpretation of trial results. Any psychiatric condition that would prohibit the understanding or rendering of informed consent or that would limit compliance with trial requirements Legal incapacity or limited legal capacity Administration of a live vaccine within 30 days prior to trial entry Any subject with possible area of ongoing necrosis (nondisease related), such as active ulcer, nonhealing wound, or intercurrent bone fracture that may be at risk of delayed healing due to protocol therapy Oxygen saturation &lt; 90% at rest, known pulmonary fibrosis, or active interstitial lung disease History of congenital or active immunodeficiency, with the exception of acquired treatmentrelated hypogammaglobulinemia requiring periodic IV immunoglobulin infusion.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Avelumab</keyword>
	<keyword>M9241</keyword>
	<keyword>NHS-IL12</keyword>
	<keyword>Advanced Solid Tumors</keyword>
</DOC>