<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02986191</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Twenty patients with gingival recession will be enrolled in this trial. Gingival recession will be treated in one side by applying Mucograft速 with coronally advanced flap (CAF) while on the opposite side a connective tissue graft (from the palate) will be applied with a CAF. Patients will be followed for 3 and 6 months by measuring the clinical indexes and statistical analyses will be performed to compare the results and to assess the success of Mucograft速.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Use of Mucograft速 to Treat Gingival Recession</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Many surgical techniques have used to treat gingival recession such aas repositioned flaps, autologous soft tissue grafts (connective tissue graft or free gingival grafts) or allografts like acellular dermal which can be used as substitutes for palatal donor tissue. Mucograft速 (3D collagen matrix) is also an allograft from porcine origin and is designed for soft tissue regeneration and considered the ideal solution to autogenous soft tissue grafts and it provides an ideal matrix for blood vessel and soft tissue ingrowth.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Gingival Recession</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Presence of Type I or II (Miller Classification) of gingival recession Smoking Pregnancy or lactating Presence of any systematic diseases can affect the periodontal surgery. Subjects with significant moderate to severe periodontal disease. Patients under orthodontic treatment Presence of restorative materials (e.g. crown) Effectiveness of frenum Subjects have failed to maintain good plaque control. Subjects having previous surgical treatment for covering the recession in the chosen area.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>gingival graft</keyword>
	<keyword>free gingival graft</keyword>
	<keyword>coronally advanced flap</keyword>
	<keyword>reduced keratinized gingiva</keyword>
</DOC>