<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02986724</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this non-interventional study (NIS) study is to assess further knowledge on the routine use of Entyvio in inflammatory bowel disease therapy, particularly the use in participants with CD and UC naive to biologics.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Observe the Safety and Efficacy of Vedolizumab in Biologically Naive Participants Wtih Ulcerative Colitis (UC) or Crohn´s Disease (CD)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The drug being tested in this prospective, observational study is called vedolizumab. Vedolizumab (Entyvio) is being used to treat people who have CD or UC. This study will look in the routine use of vedolizumab in inflammatory bowel disease therapy in participants with CD or UC who did not receive a biologic treatment before. The study will enroll approximately 150 participants. All participants enrolled in this will belong to one observational group: Vedolizumab. Participants taking vedolizumab as per physician's prescription in routine clinical practice will be observed. This multi-centre trial will be conducted in Austria. The overall time to participate in this study is 2 years. Participant taking vedolizumab in routine clinical practice will make multiple visits to the clinic at Baseline, Week 20 and 52. Once a participant is switched to subsequent biologic treatment upon failing treatment with vedolizumab, the switching date will be considered as new baseline followed by visits at Week 20 and 52.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis, Ulcerative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Crohn Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Inflammatory Bowel Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vedolizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria 1 Initiating vedolizumab for moderately to severely active UC or CD. Exclusion Criteria 1. Participant is enrolled in a clinical trial in which treatment for UC or CD is managed through a protocol, 2. Prior treatment with a biologic agent, 3. Any other reason that, in the Investigator's opinion, makes the participant unsuitable to participate in this study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Drug therapy</keyword>
</DOC>