<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00643175</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Osteoporosis has been called a "silent epidemic" whose prevalence is increasing. It often presents as a fragility fracture, with hospitalizations resulting from minimally traumatic hip fractures. While the fractures are treated appropriately, the underlying pathology is often ignored. Numerous studies have shown that prior fracture increases the risk for further fracture. In 2004 the Surgeon General released a report on osteoporosis, the details of which include multi-disciplinary treatment of osteoporotic fractures. Treatment of osteoporosis after hip fracture is also being targeted as a future hospital quality assessment measure. Hospitals which have no plan in place to address osteoporosis treatment after hip fracture may be cited, and may have medicare money withheld. The goal of the study is to create an automated in-patient endocrinology consultation for osteoporotic hip fractures. We plan to gather patient data in a prospective manner including the endocrinologist recommendations, adherence to medical therapy after discharge, and future fracture rates. Possible planned interventions include only appropriate medical therapy for osteoporosis, DEXA bone scanning, and regularly scheduled telephone follow-up.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effectiveness of Automated Inpatient Endocrinology Consultation for Osteoporotic Hip Fracture</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Osteoporosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hip Fractures</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion: 1. over 55 2. nontraumatic hip fracture Exclusion criteria: 1. currently on antiosteoporosis pharmacotherapy including bisphosphonates, PTH, and calcitonin 2. high energy nature of fracture, including MVA, fall from height greater than 3 feet 3. severe dementia, lack of capacity</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>The main objective is to have an endocrinologist treat osteoporosis in patients with fragility hip fractures.</keyword>
</DOC>