<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02557282</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this clinical study is to evaluate the CARESTREAM Vue PACS 12.1.5 Computed Tomography (CT) Perfusion ("investigational device") imaging performance. Evaluation of CT Perfusion (CTP) imaging will compare CTP with the predicate device, the Olea Sphere PACS with CT Perfusion Module.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>CARESTREAM Vue PACS v12.1.5 CT Perfusion Clinical Protocol</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will demonstrate the safety and effectiveness of CTP by an assessment of 30 CTP de-identified patient cases collected retrospectively. The maps include the following: - Mean Transfer Time (MTT) - the time that the contrast material stays in the tissue - Cerebral Blood Volume (CBV) - the volume of blood that is in a known volume of the tissue based on the concentration of contrast material that is in the tissue over the time - Cerebral Blood Flow (CBF) - describes the flow of the blood to the affected tissue - Time To Peak (TTP) - the time that maximum enhancement is achieved at each volume of the tissue The retrospective data collected for each patient will include a non-contrast head CT exam completed on the same day as CTP image, and a follow-up head CT at least 1-2 days after the initial imaging study (initial non-contrast head CT) if available.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Retrospective patient CTP cases with case maps that include the following information: MTT, CBV, CBF, and TTF, Initial CT exam and CT exam 12 days after the initial exam if available, and Retrospective CTP case with subject/patient 18 years of age or older Low quality images, or images that are not clinically acceptable for clinical diagnostic reading as determined by the Principal Investigator, Subject less than 18 years of age</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>