<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02557451</DOC>
	<brief_summary>AMD is a disease of the central retina, a zone that enables fine detail activities (reading, detail…). This central zone of the retina can be affected by a haemorrhagic complication when small abnormal vessels suddenly start to bleed inside the retina. Several therapeutic approaches are currently available even though they have never been truly compared. The study will be proposed to patients who need to be treated for haemorrhage of the macula. A certain number of factors will be evaluated to compare the 2 principal approaches currently used in France: surgery followed by injections of an anti-angiogenic OR intravitreal injections of gas followed by injections of anti-angiogenics. This is a multicentre, randomized controlled trial to compare these 2 therapeutic approaches. These diametrically opposed approaches have very different consequences for patients and in terms of cost for society. The consequences for patients will be immediately measurable so as to determine the best therapeutic approach in terms of functional recovery and the impact of the disease on quality of life, while taking into account the risks inherent to these 2 treatments. The impact on quality of life of these 2 approaches as well as their consequences - an important factor in this disease, which is a cause of sensory handicap - will provide the ophthalmological community with essential information making it possible to validate one or the other of these methods for the management of these haematomas.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Surgery, Tissue Plasminogen Activator, Antiangiogenic Agents and Age Related Macular Degeneration Complications</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hematoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angiogenesis Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tissue Plasminogen Activator</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients presenting subretinal haematoma linked to AMD Occurring at least14 days before the start of therapy With the presence of a component overlying the pigmentary epithelium (PE) on the OCT And a diameter greater than two pupillary diameters on the retinal photographs Patients who have provided oral consent Patients with National Health Insurance cover Patients available for monthly followup Subretinal haematoma linked to a cause other than AMD (myopia, angioid streaks…) History of subretinal haematoma on the same side Cloudy humour making it impossible to photograph the fundus of the eye or carry out angiography Component of the haematoma exclusively underlying the pigmentry epithelium Haemorrhage without lifting of the retina Patients presenting an INR greater than 4, thus contraindicating surgery Patients requiring cataract surgery in the first 3 months of the study Patients presenting a contraindication relative to injection of the antiangiogenic (CVA or MI in the 3 preceding months)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>