<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02803216</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate the efficacy and safety of Traditional Chinese Medicine (TCM) decoction and powder combined with standard triple therapy on improving eradication rate of Helicobacter Pylori (H. pylori).A multi-center randomized control clinical trial design was adopted in the trial.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Traditional Chinese Medicine Combined With Standard Triple Region for Eradication of Helicobacter Pylori</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Helicobacter Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Omeprazole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Clarithromycin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amoxicillin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>those who met chronic gastritis (chronic superficial gastritis and chronic atrophic gastritis) diagnostic criteria; aged between 1865 years old; positive H. pylori infection confirmed by two or more methods of different principles (stop using PPI, H2RA, bismuth, and antibiotics since two weeks before examination); patients were informed consent and willing to accept corresponding treatments. Exclusion criteria: Patients having chronic atrophic gastritis with severe dysplasia, upper gastrointestinal bleeding, peptic ulcers, and gastrointestinal tumors; digestive organic disease (such as chronic pancreatitis, cirrhosis, etc.), or systemic diseases affecting intestinal motility (such as hyperthyroidism, diabetes mellitus, chronic renal insufficiency, mental, and neurological diseases, etc.); those who were accompanied by serious heart, liver and other major organs lesions, blood diseases, and cancer (ALT, AST two times higher than normal value); those who had taken medicines that might affect H. pylori detection results within two weeks (antacids, H2RA, PPIs, bismuth and antibiotics, etc.); pregnant and lactating women; patients with history of systematic and neuropsychiatric disorders; those who had history of any drug allergy; and those who were participating in other clinical trials.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>