<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02044822</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will evaluate the effect of treatment with idelalisib (IDELA) plus rituximab on overall response rate (ORR); onset, magnitude, and duration of disease control (including duration of response [DOR], progression free survival [PFS], and overall survival [OS]); and minimal residual disease (MRD) in subjects with previously untreated chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL) with 17p deletion. In addition, the study will evaluate the safety profile observed with the combination of IDELA and rituximab.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Idelalisib in Combination With Rituximab in Patients With Previously Untreated Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia With 17p Deletion</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, Chronic, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Idelalisib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Documented diagnosis of Bcell CLL, according to International Workshop on Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia 2008 Presence of 17p deletion in CLL cells as demonstrated by FISH testing No prior therapy for CLL other than corticosteroids for disease complications. CLL that warrants treatment Presence of measurable lymphadenopathy Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of ≤ 2 Known histological transformation from CLL to an aggressive lymphoma (ie, Richter transformation). Known presence of myelodysplastic syndrome. History of a nonCLL malignancy except for the following: the malignancy has been in remission without treatment for ≥ 5 years prior to enrollment, or carcinoma in situ of the cervix, or adequately treated basal or squamous cell skin cancer or other localized nonmelanoma skin cancer, or asymptomatic prostate cancer without known metastatic disease and with no current requirement for therapy or requiring only hormonal therapy and with normal prostate specific antigen for ≥ 1 year prior to enrollment, or ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS) of the breast treated with lumpectomy alone, or other adequately treated Stage 1 or 2 cancer currently in complete remission Evidence of ongoing systemic bacterial, fungal, or viral infection at the time of enrollment Ongoing liver injury History of noninfectious pneumonitis. Ongoing inflammatory bowel disease. History of prior allogeneic bone marrow progenitor cell or solid organ transplantation. Ongoing immunosuppressive therapy other than corticosteroids. Received last dose of study drug on another therapeutic clinical trial within 30 days prior to enrollment. Prior or ongoing clinically significant illness, medical condition, surgical history, physical finding, electrocardiogram (ECG) finding, or laboratory abnormality</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>CLL</keyword>
</DOC>