<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02044614</DOC>
	<brief_summary>1. To assess the feasibility and safety of applying a 12-week course of adjuvant low-frequency icodextrin-based peritoneal dialysis to an ongoing regimen of thrice-weekly in-center hemodialysis. Hypothesis: Icodextrin-based peritoneal dialysis can be safely and feasibly implemented in the context of ongoing thrice-weekly in-center hemodialysis. 2. To measure the effects of a 12-week course of adjuvant low-frequency icodextrin-based peritoneal dialysis to ongoing thrice-weekly maintenance hemodialysis on: inter-hemodialytic weight gain, achievable hemodialytic dry weight, total body water, ambulatory blood pressure, serum phosphorus, and pre-to-post hemodialysis changes in serum potassium and pH, and Kidney Disease Quality of Life-SF physical functioning, energy fatigue, and general health scores. Hypotheses: Addition of adjuvant icodextrin-based peritoneal dialysis will: 1. reduce inter-hemodialytic weight gain* 2. enable achievement of lower hemodialytic dry weight 3. reduce total body water 4. improve ambulatory blood pressure control 5. reduce serum phosphorus 6. minimize per-hemodialytic changes in serum potassium and pH 7. have favorable effects on indices of physical function and global health - Indicates co-primary outcomes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Adjuvant Peritoneal Dialysis on a Background of Thrice-Weekly Hemodialysis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Icodextrin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients who are functionally anuric (urine volume &lt;100ml/day) receiving chronic maintenance dialysis for treatment of endstage renal disease transitioning from hemodialysis (HD) to peritoneal dialysis (PD) transitioning from PD to HD receiving PD and have a functional arteriovenous access already in place &lt; 18 years of age anticipate living related kidney transplant or transfer of care away from a participating unit within the next 6 months have anticipated survival &lt;6 months have contraindications to PD therapy history of complicated bowel or abdominal aortic surgery known abdominal wall defects pregnancy (including premenopausal women not surgically sterilized or on hormonal contraception) indwelling transabdominal prosthetic devices (e.g., feeding or biliary tubes) known hypersensitivity to peritoneal dialysate</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hemodialysis/Peritoneal Dialysis</keyword>
	<keyword>functionally anuric</keyword>
	<keyword>Icodextrin</keyword>
	<keyword>Kidney Disease Quality of Life</keyword>
</DOC>