<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02044783</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Sedentary older adults are more likely to develop physical function impairments than active older adults. Physical function measured by slow usual gait speed predicts the risk of future falls, disability, institutionalization and mortality. Behavioral physical activity interventions have improved physical activity and physical function, but have not generally been implemented where they may have the most impact -- primary care settings. In part, this is due to the limited time and training for clinical staff to screen for physical function impairment and to treat with physical activity counseling. The proposed scientific goal is to overcome these barriers by adapting an evidence-based screening tool and telephone-based physical activity intervention into primary care settings. Aim1: Among older adults who screen positive for physical function impairment, to determine the estimated intervention effect size of a 12-week behavioral intervention on physical activity and physical function. Hypothesis 1a: Physical activity levels will increase more in the intervention vs. usual care group. Hypothesis 1b: Physical function will increase more in the intervention vs. usual care group. Aim 2: Among Aim 1 participants and clinical staff who deliver the functional screening and Aim 1 intervention, to evaluate standard implementation science process metrics of reach, acceptability, and implementation</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Identifying and Treating Physical Function Impairment in Elders</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Sedentary patients aged 6585 years who screen positive for physical function impairment (Physical function impairment includes any of the following: time to complete 4meter walk ≥4.82 seconds (i.e., ≥0.83 meters/second); a reported fall in the past 3 months; or a reported fear of falling) Inability to walk ≥30 feet without human assistance7 Dementia, as assessed by either a Folstein MiniMental Status Examination &lt;24 or by patient's primary care provider's assessment Severe vision loss (legally blind) Severe hearing loss Medical condition that precludes increasing physical activity per primary care provider's assessment Terminal diagnosis per primary care provider's assessment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Adults</keyword>
	<keyword>Elderly</keyword>
</DOC>