<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01884753</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main purpose of this study is to get the urethra and pelvic sonographic imaging by 4D ultrasound examinations, and to correlate the sonographic findings with urodynamic variables, pad weights and LUTS. Besides, the associations of the blood flow of vagina/urethra and sexual dysfunction can be explored.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Correlations of 3D Urethral and Paraurethral Sonographic Findings With Urodynamic Studies, Lower Urinary Tract Symptoms &amp; Sexual Dysfunction in Female Patients With Lower Urinary Tract Symptoms.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Female lower urinary tract dysfunction includes stress urinary incontinence, overactive bladder syndrome and voiding dysfunction. There are a lot of bladder studies, such as researches of bladder wall thickness and bladder volume. However, there were few studies of urethra for female patients with lower urinary tract symptoms (LUTS), especially for storage disorder. Thus, the main purpose of this study is to get the urethra and pelvic sonographic imaging by 4D ultrasound examinations, and to correlate the sonographic findings with urodynamic variables, pad weights and LUTS. The investigators hope to identify important LUTS sonographic biomarkers that can be used by primary physicians as a tool for assess female LUTS, and thus decreasing the need of further invasive urodynamic studies. Besides, the associations of the blood flow of vagina/urethra and sexual dysfunction (assessed by female sexual function index) can be explored. In addition, women who receive antimuscarinics treatment will receive follow-up 4D imaging and request to complete questionnaire 12 weeks later.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder, Overactive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lower Urinary Tract Symptoms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women with lower urinary tract symptoms Not less than 20 yearsold Patients with a history of stroke.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>lower urinary tract symptoms</keyword>
	<keyword>overactive bladder syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>antimuscarinic drug</keyword>
	<keyword>three-dimensional power Doppler ultrasound</keyword>
	<keyword>sexual dysfunction</keyword>
</DOC>