<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01884649</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Fetuin-A levels are reported to be low as a negative acute phase reactant in systemical inflammatory situations. Hashimoto thyroiditis is characterized with inflammation. In this study, we hypothesised that the serum fetuin A levels could be found to be low due to inflammation in patients with Hashimoto thyroiditis</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Fetuin A in Hashimoto Thyroiditis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients ≥ 20 years of age being followed up at the outpatient clinics of the Internal Medicine Department in Medeniyet University Goztepe Training and Research Hospital and fulfilling the eligibility criteria will be included in the study. Approval of the local ethics committee and informed consent of the participants will be received for the study. The study is conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. Demographic characteristics, concomitant diseases, smoking and alcohol drinking habits, concomitant medication usage, anthropometric and biochemistry data of the eligible patients will be recorded. Patient group will consist of patients with newly diagnosed Hashimoto thyroiditis and the control group will consist of healthy volunteers. Groups will be compared according to their demographic, an¬thropometric and biochemistry data and serum fetuin-A levels. In order to detect the relationship between the serum fetuin-A levels and clinical features, correlation analyses will be done.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Thyroiditis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hashimoto Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients newly diagnosed with Hashimoto thyroiditis Acute infection Acute or chronic inflammatory disease Antiinflammatory treatment (nonsteroidal antiinflammatory, corticosteroids etc.) Hypoxic situations (chronic obstructive pulmonary disease etc.) Severe heart, kidney and liver disease Pregnancy Endocrine disorders Malignancy Usage of drug that affects thyroid hormone levels</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acute phase reactant, fetuin A, Hashimoto thyroiditis</keyword>
</DOC>