<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00703924</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is to determine the effectiveness and safety of WR 279,396, a topical cream for the treatment of cutaneous leishmaniasis. This study is to be conducted with a placebo control under double-blind conditions in a local population group in Tunisia where leishmaniasis is endemic.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Topical Treatment of Cutaneous Leishmaniasis With WR 279,396: A Phase 2 Study in the Old World</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>WR 279,396 is a paromomycin-based topical cream that has shown some suggestion of being effective for the treatment of non-serious, non-complicated cutaneous leishmaniasis in previous clinical studies. The goal of this study is to expand those observations in a larger, more rigorous study to clearly define the efficacy of this product and collect information about adverse effects. Subjects will be randomized to receive either WR 279,396 or vehicle placebo; applied twice a day for 20 days.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leishmaniasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leishmaniasis, Cutaneous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paromomycin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 575 years Lesions must measure at least 1 cm and be primarily ulcerative Have cutaneous leishmaniasis proven parasitologically in the lesion selected for study Must have given written informed consent to participate in the study Known drug intolerance to aminoglycosides in the patient or immediate family Previous use of antileishmanial drugs (within 3 months) or present use of routinely nephrotoxic or ototoxic drugs Patients with tuberculosis under treatment Potential for followup: have less than 7 months time remaining in present address and/or plan to leave the area for more than 30 days Extent of disease: more than 5 lesions or lesion equal to or greater than 5 cm or a lesion less than 5 cm from the eye, or a lesion in the face that, in the opinion of the attending dermatologist could potentially cause significant disfigurement Location of disease: mucosal involvement Disseminated disease: clinically significant lymphadenitis with nodules that are painful and greater than 1 cm in size in the lymphatic drainage of the ulcer Concomitant medical problems: significant medical problems of the kidney or liver as determined by history and by the following laboratory studies: Hearing abnormality Ongoing pregnancy or have plans to become pregnant Females of child bearing age (Tunisia Only) Signs or symptoms of peripheral neuropathy Kidney: clinically significant abnormalities of urine analysis, serum levels of creatinine, BUN, total proteins greater than the upper limit of normal for the laboratory. Liver: AST or ALT greater than the upper limit of normal for the laboratory General: glucose, Na+, or K+ greater than the upper limit of normal for the laboratory</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>cutaneous leishmaniasis topical treatment safety efficacy</keyword>
</DOC>