<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00703846</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Extina (ketoconazole) Foam, 2% was approved for marketing in the United States (US) in June 2007. Extina foam is indicated for topical treatment of seborrheic dermatitis in immunocompetent patients 12 years of age and older. The approved dosing regimen is twice daily for 4 weeks. The treatment of recurrent seborrheic dermatitis demands a topical preparation that is safe for both short-term and chronic application. This study is being conducted in order to obtain long-term safety data on the use of Extina (ketoconazole) Foam, 2% in the treatment of seborrheic dermatitis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>STUDY TO ASSESS THE LONG-TERM SAFETY OF EXTINA (KETOCONAZOLE) FOAM, 2%</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label, multicenter, single-group study to assess the long-term safety of twice daily treatment with Extina (ketoconazole) Foam, 2% in subjects with seborrheic dermatitis. The study subjects must have seborrheic dermatitis with an Investigator's Static Global Assessment (ISGA) of 2, 3, or 4 at baseline. In addition, subjects must have a discrete, evaluable target area of at least 0.5 cm2, with a score of 2, 3, or 4 for erythema and scaling. All subjects will apply Extina (ketoconazole) Foam, 2% topically twice a day (morning and evening) to all seborrheic dermatitis lesions on the face, scalp, ears, neck, and chest. Study product should be applied at the first sign of a seborrheic dermatitis flare, and twice daily applications should continue until the area(s) has cleared. All symptom flares should be treated throughout the 12-month study period. Study visits will occur at baseline (day 1) and at weeks 4, 8, 16, 26, 39, and 52 (or early withdrawal). See the study flowchart (section 3) for the assessments to be performed at each visit. Primary Objective: To assess the long-term safety of Extina (ketoconazole) Foam, 2% in the treatment of seborrheic dermatitis.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dermatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dermatitis, Seborrheic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ketoconazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects must fulfill all of the following conditions or characteristics in order to be considered for study enrollment: 1. Capable of understanding and willing to provide signed and dated written voluntary informed consent before any protocolspecific procedures are performed. For subjects between the ages of 12 and 17 years, a parent or legal guardian must be capable of understanding and willing to sign informed consent and subject must be capable of understanding and willing to sign an adolescent assent. 2. Male or female subjects 12 years of age or older. 3. Able to complete the study and to comply with study instructions. 4. Female subjects of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test. Sexually active women of childbearing potential participating in the study must use a medically acceptable form of contraception (which includes oral contraception, injectable or implantable methods, or intrauterine devices). Barrier methods of contraception are not acceptable. A woman of childbearing potential is defined as one who is biologically capable of becoming pregnant. Abstinence is considered an appropriate barrier control method. 5. Seborrheic dermatitis on the face, scalp, ears, neck, or chest with an ISGA of 2, 3, or 4 at baseline 6. Subjects must have a discrete, evaluable target area of at least 0.5 cm2, with a score of 2, 3, or 4 for erythema and scaling on the Seborrheic Dermatitis Grading Scale Subjects with any of the following conditions or characteristics will be excluded from study enrollment: 1. Use of systemic antifungal agents, corticosteroids or other immunosuppressive therapies, or systemic retinoids within 4 weeks prior to the baseline visit. 2. Use of topical antifungal therapy, corticosteroid therapy, or calcineurin inhibitors to the face, scalp, ears, neck, or chest within 2 weeks prior to the baseline visit. 3. Use of any investigational drugs within 8 weeks prior to the baseline visit, or subjects who are scheduled to receive an investigative drug other than the study product during the period of the study. 4. History of known or suspected intolerance to any of the ingredients of the study product. 5. Female subjects who are pregnant, trying to become pregnant, or lactating. 6. Any clinically relevant abnormal vital signs or findings on the physical examination. 7. A clinically relevant history of abuse of alcohol or other drugs. 8. Any major illness within 30 days prior to the baseline visit. 9. Subjects with any clinically significant condition which would, in the opinion of the investigator, compromise the subject's participation in the study. 10. Subjects who are immunocompromised. 11. Considered unable or unlikely to attend the necessary visits. 12. Employees of Stiefel Laboratories or a contract research organization involved in the study, or an immediate family member (partner, offspring, parents, siblings, or sibling's offspring) of an employee. 13. Currently using any medication, which in the opinion of the investigator may affect the evaluation of the study product or place the subject at undue risk. 14. Only one subject per household may be entered into the study. These inclusion and exclusion criteria will be strictly adhered to throughout the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Phase 4</keyword>
	<keyword>Seborrheic</keyword>
	<keyword>Ketoconazole</keyword>
	<keyword>Dermatitis</keyword>
</DOC>