<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00052221</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Epoetin alfa may help improve energy levels and quality of life in patients who have advanced solid tumors. PURPOSE: Randomized clinical trial to study the effectiveness of epoetin alfa in treating fatigue in patients who are not receiving chemotherapy for advanced solid tumors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Epoetin Alfa in Treating Fatigue in Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors Who Are Not Receiving Chemotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the efficacy of epoetin alfa in treating fatigue in patients with advanced solid tumors who are not receiving chemotherapy. - Determine the efficacy of this drug on functional status and overall quality of life in these patients. - Correlate self-reported level of energy with other commonly occurring symptoms (e.g., pain, depression, anxiety, dyspnea, appetite disturbance, or sleep disturbance) in these patients. - Correlate anemia with other common symptoms in these patients. - Determine the internal consistency of fatigue self-report using three single-item measures of this symptom and the responsiveness of each item to change over time in these patients. OUTLINE: This is a double-blind, placebo-controlled, randomized, multicenter study. Patients are stratified according to participating center, ECOG performance status (0-1 vs 2-3), and hemoglobin prior to study (10 mg/dL or less vs greater than10 mg/dL). Patients are randomized to one of two treatment arms. - Arm I: Patients receive epoetin alfa subcutaneously (SC) once weekly for 6 weeks. - Arm II: Patients receive placebo SC once weekly for 6 weeks. Patients in either arm that do not respond to therapy may receive an additional 6 weeks of open-label epoetin alfa SC once weekly. In both arms, quality of life and fatigue are assessed at baseline and at 3 and 6 weeks. If patients receive an additional 6 weeks of therapy, quality of life and fatigue are also assessed at 9 and 12 weeks. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 128 patients (64 per treatment arm) will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fatigue</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epoetin Alfa</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Diagnosis of stage III or IV invasive nonmyeloid malignancy Not currently hospitalized At least somewhat bothered by fatigue based on selfreport No significant psychological distress indicated by total score of 6 or more on questions 1 and 2 of the ThreeQuestion Screening Survey (3QSS) No score less than 2 on question 3 of 3QSS indicating low level of fatigue within the past week No uncontrolled brain metastases or leptomeningeal involvement PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 18 and over Performance status: Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) 03 Life expectancy: At least 12 weeks Hematopoietic: Hemoglobin at least 8.5 g/dL but no greater than 11 g/dL No anemia due to factors other than cancer or chemotherapy (e.g., iron or folate deficiency, hemolysis, or bleeding) No prior or concurrent hematological disease Hepatic: Not specified Renal: Not specified Cardiovascular: No uncontrolled hypertension (diastolic blood pressure greater than 100 mm Hg or systolic blood pressure greater than 200 mm Hg) No significant uncontrolled concurrent cardiovascular disease or dysfunction not attributable to malignancy or chemotherapy No history of deepvein thrombosis Pulmonary: No significant uncontrolled concurrent pulmonary disease or dysfunction not attributable to malignancy or chemotherapy Other: Not pregnant or nursing Fertile patients must use effective contraception during and for 3 months after study participation Able to understand and complete selfreport symptom assessment forms in English No serious concurrent infection No known hypersensitivity to mammalian cellderived products or human albumin No uncontrolled seizures No significant uncontrolled concurrent endocrine, neurologic, gastrointestinal, or genitourinary system disease or dysfunction not attributable to malignancy or chemotherapy PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: See Chemotherapy More than 4 weeks since prior biologic therapy (e.g., interferon or interleukin2) More than 2 months since prior red blood cells (RBC) transfusion More than 1 month since prior epoetin alfa or investigational forms of epoetin alfa (e.g., geneactivated, novel erythropoiesisstimulating protein) Concurrent nonmyelosuppressive therapy (e.g., monoclonal antibody infusions, antiangiogenesis inhibitors, or signal transduction inhibitors) allowed No other concurrent biologic therapy Chemotherapy: No prior highdose chemotherapy (e.g., with bone marrow or stem cell transplantation) More than 4 weeks since prior chemotherapy No concurrent chemotherapy Endocrine therapy: Concurrent hormonal therapy allowed (e.g., luteinizing hormonereleasing hormone agonists or tamoxifen) Radiotherapy: More than 4 weeks since prior radiotherapy No concurrent radiotherapy Surgery: Not specified</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>unspecified adult solid tumor, protocol specific</keyword>
	<keyword>fatigue</keyword>
</DOC>