<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01557881</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This clinical trial studies positron emission tomography (PET)/magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) in patients undergoing PET/computed tomography (CT). Diagnostic procedures, such as PET/MRI, may help doctors diagnose cancer or help doctors predict a patient's response to treatment</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Positron Emission Tomography/Magnetic Resonance Imaging in Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To acquire PET/MRI scans of 100 patients which will be compared with PET/CT scans of the same subjects. The PET/CT scans will be used to provide the gold standard for evaluating the image quality and quantitative performance of the PET/MRI scans. After comparison and evaluation of the imaging capabilities and performance of the sequential PET/MRI imaging system for these 100 subjects, a second cohort of hundred consecutive subjects may be necessary and again comparisons made to the current standard of PET imaging, PET/CT. This validation of the attenuation correction methods and quantitative accuracy of the PET/MRI device compared to PET/CT will be a continuous iterative process that will result in optimized performance of the PET/MRI and will be a key step in its becoming available to other clinical research projects both within the Seidman Cancer Center as well as in other institutions. OUTLINE: After undergoing standard PET/CT, patients undergo PET/MRI.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Only patients who are referred by their physician to have a clinical PET/CT will be eligible to participate in the study we propose to obtain a second PET/MRI on 100 patients after their clinical PET/CT imaging that spans several disease categories and includes the following cancers: lung, colon, melanoma, head/neck and lymphoma In addition to oncology patients, we anticipate imaging a subset of noncancer patients who will also be imaged subsequent to their clinical PET/CT who will be referrals from neurology and cardiology All subjects will be at least 18 years old, or if under 18, parents or guardians must give consent Subjects must be stable and have experienced no adverse events from previous clinical PET/CT examination Subjects who do not meet the above inclusion criteria Subjects unwilling or unable to sign the informed consent form Subjects who are cognitively impaired and thus unable to give informed consent Subjects unable to undergo MRI scanning due to exclusion via University Hospital Case Medical Center (UHCMC) MRI restrictions (e.g. implanted metallic or electronic devices, hip or other joint replacements, history of kidney disease, unacceptable creatinine or glomerular filtration rate [GFR], etc) Patients who are pregnant</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>