<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01557933</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary purpose of this study is to use magnetic resonance spectroscopy (MRS) to measure the levels of several brain chemicals including, but not limited to, glutamate, glutamine, and N-acetylaspartate, before and after treatment with ECT. In addition to MRS, the investigators will use several other MRI techniques including structural MRI, resting state functional MRI (fMRI), and diffusion tensor imaging (DTI) to measure how the structure and function of the brain changes with ECT. The investigators hypothesize that the Gln/Glu ratio is increased in the anterior cingulate cortex (ACC), but not the parieto-occipital cortex (POC), following the first ECT treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Electroconvulsive Therapy (ECT) in Bipolar Depression</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bipolar Disorder</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female age 1855 Meets DSMIV criteria for Bipolar Disorder Type I, II, or NOS with current episode depressed Has been scheduled to be evaluated by an ECT consultant from the McLean Hospital ECT service Current score of greater than or equal to 24 on the MontgomeryAsberg Depression Rating Scale (MADRS) Unwillingness or inability to provide informed consent Lifetime history of schizophrenia DSMIV diagnosis of alcohol or substance dependence, with the exception of nicotine dependence, within three months prior to screening Positive urine toxicology screen at screening (NOTE: Participants with a positive urine toxicology screen who are prescribed benzodiazepine, stimulant, or opiate medications by their physician will be permitted to enroll in the study as long as they do not meet abuse or dependence criteria for these substances) Female participants with a positive urine pregnancy test at screening Pregnancy. Females of childbearing potential must be using an effective contraceptive method (e.g., abstinence, prescription oral contraceptives, contraceptive injections, MRIsafe intrauterine device, doublebarrier method, male partner sterilization) Any contraindications to having an MRI scan, including cardiac pacemakers, metal vascular clips or stents, artificial heart valves, certain kinds of prostheses, brain stimulator devices, implanted drug pumps, ear implants, eye implants or known metal fragments in eyes, exposure to shrapnel or metal filings (wounded in military combat, sheetmetal workers, welders, and others), transdermal drug delivery systems, and certain tattoos with metallic ink. NOTE: Participants will be screened for these conditions at screening, and will be required to fill out a standard MRI screening form at the Brain Imaging Center, which will be reviewed by an MRI technician prior to each MRI scan Scheduled to receive first ECT treatment on a Friday</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>ECT</keyword>
	<keyword>Bipolar Disorder</keyword>
</DOC>