<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01557192</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To demonstrate the efficacy of multiple applications of Low Field Magnetic Stimulation (LFMS) as an antidepressant treatment in subjects with mood disorders.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Low Field Magnetic Stimulation (LFMS) in Mood Disorders: 6 Treatments</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The Low Field Magnetic Stimulation (LFMS) procedure is an application of a series of electromagnetic pulses to the brain lasting twenty minutes. The field and timing parameters of the LFMS pulses, such as pulse timing, duration, frequency, and electric and magnetic field distribution and direction are different from other neurostimulation methods. The mechanism of action for the antidepressant effects of LFMS is hypothesized to be an effect on dendritic or synaptic activity in the cortex, brought about by low level electrical stimulation applied with particular timing. This is analogous to the synaptic effects of pharmaceutical antidepressants in providing a "boost" to synapses in certain brain regions. Previous investigations of LFMS included depressed subjects with bipolar disorder. This study will evaluate the antidepressant effects of multiple LFMS treatments in bipolar disorder and major depressive disorder.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mood Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bipolar Disorder</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Subjects MUST be significantly depressed, currently. 2. Subjects must not have serious physical illnesses, neurological diseases or dementias. 3. Subjects will meet DSMIV criteria for Bipolar Disorder Type I or II, Major Depressive Disorder, Post Traumatic Stress Disorder, or Obsessive Compulsive Disorder, and be currently depressed. 4. Subject must have a HamD score &gt; 17, YMRS score &lt; 7 (bipolar subjects only), and a MADRS score &gt; 18. 5. Subjects must be capable of providing informed consent. 6. Subjects must have an established residence and phone. 7. Subjects may be medicated or unmedicated. 1. Dangerous or active suicidal ideation. 2. Pregnant or planning on becoming pregnant. 3. Substance abuse (cannot meet DSM criteria for substance abuse, no significant drug abuse within last 3 months, no major polysubstance abuse history, no history of dependence in last year, no drug use within last month). 4. Mixed mood state or rapid cycling. 5. Presence of a pacemaker, neurostimulator, or metal in head or neck.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Depression</keyword>
	<keyword>Bipolar Depression</keyword>
	<keyword>LFMS</keyword>
	<keyword>Electromagnetic Stimulation</keyword>
</DOC>