<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01557036</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to further expand the body of clinical knowledge in patients undergoing Pipeline Embolization Device (Pipeline or PED) placement for intracranial aneurysms (IAs or ICAs) according to Pipeline's labeled indication.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Aneurysm Study of Pipeline in an Observational Registry</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Aneurysm</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Intracranial Aneurysm</mesh_term>
	<criteria>(All sites, All countries) 1. At least 1 Pipeline placed for treatment of an ICA 2. Patient or patient's Legally Authorized Representative (LAR) has signed an IRB or ECapproved informed consent form, if required 3. Patient is willing and able to comply with followup visits United States: Additional Inclusion Criteria for subjects enrolled in the United States: 4US) Subjects who are age 22 or higher 5US) IA of at least 10 mm in maximum dimension along the internal carotid artery between the petrous and superior hypophyseal segments Canada: Additional Inclusion Criteria for subjects enrolled in Canada: 4C) In Canada, the Pipeline™ Embolization Device is intended for use with or without embolic coils for the treatment of complex intracranial aneurysms that are not amenable to treatment with surgical clipping. 5C) Canadian licensing/approval is limited to devices that are between 3.25 mm and 5.00 mm in diameter. France: Additional Inclusion Criteria for subjects enrolled in France: 4F) Unruptured IA, saccular or fusiform with an aneurysm sac diameter &gt; 15mm and not treatable with other current therapies ( EVT with coils with or without assisting system (intracranial stent) or balloon remodeling, or surgery) due to its specific morphology. 5F) IA previously treated with unruptured recanalization of the aneurismal sac &gt; 7 mm, not treatable with conservative treatment. (based on contraindications PED IFU) 1. Active bacterial infection 2. A patient in whom dual antiplatelet therapy (aspirin and clopidogrel) is contraindicated 3. A patient who has not received dual antiplatelet agents prior to the procedure 4. Preexisting stent is in place in the parent artery at the target aneurysm location 5. Angiography demonstrates inappropriate anatomy, e.g., severe preor postaneurysm narrowing 6. Acutely ruptured aneurysm, defined as rupture of the target aneurysm Each site should refer to their country specific Instructions for Use/Approval(France) to determine final eligibility into the ASPIRe Registry.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Brain Aneurysm</keyword>
</DOC>