<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02885792</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Schizophrenia is a severe mental illness associated with excess mortality and affecting nearly 1% of the population. The average life expectancy for patients diagnosed with schizophrenia has been 55-60 years through the last generations in Denmark, while the general population has over the same period of time experienced an increase in life expectancy. As a result, the standardized mortality rate for patients with schizophrenia has increased markedly over the last three decades and is currently a major public health concern. Causes of death are mainly cardiovascular disease and patients diagnosed with schizophrenia has a relative risk of cardiovascular disease that is about 2-fold higher than the general population.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Coronary Artery Disease in Patients Suffering From Schizophrenia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Little is known about severe progression of premature coronary arteriosclerosis in patients suffering from schizophrenia. Coronary artery calcium score is a well-defined measure to predict cardiovascular disease events, however there has not yet been any attempt to investigate whether there is an association between coronary artery calcium score and premature morbidity and mortality in patients diagnosed with schizophrenia. The objective of this study is to investigate the progression of arteriosclerosis in patients with schizophrenia at different stages of the disease, and to offer and implement adequate treatment for these patients according to their somatic condition. This study will identify risk factors of somatic diseases in these patients, with specific focus on early diagnoses, prevention, intervention and treatment of arteriosclerosis in schizophrenic patients. The investigation is about the possibility of detecting any differences between developing arteriosclerosis in schizophrenia patients versus the general population, and how common risk factors are contributing to this process. The results of this study should provide important modifications in the clinical guidelines for treatment of patients diagnosed with schizophrenia.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participants with a diagnosis of F20 schizophrenia. Informed statement of consent Age &gt; 18 Incompetency to create stabile relation or make agreements Pregnancy and also breastfeeding women Participants with severe claustrophobia Participants with lack of ability to cooperate with the planned study program.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Schizophrenia</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiovascular disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Premature mortality</keyword>
	<keyword>Arteriosclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Risk factor</keyword>
	<keyword>Intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>Somatic morbidity</keyword>
</DOC>