<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02885701</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if any difference exists among 3 different postoperative splinting regimens- no splint, removable splint, and plaster non-removable splint- following mini-open carpal tunnel release (CTR) surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Splinting After Mini-Open Carpal Tunnel Release</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>We sought to determine if any significant difference in patient-reported or clinical outcomes existed among 3 different postoperative splinting regimens- no splint, removable splint, and plaster non-removable splint- following mini-open carpal tunnel release (CTR) surgery for symptomatic, isolated, nerve conduction study positive carpal tunnel syndrome (CTS). A total of 249 patients received a mini-open CTR and were subsequently randomized into 1 of the 3 splinting regimens to be removed at the first postoperative visit 10-14 days later. Patient-reported outcomes included QuickDASH surveys, Levine-Katz Symptom Severity Scale (SSS) and Functional Status Scale (FSS) and Pain at Rest and in Action using a Numerical Pain Rating Scale (NPRS). Clinical outcomes included wrist range of motion (ROM), grip and lateral pinch strengths. All outcomes were evaluated bilaterally at 10-14 days, 6 weeks, 3 months, 6 months and 12 months after surgery. Demographic information was obtained preoperatively and complications were observed for and recorded throughout the study</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carpal Tunnel Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients were required to have failed conservative treatment for symptomatic, isolated, nerve conduction study positive CTS. Exclusion criteria omitted patients who presented with acute onset CTS, concomitant peripheral neuropathy, metabolic disease, postoperative recurring CTS, or who required another operative procedure during carpal tunnel release.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>postoperative dressing</keyword>
	<keyword>postoperative splint</keyword>
	<keyword>mini-open carpal tunnel release</keyword>
</DOC>