<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02644967</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this clinical research study is to find the highest tolerated dose of the study drug IMO-2125 that can be given in combination with ipilimumab or in combination with pembrolizumab to patients with metastatic melanoma. Researchers also want to learn if the study drug combination can help to control the disease. The safety of the drug combination will also be studied.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Assess the Safety and Efficacy of Intratumoral IMO-2125 in Combination With Ipilimumab or Pembrolizumab in Patients With Metastatic Melanoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label Phase 1/2 study to determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) and assess the safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics (PK), immunogenicity, and efficacy of IMO-2125 when administered in combination with ipilimumab or pembrolizumab. The study will be conducted in 2 parts; a dose-escalation portion (Phase 1) to evaluate safety and tolerability of multiple dose levels and a Phase 2 portion to assess efficacy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients must have histologically confirmed metastatic melanoma with measurable, stage III (lymph node or in transit lesions) or stage IVA, IVB, or IVC disease. Patients must have symptomatic or radiographic confirmed progression after treatment with a PD1 inhibitor administered either as monotherapy or in combination (except for ipilimumab or other CTLA4 inhibitor combination). 1. The interval between last PD1 directed treatment and start of study treatment should be at least 21 days. 2. No intervening anticancer therapy between the last course of antiPD1 containing treatment and the first dose of study treatment is allowed except for local measures (e.g., surgical excision or biopsy, focal RT). 3. Prior adjuvant ipilimumab is acceptable. 4. Prior BRAF or MEK inhibitor treatment is not required. 5. Previous treatment with either a PD1 or CTLA4 inhibitor (if applicable) should not have been accompanied DLT for which permanent discontinuation is recommended (per USPI). Patients must have at least two measurable tumor lesions ≥ 1.0 cm that are accessible to biopsy. Patients must be ≥ 18 years of age. Patients must have Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status ≤ 2. Patients must meet the following laboratory criteria: Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1.5 x 10^9/L (1500/mm3) Platelet count ≥ 100 x 10^9/L (100,000/mm3) Hemoglobin ≥ 8.0 g/dL (4.96 mmol/L) Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) or 24hour creatinine clearance ≥ 60 mL/minute Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) ≤ 2.5 x ULN; alanine aminotransferase (ALT) ≤ 2.5 x ULN; AST/ALT &lt; 5 x ULN if liver involvement Serum bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x ULN, except in patients with Gilbert's Syndrome who must have a total bilirubin &lt; 3 mg/dL Women of childbearing potential (WOCBP) and men must agree to use effective contraceptive methods from Screening throughout the study treatment period and until at least 3 months after the last dose of ipilimumab or at least 4 months after the last dose of pembrolizumab. Patients must have an anticipated life expectancy &gt; 3 months. Patients who have received prior therapy with a TLR agonist ,excluding topical agents. Patients who have received experimental vaccines or other immune therapies should be discussed with the Medical Monitor to confirm eligibility. Patients who have received systemic treatment with IFNα within the previous 6 months prior to enrolling into this study. Patients with known hypersensitivity to any oligodeoxynucleotide. Patients with active autoimmune disease requiring disease modifying therapy. Patients requiring concurrent systemic steroid therapy higher than physiologic dose (7.5 mg/day of prednisone). Patients with any form of active primary or secondary immunodeficiency. Patients with another primary malignancy that has not been in remission for at least 3 years. Patients with active systemic infections requiring antibiotics or active hepatitis A, B, or C. Patients with a known diagnosis of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection. Patients with known central nervous system, meningeal, or epidural disease. Patients with stable brain metastases following definitive local treatment are eligible if steroid requirement is less than 7.5 mg/day of prednisone (or equivalent). Women who are pregnant or breastfeeding. Patients with impaired cardiac function or clinically significant cardiac disease. Patients with ocular melanoma.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>