<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03071328</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to plan the delivery of the PVSRIPO therapeutic poliovirus in a future prostate cancer clinical trial. Virus-free, diluted iodinated contrast will be injected intra-tumorally under CT fluoroscopy guidance into bone, lymph node, and liver metastases in subjects with Metastatic Castration-resistant Prostate Cancer (mCRPC), and pre and post-injection CT images will be obtained to determine the injection parameters needed for optimal distribution throughout metastases of a given size. A biopsy of the metastatic site will also be obtained to validate the expression of the poliovirus receptor CD155 in prostate cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>INJECT: A Pilot Study of Intra-tumoral Injections in Metastatic Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Histologically confirmed diagnosis of adenocarcinoma of the prostate. Small cell or neuroendocrine tumors of the prostate are also permitted. 2. Radiographic evidence of at least one bone, lymph node, or liver metastasis, measuring between 2 cm to 8 cm (short axis for lymph nodes, long axis for bone and liver metastases), that is amenable to iodinated contrast injection, as judged by the study radiologist 3. For subjects undergoing contrast injection of a bone metastasis: histologically confirmed metastatic prostate adenocarcinoma must be present on a biopsy of the bone metastasis to be injected. Biopsy must be done within two weeks of Day 1. 4. Adequate laboratory values: 1. Platelets &gt; 75,000 2. INR ≤ 1.5 5. Age &gt; 18 years. 6. Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document. 1. History of intercurrent or past medical or psychiatric illness that would make participation in a research biopsy protocol difficult or not feasible at the discretion of the principal investigator or coinvestigator(s). 2. Cr &gt;2.0 3. History of iodinated contrast allergy 4. Requirement for anticoagulation with heparin, low molecular weight heparin, clopidogrel, rivaroxaban, dabigatran, apixaban, warfarin, Aggrenox, fondaparux, ticagrelor, etc (aspirin and other NSAIDs are ok but should be held prior to biopsy in accordance with institutional standard of care) 5. Any other contraindication to CT with iodinated contrast, as CT with contrast will be used in the study.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>