<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02424513</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a prospective, multicenter, open-label, non-randomized study evaluating the ability of [89]Zr-Df-IAb2M to detect local, regional and metastatic prostate cancer confirmed by pathology.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Positron Emission Tomography (PET) With [89]Zr-Df-IAb2M in Patients With High-risk Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>IAB2M is an approximately 80 kDA molecular weight antibody fragment (a "Minibody") chelated with Desferroxamine and radiolabeled with [89]Zr. [89Zr]-Df-IAB2M targets the extracellular domain of Prostate Membrane Specific Antigen (PSMA) expressed on most primary and metastatic prostate cancer lesions. This is a phase 2, prospective, multi-center, open-label, non-randomized study evaluating the ability of [89]Zr-Df-IAb2M to detect local, regional and metastatic prostate cancer confirmed by pathology in patients with biopsy-proven prostate cancer thought to be candidates for radical prostatectomy and pelvic lymph node dissection who are at high-risk for pelvic lymph node metastasis. These patients may have identified lymphadenopathy on conventional imaging but are considered eligible if still judged to be candidates for radical prostatectomy and lymph node dissection.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Histological diagnosis of prostate adenocarcinoma. 2. Patients considered candidates for radical prostatectomy and pelvic lymph node dissection. These patients may or may not have identified nodal metastasis on conventional imaging but would still be candidates for radical prostatectomy and pelvic lymph node dissection. 3. Patients, who are at highrisk for pelvic lymph node metastasis as defined by a lymph node involvement risk of greater than or equal to 20% using the Briganti nomogram. 4. Age ≥ 18 years. 5. Ability to understand and willingness to sign IRB approved consent form 6. For men of childproducing potential, the use of effective contraceptive methods during the study. 1. Treatment or plans for treatment with radiation therapy, surgery, chemotherapy, or investigational therapy between the time of conventional imaging, [89]ZrDfIAB2M PET/CT and the surgical resection or biopsy procedures used for the study evaluation. 2. Unwillingness or inability to comply with procedures required in this protocol. 3. Other cancers that might potentially interfere with the reading and interpretation of [89]ZrDfIAB2M PET/CT scans. 4. Patients who are currently receiving any other investigational agent. 5. Patients who have had or are currently receiving androgen deprivation therapy</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>