<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00737568</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of therapy for the treatment of chronic hepatitis B virus (HBV) is to maintain suppression of viral replication to prevent the emergence of complications, which requires long-term therapy. Durable suppression of viral replication is achieved in the treatment of chronic viral diseases by preventing of the emergence of drug-resistant mutations. The clinical guidelines for the management of lamivudine resistant patients are variable. Some recommend switching to another agent without cross-resistance, while others recommend adding on another agent without cross-resistance. Limited clinical data exists to demonstrate whether tenofovir disoproxil fumarate (tenofovir DF; TDF) is an effective monotherapy for lamivudine resistant patients or if it should be used as part of a combination therapy regimen. This study is designed to evaluate the effectiveness, safety, and tolerability of tenofovir DF monotherapy versus emtricitabine (FTC)/tenofovir DF combination therapy in participants with chronic HBV with lamivudine resistance (presence of the rtM204I/V mutation with or without the rtL180M mutation) over a 240-week period. Participants in this study must be receiving lamivudine treatment at the time of enrollment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Tenofovir Disoproxil Fumarate (Tenofovir DF) Versus Emtricitabine/Tenofovir DF in Subjects Resistant to Lamivudine</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tenofovir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Emtricitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lamivudine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Chronic HBV infection, defined as positive serum HBsAg for at least 6 months 18 through 75 years of age, inclusive HBV DNA ≥ 10^3 IU/mL Receiving treatment with lamivudine with confirmation of HBV reverse transcriptase mutation(s) known to confer resistance to lamivudine (rtM204I/V with or without rtL180M) by central laboratory assessment prior to randomization; adefovir dipivoxil treatment of ≤ 48 weeks at the time of screening (inclusive of combination adefovir dipivoxil + lamivudine at entry) was allowed Willing and able to provide written informed consent Negative serum pregnancy test (for females of childbearing potential only) Calculated creatinine clearance ≥ 50 mL/min Hemoglobin ≥ 10 g/dL Neutrophils ≥ 1000 /mm^3 No prior oral HBV therapy with approved nucleotide and/or nucleoside therapy or other investigational agents for HBV infection other than lamivudine or adefovir dipivoxil Exclusion Criteria Pregnant women, women who are breast feeding or who believe they may wish to become pregnant during the course of the study Males and females of reproductive potential who are not willing to use an effective method of contraception during the study Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) ≥ 10 × the upper limit of the normal range (ULN) Decompensated liver disease Interferon or pegylated interferon therapy within 6 months of the screening visit Alpha fetoprotein &gt; 50 ng/mL Evidence of hepatocellular carcinoma Coinfection with hepatitis C virus, HIV, or hepatitis D virus Significant renal, cardiovascular, pulmonary, or neurological disease Received solid organ or bone marrow transplantation Receiving therapy with immunomodulators (eg, corticosteroids, etc.), investigational agents, nephrotoxic agents, or agents susceptible of modifying renal excretion Proximal tubulopathy Known hypersensitivity to the study drugs, the metabolites or formulation excipients</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Tenofovir DF</keyword>
	<keyword>Emtricitabine</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic hepatitis B</keyword>
	<keyword>Combination therapy</keyword>
</DOC>