<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00737321</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This pilot study is designed to assess the impact of ischemia/ diminished wound vascularization and stress on wound healing by comparing patterns of gene expression in specific cell types critical to wound healing biology, e.g. macrophages or endothelial cells.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mechanisms Regulating Wound Vascularization</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Chronic wounds affect approximately 2% of the U.S. population at any given time. Animal models can not simulate the complex set of pre-existing conditions in each individual that results in failed wound healing. Therefore, human subjects must be used to obtain valid data. Adequate wound vascularization that permits blood vessels to deliver oxygen to the wound is a requirement for wound healing to occur. This protocol will attempt to gain greater understanding of the mechanisms of chronic wounds through 3 specific aims: 1) identify the angiogenic mechanisms in wound site macrophages, which are required for healing, 2) determine the impact of stress and glucocorticoid resistance on endothelial cell and macrophage biology and ultimately wound healing outcomes, 3) identify patterns of gene expression in wound endothelial cells that are found in healing versus non-healing wounds. This data will be correlated with the wound oxygenation status to determine the impact of wound vascularization on the observed biological responses.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neovascularization, Pathologic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 1869 years ischemic wound group nonischemic wound group diabetes with good glycemic control lower extremity wound Age greater ≥ 70 years End stage renal disease Unable to provide informed consent Pregnant women Therapeutically anticoagulated Prisoners Periwound TcOM &lt; 25mmHg Spinal cord injury Taking immunosuppressive medications Individuals with current diagnosis of a major psychiatric illness (e.g.schizophrenia,psychosis) Severe protein malnutrition prealbumin &lt; 10 mg/dl or albumin &lt; 2 g/dl Diabetes with poor glucose controldefined as hgb A1c &gt; 8.4%</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>69 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Impact of ischemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Impact of stress and</keyword>
	<keyword>Identify patterns of gene expression</keyword>
</DOC>