<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3082">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03066778</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>3475-604</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2016-004309-15</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03066778</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of Pembrolizumab (MK-3475) in Combination With Etoposide/Platinum (Cisplatin or Carboplatin) for Participants With Extensive Stage Small Cell Lung Cancer (MK-3475-604/KEYNOTE-604)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase III Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-controlled Trial of Pembrolizumab (MK-3475/SCH900475) in Combination With Etoposide/Platinum (Cisplatin or Carboplatin) for the First-line Treatment of Subjects With Extensive Stage Small Cell Lung Cancer (KEYNOTE-604)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to assess the safety and efficacy of pembrolizumab plus
      standard of care (SOC) chemotherapy (etoposide/platinum [EP]) in participants with newly
      diagnosed extensive stage small cell lung cancer (ES-SCLC) who have not previously received
      systemic therapy for this malignancy.

      The primary study hypotheses are that pembrolizumab+EP prolongs Progression-free Survival
      (PFS) per Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) version 1.1 by blinded
      independent central review (BICR) and Overall Survival (OS) compared with placebo+EP in
      adult participants with ES-SCLC.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free Survival (PFS) per Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors version 1.1 (RECIST 1.1) as Assessed by Blinded Independent Central Review (BICR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 2 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 2 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective Response Rate (ORR) per RECIST 1.1 as Assessed by BICR</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 2 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of Response (DOR) per RECIST 1.1 as Assessed by BICR</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 2 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Experiencing an Adverse Event (AE)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 27 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Discontinuing Study Treatment Due to an AE</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 2 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Experiencing Any Grade 3 to 5 AE as Assessed by National Cancer Institute (NCI) Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events Version 4.0 (CTCAE 4.0)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 27 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">430</enrollment>
  <condition>Small Cell Lung Cancer (SCLC)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pembrolizumab+EP</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>During each 21-day cycle, participants receive pembrolizumab 200 mg intravenously (IV) Day 1 PLUS etoposide 100 mg/m^2 IV on Days 1, 2 and 3 PLUS investigator's choice of platinum (carboplatin titrated to an area under the plasma drug concentration-time curve [AUC] 5 IV on Day 1 OR cisplatin 75 mg/m^2 IV on Day 1).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo+EP</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>During each 21-day cycle, participants receive placebo (normal saline solution) IV on Day 1 PLUS etoposide 100 mg/m^2 IV on Days 1, 2 and 3 PLUS investigator's choice of platinum (carboplatin titrated to an AUC 5 IV on Day 1 OR cisplatin 75 mg/m^2 IV on Day 1).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pembrolizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>IV infusion on Day 1 of each cycle prior to chemotherapy</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pembrolizumab+EP</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>MK-3475</other_name>
    <other_name>KEYTRUDA®</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Normal saline solution</intervention_name>
    <description>IV infusion on Day 1 of each cycle prior to chemotherapy</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo+EP</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Carboplatin</intervention_name>
    <description>IV infusion on Day 1 of each cycle</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pembrolizumab+EP</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo+EP</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PARAPLATIN®</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cisplatin</intervention_name>
    <description>IV infusion on Day 1 of each cycle</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pembrolizumab+EP</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo+EP</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PLATINOL®</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Etoposide</intervention_name>
    <description>IV infusion on Days 1, 2 and 3 of each cycle</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pembrolizumab+EP</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo+EP</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>TOPOSAR™</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Has a documented new diagnosis of SCLC by histology or cytology from brushing,
             washing, or needle aspiration of a defined lesion. Participants who do not have
             histology samples (defined as core or excisional biopsy, or resections) will need to
             undergo a new biopsy to provide a tissue sample.

          -  Has extensive-stage disease defined as Stage IV (T any, N any, M 1a/b) by the
             American Joint Committee on Cancer (AJCC), Seventh Edition

          -  Has ≥1 lesion that meets the criteria for measurable, as defined by RECIST 1.1, and
             is appropriate for selection as a target lesion, as determined by local site
             investigator/radiology assessment

          -  Has provided archival tumor tissue sample or newly obtained core or excisional biopsy
             of a tumor lesion not previously irradiated

          -  Has Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status of 0 or 1

          -  Has a life expectancy of ≥3 months

          -  Has adequate organ function

          -  Female and male participants of childbearing potential must be willing to use an
             adequate method of contraception, starting with the first dose of study treatment
             through 120 days after the last dose of study treatment and up to 180 days after last
             dose of chemotherapeutic agents

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Has received prior systemic therapy for the treatment of SCLC

          -  Is currently participating and receiving study treatment or has participated in a
             study of an investigational agent and received study treatment or used an
             investigational device within 4 weeks of the first dose of treatment for another
             health-related problem

          -  Is expected to require any other form of antineoplastic therapy for SCLC, including
             radiation therapy, while on study. (Prophylactic cranial irradiation will be possible
             for those participants with stable disease or better at the completion of the 4
             cycles of chemotherapy with or without pembrolizumab.)

          -  Has known active central nervous system (CNS) metastases and/or carcinomatous
             meningitis.

          -  Has had major surgery within 3 weeks prior to receiving the first dose of study
             treatment or has not recovered adequately from toxicity and/or complications from an
             intervention prior to receiving the first dose of study treatment.

          -  Has a history of (non-infectious) pneumonitis that required steroids or has current
             pneumonitis

          -  Has a known history of interstitial lung disease

          -  Has a known additional malignancy that is progressing or requires active treatment.
             Exceptions include early stage cancers (carcinoma in situ or Stage 1) treated with
             curative intent, basal cell carcinoma of the skin, squamous cell carcinoma of the
             skin, in situ cervical cancer, or in situ breast cancer that has undergone
             potentially curative therapy.

          -  Has active autoimmune disease that has required systemic treatment in the past 2
             years. Replacement therapy is not considered a form of systemic treatment.

          -  Has a known history of, or active, neurologic paraneoplastic syndrome

          -  Has clinically active diverticulitis, intra-abdominal abscess, gastrointestinal
             obstruction, and/or abdominal carcinomatosis

          -  Has a history of a severe hypersensitivity reaction to treatment with another
             monoclonal antibody

          -  Is taking chronic systemic steroids (in doses exceeding 10 mg daily of prednisone
             equivalent) within 7 days prior to the first dose of study treatment

          -  Has a diagnosis of immunodeficiency or is receiving any form of immunosuppressive
             therapy within 7 days prior to the first dose of study treatment

          -  Has received a live vaccine within 30 days prior to the first dose of study treatment

          -  Has received prior therapy with an anti-programmed cell death protein-1 (anti-PD-1),
             anti-programmed cell death-ligand 1 (anti-PD-L1), or anti-programmed cell
             death-ligand 2 (anti-PD-L2) agent or with an agent directed to another co-inhibitory
             T-cell receptor (i.e., cytotoxic T-lymphocyte-associated protein 4 [CTLA-4], tumor
             necrosis factor receptor superfamily member 9 [TNFRSF9, OX-40, CD137]) or has
             previously participated in a Merck pembrolizumab (MK-3475) clinical trial

          -  Has severe hypersensitivity (Grade ≥3) to pembrolizumab and/or any of its excipients

          -  Has an active infection requiring systemic therapy

          -  Has a known history of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection

          -  Has a history of or known active Hepatitis B or Hepatitis C virus

          -  Has a known history of active TB (Bacillus Tuberculosis)

          -  Has symptomatic ascites or pleural effusion. A participant who is clinically stable
             following treatment for these conditions (including therapeutic thoraco- or
             paracentesis) is eligible.

          -  Is pregnant or breastfeeding, or expecting to conceive or father children within the
             projected duration of the study starting with the screening visit through 120 days
             after the last dose of study treatment through and up to 180 days after last dose of
             chemotherapeutic agents
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Medical Director</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 13, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>February 23, 2017</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Extensive stage small cell lung cancer (ES-SCLC)</keyword>
  <keyword>Programmed cell death protein-1 (PD-1)</keyword>
  <keyword>Programmed cell death-ligand 1 (PD-L1)</keyword>
  <keyword>PD1</keyword>
  <keyword>PDL1</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Etoposide phosphate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Etoposide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
