<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02528773</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators are conducting a study to learn more about the spread of HIV infection within different geographic regions and populations in San Diego County, with the goal of demonstrating that early use of HIV treatment can reduce the number of new infections in our community. At the study visits, participants will be examined by the study staff and asked to donate some blood. Participants will also be asked several questions about themselves, their background, behaviors, health, and the general geographic area in which they live. By collecting information about antiretroviral treatment choices that are made by study participants, the investigators will be better able to measure how effectively HIV treatment can interrupt (i.e., block) the spread of HIV. All of the information gathered at the study visits will be de-identified and analyzed. Study staff will use the information to better understand in which groups of people, and in what areas of San Diego, HIV is spreading most quickly. This information will be used to determine how well Antiretroviral Therapy (HIV treatment) by certain individuals can control the spread of HIV within the population.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of ART to Interrupt HIV Transmission Networks</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>1. Age ≥18 years of age 2. Newly diagnosed HIV infection 3. ART naïve (≤7 days ART, previous use of PEP or PrEP are not exclusions) 4. Subject must be able to provide written consent 5. Subject must agree to study specific specimen collections and visit schedule. 6. Subjects with newly diagnosed HIV infection who were identified on or after May 1, 2014 will be eligible for enrollment as long as they are coenrolled to either AEH020 (project 080278) or AEH030 (project 140093) and DID meet the above study inclusion criteria (items at the time of enrollment to protocols AEH020 or AEH030). 1. Any factor or factors that in the opinion of the local investigator that could prevent compliance with study requirements. 2. Contraindication to phlebotomy or specimen collection.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>