<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02607449</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Drug-resistant tuberculosis is becoming a major problem for the whole humanity, and development of new Anti-TB drugs is of great importance. Since Kazakhstan is a country with the high burden of tuberculosis, The Government of The Republic of Kazakhstan has founded initiative on the development of new Anti-TB drug to treat drug-resistant forms of this infectious disease. JSC "Scientific Center for Anti-infectious Drugs" has developed original drug FS-1 for the treatment of multidrug resistant tuberculosis (MDR-TB).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>FS-1 Drug for Treatment of Multiple Drug-resistant Tuberculosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Phase 3 clinical study of FS-1 drug is a randomized, interventional, multicenter, placebo-controlled (add-on), double-blind and two arms trial. The study consists of two following phases: treatment phase - 12 months and follow-up phase 12 months. It is planned to recruit 480 patients with verified MDR-TB diagnosis. All data will be compiled in an Electronic Data Capture System with further statistical analysis according to approved Statistical Analytical Plan.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects suffering from a multidrugresistant form of pulmonary tuberculosis which is defined by: confirmed growth of M. tuberculosis in a sputum sample obtained at screening and obtained with the culture method described in detail in the appendix of the protocol. resistance to isoniazid and rifampicin as demonstrated by drug susceptibility testing (BK+) on liquid MGIT BACTEC medium preservation of sensitivity to fluoroquinolones and aminoglycoside/capreomycin Subjects fo all ethnicities, intellectually capable of understanding their own condition and the requirements of the study protocol Willing to freely und voluntarily provide informed consent in agreement with sec. 8 of ICH E6 (ICH E6, 2002) Willing and capable to comply with all requirements of the protocol Pregnancy or breastfeeding; Patients with decompensated concomitant diseases (cardiovascular, renal, hepatic failure) that may affect the conduct of the study; Patients with severe mental disorders; Patients with allergy to iodinecontaining drugs, hypersensitivity to iodine; intolerance to secondline drugs; Epidermomycosis Socially maladjusted patients suffering from alcoholism and drug addiction; Hypothyroidism; Hashimoto's thyroiditis; The use of TB treatment for more than two months before the start of the study; Nonadherence to the DOTS+ therapy; Serious side and/or adverse effects; Decision of a subject to terminate his/her participation in the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>