<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02607436</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a prospective interventional study to assess the effect of sarpogrelate compared with aspirin in Korean type 2 diabetic patients with atherosclerosis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Sarpogrelate, a Serotonin Receptor Antagonist, on Coronary Artery Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Type 2 diabetes has been increased exponentially, arousing serious economic, social and health repercussions. Also, macrovascular complications of diabetes such as myocardial infarct or stroke have been increased. Individuals with diabetes have a greater risk of cardiovascular disease (CVD), approximately two to four times than that of those without diabetes. Currently, the U.S. Food and Drug Administration requires demonstration that new anti-hyperglycemic agents do not increase cardiovascular risk. The comprehensive and multifactorial management in type 2 diabetes, which includes control of hypertension, dyslipidemia and obesity, is known to significantly reduce the risk of CVD as shown in Steno-2 study. However, most anti-diabetic agents currently used in clinical practice do not seem to provide enough cardiovascular protection.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aspirin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sarpogrelate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Serotonin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Serotonin Antagonists</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Type 2 diabetes with HbA1c ≥ 6.5% at screening visit Male or female between 30 and 80 years of age Coronary artery stenosis: 1075% without no evidence of acute coronary syndrome No history of previous myocardial infarction Systolic blood pressure / diastolic blood pressure &gt; 160/110 mmHg Congestive heart failure Allergy to radiocontrast dye Allergy to aspirin or sarpogrelate Acute bleeding History of ulcer bleeding GOT/GPT &gt; 100/100 Other antiplatelet medication</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>