<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02607540</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A two-arm Phase III trial was started in Oct. 2014. Definitive chemoradiotherapy with cisplatin plus 5-fluorouracil is the standard in Western countries in esophagus cancer. But in China because of its toxic reaction, most of patients stop the halfway. The purpose of this study is to confirm the difference of 2 and 4 cycles of cisplatin plus 5-fluorouracil in the definitive chemoradiotherapy for esophagus squamous cell carcinoma. A total of 210 patients will be accrued from China within 2 years. The primary endpoint is overall survival and the secondary endpoints include progression-free survival, response rate, pathologic complete response rate and adverse events.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Different Cycles of Cisplatin-5-fluorouracil for the Chemoradiotherapy of Esophageal Squamous Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>We plan to recruit the patients who were pathologically confirmed with esophageal squamous cell carcinoma from the Oct 2014. The patients will be divided into two groups.Experimental group: Two cycles of cisplatin plus 5-fluorouracil concurrent radiotherapy.Control group:Four cycles of cisplatin plus 5-fluorouracil and concurrent radiotherapy.To evaluate the overall survival of the 2 group. Also observe the patient's progression-free survival, response rate, pathologic complete response rate and adverse events.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Esophageal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>age 4575years old Histologically proven squamous cell carcinoma of the esophagus the tumor was in T24N02M0 The patients have not received the surgery or chemoradiotherapy. Hb≥80g/L, absolute neutrophil count ≥1.5×109/L, Plt≥90×109/L, ALT、AST≤2.5*N,Cr≤1.5*N. performance status score 02 pregnant, lactating women Oxaliplatin or fluorouracil Allergy or metabolic disorders Radiotherapy contraindications History of organ transplantation Brain metastasis The peripheral nervous system disorders Severe infection Oral capecitabine who have difficulty with,such as dysphagia,The activities of digestive ulcer, Gastrointestinal bleeding Severe chronic diseases, such as, hepatopathy, nephropathy, respiratory disease,high blood pressure, diabetes. Other malignant tumor in recent 5 years.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chemoradiotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Esophageal Squamous Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Cisplatin-5-fluorouracil</keyword>
</DOC>