<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00100906</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Tretinoin may help cells that are involved in the body's immune response to work better. Interleukin-2 may stimulate the white blood cells to kill kidney cancer cells. Giving tretinoin together with interleukin-2 may kill more tumor cells. PURPOSE: This randomized phase II trial is studying how well giving three different doses of tretinoin together with interleukin-2 works in treating patients with stage IV kidney cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sequential ATRA Then IL-2 for Modulation of Dendritic Cells and Treatment of Metastatic Renal Cell Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Determine the ratio of dendritic cells (DC) to circulating immature cells (ImC) before and after treatment with 3 different doses of tretinoin in patients with stage IV renal cell cancer. - Assess in vitro immune response assays to tetanus toxoid and influenza virus peptide before and after treatment with tretinoin and interleukin-2 in these patients. Secondary - Determine the frequency of treatment-related side effects in these patients. - Determine clinical objective response and progression-free survival of patients treated with this regimen. - Correlate DC:ImC ratio with clinical objective response in patients treated with this regimen. - Correlate the extent of change of the DC:ImC ratio with tretinoin dose and tretinoin blood levels in these patients. OUTLINE: This is a randomized, open-label study. Specimens are stratified according to patient prognostic factors, tumor bulk, and extent of dendritic cell to circulating immature cell ratio derangement. Patients are randomized to 1 of 3 tretinoin doses. Patients are followed for up to 2 years. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 27-36 patients (9-12 per treatment arm) will be accrued for this study within 2 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aldesleukin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interleukin-2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tretinoin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed renal cell cancer Stage IV disease Histology with clear cell component Metastatic OR incompletely resected disease Nonmeasurable disease allowed Underwent complete or partial nephrectomy more than 90 days ago No unresected primary cancer No more than 2 of the following adverse factors: Hemoglobin &lt; 10.0 g/dL Corrected calcium &gt; upper limit of normal (ULN) Lactic dehydrogenase &gt; 1.5 times ULN Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 2 Brain metastasis allowed provided more than 90 days of clinical and radiologic stability after the end of its active treatment PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age Over 18 Performance status See Disease Characteristics ECOG 02 Life expectancy Not specified Hematopoietic See Disease Characteristics Hepatic See Disease Characteristics Serum glutamic oxaloacetic transaminase (SGOT) &lt; 3 times normal Bilirubin &lt; 2 times normal Renal See Disease Characteristics Creatinine clearance &gt; 40 mL/min Cardiovascular None of the following cardiovascular conditions within the past year: Uncontrolled hypertension Myocardial infarction Unstable angina New York Heart Association class IIIV congestive heart failure Serious cardiac arrhythmia requiring medication Class IIIV peripheral vascular disease within the past year Other clinically significant cardiovascular disease Immunologic No history of immunodeficiency disease No HIV infection No ongoing serious infection Other Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use two methods of effective contraception during and for 1 month (for women) or 6 months (for men) after study treatment Other prior malignancy allowed provided there is no evidence of active disease No other medical contraindication to tretinoin or interleukin2 No serious nonhealing wound, ulcer, or bone fracture PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy At least 60 days since prior immunotherapy Chemotherapy At least 60 days since prior cytotoxic chemotherapy Endocrine therapy See Radiotherapy No prior corticosteroids at &gt; physiologic replacement doses for &gt; 3 days within the past 90 days Concurrent tamoxifen, toremifene, megestrol, or gonadotropinreleasing hormone agonists allowed Concurrent inhaled steroids allowed Radiotherapy More than 7 days since prior externalbeam radiotherapy No steroid requirement during radiotherapy Surgery See Disease Characteristics At least 30 days since other prior debulking surgery Other Prior adjuvant therapy for resected, synchronous stage IV disease allowed Prior adjuvant therapy allowed Study therapy is not to be used as adjuvant therapy for completely resected late (&gt; 1 year until identification) solitary site of disease metastasis or nonmetastatic disease No prior participation in this clinical study At least 60 days since other prior anticancer drugs Concurrent seizure medication allowed</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage IV renal cell cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent renal cell cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>clear cell renal cell carcinoma</keyword>
</DOC>