<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00100893</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Chemoprevention is the use of certain drugs to keep cancer from forming, growing, or coming back. The use of IH636 grape seed extract may prevent breast cancer. PURPOSE: This phase I trial is studying the side effects and best dose of IH636 grape seed extract in preventing breast cancer in postmenopausal women at risk of developing breast cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>IH636 Grape Seed Extract in Preventing Breast Cancer in Postmenopausal Women at Risk of Developing Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the efficacy of IH636 grape seed proanthocyanidin extract, in terms of suppression of estrogen biosynthesis, in healthy post-menopausal women at high risk of developing breast cancer. - Determine the safety and tolerability of this dietary supplement, in terms of symptoms and changes in markers of bone and lipid metabolism and in markers of nonspecific adrenal suppression, in these participants. - Determine, preliminarily, an optimum biologic dose of this dietary supplement, as defined by suppression of serum estradiol, in these participants. - Determine a minimum duration of use of this dietary supplement to achieve aromatase inhibition in these participants. OUTLINE: This is a pilot, dose-finding, placebo-controlled study. Participants receive oral placebo once or twice daily on days -14 to 0. Participants then receive oral IH636 grape seed proanthocyanidin extract once or twice daily on days 1-85. Treatment continues in the absence of toxicity. Cohorts of 6 participants receive one of four dose levels of IH636 grape seed proanthocyanidin extract up to an established safe dose. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 24 participants will be accrued for this study within 12 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Grape Seed Extract</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Proanthocyanidin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Procyanidin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: At risk of developing breast cancer No history of breast cancer or ductal carcinoma in situ PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age 40 to 75 Sex Female Menopausal status Postmenopausal, defined by 1 of the following criteria: No spontaneous menses for ≥ 12 months Prior bilateral oophorectomy Prior hysterectomy with folliclestimulating hormone within menopausal range Performance status ECOG 01 Life expectancy Not specified Hematopoietic Hemoglobin ≥ 9.0 g/dL Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm^3 WBC ≥ 3,500/mm^3 Absolute granulocyte count ≥ 1,500/mm^3 No coagulation disorders Hepatic SGOT and SGPT ≤ 2 times upper limit of normal (ULN) Bilirubin ≤ 1.5 times ULN Renal Creatinine ≤ 1.5 times ULN Cardiovascular No major illness of the cardiovascular system Pulmonary No major illness of the respiratory system Other No history of other invasive cancer within the past 5 years except squamous cell or basal cell skin cancer No major systemic infection No Cushing's syndrome or adrenal insufficiency No osteoporosis, defined as a bone mineral density Tscore ≥ 2.5 on dualenergy xray absorptiometry scan (calcium and/or cholecalciferol [vitamin D] supplementation AND/OR bisphosphonate therapy allowed provided participant is on a stable dose during study participation) PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy Not specified Chemotherapy Not specified Endocrine therapy More than 3 months since prior hormonemodifying medications, including any of the following: Oral contraceptives Hormone replacement therapy Selective estrogen receptor modifiers Aromatase inhibitors Gonadotropinreleasing hormone modifiers Concurrent dehydroepiandrosterone (DHEA) allowed, provided dose remains constant during study participation Radiotherapy Not specified Surgery Not specified Other No red wine, red grapes, or white button mushrooms directly before or during study treatment White and seedless grapes allowed No other concurrent therapy</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>breast cancer</keyword>
</DOC>