<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01989455</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Single center, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, adaptive sequential ascending-dose study for the evaluation of the safety, tolerability, and pharmacokinetics of single doses of deferiprone administered by intravenous infusion to healthy males and females. A bioavailability comparison will be included.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Blinded, Placebo-Controlled Study of the Safety and Pharmacokinetics of Single Doses of Intravenous Deferiprone in Healthy Volunteers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Deferiprone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Main 1. Healthy adult males or females, at least 18 years old but not older than 50 years. 2. Body weight at least 60kg. 3. Body Mass Index (BMI) ≥ 18.50 and ≤ 30.00 kg/m2 4. Medically healthy with clinically insignificant screening results (e.g., laboratory profiles, medical history, ECG, vital signs, physical examination. 5. Non or exsmoker (someone who has completely stopped smoking 6 months before study start) 6. For females, negative result on a serum pregnancy test. Main 1. Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &lt;1.5x10^9/L. 2. History or presence of hypersensitivity to deferiprone or any related products. 3. History or presence of gastrointestinal, liver or kidney disease, or any other conditions known to interfere with the absorption, distribution, metabolism or excretion of drugs. 4. Presence of significant cardiovascular, pulmonary, hematologic, neurologic, psychiatric, endocrine, immunologic or dermatologic disease. 5. Any history of tuberculosis (TB) or prophylaxis for TB. 6. Suicidal tendency, history of seizures, head trauma with coma or craniotomy/trepanation, state of confusion or relevant psychiatric disease. 7. Inadequate venous access in either arm. 8. Presence of outofrange cardiac interval or clinically significant ECG abnormalities (PR &lt;110 msec or &gt; 220 msec, QRS &lt;60 msec or &gt;119 msec, QTcB &gt; 450 msec for males and &gt;460 msec for females). 9. Use of acetaminophen, acetylsalicylic acid (ASA), or nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) in the previous 7 days before study start. 10. Use of any enzymemodifying drugs, including strong inhibitors of P450 (CYP) enzymes such as cimetidine, fluoxetine, quinidine, erythromycin, ciprofloxacin, fluconazole, ketoconazole, diltiazem, and HIV antivirals OR strong inducers of CYP enzymes such as: barbiturates, carbamazepine, glucocorticoids, phenytoin, rifampin, and St. John's wart within 28 days prior to study start. 11. Maintenance therapy with any drug, or significant history of drug dependency or alcohol abuse. 12. Had a clinically significant illness during the 28 days prior to study start. 13. Receipt of an investigational product in another clinical trial within 28 days prior prior to study start. 14. Enrolment in a previous cohort of this study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Healthy</keyword>
	<keyword>Deferiprone</keyword>
	<keyword>DFP</keyword>
	<keyword>L1</keyword>
</DOC>