<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01973218</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study was to assess the immunogenicity and safety of two doses of Novartis Meningococcal B Recombinant (rMenB+OMV NZ) vaccine administered one month apart (0, 1 month schedule) in Korean adolescents aged between 11 to 17 years.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Immunogenicity Study of Two Doses of Novartis Meningococcal Serogroup B Recombinant Vaccine in Adolescents Aged 11-17 Years.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Meningococcal Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Adolescents 1117 years of age inclusive who have given their written assent and whose parent or legal guardian has given written informed consent at the time of enrollment; 2. Available for all the visits scheduled in the study (i.e. not planning to leave the area before the end of the study period); 3. In good health as determined by the outcome of medical history, physical examination and clinical judgment of the investigator; 4. With a negative urine pregnancy test (for female subjects only). 1. History of any meningococcal vaccine administration; 2. Current or previous, confirmed or suspected disease caused by N. meningitidis; 3. Household contact with and/or intimate exposure to an individual with any laboratory confirmed N. meningitidis infection within 60 days of enrollment; 4. Pregnancy or nursing (breastfeeding) mothers; 5. Female subjects who have not used or do not plan to use acceptable birth control measures, for the 2 months duration of the study; 6. Any serious chronic or progressive disease; 7. Family members and household members of research staff; 8. Any condition which in the opinion of the investigator may interfere with the evaluation of the study objectives; 9. Significant acute or chronic infection within the previous 7 days or fever within 3 days prior to enrolment; 10. Antibiotics within 6 days prior to enrollment; 11. Known or suspected impairment/alteration of the immune system, immunosuppressive therapy; 12. Receipt of blood, blood products and/or plasma derivatives, or a parenteral immunoglobulin preparation within the previous 90 days; 13. History of severe allergic reactions after previous vaccinations or hypersensitivity to any vaccine component; 14. Receipt of or intent to immunize with any other vaccine(s) within 30 days prior and throughout the study period; 15. Participation in another clinical trial within the last 90 days or planned for during study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>11 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Meningitis, adolescents, Meningococcal B</keyword>
</DOC>