<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01438086</DOC>
	<brief_summary>When a patient has a heart attack, a blockage occurs in a coronary artery that delivers oxygen to the heart muscle. The heart muscle may weaken, causing heart failure. The body naturally makes a protein called insulin-like growth factor-1 (IGF-1) that may protect the heart muscle cells from dying and may prevent heart failure or lessen the damage that occurs. IGF-1 is also available as a drug called mecasermin. In this study, heart attack patients will be given either a dose of mecasermin or a placebo (inactive treatment) after their coronary artery has been opened by a stent. The purpose of the study will be to evaluate the safety of the therapy and to test if the therapy will prevent or lessen heart failure by evaluating a cardiac magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) taken one day and eight weeks after the heart attack.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Safety and Efficacy of Using Insulin-like Growth Factor-1 in Patients With a Heart Attack</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mitogens</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 18 75 Presents within 212 hours of at least 30 minutes of myocardial ischemic pain ECG evidence of myocardial infarction Undergoing percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) for STelevation myocardial infarction Left ventricular ejection fraction during PCI of 40% or less TIMI flow grade 3 in the infarctrelated artery following reperfusion and stenting History of prior myocardial infarction Prior history of heart failure, left ventricular dysfunction or cardiomyopathy Active or suspected neoplasia Known impaired liver function Cardiogenic shock Estimated glomerular filtration rate &lt; 45 ml/min/1.73m2 History of hypoglycaemia requiring hospitalisation History of primary insulinlike growth factor1 deficiency or growth hormone disorders Contraindication to cardiac magnetic resonance imaging Pregnancy or nursing mothers Known allergy to study drug or any of its inactive ingredients Treatment with another investigational agent within 30 days of enrolment Subjects unable or unwilling to comply with followup requirements of study Subjects unable to provide written informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Heart Failure</keyword>
	<keyword>Myocardial Infarction</keyword>
</DOC>