<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01438411</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary purpose of the study is to evaluate the therapeutic efficacy and safety of cholic acid in subjects with identified inborn errors of bile acid synthesis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Open Label, Continuation Study of Cholic Acid in Subjects With Inborn Errors of Bile Acid Synthesis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase 3, open-label, single center, nonrandomized study. This continuation protocol will consist of eligible subjects who have previously received cholic acid through the Cincinnati Children's Hospital Medical Center (CCHMC) Compassionate Use (91-10-10), CAC-001-01 study protocols and newly diagnosed subjects. New subjects will be infants, children, adolescents identified from urine samples obtained from the clinical services of programs across the U.S., Canada South America, Europe and Asia. Subject or their legal representative will receive information regarding the study and the principle investigator (PI) or designee will obtain informed consent. Serum and urine samples will be collected and sent to CCHMC to measure complete bile acid profile analysis. Clinical records including medical history, physical exams, vital signs and laboratory assessments performed as standard of care will be reviewed to ensure subject eligibility and determine baseline values. Subjects who have participated in Protocols conducted under IND 45,470 will be consented to continue to receive cholic acid capsules under this continuation protocol. Subjects will serve as their own controls and no placebo will be utilized.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cholic Acids</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bile Acids and Salts</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects who received cholic acid through CCHMC protocols 911010 or CAC00201 and meet the following criteria are eligible for study participation. 1. The subject and/or parent/legal guardian must have provided informed consent prior to study start. 2. The subject must have a diagnosis of an inborn error of bile acid synthesis. 3. The subject must be willing and able to comply with all study assessments and procedures. 4. Subjects with other organ dysfunction will not be excluded</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cholic Acid</keyword>
	<keyword>Inborn Error</keyword>
	<keyword>Bile Acid Metabolism</keyword>
	<keyword>Inborn Error of Bile Acid Synthesis</keyword>
</DOC>