<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02787746</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will evaluate the safety and tolerability of donepezil in treatment of AD patients in China, and also investigate the relationship between Apo-E gene type with adverse events of donepezil.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Tolerability of Donepezil in Mild to Moderate Alzheimer's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is a multi-center, single-arm, open labeling research, which the objective is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of donepezil in Alzheimer's disease( AD) patients in China, and investigate the relationship between Apo-E gene type with adverse events of donepezil.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Donepezil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. 50 ≤ years of age &lt; 85years 2. Patients newly diagnosed as probable AD based on NINCDS ADRDA (1984) 3. MRI image supports the diagnosis of AD (medial temporal lobe atrophy, Fazekas scale of white matter lesions≤2) 4. Mild to moderate AD with MMSE1024, modified Hachinski ischaemic scale (MHIS)≤4 5. With good eyesight and hearing, can cooperate with the inspection, treatment. 6. Move freely with or without walking aid. 7. Patient and caregiver who signed the written informed consent form for the terms of personal and medical information 1. With Vascular dementia or other types of dementia; 2. With psychoor neurosystem disease (such as stroke,delirium, depression, Parkinson's disease, etc.) 3. With type I diabetes, obstructive lung disease or asthma, vitamin B12 or folic acid deficiency, thyroid dysfunction, severe liver or kidney dysfunction, severe cardiac insufficiency (congestive heartfailure, myocardial infarction, Sick Sinus Syndrome, IIIII degree atrioventricular block or heart rate&lt;50bpm). 4. With history of clinical evidence of stroke, grand mal seizure or disturbance of consciousness because of brain trauma within past 2 years 5. With Hematologic Disease or neoplasms within past 2 years 6. Has a history of alcohol dependence and drug abuse. 7. With known hypersensitivity to medicines or foods. 8. Taking oral blood glucose lowering drugs including sulphonylureas and meglitinides. 9. Taking anticholinergic agents or antihistaminic agents.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>AD</keyword>
	<keyword>Donepezil</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
</DOC>