<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02787967</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will be conducted in asthmatic children aged 5 to 11 years and is based on a single-dose, open-label, randomized, 2-way cross-over design where a Dry Powder Inhaler (DPI) fixed combination of beclometasone dipropionate (BDP) 35 μg plus formoterol fumarate (FF) 4 μg is compared with the free combination of licensed BDP DPI and FF DPI</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Pharmacology of 35/4 NEXThaler® in Children 5-11 Years Old</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a pharmacokinetic comparison of NEXThaler 35/4 μg versus the free combination of Beclomethasone DPI and Formoterol DPI in children (5 to 11 years old) of a formulation already approved in adults.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Beclomethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Formoterol Fumarate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male/female children with asthma stable enough, according to paediatrician opinion, to allow a wash out period from steroids of 3 days before study treatments. Male/female children with asthma on regular treatment with ICS or using shortacting inhaled 2agonist as reliever to control asthma symptoms. Age ≥ 5 &lt; 12 years (8 to 10 children in the age range 58 years old). Children with a forced expiratory volume in one second (FEV1)&gt;70% of predicted values (% pred) after withholding 2agonists treatment for a minimum of 4 h prior to screening and to each study treatment. A cooperative attitude and ability to be trained about the proper use of DPI, ability to use correctly the medical devices and compliant to study procedures Past or present diagnosis of cardiovascular, renal or liver disease. Known hypersensitivity to the active treatmen Exacerbation of asthma symptoms within 4 weeks prior to screening. Inability to perform the required breathing technique and blood sampling. Hospitalization due to exacerbation of asthma within 1 month prior to screening (Visit 1). Lower respiratory tract infection within 1 month prior to screening (Visit 1). Disease (other than asthma) which might influence the outcome of the study. Obesity, i.e. &gt; 97% weight percentile by local standards</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>11 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>