<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02320331</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the OHA PILI 'Ohana Project is to disseminate and evaluate the effectiveness of a community-based intervention (PILI 'Ohana Intervention Program) aimed at eliminating obesity in Pacific Peoples across the four islands. Dissemination will involve implementation of the program in eight communities through partnerships with nine different community-based organizations serving those areas (four founding community partners and five new community partners). These organizations provide services to a large number of Pacific Peoples, including (but not limited to) Native Hawaiians, Samoans, Filipinos, and Chuukese. The main aims are to: (1) train five additional community organizations and their staff to deliver the PILI 'Ohana Intervention Program, (2) to enroll 150 overweight/obese participants across 8 different communities and four different islands into the intervention program, and (3) to evaluate the effectiveness of the program in reducing weight/BMI by at least 3% of the participant's initial weight. The PILI 'Ohana Intervention is a 9-month lifestyle intervention focusing on individual health behaviors in the context of family and community environments and in the socio-cultural context of Pacific Peoples. In order to increase the likelihood that an organization will implement the PLP, they will be able to adapt the intervention and participant assessments. The POP will provide guidance on adaption of the intervention and assessments at the training (CHS #21680). What is described below is the maximum amount of contact and assessment procedures that participants will undergo. Therefore, organizations may change the timing of the 14 lessons and refrain from using all the assessment procedures, but will still provide the 14 lessons and offer the same incentives to participants for assessments.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Partnerships to Improve Lifestyle Interventions (PILI) 'Ohana Dissemination Project</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>BMI greater than or equal to 25 Clients and/or residents of communities served by 9 partnering community organizations</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>