<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00660764</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In an observational multi-centre study (HEROS), the effects of starting treatment with rosuvastatin were assessed, on low-density lipoprotein cholesterol (LDL-C) goal achievement, in patients with a dissimilar high-risk profile who had not been treated with cholesterol lowering drugs at least in the past three months. Also set-up costs of rosuvastatin treatment and proportional changes in LDL-C and high-density lipoprotein cholesterol (HDL-C) were studied.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Assessment of the Efficacy of Rosuvastatin in Patient Groups With a Dissimilar Risk Profile in an Observational Study (HEROS)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypercholesterolemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Arterial Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rosuvastatin Calcium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients who had not been treated with cholesterol lowering drugs at least in the past three months, with an LDLC 3.2 mmol/l. According to the advise of the CBO, and could be included in one of the following risk groups: secondary prevention, DM or primary prevention. The general practice investigator made the decision to start treatment with rosuvastatin irrespective of study participation. Patient approved to place anonymous results at the disposal of AstraZeneca Patients with symptoms of myalgia, myopathy or liver function insufficiency (including raised serum transaminases) which bear a causal relation to the treatment with statins, patients with familiar dyslipidemia and/or patients with contraindications for treatment with rosuvastatin</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>cholesterol</keyword>
	<keyword>coronary heart disease</keyword>
	<keyword>rosuvastatin</keyword>
	<keyword>LDL-C goal</keyword>
	<keyword>hypercholesterolemia</keyword>
	<keyword>secondary prevention</keyword>
	<keyword>primary prevention</keyword>
	<keyword>CVA</keyword>
</DOC>