<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01045213</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Integrated eHealth is an innovative, proactive approach to the management of patients with chronic cardiopulmonary disease. Our overall goal is to improve the health of patients by integrating guideline-based education, remote disease monitoring, coordinator-based disease management and healthcare provider-initiated therapy. Patients enrolled in the program receive a set of equipment, including a Health Buddy® telemonitor that connects to a normal telephone, as well as instruments to measure oxygen levels (pulse oximeter), lung function (spirometer) and activity (pedometer). Through the Health Buddy® patients receive guideline-based disease education in their own homes. The Health Buddy® also allows patients to transmit daily information about their symptoms, oxygen levels, lung function and ability to walk to program coordinators located at the University of Colorado Hospital. Our program coordinators are highly experienced nurses or respiratory therapists with expertise in the management of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and congestive heart failure (CHF). Through this remote disease education/monitoring program, patients learn to take a more active role in the management of their own disease. However, once the coordinators identify early warning signs of a potential problem, patients are contacted and connected to their primary healthcare provider for early intervention. By this integrated approach to care, patients learn self-management techniques, physician communication is enhanced, and early interventions for problems are possible. We propose to target the Integrated eHealth Program to areas of Colorado that are highly impacted by COPD. Key Objectives: The key objectives are to improve COPD care in the 16 Colorado counties with high COPD mortality rates. Target Population: We will target patients with severe or very severe COPD. Expected Outcomes: We expect that this study will increase the use of evidence-based guidelines in the screening, diagnosis and treatment of COPD, resulting in improved quality-of-life and a reduction in healthcare utilization.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Integrated Care Program for Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>COPD Diagnosis by Gold Guidelines Airflow obstruction on spirometry defined by an FEV1/FVC less than or equal to 70% and an FEV1 less than 50% predicted, or and FEV1 greater than or equal to 50% predicted with a history of a COPD exacerbation within one year, or an FEV1 greater than or equal to 50% predicted and on longterm oxygen therapy. Standard landline telephone Legal US residency status residing in Adams, Alamosa, Bent, Crowley, Dolores, El Paso, Fremont, Kiowa, Logan, Morgan, Montezuma, Otero, Prowers, Rio Blanco, or Washington counties in Colorado Asthma Coexisting conditions that are likely to cause death within two years. Patients with CXR evidence of interstitial lung disease, or other pulmonary diagnoses at the time of enrollment, aside from COPDrelated bronchiectasis. Patients with endstage liver, renal or muscle disease, HIV, or a diagnosis of dementia. Participation in another treatment study Inability or unwillingness to cooperate with selfmonitoring and reporting components Prisoners, pregnant women, institutionalized patients Current alcohol or drug abuse NonEnglish speakers Inability to complete a consent Illegal alien, nonColorado resident, or nonresident of targeted counties</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease</keyword>
	<keyword>COPD</keyword>
</DOC>