<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02441920</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Periodontitis is a highly prevalent chronic inflammatory disease that is characterized by loss of the periodontal ligament and alveolar bone, and is a major cause of tooth loss. Results from clinical and epidemiological studies have suggested that periodontitis and tooth loss are more prevalent in individuals with rheumatoid arthritis (RA). There is evidence to suggest that periodontitis could indeed be a causal factor in the initiation and maintenance of the autoimmune inflammatory response that occurs in RA. If so, chronic periodontitis might represent an important modifiable risk factor for RA. However, to date longitudinal studies on the effect of periodontitis on disease progression in RA are lacking. The aim of the present study is to assess the periodontal status of patients enrolled in an established longitudinal cohort of RA patients. These data will then be analysed to evaluate whether or not periodontal inflammation is related to parameters of rheumatoid arthritis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Chronic Periodontitis and Tooth Loss in Patients With Rheumatoid Arthritis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tooth Loss</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Fulfilling the 1987 revised criteria for the classification of Rheumatoid arthritis Under active follow−up by a rheumatologist at the Dudley Group of Hospitals Participation in study 04/Q2702/18 "Establishment of an inception cohort for the prospective evaluation of predictors of cardiovascular morbidity and mortality in patients with rheumatoid arthritis". Participation in study 04/Q2702/18 "A prospective study of micro and macro vascular disease in a cohort of patients with Rheumatoid arthritis"). Written informed consent No absolute exclusion criteria</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>