<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02441283</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a rollover study to assess resistance and durability of response to ABT-493 and/or ABT-530 in subjects who have participated in Phase 2 or 3 clinical studies with these agents for the treatment of chronic HCV.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Assess Resistance and Durability of Response to ABT-493 and/or ABT-530</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. The subject is male or female 18 years of age or older 2. The subject has received at least one dose of an ABT493 and/or ABT 530 containing regimen in a prior AbbVie HCV Phase 2 or 3 study 3. The interval between the last dose of the AbbVie DAA therapy from the previous clinical study and enrollment in Study M13576 must be no longer than 2 years. 4. The subject must voluntarily sign and date the informed consent form approved by an Independent Review Board or Ethics Committee prior to the initiation of any studyspecific procedures. 5. Subject completed the posttreatment period of an eligible prior study. 1. The investigator considers the subject unsuitable for the study for any reasons (e.g., failure to comply with study procedures in the prior AbbVie clinical study). 2. Receipt of any investigational HCV antiviral treatment after receiving ABT493 and/or ABT530 in the prior study. 3. Subjects who experienced nonvirologic treatment failure due to premature discontinuation of study drug in prior study of ABT493/ABT530. 4. Participation in AbbVie's Study M15942 protocol for retreatment for virologic failure in the prior Phase 2 or 3 study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hepatitis C</keyword>
	<keyword>Sustained virologic response</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatitis C virus</keyword>
	<keyword>Direct Acting Antiviral</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic hepatitis C</keyword>
</DOC>