<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02441452</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study was to compare the functional capacity of exercise by six-minute walk test and lung function by spirometry, before and after Nuss procedure in subjects who have undergone the early rehabiliation program with those who were under conventional care. Researchers want to find out if early rehabilitation is a strategy to enhance recovery after Nuss procedure.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Functional Capacity of Exercise and Lung Function in Patients Submitted Early Rehabilitation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The replacement of some traditional approaches in surgical care has demonstrated that surgical recovery can be accelerated and convalescence decreased. These multimodal approaches focuses on enhancing recovery and reducing morbidity by reduction of surgical stress,minimal invasive surgery, optimized pain relief, early nutrition and ambulation. In postoperative, the bed rest leads to the increase in muscle loss and weakness, impairs pulmonary function, predisposes to venous stasis and thromboembolism, increases infection complications and reduces functional capacity even in patients who are not restricted to bed. However, few studies have focused on when start the mobilization and which effects on functional capacity of exercise and lung function during hospital stay. In this trial the investigators will consider early rehabilitation to be safe and feasible in Nuss procedure.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Funnel Chest</mesh_term>
	<criteria>children who are scheduled to undergo a surgical procedure for the correction of pectus excavatum sign the informed consent form independent ambulation ability to understand and follow instructions ability to perform lung function test contraindications for epidural catheter placement patients undergoing the open surgical repair of pectus excavatum refusal to do physical exercises on postoperative patients did not perform the sixminute walk test and lung function test on postoperative</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>14 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>30 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Nuss procedure</keyword>
	<keyword>postoperative care</keyword>
	<keyword>early ambulation</keyword>
</DOC>