<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03091153</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will develop, implement and evaluate a deprescribing initiative at a Canadian Long Term Care (LTC) Facility. Residents currently undergo an annual medication review as part of the clinical pharmacy services provided in the LTC facility. For this study, eligible residents will be randomized to receive either a deprescribing focused medication review or usual care. The deprescribing focused medication therapy assessments will be done on 33 the 66 patients residing on the second floor of the home. The other half of residents will serve as the control group and continue to receive their annual medication review and regular care from the attending physicians and nurses. The deprescribing intervention will be delivered by final year pharmacy students completing their practice experiences, under the supervision of clinical pharmacists at the LTC facility and clinical pharmacists from Memorial University's Medication Therapy Services (MTS) Clinic. Currently the clinic has a well developed procedure for providing in depth medication therapy reviews for residents of the community, upon referral by their primary care physician. Students will adapt this model of medication review to have a stronger deprescribing focus and be applicable to elderly residents of a LTC facility. The intervention will consist of an in depth medication therapy review with a focus on identifying any medications that may no longer be required or are deemed to be inappropriate or potentially unsafe in the elderly based on currently guidelines/criteria. The students will work closely with members of the resident's care team on a daily basis, as well as the resident and their family, to develop and implement a deprescribing plan.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Deprescribing in a Long Term Care Facility</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria (all of the following): 1. Over 65 years of age 2. Reside in St. Patrick's Mercy Home (2 East/West or 2 North/South) Exclusion Criteria (any of the following): 1. Do not take any regularly scheduled medications 2. Are receiving palliative care 3. Resident's physician or nursing team do not support participation 4. Resident or their substitute decision maker decline participation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>