<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03091426</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study has a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled design to assess the efficacy, pharmacodynamics and safety/tolerability of omiganan in patients with mild to moderate atopic dermatitis when applied BID to all atopic dermatitis lesions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacodynamics of Omiganan BID in Patients With Atopic Dermatitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Dermatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dermatitis, Atopic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eczema</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female subjects with mild to moderate AD (IGA 2 or 3) 18 to 65 years of age,inclusive. The health status is verified by absence of evidence of any clinical significant active or uncontrolled chronic disease other than AD following a detailed medical history, a complete physical examination including vital signs, 12lead ECG, hematology, blood chemistry, virology and urinalysis; Confirmed AD diagnosis; Symptoms present for at least 1 year; EASI between 7.1 50.0, inclusive at screening; 220% body surface area (BSA) affected at screening; Body mass index (BMI) between 18 and 35 kg/m2, inclusive, and with a minimum weight of 50 kg; Able to participate and willing to give written informed consent and to comply with the study restrictions; Subjects and their partners of childbearing potential must use effective contraception, for the duration of the study and for 3 months after the last dose. Any current and / or recurrent clinical significant skin condition other than AD; Pregnant, a positive pregnancy test, intending to become pregnant, or breastfeeding; Ongoing use of prohibited atopic dermatitis treatments. Requires washout period prior to baseline (first dose of the study drug); Use of topical medication (prescription or overthecounter [OTC]) within 14 days of study drug administration, or less than 5 halflives (whichever is longer) in local treatment area; Tanning due to sunbathing, excessive sun exposure or a tanning booth within 3 weeks of enrollment; Known hypersensitivity to the compound or excipients of the compound or known hypersensitivity to one or more different emollients; Participation in an investigational drug or device study within 3 months prior to screening or more than 4 times a year; Loss or donation of blood over 500 mL within three months (males) or four months (females) prior to screening.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>