<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="133613">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01362348</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>114987</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01362348</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>12 Week Patient Study in Neovascular Age-related Macular Degeneration (AMD)</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open-label, Phase 2a Study to Evaluate Pazopanib Eye Drops Administered for 12 Weeks to Patients With Neovascular Age-related Macular Degeneration</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>GlaxoSmithKline</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>GlaxoSmithKline</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this 12 week, open-label study is to investigate the safety and efficacy of a
      single dose regimen of pazopanib eye drop for neovascular AMD.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      MD7114987 is a Phase 2a study designed to determine whether pazopanib eye drops have the
      potential to reduce retinal edema and maintain or improve visual acuity in persons with a
      previously untreated subfoveal choroidal neovascularization (CNV) lesion secondary to
      age-related macular degeneration (AMD) and to further characterize the safety and
      tolerability of pazopanib eye drops administered over a 12-week period.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Lack of efficacy identified during a preliminary analysis
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>July 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 2012</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 2012</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>central retinal thickness</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 4 (Day 29)</time_frame>
    <description>change from baseline</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>visual acuity</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 4 (day 29)</time_frame>
    <description>change from baseline</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>central retinal lesion thickness and retinal morphology</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 12</time_frame>
    <description>change from baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>safety and tolerability</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 12</time_frame>
    <description>change from baseline of vital signs, clinical chemistry, hematology, adverse events, and serious adverse events of participants at 12 weeks.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>plasma concentrations</measure>
    <time_frame>steady state</time_frame>
    <description>steady-state plasma concentration of pazopanib at week 2, 4 and 12.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">19</enrollment>
  <condition>Macular Degeneration</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>pazopanib eye drops</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>pazopanib topical ocular administration</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>pazopanib eye drops</intervention_name>
    <description>10 mg/mL (1 drop) four times daily</description>
    <arm_group_label>pazopanib eye drops</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

        Subjects eligible for enrolment in the study must meet all of the following criteria:

          -  Consent: Subject understands the procedures, agrees to participate in the study
             (including participation in the CFH Y402H pharmacogenetic research), and has signed
             and dated the informed consent form prior to the initiation of any study-related
             activities. If the subject is unable to read the consent form due to visual
             impairment then the consent must be read to the subject verbatim by the person
             administering the consent, a family member, or legally acceptable representative.
             (Note: Consent by legally acceptable representative is allowed where this is in
             accordance with local laws, regulations, and ethics committee policy.)

          -  Age-related macular degeneration: For each subject enrolled in the study, only one
             eye (study eye) will be treated, and eligibility criteria apply to the study eye. All
             of the following characteristics are required and must be confirmed by the central
             reading center:

          -  CNV caused by AMD that extends under the geometric center of the foveal avascular
             zone

          -  Center subfield thickness (inclusive of subretinal fluid) &gt; 320 microns on OCT
             [SPECTRALIS® (Heidelberg)]

          -  Total lesion area ≤12 disc areas on fluorescein angiography, where the lesion complex
             includes CNV, blood, blocked florescence not from blood, and serous detachment of the
             retinal pigment epithelium

          -  CNV comprises &lt; 50% of lesion area

          -  classic CNV comprises &lt; 50% of the lesion area

          -  fibrosis comprises ≤ 25% of lesion area

          -  if no evidence of classic CNV, then presumed to have recent disease progression based
             on deterioration (≥ 5 letter decrease in vision or evidence of growth of a CNV lesion
             on fluorescein angiography ) within the last 3 months or evidence of hemorrhage from
             CNV

          -  Visual acuity: Best-corrected visual acuity score by electronic ETDRS in the study
             eye of between 25 and 73 letters (approximately equivalent to Snellen VA of 20/320 to
             20/32) at screening

          -  Gender and age: Subject is a male or female adult 50 years of age or older.

          -  Non-childbearing potential: Female subject is of non-childbearing potential defined
             as being physiologically incapable of becoming pregnant. This includes any female who
             is post-menopausal (12 months of spontaneous amenorrhea) or who is surgically
             post-menopausal (via documented hysterectomy or bilateral tubal ligation). In
             questionable cases of postmenopausal status, a blood sample with simultaneous
             follicle stimulating hormone (FSH) &gt;40 MIU/mL and estradiol &lt;40 pg/mL (&lt;140 pmol/L)
             [or equivalent values based on local laboratory criteria] is confirmatory. Refer to
             the SPM for more information.

          -  Study Compliance: Subject is able and willing to comply with the study requirements
             and is able and willing to attend all scheduled visits.

          -  Liver function tests: Subject has liver chemistry values that are within normal
             limits or clinically insignificant as evidenced by serum aspartate aminotransferase
             (AST) and alanine aminotransferase (ALT) &lt;2xULN; alkaline phosphatase and bilirubin
             &lt;1.5xULN (isolated bilirubin &gt;1.5xULN is acceptable, if bilirubin is fractionated and
             direct bilirubin is &lt; 35%).

          -  QT interval: Subject has a QTcF value &lt; 450 msec, or &lt; 480 msec for subjects with
             Bundle Branch Block. [Note: subjects with paced rhythms may be considered pending
             discussion with the medical monitor.]

        Exclusion Criteria:

        Subjects meeting any of the following criteria must not be enrolled in the study:

        Study Eye:

          -  Additional eye disease in the study eye that could compromise best-corrected visual
             acuity (e.g. glaucoma with documented visual field loss, clinically significant
             diabetic retinopathy, ischemic optic neuropathy, infection or retinitis pigmentosa)

          -  CNV in the study eye due to other causes unrelated to age-related macular
             degeneration

          -  Presence of retinal angiomatous proliferation (RAP) in the study eye, as determined
             by the investigator (confirmation by indocyanine green angiography is not required)

          -  Geographic atrophy involving the center of the fovea in the study eye

          -  Anterior segment and vitreous abnormalities in the study eye that would preclude
             adequate observation of the fundus for photographs, fluorescein angiography and
             spectral-domain OCT

          -  Vitreous, subretinal or retinal hemorrhage in the study eye that is unrelated to AMD

          -  Presence of an RPE tear in the study eye

          -  Aphakia or total absence of the posterior capsule (Yttrium aluminum garnet (YAG)
             capsulotomy permitted) in the study eye

          -  History of vitrectomy in the study eye

          -  Intraocular surgery in the study eye within 3 months prior to treatment

          -  Any previous treatment in the study eye for neovascular AMD, approved or
             investigational

        Fellow Eye:

          -  Current intravitreal anti-VEGF therapy in the fellow eye

          -  Best-corrected visual acuity score by electronic ETDRS &lt; 56 letters in the fellow eye
             at screening

        Concurrent Conditions or Concomitant Medications:

          -  Subject has uncontrolled glaucoma (intraocular pressure &gt; 25 mmHg) despite treatment
             with anti-glaucoma medication.

          -  A known, positive test for Hepatitis B surface antigen or Hepatitis C antibody within
             3 months of screening

          -  Current or chronic history of liver disease, or known hepatic or biliary
             abnormalities (with the exception of Gilbert's syndrome or asymptomatic gallstones)

          -  Active bleeding disorder or a history of hemoptysis, cerebral or clinically
             significant gastrointestinal hemorrhage within 6 months of screening

          -  Significant uncontrolled or unstable cardiovascular, nervous system, pulmonary,
             renal, endocrine, or gastrointestinal disease for example:

          -  Uncontrolled diabetes mellitus, with hemoglobin A1c (HbA1c) &gt; 10%

          -  Myocardial infarction or stroke within 6 months of screening

          -  Major surgery within 3 months of screening

          -  Clinically relevant thyroid disease

          -  Uncontrolled hypertension:

        Systolic blood pressure &gt; 160 mmHg Diastolic blood pressure &gt; 100 mmHg Note: Initiation or
        adjustment of antihypertensive medications is permitted prior to study entry provided the
        referenced criteria are met (See Section 4.4.3).

          -  Subject has a history within the past 2 years of alcohol or substance abuse, or
             psychiatric disorder likely to confound the efficacy or safety assessments.

          -  Known HIV infection

          -  Within 6 months prior to the Screening Visit, use of any systemically administered
             anti angiogenic agent (e.g., bevacizumab, sunitinib, cetuximab, sorafenib,
             pazopanib), approved or investigational

          -  Within 6 months prior to the Screening Visit, use of medications known to be toxic to
             the retina, lens or optic nerve (e.g. desferoximine, chloroquine/hydrochloroquine,
             chlorpromazine, phenothiazines, tamoxifen, and ethambutol)

          -  Use of systemic steroids (&gt;10 mg prednisone or equivalent/day) within 14 days of the
             start of treatment

          -  Use of prohibited medications within the restricted timeframe relative to the start
             of study medication (See Section 5.5.2)

          -  Use of an investigational drug within 30 days of screening

          -  History of sensitivity to any of the study medications, or components thereof or a
             history of drug or other allergy that, in the opinion of the investigator or GSK
             Medical Monitor, contraindicates their participation

          -  A condition or situation, which, in the opinion of the investigator, may result in
             significant risk to the patient, confound the study results or interfere
             significantly with participation
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>GSK Clinical Trials</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>GlaxoSmithKline</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Phoenix</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85014</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miami</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33143</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Winter Haven</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33880</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Decatur</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Grand Rapids</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>49525</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cleveland</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44195</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Austin</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78705</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris cedex 10</city>
        <zip>75475</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris cedex 12</city>
        <zip>75571</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Muenchen</city>
        <state>Bayern</state>
        <zip>80336</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bonn</city>
        <state>Nordrhein-Westfalen</state>
        <zip>53127</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leipzig</city>
        <state>Sachsen</state>
        <zip>04103</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>January 4, 2013</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>May 19, 2011</firstreceived_date>
  <firstreceived_results_disposition_date>October 4, 2012</firstreceived_results_disposition_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Age-related Macular Degeneration</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Wet Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Ophthalmic Solutions</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tetrahydrozoline</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted, but a results disposition has been submitted -->
</clinical_study>
