<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01246349</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators studied the effect of motivational interviewing (MI) on self-efficacy, health behaviors, and health outcomes in overweight children and adolescents (ages ranging from 10 to 18 years).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Motivational Interviewing for Weight Loss</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>One empirically supported intervention with a large evidence base for improving adult outcomes in behavioral health-related disorders is Motivational Interviewing (MI). MI is strongly rooted in the client-centered therapy of Rogers (1951). Its relational stance emphasizes the importance of understanding the client's internal frame of reference and displaying unconditional positive regard for the client. Motivational interviewing can thus be defined as a client-centered, directive method of therapy for enhancing intrinsic motivation to change by exploring and resolving ambivalence. MI manifests through specific strategies, such as reflective listening, summarization, shared decision making, and agenda setting. Adolescent participants exposed to motivational interviewing in conjunction with usual care (diet and exercise program) are expected to endorse greater self-efficacy, report increased engagement in healthy behaviors, demonstrate a decrease in body weight and report improved psychological outcomes. While motivational interviewing has been shown to increase adults' motivation to make healthy behavior changes, few adolescent studies have demonstrated this effect.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Weight Loss</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pediatric Obesity</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Obese youth (with Body Mass Index (BMI) ≥ to 85th percentile for age and gender (as classified by the Center for Disease Control)) ages 1018 years attending a local obesity clinic ("Healthy Weights" clinic) Time of entry into the weightloss program was controlled for; however, both new and current participants had the option to participate in the study. taking medication whose side effects may influence weight gain or weight loss did not speak English demonstrated a developmental delay reported being pregnant and/or reported having an eating disorder</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Motivational Interviewing</keyword>
	<keyword>Child and Adolescent Self-Efficacy</keyword>
	<keyword>Health Behaviours</keyword>
</DOC>