<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00141752</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This research will assess the accuracy of the Toronto Bedside Swallowing Screening Test (TOR-BSST), a new dysphagia screening test for patients with stroke. The purpose of the TOR-BSST is to predict the presence of dysphagia in stroke patients across their continuum of care in a simple and efficient manner. This initial research will assess the accuracy of the TOR-BSST in the acute and rehabilitative settings using videofluoroscopy as the gold standard for comparison. The results from this research will also assess the stability of the TOR-BSST across nursing, its primary user, and generate an estimate for the prevalence of dysphagia in adult stroke patients in the acute and rehabilitative settings. Participants in this research will be 315 stroke patients from several teaching centres in Ontario, namely 105 acute patients from the University Health Network, Sunnybrook &amp; Women's College Health Sciences Centre, and Hamilton General Hospital, and 210 patients in the rehabilitation setting from the Toronto Rehabilitation Institute and Parkwood Hospital, London. Both the TOR-BSST and videofluoroscopic assessment will be administered within 24 hours of each other and interpreted according to published preferred practice guidelines for dysphagia. This research will be the first to implement and assess a standardised method for screening for dysphagia in stroke patients across the continuum of stroke recovery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Toronto Bedside Swallowing Screening Test (TOR-BSST) - A Bedside Swallowing Screening for Stroke Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Deglutition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients with a new diagnosis of brainstem or cerebellar stroke patients with a new diagnosis of cortical stroke with NIH Stroke Scale score of 4 or above patients with a previous history of stroke with dysphagia patients with a confirmed history of Parkinson's, Parkinsonian Syndrome, ALS, MSA, MS, dementia, or other neurodegenerative disease patients with a history of cranial neurosurgery patients with a known previous or current oropharyngeal dysphagia due to structural or neurological cause patients with active COPD or current pneumonia</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cerebrovascular Accident</keyword>
	<keyword>Deglutition Disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>dysphagia</keyword>
	<keyword>screening</keyword>
</DOC>