<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02816619</DOC>
	<brief_summary>There is growing interest for physical activity in Parkinson's disease in order to improve mobility and function of these patients. It seems from previous studies that difficulty, intensity and specificity of physical exercises are important parameters conditioning the effect of physical activity on cerebral plasticity and clinical improvement. Thus, the aim of this study is to evaluate the benefits of a Personalized Physical Activity coaching program, including scheduled and frequent follow up associated with progressive readaptation of exercise intensity depending on individual performances (during 3 months), versus free practice of physical activity in Parkinson's disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of a Personalized Physical Activity Coaching Program in Parkinson's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Type of study: a randomized, single-blind, parallel-group, controlled clinical trial. Number of centers: 1 (Clermont-Ferrand) Patients Patients eligible for inclusion will be randomized to one of the two groups: - APA + : patients will beneficiate of Personalized Physical Activity coaching program during 3 months (1 hour, twice by week, during 3 months) - APA- : patients will do free practice of physical activity during 3 months. Study Performance Patients will be evaluated 3 times : at J0 (baseline, V1), 3 months after Personalized Physical Activity coaching program (J0+3M, V2), and 3 months after the end of the Personalized Physical Activity coaching program (J0+6M) V1: - Signature of an informed consent form. - Demographic and clinical characteristics (sex, age, disease duration, treatments). V1, V2, V3 - Neurological evaluation (Unified Parkinson Disease Rating Scale part III score) - Evaluation of quality of life (Parkinson's Disease Questionnaire 39-item version (PDQ-39), participation to Daily life activities (Lawton and Brody Activities of Daily Living scale (IADL questionnaire25) - Evaluation of performances for specific tests for balance (stabilometry), muscular strength (isometry) - Evaluation of cardiorespiratory function (VO2pic et 6 min Walk Test) - Evaluation of body composition (lean body mass/fat mass) with DEXA. - Dropout rates at V2 and V3 - Evaluation of the activity with the eMOUVE application in a subgroup of patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clinical criteria for Parkinson's disease Men or women aged from 18 to 80 years old. Social security coverage. Ability to provide informed consent. neurological disease other than Parkinson's disease severe depression (Beck Depression Inventory&gt;37) or psychiatric comorbidities (UPDRS I ) significant cognitive impairment (MoCA&lt;24) orthopedic impairment with functional restriction contraindication to physical exercise</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Parkinson's disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Physical activity</keyword>
	<keyword>Physical exercise</keyword>
</DOC>