<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03038360</DOC>
	<brief_summary>CardioSAVE is a prospective 12-month controlled longitudinal study for the validation of a novel predictive model and a diagnostic tool, for the risk stratification of AMI patients undergoing PCI, with a one year follow-up.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prospective Study With AMI Patients Undergoing PCI</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>CardioSAVE is a prospective 12-month controlled longitudinal study in 600 AMI patients, with a one year follow-up conducted by the Bad Krozingen Heart Center. The objectif is to validate a novel predictive model and a diagnostic tool, for the risk stratification of AMI patients undergoing PCI. The sample and data collected by eCRF will allow to set up a prototype personalized medicine device focusing on Heart Failure (HF) induced by AMI. The primary endpoint will be the proportion of patients with left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) &lt; 40% at 6 months. The main secondary endpoint is recovery of regional wall motion measured by cMRI at 6 months. Early time point samples, cMRI at day 3 and other clinical patient data will be used to estimate the risk associated with patients and the data obtained will be correlated with the one year outcome of patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male and Female patients with non childbearing potential (postmenopausal, ovariectomised or hysterectomised) patients. Menopause is defined as &gt; 60 years, or between 45 and 60 years being amenorrheic for at least 2 years 2. Age more than 18 years old 3. Acute myocardial infarction with clinical decision to treat with percutaneous coronary intervention Primary PCI for myocardial infarction: STelevation myocardial infarction (STEMI) or Large nonSTelevation myocardial infarction (NSTEMI) with hsTroponin T ≥ 0,1 ng/mL 4. Having signed an Informed Consent to participate in the trial before any study related procedure has been taken. 5. Having signed an Informed Consent for Biobank sampling. 1. Cardiac arrest, ventricular fibrillation, cardiogenic shock, stent thrombosis, previous AMI, angina within 48h before infarction, previous CABG 3. Severe concomitant noncardiac illnesses 4. Relevant noncoronary cardiac illnesses 5. Planned major surgery 6. Participated in any investigational drug or therapy study with a nonapproved medication, within the previous 3 months 7. Being dependent on the Investigator or the Sponsor (e.g., including but not limited to affiliated employee)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>