<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02806830</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this study, ocular discomfort following intravitreal injection in naïve patients will be studied, as well as the efficacy of wetting agent (Optive eyewash) to prevent ocular discomfort.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ocular Discomfort Assessment After Intravitreal Injections</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In naive patients, the two first intravitreal injections will be studied. Within the first injection, no wetting agent will be delivered. Within 72hours after this first intravitreal injections, patients will be contacted by phone by a nurse to complete questionnaires on quality of life and on ocular pain and eye discomfort. After the second injection, a treatment with wetting agent will be prescribed. With 72hours after the second injection, quality of life, ocular discomfort as well as acceptability and tolerance of the eye drops will also be assessed by a phone questionnaire.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Retinal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetic Retinopathy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myopia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Retinal Artery Occlusion</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myopia, Degenerative</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient over 18 years old Patient with social healthcare Patient understanding French language Patient requiring antiVEGF treatment by intravitreal injection Patient treated by Ozurdex® before Patient with known and treated ocular dryness Non naive patient for intravitreal injection Hypersensitivity to Carmellose Patient who received wetting agent within the 3 last months History of povidoneiodine allergy Pregnant or breastfeeding mother</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Intravitreal injection</keyword>
	<keyword>AMD</keyword>
	<keyword>Diabetic Retinopathy</keyword>
	<keyword>Retinal Artery Occlusion</keyword>
	<keyword>Myopia, Degenerative</keyword>
	<keyword>eye drops</keyword>
</DOC>