<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02214433</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Debio 1450-103 is a trial to study the pharmacokinetics (PK) of an experimental drug called Debio 1450 in healthy adult volunteers. Originally, Part A was registered separately (in NCT02214355). The registrations have been revised so all parts of this single trial (Parts A-C) are now included in this single registration (NCT02214433). The primary purpose of each part is provided below: - 10 volunteers participate in PART A to assess the PK of a single oral dose of Debio 1450 (tablet formulation) under varying gastric conditions - 40 volunteers participate in PART B to assess the safety, tolerability and PK of multiple ascending doses of Debio 1450, administered sequentially IV and orally, once or twice daily. - An additional 10 volunteers participate in PART C which is designed to assess the absolute bioavailability of various formulations of Debio 1450 under varying gastric conditions The dose administered during Part A is based on the safety, tolerability and PK data from study Debio 1450-102 [NCT02162199], a single ascending dose (SAD) study, in which single oral doses up to 800 mg/day are being investigated. Doses are adjusted during Parts B and C based on the available safety and PK data from preceding cohorts.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Multiple Dose Study of Debio 1450 [Intravenous (IV) and Oral] in Healthy Volunteers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Bacterial Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pantoprazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Meets protocolspecified criteria for qualification and/or contraception Is willing and able to remain confined in the study unit for the entire duration of each treatment period and comply with restrictions related to food, drink and medications Voluntarily consents to participate and provides written informed consent prior to any protocolspecific procedures Has a history or current use of overthecounter medications, dietary supplements, or drugs (including nicotine and alcohol) outside protocolspecified parameters Has signs, symptoms or history of any condition that, per protocol or in the opinion of the investigator, might compromise: 1. the safety or wellbeing of the participant or study staff 2. the safety or wellbeing of the participant's offspring (such as through pregnancy or breastfeeding) 3. the analysis of results</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Antibiotic</keyword>
	<keyword>Antibiotic Resistant Bacterial Infection</keyword>
</DOC>