<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02214095</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is the first evidence based work evaluated the systemic use of glucosamine as an adjunctive therapy to closed mechanical debridement in chronic periodontitis. The use of glucosamine sulphate was correlated with clinical outcomes and IL1-β level in the GCF of patients with moderate to advanced chronic periodontitis</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Glucosamine Periodontal Adjunctive Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Targeting the inflammatory response may be a rational approach to the medical treatment of chronic periodontitis. Glucosamine sulphate (GS) was proven to have anti-inflammatory actions with minimal side effect profile. Objectives; The main objectives of this study were to evaluate clinically the efficacy of GS; as a novel adjunctive host modulating agent in periodontal therapy and to investigate its effect on gingival crevicular fluid (GCF) level of IL-1β. Methods; Forty patients with moderate to severe chronic periodontitis (CP) were included in this study. They were randomly divided into two groups. Group I (G1) patients (n=20) received 500 mg GS capsules three times daily for 3 months following full mouth scaling and root planing (SRP), while group II (G2) patients (n=20) received a placebo for the same period following full mouth SRP. Clinical periodontal parameters and GCF IL-1β levels were analyzed at baseline and 3 months following therapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Inflammatory Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. good compliance with the plaque control instructions following initial therapy 2. each subject contributed a single premolar or molar tooth with interproximal probing depth ≥ 5 mm and clinical attachment loss ≥ 4 mm 3. teeth involved were all vital with score 01 mobility 4. availability for the followup and maintenance program; 1. no systemic diseases which could influence the outcome of therapy as evidenced by Burket's Oral Medicine health history questionnaire 2. absence of periodontal treatment for the previous year 3. absence of systemic medication or antibiotic treatment for the previous six months 4. absence of a smoking habit. 5. post menopausal, pregnant or breast feeding women were excluded from participating in the study. Patients with contraindications to glucosamine sulphate therapy e.g., hypersensitivity to any of the product's components or with inadequate compliance with the oral hygiene maintenance schedule were also excluded from the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>48 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cytokines</keyword>
	<keyword>interleukin-1β</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic periodontitis</keyword>
	<keyword>host modulation</keyword>
	<keyword>glucosamine sulphate.</keyword>
</DOC>