<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01669707</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether Endostar pumping into vein with Gemcitabine-Cisplatin are more effective than Endostar with Gemcitabine-Cisplatin regularly in the treatment of Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Endostar Durative Transfusion Combining With Gemcitabine-Cisplatin to Treat Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Endostar have anti-tumor activity by against vascular endothelial growth factor for initial treatment. This study was designed to evaluate the safety and efficacy of Endostar Continued vein-pumping Combining with Gemcitabine-Cisplatin (GP)chemotherapy in patients with NSCLC,and seeking for more effective injection.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Histologically or cytologically diagnosed NSCLC; 2. primary treatment,inoperable stage IIIB/IV NSCLC; 3. Age of 1875years; Gender Not Required; 4. Adequate hematologic, renal, and hepatic function ,Specific index as follows: liver function: SBilirubin ≤1.5 ULN ; Transaminase≤2 ULN. renal function: SCreatinine ≤1.2 ULN; blood urea nitrogen ≤1.2 ULN . ULN: upper normal limit. Marrow Hemopoietic Function: WBC≥4.0×10^9/l, ANC≥2.0×10^9/l platelet count ≥100×10^9/l, Hb≥100 g/l; 5. ECOG PS 02,Life expectancy ≥ 3 months; endure more than two cycle chemotherapy; 6. The patients have explicit lung tumor lesions and the lesions were measurable; (According to the standard of RECIST1.1, they should have at least one of accurately measurable lesions with the largest diameter ≥ 10mm by spiral CT, MRI); 7. No history of serious drug allergy; 8. Informed consent should be obtained before treatment. 1. Symptomatic brain metastases with cognitive disorder,bone metastases with complications; 2. Major organ dysfunction and Serious Heart Disease( congestive heartfailure,incontrollable highrisk arrhythmia,unstable angina, valvular disease, myocardial infarct and Resistant hypertension,); 3. Serious complications and investigator consider it is unsuited enrolling; 4. Pregnant or lactating women; 5. Allergic to research drug; 6. participating in other experimental trials and receive the treatment in four weeks; 7. The position that is for observing curative effect have a radiotherapy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Endostar</keyword>
	<keyword>advanced Non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Continued Pumping into vein</keyword>
	<keyword>Gemcitabine</keyword>
	<keyword>Carboplatin</keyword>
</DOC>