<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01161927</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare experimental evaluation of relative bioavailabilities in healthy, human subjects under non-fasting conditions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bioequivalence Study of Nizatidine Capsules 300 mg of Dr.Reddy's Laboratories Limited Under Non- Fasting Conditions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Open label, balanced, randomized, two-treatment, two-period, two sequence, single dose, crossover, comparative oral bioavailability study in healthy, adult, male human subjects under non-fasting conditions.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Nizatidine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy males between 18 and 55 years of age (inclusive) living in and around Ahmedabad city of western part of India. Having a Body Mass Index (BMI) ≥ 18.0 kg/m2 (calculated as weight in kg/ height in m2). Have no significant diseases or clinically significant abnormal findings during screening, medical history, physical examination, laboratory evaluations, ECG and Xray recordings. Able to communicate effectively with study personnel. Able to give consent for participation in the trial Known hypersensitivity or idiosyncratic reaction to nizatidine or other related drugs. Any disease or condition which might compromise the haemopoietic, renal, hepatic, endocrine, pulmonary, central nervous, cardiovascular, immunological, dermatological, gastrointestinal, or any other body system. Ingestion of a medication at any time in 14 days before the start of the study. In any such case subject selection will be at the discretion of the Principal Investigator/Medical expert/coinvestigator. Any history or presence of asthma or nasal polyp. A recent history of alcoholism (&lt;2years) or of moderate (180 ml/day) alcohol use. Smokers, who smoke more than 10 cigarettes/day or those who cannot refrain from smoking during study period. The presence of clinically significant abnormal laboratory values during screening. Use of any recreational drugs or history of drug addiction or testing positive in prestudy drug scan. History of psychiatric disorders. A history of difficulty with donating blood. Donations of blood (1 unit or 450 ml) within 90 days prior to receiving the first dose of study medication. Note: Incase the blood loss is ≤ 200 L, subject may be dosed after completion of 60 days of blood donation). A positive hepatitis screen including hepatitis B surface antigen, antiHCV and antiHAV antibodies. A positive test result for HIV antibody and/or syphilis. The receipt of an investigational product or participation in a drug research study within a period of 90 days prior to the first dose of study medication (Elimination halflife of the study drug should be taken into consideration for inclusion of the subject in the study). (Note: If subject had participated in a study in which blood loss is ≤200 mL, subject can be dosed after completion of 60 days of previous study). An unusual diet, for whatever reason (eg., lowsodium), for four weeks prior to receiving the study medication and throughout the subjects, participation in the study. In any such case subject will be at the discretion of the Principal Investigator/Medical expert/Coinvestigator.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Bioavailability</keyword>
	<keyword>Nizatidine</keyword>
	<keyword>Crossover</keyword>
</DOC>