<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00443092</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary purpose of this research study is to test the ability of a proprietary cherry juice blend to be helpful in the treatment of osteoarthritis (OA) of the knee.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Proprietary Cherry Juice Blend in Osteoarthritis of the Knee</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary objective is to determine if the proprietary tart cherry juice blend improves the pain and function in persons with knee osteoarthritis. A secondary objective is to ascertain if the blend lowers serum uric acid. This is a prospective double blind, placebo controlled cross-over study. The study will be performed in the Philadelphia VA Medical Center 1 South Rheumatology Clinic with patients meeting ACR criteria for Kellgren grade 2-3 knee osteoarthritis and 4-9 pain severity on a VAS. Fifty patients will be studied with each having 5 visits. Subjects will take either the proprietary cherry blend or placebo for 6 weeks and then switch. WOMAC pain and function will be the primary outcome with acetaminophen use, walking time and serum uric acid as secondary outcomes.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis, Knee</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject is capable of giving informed consent. Subject is over 18 years and less than 80 years Subject has mild to moderate osteoarthritis of the knee based on all of the following 3: 1. Meets clinical ACR criteria 2. Kellgren score of 23 on a Standing Knee xray within previous 24 months 3. VAS pain score of 49 at screening visit Rheumatoid arthritis or other systemic inflammatory condition Chronic pain syndrome (fibromyalgia) Corticosteroid medication in last 2 months, either intraarticular or oral Intraarticular injections of hyaluronic acid in last 9 months Pregnant women (weight gain might confound degree of knee pain) Diabetes Inability to discontinue prescription medication for arthritis Unstable medical conditions that would likely prevent the subject from completing the study Food allergies cherries, apples</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>osteoarthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>gout</keyword>
	<keyword>pain</keyword>
	<keyword>uric acid</keyword>
	<keyword>tart cherry</keyword>
	<keyword>alternative medicine</keyword>
	<keyword>knees</keyword>
</DOC>