<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00443547</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to measure the benefits of anterior (from the front) cervical (neck) surgery for degenerative disc disease. The research part of this study is the answering of questionnaires by the patient concerning their quality of life, prior to, and after surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Outcome Study of Patients Treated With Translational Cervical Plate Used to Treat Degenerative Disc Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a prospective, multi-center, four-arm study designed to evaluate the clinical and radiographic outcomes in patients diagnosed with cervical degenerative disc disease (DDD) and treated using the Vectra-T Cervical Plate and the Advanced ACF or CorticoCancellous Allograft Spacer made by Synthes Spine Company (Paoli, PA). This is not an investigational study (IDE) and no investigational or experimental devices or procedures are included in this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Spinal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Intervertebral Disc Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<criteria>One to four levels (consecutive) cervical degenerative disc disease between C2 and C7, defined as at least one of the following: disc herniation axial neck pain (with or without radiculopathy or myelopathy) caused by spondylosis functional deficit neurological deficit which significantly limits patient's normal living One to four cervical levels to be plated Patient is skeletally mature and at least 18 years of age Patient signs consent form Patient is available for long term (24 month) followup Etiology must be confirmed by MRI or CT Spondylolisthesis greater than grade 1 at either level(s) to be instrumented Indications for complete corpectomy of any involved levels Posterior instrumentation is necessary at same levels More than one previous failed anterior fusion attempt at the involved level(s) Has had more than one previous open, posterior, spine surgical procedures at the involved level(s) or preop instability on Flexion/Extension radiographs. Pregnant or interested in becoming pregnant during the study followup period Has a known sensitivity to device materials Mentally incompetent or prisoner Currently a participant in a study related to the treatment of cervical spinal disorders Preop instability&gt;3mm on flexion/extension Xrays</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Prospective</keyword>
	<keyword>Degenerative Disc Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Cervical</keyword>
	<keyword>Translational Plate</keyword>
</DOC>