<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00443898</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is designed to assess the efficacy, safety and tolerability of a topical formulation of terbinafine solution applied daily in patients with toenail fungus. This trial will study patients with mild to moderate toenail fungus disease of the big toenail and their responses to two treatment durations, 24 or 48 weeks.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy, Safety, and Tolerability of Topical Terbinafine in Patients With Mild to Moderate Toenail Fungus of the Big Toenail</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Onychomycosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Terbinafine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and females 12 75 years of age Fungal toenail infection of one or both of the large (great) toenails The nail infection must be due to a dermatophyte, (mixed infections [dermatophyte and nondermatophyte] are not allowed) Target foot must not have severe plantar (moccasin) tinea pedis that would require systemic therapy. Mild to moderate tinea pedis (athlete's foot) infection should be treated with terbinifine prior to baseline or at any time during the trial. Other topical treatments for athlete's foot may be recommended at the discretion of the investigator. Subjects must not have abnormalities of the nail that could prevent a normal appearing nail if clearing of infection is achieved No administration of systemic antifungal medications within 6 months prior to screening visit No application of prescription topical antifungal medications for toenail fungus within 3 months or other commercially available topical medications for toenail fungus applied directly to the toenails within 1 month prior to screening visit No professional pedicures or application of any nail polish product or nail cosmetic to the toenails after the screening visit Known pregnancy or lactation at time of enrollment Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Toenail fungus</keyword>
	<keyword>Onychomycosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Nail fungus</keyword>
	<keyword>Toenail fungal infection</keyword>
	<keyword>Tinea unguium</keyword>
	<keyword>Dermatophytes</keyword>
	<keyword>Foot dermatoses</keyword>
</DOC>