<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00443937</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Cyclosporine (CNI), a potent immunosuppressive drug used in transplant recipients to prevent graft rejection, can cause renal impairment in some patients. The aims of this study are - To determine the influence of CNI discontinuation on the drug exposure and key pharmacokinetic parameters of everolimus and enteric-coated mycophenolate sodium (EC-MPS) - To determine the adequate dosing of everolimus and EC-MPS in a CNI-free regimen - To investigate the CNI-free regimen with EC-MPS and everolimus with respect to safety (e.g. rejection rates) and tolerability - To investigate renal function after CsA withdrawal</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacokinetics of Everolimus and Enteric-Coated Mycophenolatesodium Before and After Withdrawal of Cyclosporine in Renal Transplant Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolate mofetil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients having a kidney transplant since at least 6 months but for no longer than 5 years. Patients in a stable condition in terms of graft function Patients currently receiving ECMPS and CsA with or without corticosteroids as part of their immunosuppressive regimen for at least 1 month prior to Baseline Females of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test prior to study inclusion. If positive, the patient will not be enrolled. Effective contraception must be used during the trial. Patients with any known hypersensitivity to ECMPS or everolimus or other components of the formulation (e.g., lactose) Patients with a history of severe rejection (according to BANFF criteria) within 3 months of enrollment in this trial. Changes to the immunosuppressive regimen during the last 3 months due to immunologic reasons. Patients with thrombocytopenia (platelets &lt;100,000/mm3), with an absolute neutrophil count of &lt;1,500/mm3 and/or leukocytopenia (leukocytes &lt;4,500/mm3), and/or hemoglobin &lt;9.0 g/dL at baseline. Patients with proteinuria at baseline (&gt; 1g/d) Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>Kidney Transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>Renal Transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>Mycophenolate</keyword>
	<keyword>Cyclosporine</keyword>
	<keyword>Everolimus</keyword>
</DOC>