<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02962414</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the long-term safety in patients with TSC and refractory seizures who are currently receiving everolimus treatment in the Novartis-sponsored EXIST-3 study and who are determined to be benefiting from continued treatment as judged by the investigator at the completion of EXIST-3</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Roll-over Study to Collect and Assess Long-term Safety of Everolimus in Patients With TSC and Refractory Seizures Who Have Completed the EXIST-3 Study [CRAD001M2304] and Who Are Benefitting From Continued Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a multi-center, open label study to evaluate the long term safety of everolimus in patients with TSC and refractory seizures currently being treated in the Novartis-sponsored study EXIST-3 study and are judged by their parent study investigator as benefiting from the current study treatment. The study is expected to remain open for approximately 10 years (or until 31-Dec-2022 in the UK) from First Patient First Visit (FPFV). Patients will continue to be treated in this study until they are no longer benefiting from their everolimus treatment as judged by the Investigator or until one of the protocol defined discontinuation criteria is met or everolimus becomes commercially available according to local regulations.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Seizures</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tuberous Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key Patient is currently enrolled in the Novartissponsored EXIST3 study, receiving everolimus, and has fulfilled all its requirements Patient is currently benefiting from treatment with everolimus, as determined by the Investigator. Patient has demonstrated compliance, as assessed by the Investigator,with the parent study protocol requirements. Patient is willing and able to comply with scheduled visits and treatment plans. Written informed consent/adolescent assent obtained prior to enrolling into the rollover study. Key Patient has been permanently discontinued from everolimus study treatment in EXIST3 study Everolimus is approved for patients with TSC and refractory seizures and is reimbursed in the local country. Patients who are receiving everolimus in combination with unapproved or experimental treatments for seizure control Antiepileptic drug (AEDs) are allowed for the purpose of seizure control.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Everolimus</keyword>
	<keyword>Tuberous sclerosis complex</keyword>
	<keyword>TSC</keyword>
	<keyword>Refractory seizure</keyword>
	<keyword>Roll over study</keyword>
	<keyword>Long term safety</keyword>
	<keyword>PASS</keyword>
</DOC>