<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02962843</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate whether training teacher and staff in the Incredible Years (IY) Teacher Classroom Management (TCM) program reduce behavior problems and promote social competence in student aged 6-8 years (school) and in children aged 3-6 year (day-care). To examine group differences from baseline to 8-9 months after, a quasi-experimental control group design with pre- and post-measurements was used.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the IY TCM Program in Norwegian School and Day-care Settings</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Evaluation of the Incredible Years (IY) Teacher Classroom Management (TCM) program implemented as a school-wide preventive intervention in regular school and day-care settings, have the potential to change negative behaviors in children aged 3 - 8 year. Forty-four schools were recruited; comprising 1518 students aged 6-8 year, and 91 day-care units comprising 1049 children aged 3-6 year. Multilevel analyzes were used to examine group differences pre-post changes for behavior problems measured with the Sutter-Eyberg Student Behavior Inventory-Revised (SESBI-R) and the Teacher Report Form (TRF), as well as group differences pre-post change for social behavior measured the Social Skills Rating System (SSRS). For secondary findings, group differences pre-post changes for teacher- student and teacher-children relationship were measured with the Student-Teacher Relationship Scale (STRS) (teachers N= 444), and teacher-parents interactions were measured with the Teacher-Parent Involvement Questionnaire (INVOLVE-T/P) (parents N = 2109), as well as group differences pre-post change for teachers self- and collective efficacy measured the Norwegian Teacher Self-Efficacy Scale (NTSES) and the Collective Efficacy Scale (CES) (teachers N = 3240).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Problem Behavior</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Schools who met predefined criteria for program implementation of IY TCM (intervention) and school who not have implemented any IY program (comparison). Students/children aged 38 year (until 7 randomly selected from each class) with parents who speak Norwegian. Teachers and staff who worked with students/children aged 38 years. Schools who did not met predefined criteria for program implementation of IY TCM. Students/children aged 38 year with parents who did not speak Norwegian. Teachers and staff who did not worked with students/children aged 38 years, and who have known the students/children for fewer than 3 weeks.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>8 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Behavior Problem</keyword>
	<keyword>Social Competence</keyword>
	<keyword>Student</keyword>
	<keyword>Children</keyword>
</DOC>