<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02962284</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an open-label, single-arm, multi-center extension study to evaluate safety in patients with mCRPC of YONSA 500 mg (4 x 125 mg qd) with methylprednisolone (4 mg bid). Patients will have successfully completed an 84-day treatment with abiraterone acetate in a previous trial. Results from the final visit of the previous study will be used to determine patient's eligibility for this study. Patients in this study will be eligible to receive open-label YONSA with methylprednisolone for up to 12 months. Pharmacodynamic parameters of serum testosterone and PSA levels will be monitored. Disease progression will be assessed by PCWG2 criteria.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>One-year, Open Extension to Evaluate the Treatment of Patients With Castration-Resistant Prostate Cancer With YONSA™</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Abiraterone Acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Successful completion of 84 days of treatment with YONSA in Churchill Pharmaceuticals clinical trial, CHLAA201 Last dose of YONSA or Zytiga within 45 days prior to treatment in this study Written informed consent obtained prior to any studyrelated procedure being performed Has in the investigator's opinion, the potential to gain clinical benefit with YONSA treatment Ongoing therapy with a GnRH agonist or antagonist AND serum testosterone level &lt;50 ng/dL at screening Life expectancy of at least 9 months at screening Subject is willing and able to comply with all protocol requirements assessments Agrees to protocoldefined use of effective contraception. Serious concurrent illness, including psychiatric illness, that would interfere with study participation Inability to swallow tablets whole Known hypersensitivity to YONSA, methylprednisolone, or any excipients in study medications Moderate to severe hepatic impairment (ChildPugh Classes B and C)</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>