<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00185042</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to learn if CS-505 is safe and effective for slowing down or possibly reversing the buildup of tissue, cells and fatty deposits (plaque) in the blood vessels of the heart (coronary artery atherosclerosis).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of the ACAT Inhibitor CS-505 (Pactimibe) for Reducing the Progression of Coronary Artery Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atherosclerosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Standard: 1. Male or female subjects, age 18 years or greater; and 2. Diagnosed or suspected coronary artery disease with a clinical indication for coronary angiography. Angiographic: 1. Evidence of coronary heart disease 2. Identification of a target native coronary artery for the plaque volume measurement. Standard: 1. Breast feeding or lactating women, or women who have had a pregnancy (regardless of outcome) within the past 12 months; 2. Previous heart or other organ transplantation; 3. Treatment with any of the following agents within 4 weeks prior to randomization: Immunosuppressive agents (cyclosporine, azathioprine); Rifampin; and Phenytoin, phenobarbital, valproic acid, or other anticonvulsants. 4. Any of the following manifestations of cardiac disease: Myocardial infarction or unstable angina within 24 hours prior to randomization or clinically unstable; Clinically significant heart disease; and Coronary artery bypass surgery within previous 3 months. 5. Stroke (CVA) within previous 3 months; 6. Evidence of severe symptomatic heart failure (NYHA Class III or IV) or known ejection fraction less than 30%; 7. Uncontrolled diabetes mellitus; 8. Uncontrolled hypertension; and 9. Nephrotic syndrome, significant nephropathy, or other significant renal disease. Angiographic: 1. Presence of any lesion with greater than 50% reduction in lumen diameter; or 2. Any lesion with a greater than 50% occlusion in the left main coronary artery; 3. A target vessel, including any of its branches, that has undergone or will be undergoing coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG) or percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI); 4. A target vessel that is itself a bypass graft.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>Atherosclerosis, intravascular ultrasound</keyword>
</DOC>