<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00701415</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study was to determine whether 2 alternative dosing regimens of Fabrazyme (Agalsidase beta) (1.0 mg/kg every 4 weeks or 0.5 mg/kg every 2 weeks) were effective in treatment-naïve pediatric participants without severe symptoms. Participants were to be treated for 5 years.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Two Fabrazyme (Agalsidase Beta) Dosing Regimens in Treatment-naïve, Male Pediatric Patients Without Severe Symptoms</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fabry Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The participant and/or participant's parent(s)/legal guardian(s) must provide written informed assent/consent prior to any protocolrelated procedures being performed. The participant must had a confirmed diagnosis of Fabry disease as documented by leukocyte αGalactosidase A (αGAL) activity of &lt;4 nmol/hr/mg leukocyte (preferred assay; resulted from a central laboratory). If the leukocyte αGAL activity assay was difficult to obtain, the participant might be enrolled based on documented plasma αGAL &lt;1.5 nmol/hr/mL, with the agreement of the Medical Monitor (resulted from a central laboratory). The participant must had evidence of globotriaosylceramide (GL3) accumulation as documented by plasma GL3 (&gt;7.0 µg/mL) or urinary GL3 (&gt;0.3 mg GL3/mmol creatinine) levels (results from a central laboratory). The participant must be male ≥5 and ≤18 years of age. Participant had albuminuria (first morning void urinary albumin/creatinine ratio &gt;30 mg/g on at least 2 out of 3 consecutive samples, each at least 1 week apart). Participant had a Glomerular Filtration Rate (GFR) by iohexol &lt;90 L/min/1.73m^2. In case of properly documented low protein intake, values as low as 80 mL/min/1.73 m^2 might be acceptable, after consultation with the Medical Monitor. Participant had documented evidence of stroke or transient ischemic attack (TIA), or if a brain magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) had been performed, bright lesions &gt;2 mm on T2 or fluid attenuated inversion recovery (FLAIR) weighted images within the white matter or the basal ganglia. Participant had severe and recurrent acroparesthesia, judged by the physician as frequent (more than once a week) pain episodes for at least 3 months that influenced daily activities, irrespective of medication. Participant had an enddiastolic left ventricular posterior wall thickness (LVPWTd) and/or an enddiastolic interventricular septum thickness (IVSTd)≥2 standard deviations (SD) compared to normal (based on body surface area [BSA] normal ranges from Kampmann, et al 2000) as read at the study site. Participant had received prior treatment specific to Fabry Disease. Participant had participated in a study employing an investigational drug within 30 days of the start of their participation in this study. Participant had any medical condition or extenuating circumstance, which in the opinion of the Study Investigator, could interfere with study compliance. Participant had any medical condition or extenuating circumstance, for example diabetes mellitus, which in the opinion of the Study Investigator, could interfere with the interpretation of study results. Participant was on treatment with angiotensin converting enzyme inhibitors/angiotensin receptor blockers (ACEIs/ARBs). Participant had any contraindication mentioned in the labeling of Fabrazyme and/or iohexol (Omnipaque). Participant or parent(s)/legal guardian(s) was unwilling to comply with the requirements of the protocol.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>α-GAL, α-Galactosidase-A, r-hαGAL</keyword>
</DOC>