<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01573845</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The central hypothesis of The GREEN Project Lunch Box Study is that a school-based communication campaign that combines healthy eating and eco-friendly messages will improve the quality of foods that children bring from home to school more than a healthy eating campaign alone and compared to a control/delayed intervention condition at the end of one school year.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The GREEN Project Lunch Box Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The proposed intervention seeks to improve the quality of foods brought to school from home by taking advantage of a natural synergy between healthy eating and eco-friendly behaviors to increase motivation to adopt healthy eating behaviors. The project involves the design, implementation and evaluation of a novel, school based communications campaign to simultaneously improve the nutrition quality and eco-friendliness of foods that elementary school children bring from home to school. The intervention is a theory-based multi-channel communications campaign based on qualitative research with the target population: children in grades three and four in public schools in Eastern Massachusetts and their caregivers. Schools were randomized to one of three conditions: (1) a campaign that includes healthy eating and eco-friendly messages; (2) a campaign that includes healthy eating messages only; and (3) a delayed healthy eating eco-friendly campaign after serving as a control group. Foods brought from home and the packaging associated with those foods will be assessed at baseline and at the end of the school year using a photographic technique. The primary outcome of interest is change in the number of servings of fruits and vegetables. Secondary outcomes will include changes in the quantity of sugar-sweetened beverages; changes in processed, energy-dense foods; and changes in sugar sweetened beverages brought from home. We will also be able to assess changes in trash associated with foods brought from home.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>CHILD PARTICIPANTS 3rd or 4th grade student in participating classroom Brings food from home to school at least 3 days per week Not a 3rd or 4th grade student Not enrolled in a participating classroom Does not bring food from home to school at least three days per week PARENT/CARETAKER PARTICIPANTS Child is a 3rd or 4th grade student in participating classroom Child brings food from home to school at least 3 days per week Child is not a 3rd or 4th grade student Child is not enrolled in a participating classroom Child does not bring food from home to school at least three days per week</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>child</keyword>
	<keyword>communication</keyword>
	<keyword>diet</keyword>
	<keyword>food</keyword>
	<keyword>health communication</keyword>
	<keyword>nutrition</keyword>
	<keyword>parents</keyword>
	<keyword>primary schools</keyword>
	<keyword>school age population</keyword>
	<keyword>school health</keyword>
</DOC>