<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00814489</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety, reactogenicity and immunogenicity of 2 formulations of a non-typable Haemophilus influenzae and pneumococcal candidate vaccine in young adults. Subjects will be vaccinated 2 times in an observer-blind manner with an interval of 2 months. The subjects receiving Engerix-B will receive in an open-manner a third dose of the vaccine at Month 6. The protocol posting has been updated following a protocol amendment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Non-typable Haemophilus Influenzae and Pneumococcal Protein Vaccine Formulations in Young Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This Protocol Posting has been updated following amendment of the Protocol, January 2010. The sections impacted are: study design and study endpoints.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Haemophilus Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects who the investigator believes will comply with the requirements of the protocol should be enrolled in the study. A male or female between, and including, 18 and 40 years of age at the time of the first vaccination. Written informed consent obtained from the subject. Subject without medical history, clinical finding or laboratory finding, which, in the opinion of the investigator, could pose a safety concern or interfere with the protocol. If the subject is female, and of childbearing potential, she agrees to use adequate contraception and not become pregnant for the duration of the study. Pneumonia within 3 years prior to 1st vaccination. Invasive Pneumococcal Disease within 3 years prior to 1st vaccination. Use of any investigational or nonregistered product other than the study vaccine(s) within 30 days preceding the first dose of study vaccine, or planned use during the study period or participation to another pharmaceutical/vaccine study. Chronic administration of immunosuppressants or other immunemodifying drugs within six months prior to the first vaccine dose. Planned administration/administration of a vaccine not foreseen by the study protocol within 30 days of the first dose of vaccines, with the exception of the influenza vaccine which can be administered &gt;14 days prior to or &gt;14 days following vaccine doses 1 and 2. Administration of immunoglobulins and/or any blood products within the 3 months preceding the first dose of study vaccine or planned administration during the study period. Any confirmed or suspected immunosuppressive or immunodeficient condition, including human immunodeficiency virus infection. History of reaction or hypersensitivity to any component of the vaccine. Any serious, uncontrolled disease likely to interfere with the study as determined by history, physical examination or laboratory screening, as per the judgment of the Investigator. Inflammatory processes such as known chronic infections. All past or current malignancies and lymphoproliferative disorders. Laboratory evidence of haematological and biochemical abnormalities. Acute disease at the time of enrolment/vaccination. Pregnant or lactating female. Female planning to become pregnant or planning to discontinue contraceptive precautions. History of chronic alcohol consumption and/or drug abuse. Other conditions that the principal investigator judges may interfere with study findings. Previous vaccination for hepatitis B. As a portion of the subjects will be randomized to receive EngerixB comparator, it is important that all subjects meet EngerixB eligibility criteria.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Non-typable Haemophilus influenzae</keyword>
	<keyword>protein vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>Streptococcus pneumoniae</keyword>
	<keyword>young adults</keyword>
</DOC>