<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00455923</DOC>
	<brief_summary>An 18 months randomised double-blind study with two parallel arms with start dose of inhaled SERETIDE 50/100mcg BD or FLIXOTIDE 100mcg BD, Phase I is 6 months where the patient will be up-titrated until well controlled is achieved, After 6 months the treatment continues without changes during 9 months = PhaseII. The aim is to investigate and evaluate the assumption that the combination therapy with SERETIDE controls mild persistent asthma better than inhaled corticosteroids(FLIXOTIDE) alone.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>SERETIDE Vs FLIXOTIDE In Mild Persistent Asthma (GINAII)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluticasone Propionate, Salmeterol Xinafoate Drug Combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluticasone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Willing to give informed consent. Males or females aged 1870. Able to understand and complete dairy cards. Mild persistent asthma according to GINA. In addition, at randomisation subjects were required to have: 1. Day time symptoms more than once a week but not every day. 2. Nighttime symptoms not more than once a week. 3. FEV1 &gt;80% predicted 4. PC20 &lt;8mg/mL Change to regular asthma medication in 4weeks prior to visit 1. Use of oral, depot or parenteral corticosteroids within 8 weeks of visit 1. Lower respiratory tract within 4 weeks of Visit 1 Received investigational study drug within 4 weeks of visit Smoking history of &gt;10 pack years of more. Serious uncontrolled disease. Medical conditions or medications known to affect the assessments or endpoints. Evidence of alcohol or drug abuse. Known pregnancy or planned pregnancy. Known or suspected hypersensitivity to inhaled corticosteroids, betaagonists or lactose. Previous enrollment in the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>asthma</keyword>
	<keyword>exacerbation</keyword>
	<keyword>persistent</keyword>
	<keyword>bronchial hyperresponsiveness</keyword>
	<keyword>mild</keyword>
	<keyword>GINAII</keyword>
</DOC>