<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02943447</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of GS-9674 in adults with primary biliary cholangitis (PBC).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety, Tolerability, and Efficacy of GS 9674 in Adults With Primary Biliary Cholangitis Without Cirrhosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Cholangitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key Meets all of the following conditions Definite or probable PBC as defined by at least 2 of the 3 following criteria: Serum alkaline phosphatase (ALP) &gt; the upper limit of normal (ULN) Presence of antimitochondrial antibodies (AMA) in serum (≥ 1:40 on immunofluorescence) Liver histological (based on liver biopsy) findings consistent with PBC including nonsuppurative, destructive cholangitis affecting mainly the interlobular bile and septal bile ducts Serum ALP &gt; 1.67 x ULN and/or total bilirubin &gt;ULN but ≤ 2 x ULN Ursodeoxycholic acid (UDCA) use at a stable dose for at least 12 months or intolerant of UDCA with no UDCA use for at least 12 months before screening Screening FibroSURE/FibroTest® &lt; 0.75 unless a historical liver biopsy within 12 months of screening does not reveal cirrhosis. In adults with Gilbert's syndrome or hemolysis, FibroSURE/FibroTest® will be using direct bilirubin instead of total bilirubin. Key Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) &gt; 5 x ULN Total bilirubin &gt; 2 x ULN International normalized ratio (INR) &gt; 1.2 unless on anticoagulant therapy Other causes of liver disease including viral, metabolic, alcoholic, and other autoimmune conditions. Participants with hepatic steatosis may be included if there is no evidence of nonalcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH) in the opinion of the investigator or on liver biopsy. Use of fibrates or obeticholic acid within 3 months prior to screening through the end of treatment Cirrhosis of the liver as defined by any of the following: Historical liver biopsy demonstrating cirrhosis (eg, Ludwig stage 4 or Ishak stage ≥ 5) History of decompensated liver disease, including ascites, hepatic encephalopathy or variceal bleeding Liver stiffness &gt; 16.9 kPa by FibroScan Note: Other protocol defined Inclusion/Exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>