<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02943616</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The ABSORB Post-Approval Clinical Study is a prospective, open-label, multi-center, single-arm, non-randomized trial designed to observe Absorb continued safety during commercial use in real world settings.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>ABSORB Post-Approval Clinical Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>After approval of commercial use of Absorb GT1 Bioresorbable Vascular Scaffold (BVS) System in over 75 countries as of December 31, 2015, Abbott Vascular has developed a post-approval commitment plan that includes the initiation of the ABSORB Post-Approval Clinical Study, a single-arm trial that will include approximately 3000 subjects at approximately 265 sites in the US and Canada. The objectives of ABSORB PostApproval Study are the following: - Evaluate the safety of the use of Absorb in a real world setting following commercial physician training. - Observe the effectiveness of commercial physician training on appropriate vessel sizing in the use of Absorb in a real world setting. The study design allows evaluating low frequency events, effectiveness of commercial physician training and education for very small vessels (&lt; 2.25 mm as assessed by quantitative coronary angiography (QCA)), and confirmation of generalizability of the treatment with Absorb to real-world practice. The clinical followup will occur at 30 days, 180 days, 1 year, 2 years and 3 years by investigator or designee through telephone contacts or office visits. Angiographic Subgroup: Approximately the first 500 consecutive subjects implanted by operators inexperienced in the usage of Absorb GT1 BVS to receive baseline assessment of reference vessel diameter (RVD) by the angiographic core laboratory. An inexperienced operator is defined as having performed two or fewer Absorb implants prior to commercial approval. The purpose of the angiographic subgroup is to evaluate the effectiveness of training in the selection of appropriately sized coronary arteries for GT1 BVS implantation. Study staff will be notified after the procedure if the subject is in the angiographic subgroup, and instructed to send pre-procedure angiogram and supporting materials to core laboratory for assessment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The subject agrees and signs the Institutional Review Board (IRB) approved informed consent form The subject receives an Absorb Subject is a member of a vulnerable population. Vulnerable population: Defined as subject whose willingness to volunteer in a clinical investigation could be unduly influenced by the expectation, whether justified or not, of benefits associated with participation or of retaliatory response from senior members of a hierarchy in case of refusal to participate. Examples of populations which may contain vulnerable subjects include: Individuals with lack of or loss of autonomy due to immaturity or through mental disability, persons in nursing homes, children, impoverished persons, subjects in emergency situations, ethnic minority groups, homeless persons, nomads, refugees, and those incapable of giving informed consent. Other vulnerable subjects include, for example, members of a group with a hierarchical structure such as university students, subordinate hospital and laboratory personnel, employees of the sponsor, members of the armed forces, and persons kept in detention</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Absorb GT1 BVS</keyword>
	<keyword>BVS</keyword>
	<keyword>Bioabsorbable</keyword>
	<keyword>Myocardial ischemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Stent thrombosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Stents</keyword>
</DOC>