<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02333721</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to explore the short-term, long-term and oncological outcomes of laparoscopic spleen-preserving No. 10 lymph node dissection in a left-sided approach for advanced middle or upper third gastric cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study on Laparoscopic Spleen-Preserving No. 10 Lymph Node Dissection for Advanced Middle or Upper Third Gastric Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A prospective randomized comparison of laparoscopic spleen-preserving No. 10 lymph node dissection for gastric cancer will be performed, to evaluate the short-term, long-term and oncological outcomes. The evaluation parameters are perioperative clinical efficacy, postoperative life quality, immune function and 3-year survival and recurrence rates.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stomach Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age from 18 to 75 years Primary distal gastric adenocarcinoma (papillary, tubular, mucinous, signet ring cell, or poorly differentiated) confirmed pathologically by endoscopic biopsy cT24a, N03, M0 at preoperative evaluation according to the American Joint Committee on Cancer (AJCC) Cancer Staging Manual Seventh Edition No distant metastasis is observed. And the spleen, pancreas or other adjacent organs are not involved by the tumor. Performance status of 0 or 1 on Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group scale (ECOG) American Society of Anesthesiology score (ASA) class I, II, or III Written informed consent Women during pregnancy or breastfeeding Severe mental disorder History of previous upper abdominal surgery (except laparoscopic cholecystectomy) History of previous gastrectomy, endoscopic mucosal resection or endoscopic submucosal dissection Enlarged or bulky regional lymph node diameter over 3cm by preoperative imaging History of other malignant disease within past five years History of previous neoadjuvant chemotherapy or radiotherapy History of unstable angina or myocardial infarction within past six months History of cerebrovascular accident within past six months History of continuous systematic administration of corticosteroids within one month Requirement of simultaneous surgery for other disease Emergency surgery due to complication (bleeding, obstruction or perforation) caused by gastric cancer FEV1＜50% of predicted values</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Stomach Neoplasms</keyword>
	<keyword>Laparoscopy</keyword>
</DOC>