<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02333487</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this PET study is to verify the binding of Lu AF35700 after multiple oral dosing at the dopamine and the serotonin receptors in male patients with schizophrenia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Positron Emission Tomography (PET) Study Investigating Dopamine and Serotonin Receptor Occupancy After Multiple Oral Dosing of Lu AF35700</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Serotonin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dopamine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dopamine Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. The patient is a man aged between ≤18 and ≥60 years 2. BMI of ≥19 kg/m2 to ≤ 37 kg/m2 3. The patient has a primary diagnosis of schizophrenia according to DSM5™ (code 295.90) 4. The patient has a Clinical Global Impression Severity of Illness (CGIS) score ≤ 4 (moderately ill) at screening and safety baseline 5. The patient is currently under oral therapy with one or more of the antipsychotic medications listed in Appendix II. 6. The patient has a Positive and Negative Syndrome Scale (PANSS) total score ≤ 80 7. The patient has a score of ≤ 4 (moderate) on the following PANSS items at screening and at safety baseline: P7 (hostility), G8 (uncooperativeness) 1. The patient experienced an acute exacerbation requiring hospitalization within the last 3 months. 2. The patient experienced an acute exacerbation requiring change in antipsychotic medication (with reference to drug or dose) within the last 4 weeks. 3. The patient has a diagnosis or history of substance use disorder (except nicotine) according to DSM5TR® criteria ≤3 months prior to screening 4. The patient is at significant risk of harming himself or others according to the investigator's judgment or as indicated by an answer of "yes" to the question 4 or 5 on the ColumbiaSuicide Severity Rating Scale (CSSRS) at the Screening Visit within the last six months on the lifetime version of CSSRS. 5. Based on investigators judgment the patient has a medical or neurological disorder or treatment for such disorder that could interfere with the study treatment or impair treatment compliance. 6. The patient has had past episodes of extrapyramidal symptoms (EPS) under current medication within the last 6 month 7. The patient takes other medication than those listed as allowed concomitant medication in Appendix III 8. The patient is occupationally exposed to significant levels of ionizing radiation. Other protocoldefined inclusion and exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>