<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02333604</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Cancer Support Community's (CSC) Research and Training Institute has created the Cancer Experience Registry: An Online Initiative to Change the Future of Cancer Care to identify and understand the emotional and social needs of cancer survivors. Armed with this knowledge, the investigators will raise awareness about and help develop programs to address the needs of cancer survivors. Anyone who has ever received a cancer diagnosis, whether recently diagnosed, in treatment, or years post-treatment can participate. Interested cancer survivors can register at www.cancerexperienceregistry.org</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cancer Experience Registry</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The online registry will allow CSC's Research and Training Institute to report annually on trends and changes in the emotional health status of cancer survivors. Such data collection and tracking will serve as the basis for increasing public awareness and in developing effective programs to address the often misunderstood and under served needs of cancer survivors. The registry will fill a critical gap by providing a mechanism to learn directly from cancer survivors what issues they face. The Cancer Support Community's Research and Training Institute will disseminate an annual report to highlight the findings of the registry. The report will be available to the cancer community at large.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Having received a cancer diagnosis or caring for someone with cancer</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>cancer survivor ship</keyword>
	<keyword>psychosocial needs</keyword>
	<keyword>cancer experience</keyword>
	<keyword>metastatic breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>multiple myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic myeloid leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Prostate</keyword>
	<keyword>Colon</keyword>
	<keyword>Kidney</keyword>
	<keyword>Lung</keyword>
	<keyword>Melanoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Caregiver</keyword>
</DOC>