<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02182180</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to collect samples of blood, urine, cerebrospinal fluid (CSF, the fluid that surrounds the brain and spinal cord), wound tissue and/or wound fluids, and other body fluids and tissues from people who have been seriously injured or ill. The samples will be used to develop and assess tests and/or tools that doctors can use to decide the best treatment plan for seriously injured or ill military personnel and for civilians. Additonal protocols to use the samples will be submitted as separate protocols.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>SCCI Tissue and Data Repository Protocol</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Critical Illness</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with injury or illness requiring surgical care or treatment in a critical care or emergency setting who are being cared for at SC2I sites (Grady Memorial Hospital, Emory Univeristy Hospital, and Duke University Health Systems) Healthy volunteer control subjects to include individuals without any known injury or endstage organ disease and patients who have recovered from prior injury. Ability to understand the purposes and risks of the study and willingly give written informed consent, or in the case of incapacitated patients, a willing surrogate able to give written informed consent. Any condition that, in the opinion of the attending physician, would place the patient or volunteer subject at undue risk by participating. Specific conditions include but are not limited to anemia prohibitive of phlebotomy, coagulopathy, or technical considerations that would prevent acquisition of sufficient tissue or fluid for clinical use. Acquisition of samples from patients requiring active transfusion or with transfusionassociated coagulopathy will be considered as appropriate study candidates at the discretion of the attending physician.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>