<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01004224</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will determine the maximum tolerated dose and thus the recommended phase II dose and schedule of the compound and characterize the safety.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Dose Escalation Study in Adult Patients With Advanced Solid Malignancies</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with histologically/cytologically confirmed advanced solid tumors with FGFR1 or FGFR2 amplification or FGFR3 mutation, for which no further effective standard anticancer treatment exists Adequate bone marrow function Adequate hepatic and renal function Adequate cardiovascular function Contraception. For women: Must be surgically sterile, postmenopausal, or compliant with a medically approved contraceptive regimen during and for 3 months after the treatment period; must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy test and must not be nursing. For men: Must be surgically sterile or compliant with a contraceptive regimen during and for 3 months after the treatment period Patients with primary CNS tumor or CNS tumor involvement Patients with history and/or current evidence of endocrine alteration of calciumphosphate homeostasis History and/or current evidence of ectopic mineralization/ calcification including but not limited to the soft tissue, kidneys, intestine, myocard and lung with the exception of calcified lymphnodes and asymptomatic coronary calcification Current evidence of corneal disorder/ keratopathy incl. but not limited to bullous/ band keratopathy, corneal abrasion, inflammation/ulceration, keratoconjunctivitis etc., confirmed by ophthalmologic examination. History or current evidence of cardiac arrhythmia and/or conduction abnormality Women who are pregnant or nursing. Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>advanced solid tumors</keyword>
	<keyword>lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>bladder cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>BGJ398</keyword>
	<keyword>FGFR</keyword>
	<keyword>kinase inhibitor</keyword>
	<keyword>advanced solid malignancies</keyword>
</DOC>