<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01004107</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the safety and effectiveness of Radiesse® Injectable Dermal Filler for hand treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Radiesse® Dermal Filler for Hand Rejuvenation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Has right and left hands with a rating of 3 or 4 on the BHVSS as determined by the treating physician Is at least 18 years of age Signs a written informed consent Understands and accepts the obligation not to receive any other procedures in the dorsum of the hands through 12 month follow up Understands and accepts the obligation and is logistically able to present for all scheduled followup visits Exclusion Criteria Has planned activities during study that could interfere with treatment (i.e., boxing) or that impose significant force to the hands. Has history of hypertropic scarring. Has a known bleeding disorder (e.g., thrombocytopenia, thrombasthenia, or von Willebrand's disease). Has received or is anticipated to receive antiplatelets, anticoagulants, thrombolytics , vitamin E or antiinflammatories within 2 weeks pre treatment. Is receiving systemic corticosteroids or anabolic steroids (standard doses of inhaled or nasal corticosteroids are acceptable). Has a history of chronic or recurrent infection (e.g., Pseudomona paronychia) or inflammation (e.g., rheumatoid arthritis) that would preclude participation in the study. Has a known hypersensitivity to any of the components of Radiesse or local anesthesia. Has received the following in the dorsum of the hand within 4 weeks of treatment or intends to receive these products and or treatments during the study: Over thecounter wrinkle products (e.g., alphahydroxy acids) or prescription treatments (e.g., Renova, RetinA, microdermabrasion, chemical peels) Has had any dermal fillers or surgery in the dorsum of the hand. Is a female of child bearing potential and not using medically effective birth control or is pregnant or lactating.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>