<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00623844</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Objectives: The PAKT project shall evaluate the effects of an exercise intervention in kindergarten combined with an educational training of parents and kindergarten teachers on behavior and health status of children. Study design: Baseline measurements were performed on more than 700 kindergarten children aged 43-67 months in May to July 2007. The kindergartens are located in and around Wuerzburg in Germany. Kindergartens were then randomized in an intervention (21 kindergartens) and a control (20 kindergartens) group. The intervention group offers a daily exercise class lasting at least 30 min. Parents and teachers of the children in the intervention program receive educational training. In addition, the children have activity homework involving the entire family. The control kindergartens keep their routine. Follow-up measurements of physical activity (actigraph), motor skills, body mass index, skinfold thickness, and blood pressure take place in January/February 2008, June/July 2008, and September/October 2008. The number of accidents in and outside of the kindergartens and the number of children missing the kindergarten due to infections are monitored continuously. Use of results: If the PAKT program should proof effective, the results will be published in scientific journals and made public using the press. With the help of the GEK, the program will then be implemented nationwide in kindergartens.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prevention Through Activity in Kindergarten Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Children in participating kindergartens Health conditions restricting physical activity Age &lt; 43 months or &gt; 67 months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>43 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>67 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Prevention</keyword>
	<keyword>Physical activity</keyword>
	<keyword>Obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>Motor skills</keyword>
	<keyword>Kindergarten</keyword>
</DOC>