<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00623441</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The safety and efficacy of the Endeavor(TM) ABT-578 Eluting Coronary Stent System has been assessed in a series of studies. The stent is coated with a proprietary drug compound that is designed to reduce restenosis. This prospective multi-center study has been initiated: - To document the acute and mid-term safety and overall clinical performance of the stent system in a "real world" patient population requiring stent implantation. - To assess the event rate in patient subgroups with specific clinical indications and/or vessel or lesion characteristics.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>E-Five Registry: A World-Wide Registry With The Endeavor Zotarolimus Eluting Coronary Stent</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient is &gt;18 years of age (or minimum age as required by local regulation) The patient has consented to participate by signing the "Patient Informed Consent Form" and/or has authorized the collection and release of his medical information by signing the "Patient Data Release Consent Form". The patient is suitable for implantation of one or more Endeavor(TM) ABT578 Eluting Coronary Stent System in one or more native artery target lesions. Lesion length and vessel diameter of the target lesion(s) are according to the "Indications for Use" as mentioned in the "Instructions for Use" that comes with every Endeavor(TM) ABT578 Eluting Coronary Stent System. The patient is willing and able to cooperate with registry procedures and required follow up visits. Women with known pregnancy or who are lactating. Patients with hypersensitivity or allergies to aspirin, heparin, clopidogrel, ticlopidine, drugs such as ABT578, rapamycin, tacrolimus, sirolimus or similar drugs, or any other analogue or derivative, cobalt, chromium, nickel, molybdenum or contrast media. Patients in whom antiplatelet and/pr anticoagulation therapy is contraindicated. Patients who are judged to have a lesion that prevents complete inflation of an angioplasty balloon. Current medical condition with a life expectancy of less than 12 months. The subject is participating in another device or drug study. Subject must have completed the followup phase of any previous study at least 30 days prior to enrollment in this trial. The subject may only be enrolled in this Efive registry once. Patients with medical conditions that preclude the followup as defined in the protocol or that otherwise limits participation in this registry.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Coronary Artery Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug-eluting stent</keyword>
</DOC>