<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01920737</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to find out whether the combination of chemotherapy drugs that are routinely used in children with ALL, will be safe and effective in treating adult patients with ALL. The standard treatment for adults with ALL consists of many chemotherapy drugs that are given in different combinations and in several steps. In adult ALL there is no standard which drugs to give and how to combine them. Some leukemias have a chromosome abnormality called Philadelphia chromosome (also called Ph Positive) and some leukemias do not (called Ph Negative). In this study we want to see whether this combination of chemotherapy drugs will be safe and effective in treating adult patients with Ph Negative ALL.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Novel "Pediatric-Inspired" Regimen With Reduced Myelosuppressive Drugs for Adults (Aged 18-60) With Newly Diagnosed Ph Negative Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Precursor Cell Lymphoblastic Leukemia-Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pegaspargase</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methotrexate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cytarabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Daunorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Asparaginase</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>6-Mercaptopurine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vincristine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Previously untreated Ph negative precursor Bcell or Tcell ALL confirmed by conventional flow cytometry or immunohistochemical stain Patients who have untreated Bcell or Tcell ALL confirmed by conventional flow cytometry or immunohistochemical stain, but Ph status is unknown, may also enroll. Patients with Tcell or B cell lymphoblastic lymphoma confirmed by conventional immature T or pre B cell markers even if the bone marrow is not involved are also eligible Age 18 60 years ECOG performance status of 02 Adequate renal function as demonstrated by a serum creatinine ≤ 2.0 mg/dl or a creatinine clearance of &gt; 60 ml/min. Adequate hepatic function as demonstrated by a total bilirubin &lt; 2.0 mg/dl (unless attributable to Gilbert's disease) and an alkaline phosphatase, AST, and ALT ≤ 4 times the upper limit of normal (unless clinically considered to be related to liver involvement with leukemia Normal cardiac function as demonstrated by a left ventricular ejection fraction ≥ 50% on echocardiogram or MUGA scan Negative serum pregnancy test in women of childbearing potential Men and women of childbearing potential must be willing to practice an effective method of birth control during treatment and at least 4 months after treatment is finished. Patients with central nervous system involvement by ALL are eligible and may receive concomitant treatment with radiation therapy and/or intrathecal chemotherapy in accordance with standard medical practice. For patients with CNS disease, dexamethasone may be temporarily administered instead of prednisone to reduce CNS pressure, at the discretion of the treating physician and after discussion with the MSK PI. Once dexamethasone is no longer needed, prednisone should be given as per protocol for 28 days. Previous treatment for ALL, except for prior steroids and/or hydroxyurea Patients known to have Philadelphia (Ph)+ ALL are not eligible. Leukemia cell samples will be obtained from all patients enrolled before starting protocol treatment and submitted for Philadelphia chromosome testing by either karyotyping, or for bcr/abl1 translocation by FISH or by PCR for bcr/abl1. Patients who are later found to have Ph+ ALL should have treatment on this trial discontinued and will not be considered in the evaluation Lymphoid blastic crisis of chronic myelogenous leukemia Mature Bcell (Burkitt's) ALL Active serious infections not controlled by antibiotics Pregnant women or women who are breastfeeding Concurrent active malignancy requiring immediate therapy Clinically significant cardiac disease (NY Heart Association Class III or IV), including chronic arrhythmias, or pulmonary disease Known HIV positive status Other serious or lifethreatening conditions deemed unacceptable by the principal investigator</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>ALL</keyword>
	<keyword>Bone Marrow</keyword>
	<keyword>Ph Negative</keyword>
	<keyword>Daunorubicin</keyword>
	<keyword>Vincristine</keyword>
	<keyword>Prednisone</keyword>
	<keyword>PEG-Asparaginase</keyword>
	<keyword>Methotrexate</keyword>
	<keyword>16-MP (6-Mercaptopurine)</keyword>
	<keyword>Cyclophosphamide</keyword>
	<keyword>Cytarabine</keyword>
	<keyword>Leucovorin</keyword>
	<keyword>Dexamethasone</keyword>
	<keyword>12-266</keyword>
</DOC>