<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01920893</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary Objective: To evaluate the efficacy of dupilumab (SAR231893 / REGN668) in the treatment of bilateral Nasal Polyposis (NP) by assessment of the endoscopic nasal polyp score in comparison to placebo. Secondary Objectives: To evaluate effect of dupilumab with regards to: - symptoms of sinusitis - sinus Computed Tomography (CT) scan - nasal polyp score in the sub-group of patients with co-morbid asthma - Safety and tolerability</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An Evaluation of Dupilumab in Patients With Nasal Polyposis And Chronic Symptoms Of Sinusitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Screening period (4 weeks) + Randomized Treatment Period (16 weeks)+ Post-Treatment Period (16 weeks) = 36 weeks. To ensure at least 28 patients with co-morbid asthma needed for subgroup analysis, recruitment of NP patients without co-morbid asthma will stop when approximately 28 patients without asthma are randomized.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sinusitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nasal Polyps</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mometasone Furoate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Patients with: A minimum bilateral nasal polyp score of 5 out of a maximum score of 8 (with a unilateral score of at least 2 for each nostril) despite completion of a prior intranasal corticosteroid (INCS) treatment for at least 8 weeks before screening. Presence of at least two of the following symptoms prior to screening: nasal blockade/obstruction/congestion or nasal discharge (anterior/posterior nasal drip); facial pain/pressure; reduction or loss of smell. Exclusion criteria: Patients &lt;18 or &gt;65 years of age. Sinonasal outcome test (SNOT22) &lt;7. Patients who have taken other investigational drugs or prohibited therapy for this study within 2 months before screening or 5 halflives, whichever is longer: Burst of systemic corticosteroids within the 2 months before screening or are scheduled to receive systemic corticosteroids during the study period for another condition; Intranasal corticosteroid drops within 1 month prior to screening; Monoclonal antibody (mAB) and immunosuppressive treatment; Antiimmunoglobulin E (IgE) therapy (omalizumab) within 130 days of Visit 1; .Leukotriene antagonists / modifiers unless patient is on a continuous treatment for at least 30 days prior to Visit 1. Patients who have undergone any nasal surgery (including polypectomy) within 6 months before screening or have had more than 5 sinonasal surgeries in the past of which maximal 2 were surgeries changing the lateral wall structure of the nose. Patients with asthma having: Forced Expiratory Volume (FEV1) ≤ 60%, or an asthma exacerbation requiring systemic (oral and/or parenteral) steroid treatment or hospitalization for &gt;24h for treatment of asthma, within 3 months prior to screening or are on a dose of greater than 1000 μg fluticasone or an equivalent inhaled corticosteroids. The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>