<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01920035</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Localized cooling/hypothermia using the UroCool System during robotic-assisted radical prostatectomy (RARP) surgery results in an improved overall return to continence, (defined as not wearing any protective urinary pads), compared with standard of care in men presenting for RARP.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Endorectal Cooling During RARP to Minimize Trauma and Promote Earlier Return to Continence</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will assess the use of an endorectal cooling device, UroCool, to achieve controlled, local hypothermia of the pelvis. The study will evaluate the safety and effectiveness of the device in inducing hypothermia of the neuromuscular tissues impacting continence during RARP. The UroCool system is designed to apply targeted temperature control to the pelvic anatomy during RARP. The pelvis is cooled transrectally via a closed cycle recirculation of chilled sterile saline using a single-use disposable balloon catheter connected via a circulation IV set to a control console that is covered by a current 510(k) and commercially available. The UroCool polymeric catheter is designed to be inserted within the rectal cavity adjacent to the prostate prior to surgery and removed upon completion of surgery. It is used in conjunction with the InnerCool Console which circulates cold saline in a closed loop within the UroCool catheter to allow for therapeutic localized cooling of the prostate gland and surrounding areas during prostate surgery.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Patient is male and a candidate for robotic assisted radical prostatectomy (RARP) for the treatment of prostate cancer Patient is over eighteen (&gt;18) years of age Patient reads, understands and speaks English fluently (U.S. Sites only) Subject understands and agrees to all preoperative preparation procedures including a "selfadministered" fleet enema Subject understands study procedures, risks of such procedures and is willing to comply with all study procedures Patient is willing and able to comply with all postsurgical milestones including completing and returning postsurgery follow up questionnaires at specified intervals over a 12 month period Subject agrees to participate in the study and is willing to sign the written informed consent per the enrolling site's institutional procedure Presents with baseline or has a history of urinary incontinence Rectal or GI pathology deemed unsuitable for placement of the treatment device by the examining physician Prior extensive pelvic surgery such as low anterior resection, abdominoperineal resection, or proctocolectomy continent stool pouch, or any other extensive abdominopelvic surgery that would render the patient a highrisk for complications as deemed by the surgeon History of prior treatment of any kind for prostate cancer; e.g. radiation therapy, cryotherapy, highintensity focused ultrasound (HIFU), hormonal or chemotherapy Prior intraoperative injuries (for example: rectal injury) Inadequate hemostasis Serious concurrent medical condition likely to result in death during the next 12 months. Any other acute or chronic condition which the Investigator believes will unacceptably increase the risk of study participation or interfere with study procedures and assessments. Active or recent (within 1 month prior to study enrollment) participation in another investigational clinical research study or planned to be enrolled in another study of prostate therapy.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Incontinence post RARP</keyword>
	<keyword>Surgery induced incontinence</keyword>
	<keyword>Incontinence after prostatectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>Neuropathy-induced incontinence</keyword>
</DOC>