<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00448539</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is an open-label extension of Study E2080-A001-301. All patients will initiate the study at the total daily doses they were receiving at the end of the transition phase in E2080-A001-301 (2400 or 3200 mg/day) with an option, at the discretion of the Investigator, to incrementally increase doses to a maximum of 4800 mg/day. Safety variables and seizure frequency will be monitored throughout the study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Open-Label Extension Study of Rufinamide Given as Adjunctive Therapy in Patients With Refractory Partial Seizures</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Seizures</mesh_term>
	<criteria>INCLUSION CRITERIA: 1. Completion of Study E2080A001301 and full compliance with the inclusion and exclusion criteria for that study (excluding criteria that are related to seizure occurrences). 2. Patient willing to participate and written consent signed by patient or legal guardian provided prior to entering this study or undergoing any study procedures. In addition, if the patient is unable to provide written informed consent and it is provided by a legal guardian, assent of the patient (if the patient is able) must also be obtained. 3. Female patients of nonchildbearing potential by reason of surgery, radiation, or menopause (at least one year post onset); female patients of childbearing potential who are using at least two approved methods of contraception (such as an intrauterine device [IUD], implant, oral contraceptive, or barrier method plus spermicide). Use of a lowdose estrogen oral contraceptive alone will not be permitted. Female patients of childbearing potential must agree to continue to use two approved methods of contraception through the followup visit or for 30 days after their final dose of study medication, whichever is longer. EXCLUSION CRITERIA: 1. Discontinuation from Study E2080A001301 for any reason, before the termination of the study. 2. Evidence of noncompliance with study drug or ongoing AED dosing during Study E2080A001301. 3. Evidence of clinically significant disease (cardiac, respiratory, gastrointestinal, hepatic (e.g., ALT &gt; 3x ULN), hematologic, renal, or psychiatric disease, etc.) that in the opinion of the Investigator could affect the patient's safety or trial conduct. 4. Progressive central nervous system (CNS) disease, including degenerative CNS diseases and progressive tumors. 5. History of alcohol abuse in the past 2 years. 6. History of suicide attempt within the previous 10 years. 7. Multiple drug allergies (dematological, heatological or organ toxicity) or more than one severe drug reaction. 8. Concomitant use of felbamate or vigabatrin. 9. Pregnancy. 10. Clinically significant ECG abnormality. 11. All patients with a diagnosis of Congenital Short QT Syndrome. Patients with a family history of Congenital Short QT Syndrome may be excluded on the basis of the Investigator's clinical judgement. 12. Presence of major active psychiatric disorder. Patients will be allowed who are taking a stable dose of selective serotonin reuptake inhibitor (SSRI) or mixed serotonin and norepinephrine uptake inhibitor antidepressant.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Refractory Partial Onset Seizures, epilepsy</keyword>
</DOC>