<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00448357</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Giving chemotherapy, such as fludarabine and busulfan, before a donor peripheral stem cell transplant helps stop the growth of cancer or abnormal cells. It also helps stop the patient's immune system from rejecting the donor's stem cells. When the healthy stem cells from a donor are infused into the patient they may help the patient's bone marrow make stem cells, red blood cells, white blood cells, and platelets. Sometimes the transplanted cells from a donor can make an immune response against the body's normal cells. Giving a monoclonal antibody, alemtuzumab, before the transplant and tacrolimus after the transplant may stop this from happening. PURPOSE: The phase I portion of this trial identified the maximum tolerated dose of busulfan after treating 40 patients on a dose-escalation scheme. We are now treating an additional 26 patients on the phase II portion of the trial at a PK-directed dose of total AUC 6912 uM-min/24 hours. We transitioned to the Phase II portion of the study in October 2009.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Fludarabine and PK-Directed Busulfan With or Without ATG Followed By Donor Peripheral Stem Cell Transplant in Treating Patients With Hematologic Cancer or Other Diseases</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Phase I Objective: To identify the maximum tolerated dose of continuous infusion IV busulfan based on blood levels derived from a test dose in conjunction with fludarabine, ATG and methotrexate plus tacrolimus for GVHD prophylaxis - Phase II Objective: To determine the one-year disease-free survival (DFS) rate at the maximum tolerated dose identified during Phase I of the trial (target AUC 6912) Secondary - Determine the overall and disease-free survival of patients treated with this regimen. - Determine the dose-limiting toxicities of this regimen in these patients. - Determine the capacity of test dosing of busulfan that would result in the desired area under the curve concentration exposure of patients receiving a full-dose busulfan regimen. - Determine the incidence of graft-vs-host disease and DNA chimerism between 1 month and 2 years post-transplantation in these patients. - Compare the overall survival (OS) and disease-free survival (DFS) rates for patients treated with Campath vs. patients treated with ATG/Methotrexate for GVHD control OUTLINE: This is a non-randomized, open-label, parallel group study of busulfan. Patients are stratified according to donor relationship (matched related donor [MRD] vs matched unrelated donor [MUD]). - Conditioning regimen: Patients receive fludarabine phosphate IV over 30 minutes on days -7 to -3 and busulfan IV over 2 hours once within days -15 to -10 and then IV continuously over 90 hours on days -7 to -4. Patients with a MRD also receive Methotrexate (MTX) on Days +1, +3, and +6. Patients with a MUD receive ATG on Days -3 and -2 and MTX on Days +1, +3 and +6. Phase I portion only: Cohorts of 3-6 patients receive escalating doses of busulfan until the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) is determined. The MTD is defined as the dose preceding that at which 2 of 3 or 2 of 6 patients experience dose-limiting toxicity. - Allogeneic peripheral blood stem cell transplantation: Patients undergo allogeneic peripheral blood stem cell transplantation on day 0. Patients then receive sargramostim (GM-CSF) subcutaneously beginning on day 5 and continuing until blood counts recover. - Graft-vs-host disease (GVHD) prophylaxis: Patients receive oral tacrolimus twice daily on days -1 to 180 or days -1 to 240. - Donor lymphocyte infusion (DLI): Patients who do not achieve CR, do not have GVHD, and have been off immunosuppressants for at least 30 days may receive up to 3 DLIs, at least 8 weeks apart, after completion of tacrolimus. After the completion of study treatment, patients are followed periodically for up to 5 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myelodysplastic Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Preleukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Plasmacytoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myeloproliferative Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methotrexate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fludarabine phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tacrolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antilymphocyte Serum</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Busulfan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fludarabine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed diagnosis of any of the following: Chronic lymphocytic leukemia or prolymphocytic leukemia Chemotherapyrefractory or advanced disease after ≥ 3 prior treatments Chronic myelogenous leukemia Diagnosis based on t(9;22) or related t(9;12) cytogenetic abnormalities AND characterized by elevated WBC counts in peripheral blood or marrow Patients with progressive disease on imatinib mesylate or other protein tyrosine kinase inhibitors; less than a major cytogenetic or fluorescent in situ hybridization (FISH) complete response (CR) after a minimum of 6 months of targeted therapy; or less than a complete FISH or cytogenetic response after 12 months of targeted therapy are eligible Patients with other cytogenetic abnormalities, such as t(9;12), that are associated with an aggressive clinical course are eligible NonHodgkin's lymphoma (NHL) or Hodgkin's lymphoma Any WHO classification histologic subtype allowed Must have advanced disease as defined by relapse after initial CR or failure to achieve CR OR deemed to have less than a 30% likelihood of durable response with an autologous stem cell transplant Refractory lowgrade NHL histologies or any intermediate or aggressive large cell or mantle cell lymphoma allowed Acute myeloid leukemia (AML) Highrisk disease in first CR (CR1) OR evidence of any recurrent disease beyond CR1 Highrisk individuals are those requiring more than 1 course of induction therapy to achieve remission; those with extramedullary disease at presentation; or those with highrisk cytogenetic abnormalities (abnormalities of chromosomes 5, 7, 2, trisomy 8, or 3) or &gt; 2 cytogenetic abnormalities Multiple myeloma Myelodysplastic syndromes (MDS) Must have MDS defined by WHO criteria with &gt; 5% blasts or highrisk cytogenetic abnormalities (abnormalities of chromosomes 5, 7, 2, trisomy 8, or 3) Acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL) Highrisk disease in CR1 OR beyond CR1 Highrisk disease includes the following: t(9;22) or t(4;11); WBC &gt; 30,000/mm³ at presentation; nonTcell phenotype; or more than 30 years of age Myelofibrosis/agnogenic myeloid metaplasia Patients must be transfusion dependant or have evidence of evolving AML as evidenced by an excess of blasts or a state of marrow failure/fibrosis Myeloproliferative disorders with advanced disease (e.g., progressive or spent phase polycythemia vera, myelofibrosis, or essential thrombocythemia) Any of the following categories of donors are acceptable*: HLAidentical or 1 antigenmismatched sibling (5/6, 6/6, or 8/10) donor Minimal serologic typing required for class I (A, B); molecular typing required for class II (DRB1) 8/10 matched unrelated donor (MUD) Molecular analysis at HLAA, B, C, DRB1 and DQB1 (8/10 match) by high resolution typing is required 5/6 MUD Molecular analysis at HLAA, B, and DRB1 required NOTE: *No syngeneic donors PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Performance status 02 Bilirubin ≤ 2 times upper limit of normal (ULN) AST ≤ 2 times ULN Creatinine clearance ≥ 50 mL/min Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception DLCO &gt; 60% with no symptomatic pulmonary disease LVEF ≥ 50% by MUGA No uncontrolled or severe cardiovascular disease, pulmonary disease, or infection that, in the opinion of the treating physician, would make this study unreasonably hazardous to the patient No other serious illness that would limit survival to &lt; 2 years No psychiatric condition that would preclude study compliance No uncontrolled diabetes mellitus or active serious infection No active second malignancy except for nonmelanomatous skin cancer No known hypersensitivity to E. coliderived products No HIV positivity PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: See Disease Characteristics More than 4 weeks since prior chemotherapy, radiotherapy, or surgery Cranial radiotherapy or intrathecal therapy as prophylaxis against CNS recurrence within the past 4 weeks allowed (in highrisk patients)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>refractory multiple myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>relapsing chronic myelogenous leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>secondary acute myeloid leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II multiple myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III multiple myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV adult Burkitt lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV adult diffuse large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV adult diffuse mixed cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV adult diffuse small cleaved cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV adult immunoblastic large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV adult lymphoblastic lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV adult Hodgkin lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV grade 1 follicular lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV grade 2 follicular lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV grade 3 follicular lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV mantle cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV marginal zone lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV small lymphocytic lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Waldenstrom macroglobulinemia</keyword>
	<keyword>accelerated phase chronic myelogenous leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute myeloid leukemia in remission</keyword>
	<keyword>blastic phase chronic myelogenous leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic eosinophilic leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic neutrophilic leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>extranodal marginal zone B-cell lymphoma of mucosa-associated lymphoid tissue</keyword>
	<keyword>nodal marginal zone B-cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult Burkitt lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult diffuse large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult diffuse mixed cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult diffuse small cleaved cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult Hodgkin lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult immunoblastic large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult lymphoblastic lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent grade 1 follicular lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent grade 2 follicular lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent grade 3 follicular lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent mantle cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent marginal zone lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent small lymphocytic lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III adult Burkitt lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III adult diffuse large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III adult diffuse mixed cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III adult diffuse small cleaved cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III adult Hodgkin lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III adult immunoblastic large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III adult lymphoblastic lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III grade 1 follicular lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III grade 2 follicular lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III grade 3 follicular lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III mantle cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III marginal zone lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III small lymphocytic lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute myeloid leukemia with 11q23 (MLL) abnormalities</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute myeloid leukemia with inv(16)(p13;q22)</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute myeloid leukemia with t(15;17)(q22;q12)</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute myeloid leukemia with t(16;16)(p13;q22)</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute myeloid leukemia with t(8;21)(q22;q22)</keyword>
	<keyword>primary myelofibrosis</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic phase chronic myelogenous leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>de novo myelodysplastic syndromes</keyword>
	<keyword>previously treated myelodysplastic syndromes</keyword>
	<keyword>prolymphocytic leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult acute lymphoblastic leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult acute myeloid leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>refractory chronic lymphocytic leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>secondary myelodysplastic syndromes</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III chronic lymphocytic leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV chronic lymphocytic leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute lymphoblastic leukemia in remission</keyword>
	<keyword>polycythemia vera</keyword>
	<keyword>essential thrombocythemia</keyword>
	<keyword>splenic marginal zone lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent mycosis fungoides/Sezary syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent cutaneous T-cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I multiple myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult grade III lymphomatoid granulomatosis</keyword>
	<keyword>adult nasal type extranodal NK/T-cell lymphoma</keyword>
</DOC>