<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00448838</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Monoclonal antibodies, such as cetuximab, can block tumor growth in different ways. Some block the ability of tumor cells to grow and spread. Others find tumor cells and help kill them or carry tumor-killing substances to them. Cetuximab may also stop the growth of pancreatic cancer by blocking blood flow to the tumor. Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as gemcitabine and oxaliplatin, work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing. Giving cetuximab together with combination chemotherapy may kill more tumor cells. PURPOSE: This clinical trial is studying how well giving cetuximab together with gemcitabine and oxaliplatin works in treating patients with locally advanced or metastatic pancreatic cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cetuximab, Gemcitabine, and Oxaliplatin in Treating Patients With Locally Advanced or Metastatic Pancreatic Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Determine the progression-free survival of patients with locally advanced or metastatic pancreatic cancer treated with cetuximab, gemcitabine hydrochloride, and oxaliplatin. Secondary - Determine the complete response and partial response in patients treated with this regimen. - Determine the time to progression in patients treated with this regimen. - Determine the duration of response in patients treated with this regimen. - Determine the survival of patients treated with this regimen. - Determine the toxicity of this regimen in these patients. OUTLINE: This is a nonrandomized, open-label, pilot study. Patients receive cetuximab IV over 1-2 hours on days 1 and 8, gemcitabine hydrochloride IV over 100 minutes on day 1, and oxaliplatin IV over 2-4 hours on day 2. Treatment repeats every 14 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed every 3 months. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 40 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cetuximab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically or cytologically confirmed pancreatic cancer Locally advanced or metastatic disease No active CNS metastases Patients with stable CNS disease, who have undergone radiotherapy within the past 4 weeks and who have been on a stable dose of corticosteroids for &gt; 3 weeks, are eligible PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: ECOG performance status 01 Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,500/mm³ Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm³ Bilirubin ≤ 1.5 mg/dL Alkaline phosphatase ≤ 3 times upper limit of normal (ULN) (5 times ULN if known hepatic metastases) AST and ALT ≤ 3 times ULN (5 times ULN if known hepatic metastases) Creatinine ≤ 1.5 mg/dL Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception during and for 90 days after completion of study treatment No significant history of uncontrolled cardiac disease, including any of the following: Uncontrolled hypertension Unstable angina Myocardial infarction within the past 6 months Uncontrolled congestive heart failure Cardiomyopathy with decreased ejection fraction No prior severe infusion reaction to a monoclonal antibody No active infection or fever ≥ 38.5°C within the past 3 days No known hypersensitivity to any components of gemcitabine hydrochloride, oxaliplatin, or to a monoclonal antibody No peripheral neuropathy ≥ grade 2 No known HIV positivity No hepatitis B or C infection (active, previously treated, or both) No other medical condition, including mental illness or substance abuse, that would preclude study compliance PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: See Disease Characteristics Recovered from all prior therapy, including surgery More than 30 days since prior investigational therapy More than 4 weeks since prior radiotherapy No prior radiotherapy to more than 25% of bone marrow More than 30 days since prior chemotherapy No prior chemotherapy for metastatic pancreatic cancer Prior fluoropyrimidine as a radiosensitizer allowed Prior gemcitabine hydrochloride in the adjuvant setting allowed No prior therapy that specifically and directly targets the epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) pathway No prior allogeneic transplantation No other concurrent investigational therapy, chemotherapy, or systemic antineoplastic therapy No other concurrent treatment that targets the EGFR No other concurrent monoclonal antibody therapy No concurrent radiotherapy except for local control of bone pain</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>120 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent pancreatic cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III pancreatic cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV pancreatic cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II pancreatic cancer</keyword>
</DOC>