<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01813110</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess whether the marine omega-3 fatty acids can attenuate inflammatory responses to endotoxin challenge.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of a Prescription Omega-3 Fatty Acid Concentrate on Induced Inflammation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>1. Men between the ages of 20 and 45. 2. BMI ≥20 and ≤30 3. Participants who are able to give written informed consent and willing to comply with all studyrelated procedures. 4. Any race or ethnic background is acceptable 5. Nonsmoking The specific exclusion criteria are: 1. Previous history of vasovagal reactions or unprovoked fainting (I.e. fainting as a result of prolonged standing, exercise) 2. Resting heart rate &lt; 55 bpm 3. History of atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease, including coronary disease, cerebrovascular disease, or peripheral vascular disease 4. History of diabetes mellitus (and/or a fasting glucose &gt;126 mg/dL at screening) 5. Chronic antiinflammatory medication use or treatment with aspirin, NSAIDs, COX2 inhibitors; steroids or any immunomodulatory therapy 2 weeks prior to the screening visit 6. Selfreported history of allergy to fish 7. History of a nonskin malignancy within the previous 5 years 8. Renal insufficiency as defined by creatinine outside of lab defined normal range at Screening Visit 9. History of liver disease or abnormal LFTs (AST, ALT, Alk. Phos., GGT &gt; 1.5x ULN; bilirubin &gt; 2x ULN) at Screening Visit 10. Total white blood cell count less than or equal to 3.0 THO/uL 11. Hemoglobin less than 11.0 g/dL 12. Any major active rheumatologic, pulmonary, or dermatologic disease or inflammatory condition or minor active infection 13. Selfreported history of HIV positive 14. Participants who have undergone any organ transplant 15. Individuals who currently use tobacco products or have done so in the previous 30 days. 16. Participants who are unwilling to discontinue use of nutritional supplements, herbs or vitamins unless approved by study staff. 17. Participants who are unwilling to eliminate omega3 fatty acid (EPA + DHA) supplements and/or fortified food, or have a usual intake of high omega3 fish (tuna and other nonfried fish) &gt; 2 servings per week 18. Elevated blood pressure (BP &gt; 159/99) or use of any antihypertensive medications. 19. Latex allergy 20. Unwillingness to refrain from blood donation for 2 months prior to and following endotoxin administration 21. Any medical condition or abnormal laboratory value that is judged clinically significant by an investigator 22. Inability to take study capsules 23. History of severe, repeated headaches 24. History of migraine 25. Medical condition that causes severe nausea or vomiting 26. Low resting blood pressure (SBP &lt; 90 mmHg) 27. History of atrial fibrillation/flutter 28. Abnormal coagulation parameters (platelet count, prothrombin time with INR), documented coagulation abnormality, or use of anticoagulant medication 29. High LDLC (&gt; or = 160 mg/dL)</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>inflammation</keyword>
	<keyword>omega-3</keyword>
	<keyword>fish oil</keyword>
</DOC>