<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01813019</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether AFQ056 as an add on therapy to SSRIs can have beneficial effects by reducing the total score of Y-BOCS (Yale and Brown Obsessive Compulsive Scale) in OCD patients resistant to SSRI treatment (failed SSRI over 12 weeks at appropriate doses).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Evaluate the Effect of AFQ056 in Obsessive Compulsive Disorder (OCD) Patients Resistant to Selective Serotonin Reuptake Inhibitor (SSRI) Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This was a randomized, double-blind, parallel group, placebo-controlled, 12-weeks 200 mg b.i.d oral dose treatment of AFQ056 (following a 4 week up-titration period and followed by a 3 week down-titration period) or matched placebo in patients diagnosed with OCD and on background SSRI treatment for at least 12 weeks. Study was prematurely terminated at the time of the first Interim Analysis (IA) as the study did not meet its primary efficacy objective.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Compulsive Personality Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Compulsive Behavior</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Serotonin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Serotonin Uptake Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female , nonsmokers patients aged between 18 to 65 years (inclusive), A primary diagnosis of obsessivecompulsive disorder (OCD) as per Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (DSMIVTR 4th ed, year 2000), as confirmed by an Independent Rater. Be on a stable appropriate dose of selective serotonin reuptake inhibitor (SSRI) treatment for at least 12 weeks prior to Baseline. Have an insufficient response to current SSRI treatment (as per Inclusion Criterion 4) and confirmed by an Independent Rater. Have a YaleBrown Obsessive Compulsive Scale (YBOCS) of score ≥ 16 at Screening (and confirmed by an Independent Rater). Patient must have their eligibility confirmed following the remote interview conducted by the Independent Rater. Able to communicate well with the investigator, to understand and comply with the requirements of the study. Diagnosis of primary OCD symptom of hoarding. Women of childbearing potential, defined as all women physiologically capable of becoming pregnant, unless they are using effective methods of contraception (not including oral contraceptives) during dosing and for 30 days after last dosing of study medication. History of more than two unsatisfactory trials with different SSRI within a period of 2 years prior to screening (not including the current treatment with SSRI's given in an adequate dose for at least 12 weeks). Diagnosed with any primary DSMIVTR Axis I disorder other than OCD (as confirmed by an Independent Rater); with the exception of depression. History of eating disorder (e.g. anorexia, bulimia) according to DSMIV within the last 6 months prior to Screening, (as confirmed by an Independent Rater). Diagnosed with antisocial personality disorder (DSMIVTR Axis II), as confirmed by an Independent Rater. Has current or past medical history of bipolar disorder, schizophrenia or other psychotic disorders, schizoaffective disorder, autism or autistic spectrum disorders, borderline personality disorder, within the last 6 months prior to Screening. Smokers (use of tobacco products in the previous 3 months). History of hallucinations/psychosis that would require antipsychotic treatment or DSMIV criteria being met Score "yes" on item 4 or item 5 of the Suicidal Ideation section of the CSSRS, if this ideation occurred in the past 6 months, or "yes" on any item of the Suicidal Behavior section, except for the "Non Suicidal SelfInjurious Behavior" (item also included in the Suicidal Behavior section), if this behavior occurred in the past 2 years.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Obsessive compulsive disorder (OCD), obsessive fears, obsessions,</keyword>
	<keyword>compulsions, OCD SSRI resistant</keyword>
</DOC>