<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01905280</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the clinical and histologic outcomes for acellular dermal matrix and a nonresorbable membrane to determine if either provides a significant therapeutic advantage. The hypothesis is that there will be no difference in crestal ridge width between the two treatments.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ridge Preservation Comparing 2 Membranes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>30 patients will be selected that meet the following criteria: Inclusion Criteria 1. Have one non-molar tooth requiring extraction that will be replaced by a dental implant. The site must be bordered by at least one tooth. 2. Healthy male or female who is at least 18 years old. 3. Patients must sign an informed consent approved by the University of Louisville Human Studies Committee. Exclusion Criteria 1. Patients with debilitating systemic diseases, or diseases that have a clinically significant effect on the periodontium. 2. Presence or history of osteonecrosis of jaws. 3. Patients who are currently taking IV bisphosphonates or who had IV treatment with bisphosphonates irrespective of duration. 4. Patients who have been treated with oral bisphosphonates for more than three years. 5. Patients with an allergy to any material or medication used in the study. 6. Patients who need prophylactic antibiotics. 7. Previous head and neck radiation therapy. 8. Chemotherapy in the previous 12 months. 9. Patients on long term NSAID or steroid therapy. 10. Pregnant patients.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>1. Have one nonmolar tooth requiring extraction that will be replaced by a dental implant. The site must be bordered by at least one tooth. 2. Healthy male or female who is at least 18 years old. 3. Patients must sign an informed consent approved by the University of Louisville Human Studies Committee. 1. Patients with debilitating systemic diseases, or diseases that have a clinically significant effect on the periodontium. 2. Presence or history of osteonecrosis of jaws. 3. Patients who are currently taking IV bisphosphonates or who had IV treatment with bisphosphonates irrespective of duration. 4. Patients who have been treated with oral bisphosphonates for more than three years. 5. Patients with an allergy to any material or medication used in the study. 6. Patients who need prophylactic antibiotics. 7. Previous head and neck radiation therapy. 8. Chemotherapy in the previous 12 months. 9. Patients on long term NSAID or steroid therapy. 10. Pregnant patients.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>allograft</keyword>
	<keyword>acellular dermal matrix</keyword>
	<keyword>alveolar ridge</keyword>
</DOC>