<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01905228</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of the study is to determine the maximally tolerated dose and recommended Phase 2 dose of CBL0137 when administered intravenously (IV) to patients with metastatic or unresectable advanced solid malignancies.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase 1 Trial of CBL0137 in Patients With Metastatic or Unresectable Advanced Solid Neoplasm</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients must have documented recurrent or refractory solid tumors; patients enrolled in the dose-expansion part of the trial must have least one lesion that may qualify as a target lesion based on the RECIST 1.1 criteria. Following the provision of signed informed consent, patients will be screened for entry into the study. Screening numbers will be assigned by the site. Patients who do not meet entry criteria will not have their screening data entered into the database.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients must have histological or cytological evidence of a solid neoplasm Patients enrolled in the expansion cohort must have at least one measureable lesion as defined by the RECIST 1.1 criteria Patients must: have metastatic or unresectable advanced solid tumors that have recurred or progressed following standard therapy or no longer be candidates for standard therapy or have tumors for which there is no standard therapy Patients must be ambulatory and have an ECOG Performance Score of 0 or 1; Patients or their legal representative must be able to provide written informed consent; Patients must have adequate bone marrow reserve as evidenced by: White Blood Cell Count (WBC) &gt; 3,000/µL Absolute Neutrophil Count (ANC) &gt; 1,500/µL Platelet count (PLT) &gt; 75,000/µL Hemoglobin (HGB) &gt; 8.0 gm/dL (patients may be transfused to achieve this HGB level); Patients must have adequate hepatic function as evidenced by: Serum AST/ALT &lt; 3X the upper limit of normal (ULN) for the reference lab (&lt; 5X the ULN for patients with known hepatic metastases) Serum bilirubin &lt; 1.5 x the ULN for the reference lab; Patients with active infection or with a fever &gt; 38.50 C within 3 days of the first scheduled day of dosing; Patients with primary CNS tumors or symptomatic CNS metastases who have not undergone surgery and/or radiotherapy and/or who are not neurologically stable; Patients with known hypersensitivity to any of the components of CBL0137; Patients who are receiving concurrent investigational therapy; for patients who have recently received investigational therapy, 5 halflives must have elapsed between the last dose of investigational drug and the first dose of CBL0137. If the halflive is unknown, 4 weeks must have elapsed between the last dose of investigational drug and the first dose of CBL0137 (investigational therapy is defined as treatment for which there is currently no regulatory authority approved indication in the United States); Males with mean QTcF values of &gt; 450 msec and females with QTcF values of &gt; 470 msec following 3 ECGs conducted 5 minutes apart from each other; patients who are known to have congenital prolonged QT syndromes; or patients who are on medications known to cause prolonged QT intervals on ECG; Please speak with the PI for the complete Inclusion/Exclusion listing.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Metastatic Advance Solid Neoplasms</keyword>
	<keyword>Unresectable Advance Solid Neoplasms</keyword>
</DOC>