<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="29948">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02716831</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1501003366</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>1K23MH105680-01A1</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02716831</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The INSPIRE Project: Innovations in Psychological Interventions for Regulating Eating</brief_title>
  <acronym>INSPIRE</acronym>
  <official_title>Addressing Weight History to Improve Behavioral Treatments for Bulimia Nervosa</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Drexel University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Drexel University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of the study is to test a novel, acceptance-based behavioral treatment for
      bulimia nervosa (BN) in weight-suppressed adults. This treatment is a type of individual
      psychotherapy called Nutritional Counseling And Acceptance-based Therapy (N-CAAT) that
      enhances existing cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) for BN by incorporating
      acceptance-based behavioral strategies and nutritional counseling to help patients high in
      weight suppression (WS) reduce the biobehavioral bind of WS and eliminate BN symptoms.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Bulimia nervosa (BN) is an eating disorder characterized by a pattern of binge eating and
      compensatory behaviors as well as an overemphasis on body weight and shape in
      self-evaluation. BN has a lifetime prevalence rate of 1-3% and is associated with numerous
      psychiatric and medical complications. Cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) is regarded as the
      gold-standard treatment for BN and the treatment approach with the most empirical support to
      date. However, although CBT has accumulated impressive empirical support for its
      effectiveness, CBT produces abstinence from binge eating and purging in only 30-50% of
      treatment completers. Furthermore, relapse is common and many individuals do not maintain
      treatment gains. Innovative treatments that can improve rates of remission among patients
      with BN and related disorders are sorely needed for bulimia nervosa and related eating
      disorders, particularly for individuals for whom existing treatments fail.

      Weight suppression (WS) is a robust predictor of bulimic symptomatology, being positively
      correlated with frequency of objective binge eating and purging in individuals with BN. A
      recent study found that women who experienced objective binge episodes were twice as weight
      suppressed (M = 8.8kg) than those without these eating problems (M = 4.4kg). Among patients
      with threshold or sub-threshold BN, greater WS at baseline predicted increased likelihood of
      persistent BN symptoms at 10-year follow-up. Furthermore, in the comparison group of those
      without bulimic symptomatology at baseline, higher WS predicted the onset of a bulimic
      syndrome at 10-year follow-up. WS appears to be uniquely predictive of binge eating and
      purging behavior rather than disordered eating behaviors more broadly (e.g. shape and weight
      concern, drive for thinness, BMI), suggesting that WS is not merely a marker of disease
      severity. This body of research suggests that WS may not only be an important factor in the
      maintenance of BN pathology, but may be a significant contributor to its etiology.

      Additionally, WS predicts remission and treatment outcome in BN. Butryn, Lowe, and Agras
      (2006) previously found that greater WS predicts poorer outcome in the cognitive-behavioral
      treatment of BN, perhaps because those higher in WS have greater difficulty normalizing
      eating without gaining weight. Although two more recent studies have failed to replicate
      this finding, both replication studies included patients whose average WS level was
      substantially lower than the mean level in the study by Butryn and colleagues (Carter,
      McIntosh, Joyce &amp; Bulik, 2008; Zunker, Crosby, Mitchell, Wonderlich, Peterson &amp; Crow, 2011).
      This might suggest that only relatively high levels of WS are relevant to treatment outcome.
      In a more recent study, level of WS at study entry predicted time to first full or partial
      remission from the disorder over 8 years of follow-up (Lowe, Swanson, Clark, Eddy, Franko,
      Shaw, Ross &amp; Herzog 2011).

      Novel treatments are needed to address the barriers to successful treatment of BN within
      patients high in WS. The high metabolic efficiency in those with elevated WS could help
      explain why WS has consistently predicted weight gain in several BN samples, over periods as
      short as several weeks and as long as five years. If greater WS in patients triggers greater
      weight gain, this may intensify dieting efforts and compensatory behaviors to slow or
      prevent weight gain, thus perpetuating BN symptoms. Patients appear to be in a
      &quot;biobehavioral&quot; bind, whereby they need to continue utilizing disordered eating symptoms to
      prevent weight re-gain, which may explain why individuals high in WS have poorer treatment
      outcome and require significantly longer time to achieve partial and full remission. Even
      modest weight gain, which may help patients high in WS experience fewer urges to binge and
      more effectively normalize their eating behavior, is highly distressing for patients with
      BN. Treatments that specifically address the added barriers faced by patients high in WS may
      be needed to improve treatment efficacy for this sub-group. In particular, approaches that
      can alter the biobehavioral bind by 1.) increasing willingness to increase caloric intake
      and experience modest weight re-gain during treatment despite distress and 2.) promoting
      more adaptive and healthy behaviors designed to stabilize weight gain could improve
      treatment efficacy.

      Existing CBT may be enhanced by incorporating acceptance-based behavioral strategies and
      nutritional counseling to help patients high in WS reduce the biobehavioral bind of WS and
      eliminate BN symptoms. Acceptance-based behavioral treatments (ABBTs) emphasize &quot;changing
      what you can and accepting what you can't&quot;, which refers to a focus on learning how to
      accept and tolerate distressing internal experiences (e.g., thoughts, emotions, urges,
      physical sensations) that might not be directly under the patients' control while choosing
      to engage in adaptive behavioral choices that are within their control. Patients high in WS
      will likely need to gain weight to experience the improvements associated with a reduced
      biobehavioral bind (e.g., reduced urges to binge, greater ability to normalize eating
      behaviors), and will need to &quot;accept&quot; the distress that accompanies this weight gain.
      However patients may also benefit from the provision of more adaptive behavioral strategies
      to maintain weight in a healthy range, which is not a primary goal of existing behavioral
      treatments.

      Nutritional counseling (NC), which is designed to promote healthy, non-rigid dietary
      restraint and exercise habits, can lead to improvements in weight control that may also
      improve disordered eating behaviors. As described above, a primary maintenance factor for BN
      is the strict and rigid dieting behavior that triggers urges to binge. For patients high in
      WS, some degree of dietary restraint may be needed to stabilize weight gain and the
      provision of healthier and more functionally adaptive strategies to regulate weight could
      reduce the likelihood of engaging in disordered eating symptoms. Several studies have
      indicated that the provision of healthy restraint strategies to patients with BN can reduce
      binge eating and purging behaviors, suggesting that this approach can be an effective
      treatment alone or in combination with other behavioral techniques.

      Of most relevance to the current study, two recent clinical trials examined Acceptance and
      Commitment Therapy (ACT), the most widely studied ABBT, for eating pathology (Juarascio,
      Forman, &amp; Herbert, 2010; Juarascio, Shaw, Forman, Timko, Herbert, Butryn, Bunnell, Matteucci
      &amp; Lowe, 2013). The first study examined the treatment of sub-clinical eating pathology
      within the context of a larger randomized controlled trial (RCT) that compared standard CBT
      with ACT and found that those in the ACT condition experienced significantly greater
      reductions in eating pathology (as measured by the Eating Pathology Index, adapted from the
      SCOFF Assessment) (Juarascio et al., 2010). The principal investigator's dissertation
      examined whether the addition of ACT groups to treatment as usual (TAU) at a residential
      treatment facility for eating disorders could improve treatment outcome Those in the ACT
      condition showed greater reduction in global eating pathology by discharge (as measured by
      the Eating Disorder Examination), despite the fact that the ACT group was one of a dozen or
      more treatment groups patients received during their residential stay (Juarascio et al.,
      2013). Although WS was not formally assessed, a trend was observed in the PI's dissertation
      study such that individuals with lower starting weights (who were likely higher in WS)
      showed greater improvements in global EDE scores in the ACT+TAU condition.

      Study Objectives-

        -  Test the feasibility, acceptability, and preliminary efficacy of Nutritional Counseling
           And Acceptance-based Therapy (N-CAAT) for bulimia nervosa (BN) in a small pilot RCT
           trial

        -  Assess the mechanisms of action to enhance treatment development

        -  Evaluate the feasibility of recruitment, randomization, retention, assessment
           procedures, and implementation of the novel treatment to enhance the probability of
           success in subsequent larger RCTs

      The current study will evaluate the hypothesis that N-CAAT will successfully improve
      hypothesized clinical targets (e.g. distress tolerance, rigid dieting, weight suppression,
      biomarkers associated with metabolic efficiency and test the hypothesis that improvements in
      distress tolerance, rigid dieting, weight suppression, and biomarkers of metabolic
      efficiency will be associated with improvements in BN symptoms.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>May 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Outcomes Assessor</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Binge and purge frequency assessed by the Eating Disorder Examination (EDE)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from Baseline Binge and Purge Frequency at 5 months and 11 months</time_frame>
    <description>Binge and purge frequency as assessed by the Eating Disorder Examination (EDE)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Body Mass Index (BMI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from Baseline BMI at 1 month, 3 months, 5 months, and 11 months</time_frame>
    <description>Body Mass Index (BMI) will be assessed to ensure weight remains in a healthy range and to track weight change</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Broader Psychological Functioning assessed by the Symptom Checklist-90-Revisited</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from Baseline Symptom Checklist-90 Revisited at 1 month, 3 months, 5 months, and 11 months</time_frame>
    <description>Broader psychological functioning will be assessed by the Symptom Checklist-90-Revisited (SC) which assesses a broad range of psychological problems and symptoms of psychopathology</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Bulimia Nervosa</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Nutritional Counseling &amp; Acceptance-based Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Nutritional Counseling &amp; Acceptance-based Therapy (N-CAAT) incorporates acceptance-based behavioral strategies and nutritional counseling designed to encourage willingness to tolerate distress and the ability to pursue chosen values in an adaptive manner despite distressing internal experiences. In addition to these skills, a principal focus of the treatment will be on identifying, practicing, and achieving behavioral goals, such as normalization of eating, reduction of maladaptive dietary restraint and restriction, and elimination of compensatory behaviors.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cognitive Behavioral Therapy for Eating Disorders</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in the Cognitive Behavioral Therapy for Eating Disorders (CBT) condition will receive 20-sessions of standard CBT for eating disorders based on the treatment approach developed by Dr. Christopher Fairburn and published in his book Cognitive Behavioral Therapy and Eating Disorders.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nutritional Counseling &amp; Acceptance-based Therapy</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Nutritional Counseling &amp; Acceptance-based Therapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cognitive Behavioral Therapy for Eating Disorders</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Cognitive Behavioral Therapy for Eating Disorders</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Meets Diagnostic Statistical Manual(DSM)-5 criteria for Bulimia Nervosa

          -  Age 18 or above

          -  Current level of Weight Suppression at or above 9.0 kilograms

          -  Medical clearance from Primary Care Physician

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Body Mass Index (BMI) below 85% of ideal body weight or other medical complications
             that prevent ability to engage in outpatient treatment

          -  Acute suicide risk

          -  Co-morbid diagnosis of a psychotic disorder, bipolar disorder, or substance
             dependence

          -  Diagnosis of mental retardation or a pervasive development disorder

          -  Current pregnancy
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Adrienne S Juarascio, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Drexel University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Adrienne S Juarascio, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>215-553-7154</phone>
    <email>asj32@drexel.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Arielle S Wolinsky, BA</last_name>
    <phone>215-553-7137</phone>
    <email>asw76@drexel.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Drexel University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Adrienne S Juarascio, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>215-553-7154</phone>
      <email>asj32@drexel.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Adrienne S Juarascio, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://drexel.edu/coas/academics/departments-centers/psychology/research/faculty-research-laboratories/innovation-health-related-behavior-change-lab/projects/</url>
    <description>Scroll down the web page to &quot;INSPIRE- Now Recruiting&quot;</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 28, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 11, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Bulimia Nervosa</keyword>
  <keyword>Eating Disorders</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Bulimia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bulimia Nervosa</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
