<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02395393</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Bronchoscopy-guided tissue sampling is a central technique in many diseases including diagnosing and staging lung cancers, diagnosing interstitial lung diseases, and acute and/or chronic rejections following lung transplantation. Confocal fluorescence microscopy is a novel technique used for real-time microscopic imaging of proximal and distal airways, microvessels, and inflammatory cells. We hypothesize that confocal fluorescence microscopy images of airways and alveolar structures during standard bronchoscopy could help recognize and classify the presence or absence of acute or chronic rejection in lung transplant recipients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Confocal Fluorescence Microscopy of the Human Airways in Diagnostics of Lung Transplantation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Bronchoscopy-guided tissue sampling is a central technique in many diseases including diagnosing and staging lung cancers, diagnosing interstitial lung diseases, and acute and/or chronic rejections following lung transplantation. Confocal fluorescence microscopy is a novel technique used for in vivo microscopic imaging of proximal and distal airways including bronchial and alveolar walls, microvessels, and inflammatory cells. We hypothesize that confocal fluorescence microscopy images of bronchiolar and alveolar structures during standard bronchoscopy could help recognize and classify the presence or absence of acute or chronic rejection in lung transplant recipients. The objectives and outcomes of this study are: 1. To assess the safety of confocal microscopy imaging in pediatric patients 2. To create diagnostic criteria for fibered confocal fluorescence microscopy image interpretation of acute and chronic rejections following lung transplantation 3. To determine the sensitivity and specificity of confocal imaging in these patient groups compared to the transbronchial biopsies 4. Correlate confocal images to FEV1 results 5. Correlate with CXRs and/or CT images</detailed_description>
	<criteria>to be older than six years of age to be undergoing surveillance or clinically indicated bronchoscopies with transbronchial biopsy as part of their routine care to be willing and able to comply with study procedures and provide written informed consent/assent to participate in the study to be unwilling to consent to be unable to safely tolerate a bronchoscopic procedure to have any contraindications to shortacting anesthetic agents to have any contraindications to transbronchial biopsies</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>22 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acute rejection</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic rejection</keyword>
	<keyword>Confocal microscopy</keyword>
</DOC>