<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02395731</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This Center for Medicare and Medicaid funded health care innovation award will implement the MIND at Home dementia care coordination program (called MIND at Home-Plus) through two community-based service agencies (Jewish Community Services, Johns Hopkins Home Care Group) to rapidly improve the ability of 600 dually eligible older adults with dementia in the Baltimore region to remain at home while improving care quality, enhancing quality of life, and reducing total health care costs. MIND at Home participants receive an in-home needs assessment followed by up to 18 months of care coordination aimed at filling unmet needs.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comprehensive Home-based Dementia Care Coordination for Medicare-Medicaid Dual Eligibles in Maryland</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The demonstration project has 3 major tasks which will be implemented in concurrent, iterative phases: (1) implement MIND-Plus in 2 community-based health service agencies to rapidly improve the ability of 600 community-living dually eligible older adults with AD in the Baltimore region to remain at home while improving care quality, enhancing quality of life, and reducing total health care costs associated with institutional care or hospitalization; (2) develop a replicable model for nationwide diffusion of the MIND program through a web-based certification package designed to prepare for implementation, build work-force capacity through training certification modules, and provide automated self-monitoring and quality improvement tools; and (3) develop and test a detailed payment model that takes a blended approach and includes provider care management fees with provider performance incentives from division of shared savings. The investigators hypothesize that the MIND-Plus dementia care coordination program will (1) rapidly improve health &amp; care quality and reduce total health care costs among Medicare-Medicaid dually eligible community-living older adults with AD, (2) drive health care system transformation by creating a new CMS financed benefit that would shift the hub of dementia care coordination to well-trained, dementia competent, interdisciplinary teams based in community health agencies, (3) achieve a sustainable payment model that produces significant net savings and incentives provider performance. This "shovel ready" community-based model is expected to improve outcomes within 6 months and save an estimated net-saving of $12.5 million by over 3 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dementia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>diagnosis of dementia community living has identified study partner willing to participate english speaking situation at time of referral is a medical or mental health crisis they plan to move out to another area or into a residential care facility in the next 6 months they are currently on hospice.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>dual eligible</keyword>
	<keyword>care coordination</keyword>
	<keyword>community-based</keyword>
	<keyword>care quality</keyword>
	<keyword>care needs</keyword>
	<keyword>health services</keyword>
	<keyword>care management</keyword>
	<keyword>low income</keyword>
	<keyword>Neuropsychiatric behaviors</keyword>
</DOC>