<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02395354</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will be a multicentre randomized controlled trial to assess the efficacy between balloon dilatation and self-expanding metallic stent placement for endoscopic treatment of stenosis in Crohn´s Disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PROTDILAT (PROtesis DILATation)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A Prospective, randomized, multicenter clinical trial. Duration: Beginning in mid-2013 with a minimum of three years depending on the patient inclusion rate. The participation of at least 20 hospitals in Spain with an inclusion of about 6 patients per hospital is required. Calculation of sample size: The calculation of sample size was performed considering that the efficacy of endoscopic treatment by endoscopic stent placement is superior to endoscopic dilatation: 75% vs 50% for balloon dilation (% of patients free of therapeutic intervention -endoscopic or surgically a year follow-up). For all 61 patients are required for each treatment group, the total of 122 patients. This calculation is made taking into account: - Bilateral Contrast: any two samples may be superior in terms of efficacy. - Error type I: 0.05 - Error type II: 0.20 (statistical power 80%) - Percentage of efficacy at one year follow-up: 75% in the prosthetic group and 50% in the balloon dilatation group - Percentage of losses: 5%. Schedule 1. Screening Visit 2. Sheet Inclusion 3. Expansion notebook / prosthesis placement notebook 4. Monitoring Worksheet to the 7 days. Symptomatic / complications-incidents assessment. 5. Monitoring Worksheet to the 30 days. Symptomatic / complications-incidents assessment. Includes analytical. In case of placement of prostheses include prosthetic removal sheet 6. Monitoring Worksheet to the 2 months. Symptomatic / complications-incidents assessment. 7. Monitoring Worksheet to the 3 months. Symptomatic / complications-incidents assessment. 8. Monitoring Worksheet to the 4 months. Symptomatic / complications-incidents assessment 9. Monitoring Worksheet to the 5 months. Symptomatic / complications-incidents assessment 10. Monitoring Worksheet to the 6 months. Symptomatic / complications-incidents assessment. Include analytical 11. Monitoring Worksheet to the 7 months. Symptomatic / complications-incidents assessment 12. Monitoring Worksheet to the 8 months. Symptomatic / complications-incidents assessment 13. Monitoring Worksheet to the 9 months. Symptomatic / complications-incidents assessment 14. Monitoring Worksheet to the 10 months. Symptomatic / complications-incidents assessment 15. Monitoring Worksheet to the 11 months. Symptomatic / complications-incidents assessment 16. Monitoring Worksheet to the 12 months. Symptomatic / complications-incidents assessment Include analytical. 17. Final assessment. 18. Monitoring Worksheet to the recurrence. Symptomatic / complications-incidents assessment. Include analytical</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Constriction, Pathologic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Crohn Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dilatation, Pathologic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 1875 years. Crohn's Disease with a predominantly fibrotic stenosis de novo and / or post surgical confirmed by endoscopic and radiological tests, accessible by endoscopy (colonoscopy). Patients with stenosis already known and previously treated with stent and / or dilation with&gt; 1 Year asymptomatic Symptoms of intestinal partial occlusion Refractory to Conventional medical treatment (no response to usual therapeutic range "accelerated stepup"). Length of stenosis &lt;10 cm. Submit a maximum of 2 stenosis. Patient Informed consent No patient Informed consent. Stenosis complicated with abscess, fistula or important activity associated with your EC not limited to the stenosis area. Patients with stenosis already known and previously treated with stent and / or dilation with &lt;1 year asymptomatic. Pregnancy and lactation Any clinical situation that prevents the performance of endoscopy Stenosis not accessible by endoscopy Asymptomatic patient Length of stenosis ≥ 10 cm. Submit&gt; 2 stenosis. Severe coagulation disorders (platelets &lt;70000; INR&gt; 1.8)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Endoscopic treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>Stenosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Crohn's Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>balloon dilatation</keyword>
	<keyword>self-expanding metallic stent</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic transmural inflammation</keyword>
	<keyword>steady narrowing of the intestinal lumen</keyword>
</DOC>