<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01153932</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether GSK2402968 given as a continuous dose and as an intermittent dose is effective and safe in the treatment of Duchenne muscular dystrophy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase II Doubleblind Exploratory Study of GSK2402968 in Ambulant Subjects With Duchenne Muscular Dystrophy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a phase II, double-blind, exploratory, parallel-group, placebo-controlled clinical study in ambulant subjects with DMD resulting from a mutation that can be corrected by exon skipping induced by GSK2402968. The study aims to randomise 54 subjects. There will be 2 parallel cohorts. Each cohort will include subjects on GSK2402968 and matched placebo in a 2:1 ratio.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Muscular Dystrophies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Muscular Dystrophy, Duchenne</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Ambulant subjects with Duchenne muscular dystrophy resulting from a mutation in the DMD gene, confirmed by a stateoftheart DNA diagnostic technique covering all DMD gene exons, including but not limited to MLPA (Multiplex Ligationdependent Probe Amplification), CGH (Comparative Genomic Hybridisation) or HRMCA (HighResolution Melting Curve Analysis), and correctable by GSK2402968induced DMD exon 51 skipping, Males, at least 5 years of age and with a life expectancy of at least 1 year Able to rise from floor in ≤7 seconds (without aids/orthoses), Able to complete the 6MWD test with a distance of at least 75m Receiving glucocorticoids for a minimum of 6 months immediately prior to screening, with no significant change in total daily dosage or dosing regimen for a minimum of 3 months immediately prior to screening and a reasonable expectation that total daily dosage and dosing regimen will not change significantly for the duration of the study QTc &lt;450msec On adequate contraception Able to comply with and complete all protocol requirements any additional missing exon for DMD Current of history of liver or renal disease or impairment Acute illness within 4 weeks of the first dose Use of prohibited meds within 6 months of fist dose Current participation in any other investigational clinical trial Positive hepatitis B surface antigen, hepatitis C antibody test, or human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) test at screening Symptomatic cardiomyopathy Children in Care</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>968</keyword>
	<keyword>muscular dystrophy</keyword>
	<keyword>duchenne</keyword>
	<keyword>DMD</keyword>
</DOC>