<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01699984</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This prospective observational cohort study aims at studying functional and clinical outcomes of patients (N = 329) admitted to 4 geriatric hospital facilities of the St John of God Order in Northern Italy during an index period of 4 months. Other areas assessed include variables that help or hinder the discharge of patients with sufficient residential autonomy and the predictive ability of clinicians compared with the evaluation of selective indicators of outcome (clinical and instrumental). Patients are followed from the first day of hospitalization until discharge or up to 3 months and 1 day after the date of admission ("long-term care" patients). At admission a "Patient Form" including social, demographic and clinical informations and a series of standardized assessment tools is completed with the help of clinicians, nurses and caregivers (when available). For each patient, during hospitalization, an analysis of apolipoprotein ApoE polymorphisms is performed and adverse events occurred during hospitalization are monitored, as well as the predictive abilities of clinicians and any recent CT and MRI. Patients are reassessed at discharge (or after 3 months for "long-term care" patients) and at 6 months follow-up of with a standardized telephone interview to assess clinical and functional status and possible changes in the residential status of the patient.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PERDOVE ANZIANI: a Prospective Cohort Study on Older Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Dementia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>age 65 or older informed consent provided younger than 65 years informed consent not provided</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cognitive impairment.</keyword>
	<keyword>Geriatrics.</keyword>
	<keyword>Hospital admission.</keyword>
	<keyword>Hospital discharge.</keyword>
</DOC>