<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03026517</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to test whether it is safe to give phenformin with the standard drug combination of dabrafenib + trametinib. The combination of dabrafenib plus trametinib is a standard treatment for patients with metastatic melanoma whose melanoma has a mutation in a gene called BRAF.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Trial of Phenformin in Combination With Dabrafenib and Trametinib for Patients With BRAF-mutated Melanoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trametinib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dabrafenib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Phenformin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>AJCC (2009) stage IV melanoma, or stage III melanoma not curable by surgery and which is progressing. Patients must have at least 1 target lesion measurable by RECIST 1.1 criteria. The melanoma must harbor an activating BRAF V600 mutation. Prior therapy with a BRAF and/or MEK inhibitor is allowed in the doseescalation phase only. However, patients who discontinued previous RAF inhibitor due to intolerance of the drug rather than due to progression will not be eligible. Histologic proof of melanoma reviewed and confirmed by the treating institution. The melanoma must have a documented BRAFV600E or BRAFV600K mutation by genotyping or IHC12 performed by a CLIA certified laboratory. At MSK, the Diagnostic Molecular Pathology laboratory has developed and implemented a targeted capturebased nextgeneration DNA sequencing assay, MSKIMPACTTM, to profile all proteincoding exons and selected introns from 410 oncogenes and tumor suppressor genes in formalinfixed paraffin embedded tissues (Cheng, D.T., et al., J Mol Diagn, 2015. 17(3): p. 25164). MSKIMPACTTM has been approved by the NY State Department of Health to be run as a clinical assay in the CLIAcompliant Diagnostic Molecular Pathology laboratory. MSKIMPACTTM is capable of detecting mutations, copy number alterations, and structural variations. BRAF Exon15 was captured by the MSKIMPACTTM panel and the c.1799T&gt;A (p.V600E) mutation was fully validated as per NYS requirements. Detailed results of the validation of this mutation were included in the validation package submitted to NY State Department of Health. At MGH, samples will be tested using a multiplex polymerase chain reaction (PCR) technology called Anchored Multiplex PCR (AMP) for single nucleotide variant (SNV) and insertion/deletion (indel) detection in genomic DNA using next generation sequencing (NGS). Briefly, genomic DNA was isolated from a formalinfixed paraffin embedded tumor specimen is sheared with the Covaris M220 instrument, followed by endrepair, adenylation, and ligation with an adapter. A sequencing library targeting hotspots and exons in 39 genes (including BRAF, exons 11 and 15) is generated using two heminested PCR reactions. Illumina MiSeq 2 x 147 base pairedend sequencing results are aligned to the hg19 human genome reference using BWAMEM (Li H and Durbin R. Bioinformatics 2009;25(14):175460). MuTect (Cibulskis K, et al. Nat Biotechnol 2013;31(3):2139) and a laboratorydeveloped insertion/deletion analysis algorithm are used for SNV and indel variant detection, respectively. This assay has been validated to detect SNV and indel variants at 5% allelic frequency or higher in target regions with sufficient read coverage. This test was developed, and its performance characteristics were determined by the MGH Center for Integrated Diagnostics. Patients must be adequately recovered from surgery, radiation therapy, or any surgical complications prior to enrollment. Age ≥ 18 years old. ECOG performance status of 02. The ability to swallow pills and otherwise follow the protocol. Patients with treated CNS metastases will be eligible if not symptomatic and if the CNS disease has been stable for at least 6 weeks and the patient requires ≤ the equivalent of 2 mg/day of dexamethasone. Patients must have adequate organ and marrow function as defined below: Absolute neutrophil count ≥1.5 K/mcL Platelets ≥100 K/mcL Hemoglobin ≥ 9.0 g/dL Total bilirubin ≤ 1.2 X institutional upper limit of normal (ULN) ≤ 3.0 X institutional ULN if the patient has Gilbert's Syndrome AST (SGOT) and ALT (SGPT) ≤ 1.2 X institutional ULN Creatinine ≤ 1.4 mg/dl Hgb A1c ≤ 5.7%, or 5.86.5% with a normal fasting glucose Type 1 or Type II diabetes, or Hgb A1c &gt;6.5%. A history of renal failure (unless recovered for at least 6 months), lactic acidosis, recurrent or severe hypoglycemia, or significant chronic obstructive lung disease. Patients will not be excluded for reversible episodes of elevated creatinine due to hypovolemia. Acute or chronic liver or renal disease. Concurrent use of hypoglycemic agents or any systemic therapy for melanoma. Palliative limitedfield radiation therapy will be allowed Current use of a prohibited medication while on dabrafenib/trametinib Presence of conditions that will interfere significantly with the absorption of drugs. A history of known glucose6phosphate dehydrogenase (G6PD) deficiency. Pregnant women and lactating women A prior or concurrent metastatic second malignancy within 3 years, even if it does not require active therapy. For example, patients with a concomitant indolent Bcell malignancies will not be eligible. Patients with a prior resected insitu or stage I malignancy felt to be cured will be eligible. Other uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements. New York Heart Association class ≥2 will be an exclusion criterion. QTc interval &gt; 500 msec, unless a bundle branch block is also present. Patients with brain metastases unless they meet the criteria of section 6.1.8. In the dose expansion phase of the trial, prior treatment with a BRAF inhibitor will be an exclusion criterion. Inclusion of Women and Minorities: Both men and women, and members of all races and ethnic groups are eligible for this trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Phenformin</keyword>
	<keyword>Dabrafenib</keyword>
	<keyword>Trametinib</keyword>
	<keyword>BRAF</keyword>
	<keyword>15-318</keyword>
</DOC>