<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02995564</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is investigating the development of a social skills training program for adults with Asperger's Syndrome or high-functioning autism, ages 18 to 35 years. The Principal Investigator for this study is Dr. Michael Murray, the director of the Autism Studies Division at the Penn State Hershey Medical Center. The purpose of this study is to adapt a social skills training program to address and enhance the social skills of adults with Asperger's Syndrome and high-functioning autism.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Multi-Media Social Skills Project for Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>During group study visits, a group of six young adults with Asperger's Syndrome or high-functioning autism will meet weekly for about 90 minutes. The purpose of the group sessions is to work on everyday social skills such as initiating and maintaining conversations, establishing friendships, and dealing with situations such as job interviews and dating. A generalization session will be held every week after the group therapy session with same-age peers who have been screened to participate in the study. The purpose of including peers in the class is to give young adults with Asperger's syndrome and high-functioning autism a chance to practice the social skills learned in the group study visit with a peer group. Study participants will be paired with a typically developing peer for an outing in the community to a nearby restaurant or shop or an in-class exercise such as a mock job interview.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Autistic Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Autism Spectrum Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Child Development Disorders, Pervasive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Between 18 and 35 years of age Must be a Pennsylvania resident A primary diagnosis of Asperger's Syndrome or highfunctioning autism, as confirmed by the SRS2 A verbal IQ of 85 or above on the Kaufman Brief Intelligence Test, Second Edition English as primary language spoken Ability to fluently speak in full sentences A significant language delay Difficulty with aggression directed at peers A primary thought disorder A secondary disorder of anxiety or depression so severe as to prevent the individual's participation in the treatment A current high school student at start of intervention Low social motivation demonstrated through formalized assessment and/or by responses given to screening interview</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Social Skills</keyword>
	<keyword>Asperger's</keyword>
	<keyword>High-functioning autism</keyword>
	<keyword>Young adults</keyword>
</DOC>