<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00687362</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Middle Eastern subjects with moderate-to-severe chronic plaque psoriasis will be administered infusions of infliximab (Remicade) at 5 mg/kg of body weight at Weeks 0, 2, 6, 14, and 22. The safety and efficacy of infliximab monotherapy will be evaluated.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate Remicade (Infliximab) in Moderate-to-Severe Chronic Plaque Psoriasis in the Middle Eastern Population (Study P04528)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Psoriasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Infliximab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>18 years or older, either gender, and any race. Psoriasis affecting &gt;=5% of body surface, PASI score &gt;=10 (maximum score 72). History of plaque psoriasis for &gt;6 months. Informed written consent. Refractory to other antipsoriasis agents (topical corticosteroids, phototherapy UVa [PUVA], or systemic therapy). Negative chest xray and purified protein derivative (PPD) within 1 month. Understand and be able to adhere to dosing and visit schedules. Screening laboratory tests must meet protocolspecified criteria. Women and men of childbearing potential must be using adequate birth control measures and should continue such precautions for 6 months after last infusion of infliximab. Pregnant, nursing, or planned pregnancy within 6 months after last scheduled treatment. Used topical corticosteroids in previous 14 days or systemic therapy (phototherapy UVb [UVB], PUVA, cyclosporine, methotrexate) in previous 28 days, or received treatment with antitumor necrosis factor (TNF)alpha monoclonal antibodies, human or murine immunoglobulins, TNFalpha receptor fusion proteins, or other bioengineered fusion proteins. Received previous immunobiologics. Have HIV, hepatitis B or C. Recently transplanted (exception corneal transplant &gt;3 months prior to first infusion) or known malignancy or history of malignancy within previous 5 years (exception basal or squamous cell carcinoma of skin that has been treated with no evidence of recurrence). Concurrent medications that are not permitted. congestive heart failure (CHF) Use of cyclosporine or tacrolimus within 4 weeks prior to Screening. Use of intramuscular (IM), intravenous (IV), or oral corticosteroids within 4 weeks prior to Screening. Treatment with any investigational drug within 3 months prior to Screening. Allergy to murine proteins. Serious infections (hepatitis, pneumonia, pyelonephritis) in previous 3 months. History of active tuberculosis (TB) requiring treatment within previous 3 years, or history of opportunistic infections (herpes zoster) within 2 months of Screening. Current signs or symptoms of severe, progressive or uncontrolled renal, hepatic, hematologic, endocrine, pulmonary, cardiac, neurological or cerebral disease. Current signs or symptoms of other severe uncontrolled disease which in investigator's opinion would put the subject at an unacceptable risk. History of current alcohol or drug abuse. Not observed designated washout periods for any of the prohibited medications in protocol.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>