<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00687713</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is to assess the efficacy of bupropion in reducing methamphetamine use in subjects with methamphetamine dependence who report using methamphetamine 29 or less days during the 30 days prior to the start of signing consent.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase 2, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Trial of Bupropion for Methamphetamine Dependence</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary objective of this study is to assess the efficacy of bupropion in reducing methamphetamine use in subjects with methamphetamine dependence who report using methamphetamine 29 or less days during the 30 days prior to signing consent. Secondary objectives included but were not limited to: assessing the success or failure to achieve abstinence (confirmed by at least two methamphetaminenegative urines and no methamphetamine-positive urines) each week during the last two weeks (Weeks 11 and 12) for subjects using methamphetamine 18 or less days during the 30 days prior to signing consent, assessing the safety of bupropion in this study population, assessing other measures of efficacy of bupropion in reducing methamphetamine use or craving, and other psychological assessments of methamphetamine dependence. It is hypothesized that bupropion, compared to placebo, would be associated with an increase in the proportion of subjects who achieved abstinence (confirmed by at least two methamphetamine-negative urines and no methamphetaminepositive urines) each week during the last two weeks (Weeks 11 and 12) for non-daily users.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Methamphetamine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bupropion</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Must have a DSMIV diagnosis of methamphetamine dependence as determined by MINI Must have at least 1 amphetamine or methamphetamine positive urine specimen after the start of screening and before randomization or provide information to verify recent use if a positive urine sample can't be obtained Must report using methamphetamine for 29 days or less during the 30 day period prior signing consent using the timeline followback method Must be willing and able to comply with study procedures Must be able to verbalize and understand consent forms and provide written informed consent Must be seeking treatment for methamphetamine dependence Please contact study site for more information</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>