<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02323334</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study involves single and multiple doses of LY3202626 and will evaluate the effects of LY3202626 on the body. There will be 4 parts to this study. In Parts A and B, single increasing doses of LY3202626 will be given in capsule form. Part A will also include itraconazole given orally as a solution. Part A will last approximately 8-12 weeks. Part B will last approximately 5-6 weeks. In Parts C and D, participants will be dosed multiple days with the study drug. Part C will last approximately 11-14 weeks. Part D will last approximately 11-14 weeks and participants must have Alzheimer's Disease. Participants may only enroll in one part.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of LY3202626 in Healthy Participants and Participants With Alzheimer's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Itraconazole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydroxyitraconazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>For Parts A, B, and C, are overtly healthy males or females (nonchildbearing potential), as determined by medical history and physical examination Have a body mass index (BMI) of 18 to 32 kilograms per square meter (kg/m^2) For Part D, present with Mild Cognitive Impairment (MCI) due to Alzheimer's Disease (AD) or mild to moderate AD Have venous access sufficient to allow for blood sampling Are reliable and willing to make themselves available for the duration of the study and are willing to follow study procedures and research unit policies Taking overthecounter or prescription medication with the exception of vitamins or minerals Smoke more than 10 cigarettes per day Are unwilling or unable to refrain from eating any food or drinking any beverage containing grapefruit or grapefruit juice for at least 2 weeks prior to first dose until completion of the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>