<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02323464</DOC>
	<brief_summary>300 patients with colorectal cancer will be investigated before surgery and 60 of them will also be investigated in the same manner after surgery. Investigations will include polysomonographic sleep apnea recordings during one night, lung function measurements, blood gas samples and a questionnaire, but only before surgery including questions on sleep, sleep apnea, lung disorders. Outcome: side effects of surgery and mortality rate, association with cancer type. Prevalence of sleep apnea, sleep quality, hypoxemia and lung function before and after surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prevalence of Sleep Apnea in Patients Undergoing Surgery for Colorectal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Group 1. Inclusion: 240 patients with colorectal cancer scheduled for surgery. Exclusion: Dementia, CPAP treated sleep apnea Methods: Patients are investigaged before surgery with Lung-function measurements, blood-gas sample, questionnaire, Overnight polysomnographic sleep apena recordings including oro-nasal airflow, thoraco-abdominal respiration belts, chin-EMG, EOG, EEG, ECG (V5) and body position. Outcome variables: complications of surgery including anastomosis insuficiency and wound infections. Short and long term mortality, Sleep apnea, hypxoia, hyprecapnia and effect on lungfunction (VC, FEV1). Detailed morphologic analysis of cancer type. Group 2. Inclusion: 35 patients with colorectal cancer scheduled for open surgery, Exclusion: Dementia, CPAP treated sleep apnea Methods: Patients are investigaged before and 2 days after surgery with Lung-function measurements, blood-gas sample, questionnaire (only before surgery), Overnight polysomnographic sleep apena recordings including oro-nasal airflow, thoraco-abdominal respiration belts, chin-EMG, EOG, EEG, ECG (V5) and body position. Outcome variables: Effect on sleep apnea, sleep parameters, blood-gas and lungfunction before and after surgery. Complications of surgery including anastomosis insuficiency and wound infections. Short and long term mortality. Detailed morphologic analysis of cancer type. Group 3. Inclusion: 25 patients with colorectal cancer scheduled for laparoscopic or robot surgery. Exclusion: Dementia, CPAP treated sleep apnea Methods: Patients are investigaged before and 2 days after surgery with Lung-function measurements, blood-gas sample, questionnaire (only before surgery), Overnight polysomnographic sleep apena recordings including oro-nasal airflow, thoraco-abdominal respiration belts, chin-EMG, EOG, EEG, ECG (V5) and body position. Outcome variables: Effect on sleep apnea, sleep parameters, blood-gas and lungfunction before and after surgery. Complications of surgery including anastomosis insuficiency and wound infections. Short and long term mortality. Detailed morphologic analysis of cancer type.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Apnea</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Apnea Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anoxia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients scheduled for surgery of colorectal cancer Dementia, CPAP treatment for obstructive sleep apnea</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>