<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02518152</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The present study is designed to evaluate the combined efficacy of Platelet Rich Fibrin (PRF) and 1% Alendronate (ALN) with open flap debridement (OFD) in treatment of intrabony defects in chronic periodontitis patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Platelet Rich Fibrin+1% Alendronate in Treatment of Chronic Periodontitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Background: Platelet-rich fibrin (PRF) is a second-generation platelet concentrate, act as reservoirs of growth factors and cytokines which are the key factors for regeneration of the bone and maturation of the soft tissue. Alendronate (ALN), a potent member of bisphosphonate group is known to promote tissue regeneration by inhibiting osteoclastic bone resorption and promoting osteoblastogenesis. The present study was designed to evaluate the combined efficacy of PRF and 1% ALN with open flap debridement (OFD) in treatment of intrabony defects in chronic periodontitis patients. Methods: Ninety patients with single defects were categorized into three groups: OFD alone, OFD with PRF,OFD with PRF+1% ALN. Clinical parameters; site specific plaque index (PI), modified sulcus bleeding index (mSBI), probing depth (PD), clinical attachment level (CAL) and gingival marginal level (GML) were recorded at baseline before surgery and 9 months post-operatively. Percentage radiographic intra-bony defect depth reduction (IBD) was evaluated at baseline and 9 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alendronate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria Presence of 3wall IBD ≥3 mm deep (distance between alveolar crest and base of the defect on an Intraoral Periapical Radiograph [IOPA]) along with an interproximal probing depth (PD) ≥5 mm after phase I therapy (scaling and root planing[SRP]) in asymptomatic teeth. Aggressive Periodontitis patients; Systemic conditions known to affect the periodontal status; medications known to affect the outcomes of periodontal therapy; Hematological disorders and insufficient platelet count (&lt;200,000/mm3); Pregnancy/lactation; Smoking and tobacco use in any form Immunocompromised individuals. Those having unacceptable oral hygiene (plaque index27 [PI] &gt;1.5) after reevaluation of Phase I therapy . Teeth with furcation involvement, nonvital teeth, carious teeth indicated for restorations and mobility of at least grade II were also excluded.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>