<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02518672</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Monoglyceride of DHA (DHA-MAG) is a lipid compound for which intestinal absorption would increase the ratio DHA / arachidonic acid (AA) and promote the synthesis of specific metabolites involved in the resolution of inflammation. The PREMDIC project, initiated at the Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Sherbrooke, is a randomized double-blind study for people with cystic fibrosis (CF) and aims to evaluate whether daily supplementation monoglyceride of DHA (a fatty acid omega-3 family) will reduce lung inflammation and improve pulmonary function.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pro-resolving Effect of MAG-DHA in Cystic Fibrosis (PREMDIC)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The goal of the study is: To investigate the efficacity of oral administration of MAG-DHA to increase DHA bioavailability and reduce lung inflammation of patients with cystic fibrosis The specific objectives of the project are : - Determine the effect of MAG-DHA on lipid membranes of the blood mononuclear cells. - Evaluate the effect of MAG-DHA on lung inflammation (determination of Human leukocyte elastase and alpha1 antitrypsin complexes : pHLE). For this study, 20 cystic fibrosis patients are recruited. Patients are divided into 2 groups of 10 and received a daily dose equivalent to 3 g of placebo (sunflower oil) or MAG-DHA. The project takes place over a period of 3 months and patients must travel to the research center for a total of five visits including recruitment. For the 2 groups, DHA ratio / AA is measured in membranes of mononuclear cells. Forced expiratory volume in 1 second (FEV1) is determined and pHLE complexes are detected in plasma as a marker of inflammation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cystic Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. forced expiratory volume in 1 second (FEV1) between 30 90%. 2. no respiratory exacerbations during the last 2 weeks before the start of the study 3. not have clotting problems or a history of bleeding diathesis 4. patients with liver function abnormalities are included in the study 1. pregnant women or those not using contraception. 2. known allergy to fish and / or seafood.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>