<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02518464</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a prospective, open-label, single-arm pilot study treating 40 subjects to assess the hypothesis that P2Y, G protein-coupled 12 (P2Y12) inhibition with Brilinta/ticagrelor (90 mg PO twice a day) reduces episodic and/or chronic migraine headache symptoms in patients with right to left shunt. Headache frequency while on Brilinta/ticagrelor will be compared with the documented baseline for each subject. If the Brilinta/ticagrelor therapy was effective (&gt; 50% reduction in monthly headache days), the subject could elect to continue therapy for an additional two months (56 days), while continuing to complete daily headache logs.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ticagrelor Therapy for RefrACTORy Migraine Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Migraine headaches are poorly understood, and can be severely debilitating. Many types of drugs have been tried in migraine sufferers including anti-depressants, anti-seizure medications, blood pressure medicines and others. The investigators have shown that in a small number of patients, a certain type of blood thinner (Clopidogrel) can reduce or eliminate migraine headaches in patients who also have a hole in the heart wall that allows flow from the right side of the heart to the left. Ticagrelor is a blood thinning drug which works in the same way as the clopidogrel, but is broken down by the body differently and thus allows everyone to use it. The investigators wish to test this medication to see if it works as well, or better than the clopidogrel.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Headache</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Migraine Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ticagrelor</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adenosine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>At least one year history of Episodic or Chronic migraine headache symptoms At least 6 headache days per month Subject able to complete online daily headache log Inability to understand the study or history of noncompliance with medical advice Currently taking a P2Y12 inhibitor Known hypersensitivity to Brilinta/ticagrelor History of stroke/transient ischemic attack (TIA) in the previous 6 months Active bleeding from any site Active peptic ulcer disease or upper gastrointestinal (GI) bleeding within six (6) months Migraine onset after 50 years of age Renal impairment: Creatinine Clearance &lt; 60 cc/min Severe hepatic impairment with total bilirubin &gt; 3.0 mg/dL Thrombocytopenia with platelet count &lt; 100,000 / ul History of intracranial hemorrhage Contraindications to blood thinner therapy or history of major bleeding episode while taking blood thinner therapy Need for chronic oral anticoagulation therapy (i.e. Atrial Fibrillation) Need for chronic antiplatelet therapy (i.e. drugeluting (DE) Stent), including daily aspirin use Need for daily nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drug (NSAID) use Need for daily carbamazepine therapy or other strong CYP3A inhibitors or potent CYP3A inducers Need for simvastatin or lovastatin greater than 40 mg daily Symptomatic bradycardia or syncope Pregnancy or currently breastfeeding, or plan to become pregnant during the study period Planned surgery during the study timeframe Previously implanted patent foramen ovale (PFO), atrial septal defect (ASD), pacemaker, inferior vena cava filter, or left atrial appendage closure device</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>headache</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic</keyword>
	<keyword>migraine</keyword>
	<keyword>right to left shunt</keyword>
</DOC>