<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02777437</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary Outcome Measures: Disease free survival Secondary Outcome Measures: Overall survival Adverse events (Mortality, morbidity) The proportion of completion of Laparoscopic Surgery Estimated Enrollment: Oct, 2016 Study Start Date: Oct, 2016 Estimated Study Completion Date: Oct, 2019 Estimated Primary Completion Date: Oct, 2021 Groups/Cohorts 1. Laparoscopic surgery for T4 colon cancers 2. Neoadjuvantive chemotherapy + Laparoscopic surgery for T4 colon cancers</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Laparoscopic Surgery VS Laparoscopic Surgery + Neoadjuvant Chemotherapy for T4 Tumor of the Colon Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Investigators' previous studies indicated that laparoscopic surgery is feasible in T4 colon cancers with comparable clinical and oncologic outcomes. Laparoscopy may be considered as an alternative approach for T4 colon cancers with the advantage of faster recovery. The survival outcome of T4 colon cancers still dismays clinicians and patients. Preoperative chemotherapy is an attractive concept for locally advanced colon cancer. Optimal systemic therapy at the earliest possible opportunity may be more effective at eradicating distant metastases than the same treatment given after the delay and immunological stress of surgery. Besides, the shrinkage of primary tumor before surgery may reduce the risk of incomplete surgical excision and the risk of shedding of tumor cells during surgery. The aim of the present study is to compare the short-and long-term survival outcomes between laparoscopic surgery alone and laparoscopic surgery with 4 cycles of neoadjuvant chemotherapy for T4 colon cancer as well as the mortality and the morbidity. The number of patients, which needs to get power of 80%, is 1960. The average numbers of patients needs to reach approximately 200, and that of surgical centers needs to reach 10. Arrangements in the preoperative, intraoperative and postoperative period will be in complete accordance with the usual care of the center. The baseline demographics and conditions as well as the perioperative items and the postoperative occurrences will be recorded through a prior designed e-questionnaire. Globally,the disease free survival rate (chemotherapy and surgery), mortality (chemotherapy and surgery), the morbidity (chemotherapy and surgery) and the proportion of completion of laparoscopic surgery of the two surgical strategies will be analized and compared.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Colonic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Able to provide written informed consent Histologically confirmed diagnosis of colon carcinoma CT or MRI verified as T4 colon cancer without involvement of other organs. Without multiple lesions other than carcinoma in situ Tumor size &lt; 8 cm No bowel obstruction Sufficient organ function No history of gastrointestinal surgery 18 years of age or older Performance Status (ECOG) 0, 1 or 2, life expectancy &gt; 12 weeks Operable patients Completion of neoadjuvant systemic chemotherapy Women who are pregnant (confirmed by serum bHCG in women of reproductive age) or breast feeding No intention to finish neoadjuvantive systemic therapy Unstable or uncompensated respiratory or cardiac disease Serious active infections Hypersensitivity to capecitabine/fluorouracil or oxaliplatin Stomatitis or ulceration in the mouth or gastrointestinal tract Severe diarrhea Peripheral sensory neuropathy with functional impairment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Colonic Neoplasms</keyword>
	<keyword>Laparoscopic Surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>Neoadjuvant chemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>T4</keyword>
</DOC>