<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02777190</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to study if misoprostol administered orally is at least as effective as misoprostol administered vaginally for cervical ripening and the induction of labor. The main purpose is to show that oral misoprostol administration is non-inferior to vaginal misoprostol administration with respect to the time interval from misoprostol administration to onset of active phase of labor. The study is a non-inferiority, prospective randomized controlled trial comparing oral misoprostol given as 25 mcg every 2 hours versus vaginal misoprostol given as 25 mcg every 4 hours.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Comparison of Oral Misoprostol and Vaginal Misoprostol for Cervical Ripening and Induction of Labor</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Misoprostol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Pregnant Female Patients greater than or equal to 18 years of age 2. Induction of labor for a single live intrauterine pregnancy 3. Greater than or equal to 37 weeks gestational age 4. Cephalic presentation 5. 20 minute reassuring fetal heart rate (reactive nonstress test (NST)) 6. Bishop score based on sterile vaginal exam of less than or equal to 6, for which the cervical dilation is less than or equal to 2 cm. 7. Equal to 3 or less uterine contractions over 10 minutes 1. Previous uterine scar 2. Contraindication to vaginal delivery 3. Use of magnesium sulfate during administration of misoprostol 4. Nonreassuring fetal heart tones 5. Premature rupture of membranes 6. Uterine tachysystole (greater than 5 contractions in 10 minutes averaged over 30 minutes) 7. Suspected intrauterine growth restriction 8. Fetal anomalies 9. Contraindication to misoprostol (history of allergy to prostaglandins, glaucoma)</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>misoprostol</keyword>
	<keyword>cytotec</keyword>
	<keyword>cervical ripening</keyword>
	<keyword>labor, induced</keyword>
	<keyword>active labor</keyword>
</DOC>