<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00384319</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if the Life Recovery Systems Thermosuit(R) System is able to quickly and conveniently cool patients who are comatose after resuscitation from cardiac arrest.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pilot Clinical Study of the LRS ThermoSuit™ System in Post Arrest Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary purpose of this study is to clinically evaluate the use of a new cooling device (the LRS ThermoSuit(R) System) to cool patients who are comatose following resuscitation from cardiac arrest. This device cools by circulating cold water directly against the skin of the patient. Cooling to a state of mild hypothermia (32 to 34 degrees C, maintained for 12 to 24 hours) is recognized by the American Heart Association, European Resuscitation Council, and the Canadian Association of Emergency Care Physicians as a promising therapy for such patients, and is likely to be most effective if administered quickly following resuscitation. It is hypothesized that this new device will cool patients much more quickly than by historical means. Patients will be monitored for physiologic parameters such as body temperature during the cooling therapy, and will be tracked for neurological outcomes following treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Arrest</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Cardiac arrest prior to or during hospital admission, with restoration/return of spontaneous circulation (ROSC). Initial (preresuscitation) cardiac rhythm of ventricular fibrillation, nonperfusing ventricular tachycardia, pulseless electrical activity, or asystole. Estimated or known age &gt; 18 years. Intubation, ventilation and placement of esophageal probe. Persistent neurologic dysfunction i.e. comatose upon enrollment [GCS ≤ 8]. Height greater than 188 cm. Elbowtoelbow width greater than 60 cm (as measured above the supine patient). Core temperature less than 35°C after ROSC (as measured at the tympanic membrane, esophagus, sublingual space,nasopharynx, or central blood vessel). Comatose state before the cardiac arrest due to the administration of drugs that depress the central nervous system. Known pregnancy. Response to verbal commands after ROSC (but before enrollment). Known terminal illness that preceded the arrest. Known enrollment in another study of a device, drug, or biologic. Major trauma or other comorbidity requiring urgent surgery. Improving neurologic status. &gt; 4 hours since return of spontaneous circulation. Unknown time of arrest. Severe or known coagulopathy (with active bleeding). Hemodynamic instability despite vasopressors (SBP &lt; 90 mmHg or MAP &lt; 60 mmHg for &gt; 30 minutes after ROSC and before enrollment).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>resuscitation</keyword>
	<keyword>hypothermia</keyword>
</DOC>