<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00384488</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective for this pilot project is to determine the feasibility and effectiveness of the Interactive Voice Response protocol (IVR) on physical activity and eating behaviors in a group men and women who have been identified by their physician as being pre-diabetic. We hypothesize that participants receiving the IVR follow-up will have greater positive changes in their physical activity and eating behaviors when compared to those who receive only the standard-care pre-diabetes class.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Automated Diabetes Prevention Program</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients diagnosed with pre-diabetes present a unique opportunity for health care providers to implement preventive practices. Behavioral intervention strategies that target weight reduction or maintenance and increased fitness not only provide exceptional cardiovascular benefits, but also play an important role in delayed development or prevention of type 2 diabetes mellitus (DM). This study was designed to determine the feasibility and effectiveness of automated telephone support calls targeting physical activity and healthful eating as strategies for weight loss for patients with pre-diabetes. Participants with pre-diabetes who participated in a 90-minute diabetes prevention class were consented to participate in this behavioral study and were then randomly assigned to receive automated telephone support targeting physical activity and nutrition weight loss strategies or to a no-contact control group. Objective physical activity (accelerometer), self-reported dietary intake, and body weight were assessed at baseline and at 3-months follow-up.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prediabetic State</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glucose Intolerance</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female KaiserPermanente of Colorado members age 18 and above who have been diagnosed with prediabetes and who have enrolled in a clinically indicated prediabetes class. Subjects must be English speaking and have a telephone Pregnant females Enrollment in another research study involving diabetes or weight management during the time of the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2006</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetes mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>Weight control</keyword>
	<keyword>Healthy eating</keyword>
	<keyword>Physical Activity</keyword>
</DOC>