<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01255280</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to research a new behavioral treatment to reduce sexual risk-taking in men who have sex with men (MSM) who abuse crystal methamphetamine (crystal meth), and are at risk for HIV acquisition. This study proposes using a treatment based on our original pilot study that incorporates risk reduction and behavioral activation therapy. In order to help learn what types of treatment programs best help individuals who abuse crystal meth and engage in sexual risk-taking, we will compare our treatment to a control group. The treatment group will receive therapy incorporating behavioral risk reduction counseling with behavioral activation therapy to treat depression, helping individuals reengage in their life. The control group will receive the risk reduction counseling without the behavioral activation therapy. The current study hopes to explore the efficacy of this previous developed treatment in a two-arm pilot randomized controlled trial.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Behavioral Activation and HIV Risk Reduction for Men Who Have Sex With Men With Crystal Meth Abuse</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>1. To estimate, in a two-arm pilot randomized controlled trial (RCT), the effect size of the proposed intervention on reductions in sexual risk taking and crystal meth use. The primary outcome is the number of unprotected anal sex acts and a secondary outcome is reduction in crystal meth use episodes over the follow up period. 2. To explore the degree to which improvements in sexual risk taking are associated with the conceptual mediators of the effects of the intervention: reductions in crystal meth use and increases in pleasurable (but safe) activities, BAT skills, use of risk reduction skills, and reductions in depressed mood.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Methamphetamine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age: 18 years or older Selfreports as a man who has sex with men HIVuninfected and verifies serostatus at baseline (HIV antibody testing and positive tests will be confirmed by Western Blots; see Human Subjects for operational aspects) Meets DSMIV diagnostic criteria for crystal meth abuse/dependence Self reported unprotected anal intercourse—receptive or insertive—with a nonmonogamous male sexual partner, while concurrently using crystal meth (use of meth must be a few hours prior to, or during, sex) in the prior three months Unable to provide informed consent due to severe mental or physical illness, or substance intoxication at the time of interview Has lived in the greater Boston area for three months or less (as a means to enhance participant retention) Discovery of active suicidal ideation at the time of interview (these patients will be referred immediately for treatment, but may join the study when this is resolved)</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Crystal methamphetamine abuse</keyword>
	<keyword>Crystal methamphetamine dependence</keyword>
	<keyword>Sexual risk behavior</keyword>
	<keyword>Men who have sex with men (MSM)</keyword>
	<keyword>Behavioral activation</keyword>
</DOC>