<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02502786</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to find out what effect an antibody called Humanized 3F8 (Hu3F8) and a drug called GM-CSF have on the patient and whether it can keep the patient in remission longer and/or prevent recurrence of the disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Humanized Monoclonal Antibody 3F8 (Hu3F8) With Granulocyte-Macrophage Colony Stimulating Factor (GM-CSF) in the Treatment of Recurrent Osteosarcoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Osteosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients must have recurrent OS OS must be verified by histopathology review by the site's Department of Pathology. (Patients registered at MSKCC must have pathology confirmed by MSKCC Department of Pathology.) Patients must be in a ≥2nd complete remission as indicated by appropriate radiologic evaluations at the time of study entry. Patients must be older than 1 year of age and less than or equal to 40 years of age. Prior therapy: ≥3 weeks should have elapsed since last cytotoxic therapy, immunotherapy or radiation therapy. More than one week should have elapsed since major surgery. Adequate hematopoietic function defined as: Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 500/ul Absolute lymphocyte count ≥ 500/ul Platelet count ≥ 50,000/ul (transfusion independent) Adequate hepatic function as defined by: Total bilirubin of ≤ 1.5 times upper limit of normal (exception is made for patients with Gilbert's syndrome who may be considered eligible if total bilirubin is ≤ 3 times upper limit of normal). AST of ≤ 3 times upper limit of normal ALT of ≤ 3 times upper limit of normal Adequate renal function as defined by a serum creatinine of ≤ 1.5 times upper limit of normal Adequate cardiac function as defined by a shortening fraction of ≥ 28% or an ejection fraction ≥ 50% Adequate performance status as defined by ECOG score of ≤ 2 or Karnofsky/Lansky score ≥ 50% Prior treatment with other antiGD2 antibodies is allowed (prior treatment with hu3F8 is NOT allowed), but HAHA antibody titer must be ≤1300 Elisa units/mL Women of childbearing potential must be willing to practice an effective method of birth control while on treatment Signed informed consent indicating awareness of the investigational nature of this program Patients with OS in first complete remission. Presence of overt metastatic disease at any site. Active lifethreatening infection. Pregnant women or women who are breastfeeding. Inability to comply with protocol requirements.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>13 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Humanized Monoclonal Antibody 3F8 (Hu3F8)</keyword>
	<keyword>Granulocyte-Macrophage Colony Stimulating Factor (GM-CSF)</keyword>
	<keyword>15-096</keyword>
</DOC>