<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02502708</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a first-in-children phase 1 trial using indoximod, an inhibitor of the immune "checkpoint" pathway indoleamine 2,3-dioxygenase (IDO), in combination with temozolomide-based therapy to treat pediatric brain tumors. Using a preclinical glioblastoma model, it was recently shown that adding IDO-blocking drugs to temozolomide plus radiation significantly enhanced survival by driving a vigorous, tumordirected inflammatory response. This data provided the rationale for the companion adult phase 1 trial using indoximod (IND#120813) plus temozolomide to treat adults with glioblastoma, which is currently open (NCT02052648). The goal of this pediatric study is to bring IDO-based immunotherapy into the clinic for children with brain tumors. This study will provide a foundation for future pediatric trials testing indoximod combined with radiation and temozolomide in the up-front setting for patients with newly diagnosed central nervous system tumors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of the IDO Pathway Inhibitor, Indoximod, and Temozolomide for Pediatric Patients With Progressive Primary Malignant Brain Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Medulloblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gliosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ependymoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Temozolomide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dacarbazine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tryptophan</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Eligibility Criteria Age: 321 years. Group 1 or Group 3: histologically proven initial diagnosis of primary malignant brain tumor, excluding brain stem glioma, with no known curative treatment options. Group 2: histologically proven initial diagnosis of intracranial highgrade glioma (WHO grade III and IV), any relapsed / refractory ependymoma, or any relapsed / refractory medulloblastoma. MRI confirmation (with and without gadolinium contrast) of tumor progression or regrowth. Surgical debulking is permitted if clinically indicated, but should be followed with postoperative repeat of MRI. Patients must be able to swallow whole capsules. Patients with metastatic disease are eligible for enrollment. Patients may be on corticosteroids for management of elevated intracranial pressure The dose must be in a stable range or decreasing for at least 14 days. Lansky or Karnofsky performance status score must be &gt; 50%. Patients must have a life expectancy of 3 months. Creatinine &lt; 1.5times upper limit of ageadjusted normal ALT and AST &lt; 3times upper limit of normal Total bilirubin &lt; 1.5times upper limit of normal Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 750/μL Platelets ≥ 75,000/μL (transfusion independent) Hemoglobin ≥ 10 g/dL (transfusion independent) Seizure disorders must be well controlled on antiepileptic medication. Patients previously treated with temozolomide are eligible for enrollment. Patients must be 14 days from the administration of any investigational agent or prior cytotoxic therapy with the following exceptions: Temozolomide (allowed, regardless of time frame administered) 42 days from administration of antibodybased therapies (e.g., bevacizumab). Patients must be 9 months from the initial radiation fraction if they were previously treated with conventional fractionated radiation therapy and there is concern for pseudoprogression. Patients with prior therapy that included interstitial brachytherapy, Gliadel wafer, or stereotactic radiosurgery must have confirmation of progressive disease, rather than radiation necrosis, by PET scanning, Thallium scanning, MRI spectroscopy, or surgical documentation. Concurrent antineoplastic therapy: No investigational or commercial agents or therapies other than indoximod, temozolomide, and/or conformal radiation therapy may be administered with the intent to treat the patient's malignancy while they remain enrolled on this study. Sexually active female patients of childbearing age must agree to use two forms of contraception (hormonal and either barrier method of birth control or abstinence) prior to study entry and for the duration of study participation. Use of contraception and/or abstinence should continue for a minimum of 1 month after completion of the study. Female patients who are breastfeeding must agree to cease breastfeeding and switch to commercially available infant formula or other appropriate nutrition prior to study entry and for the duration of study participation, plus a minimum of 1 month after completion of the study. Sexually active male patients must agree to use barrier contraception (condoms) or abstinence prior to study entry and for the duration of study participation. Use of contraception and/or abstinence should continue for a minimum of 1 month after completion of the study. Patients and/or their parents or legal guardians must sign a written informed consent for treatment on this clinical study. Exclusion Criteria Patients with primary tumor in the brain stem, including diffuse intrinsic pontine glioma, are excluded. Patients who cannot swallow whole capsules are excluded Prior invasive malignancy, other than the primary central nervous system tumor, unless the patient has been disease free and off therapy for that disease for a minimum of 3 years Patients with baseline QTc interval of more than 470 msec at study entry, and patients with congenital long QTc syndrome. Active systemic infection requiring treatment, including any HIV infection or toxoplasmosis Other severe acute or chronic medical or psychiatric condition or laboratory abnormality that may increase the risk associated with study participation or study drug administration, or may interfere with the interpretation of study results, or in the judgment of the investigator would make the patient inappropriate for entry into this study Baseline QTc interval of more than 470 or congenital long QT syndrome Active autoimmune disease Pregnant women are excluded from this study, where pregnancy is confirmed by a positive serum hCG laboratory test (&gt; 5 mIU/mL); breastfeeding should be discontinued.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>glioblastoma multiforme</keyword>
	<keyword>glioma</keyword>
	<keyword>gliosarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>malignant brain tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>ependymoma</keyword>
	<keyword>medulloblastoma</keyword>
</DOC>