<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02482870</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators studied the correlation between the Mallampati classification and the Cormack-Lehane grades obtained with Macintosh and the King Vision video laryngoscopy in adult patients scheduled for general anesthesia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficiency of the King Vision Video Laryngoscope</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Securing the airway is essential in general anesthesia. Anesthetic problems related to airway management constitute 17% of closed claims, difficult intubation being the most common one with an occurrence rate of 5%. Problems like delayed intubation, misplaced tracheal tube, or airway trauma are frequently seen in outpatient settings and end up with either death or hypoxic brain damage. Therefore, preoperative visit should include detailed assessment of the airways according to clues of difficult intubation.Several studies compared the King Vision video laryngoscope with other laryngoscopes in manikins simulating difficult airway scenarios, and reported better glottic views. The investigators aimed to study the correlation between the Mallampati classification and the glottic views (Cormack-Lehane grade) obtained with Macintosh laryngoscopy, and the King Vision video laryngoscopy in adult patients scheduled for general anesthesia. Secondary outcomes will be successful intubation rate, time to obtain the best view, time to successful intubation, and complications related to laryngoscopy will be compared.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<criteria>scheduled for general anesthesia age higher than 18 years age lower than 60 years emergency surgery mouth opening less than 2 cm American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) score higher than 2 oropharyngeal anomaly glottic or supraglottic mass history of surgery due to oropharyngeal anomaly, glottic or supraglottic mass</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>