<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01544114</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A 6 month study of VIMOVO in adolescents aged 12-16 years with juvenile idiopathic Arthritis (JIA)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Safety Study of VIMOVO in Adolescents With Juvenile Idiopathic Arthritis (JIA)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A 6-month, Multicenter, Open-label, Safety Study of VIMOVO (250 mg/20 mg, 375 mg/20 mg, and 500 mg/20 mg Naproxen/Esomeprazole) in Adolescents Aged 12 to 16 Years, Inclusive, with Juvenile Idiopathic Arthritis (JIA)</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Juvenile</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Esomeprazole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Naproxen</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Parent or legal guardian is able to provide written informed consent and patient is able to provide written assent if appropriate. Male and female adolescents aged 12 to 16 years at the time of enrollment. Diagnosed with JIA, including all the ILAR JIA subtypes: oligoarthritis, polyarthritis (both RF+ and RF), psoriatic arthritis, enthesitisrelated arthritis,undifferentiated arthritis, and systemic arthritis. Based upon investigator judgment, it is determined appropriate for the patient to undergo 6 months of continuous treatment with VIMOVO. Body weight &gt;31 kg (68.2 lbs) and within the 5th to 95th percentile of body mass index for age. In systemic JIA patients, presence of systemic features (ie, fever, rheumatoid rash, serositis, lymphadenopathy, macrophage activation syndrome) within 6 months prior to start of study drug. Currently taking (ie, within 4 weeks prior to start of drug) naproxen &gt;20 mg/kg/day or &gt;1000 mg total daily dose. Hemoglobin ≤8.5 g/dL. Individuals who have cardiovascular or cerebrovascular disease, based on history or risk factors. Any significant hepatic, renal, pulmonary, ophthalmologic, neurologic, or any other medical conditions indicated by medical/surgical history, physical, or laboratory examination that might put the patient at greater risk during the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>16 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>