<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01544179</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the efficacy and safety of gefitinib in patients who have progressed on first line gefitinib, comparing continuing gefitinib in addition to cisplatin plus pemetrexed combination chemotherapy versus cisplatin plus pemetrexed combination chemotherapy alone.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of IRESSA Treatment Beyond Progression in Addition to Chemotherapy Versus Chemotherapy Alone</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A Phase III Randomised, Double blind, Placebo controlled, Parallel, Multicentre Study to Assess the Efficacy and Safety of continuing IRESSA 250 mg in addition to Chemotherapy versus Chemotherapy alone in Patients who have Epidermal Growth Factor Receptor (EGFR) Mutation Positive Locally advanced or Metastatic Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC) and have progressed on First Line IRESSA.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gefitinib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pemetrexed</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female patients aged 18 years or older (For Japan only male or female patients aged 20 years or older) Cytological or histological confirmation of NSCLC other than predominantly squamous cell histology with an activating EGFR TK mutation as determined locally Patients with documented 'acquired resistance' on first line gefitinib Patients suitable to start cisplatin based pemetrexed combination chemotherapy. Provision of informed consent prior to any study specific procedures. Prior chemotherapy or other systemic anticancer treatment (excluding gefitinib). Palliative bone radiotherapy must be completed at least 2 weeks before start of study treatment with no persistent radiation toxicity). Past medical history of interstitial lung disease, druginduced interstitial disease, radiation pneumonitis which required steroid treatment or any evidence of clinically active interstitial lung disease Other coexisting malignancies or malignancies diagnosed within the last 5 years, with the exception of basal cell carcinoma or cervical cancer in situ or completely resected intramucosal gastric cancer Any evidence of severe of uncontrolled systemic disease Treatment with an investigational drug within 4 weeks before randomization</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>130 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Non Small Cell Lung Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Gefitinib</keyword>
	<keyword>Pemetrexed</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment Beyond Progression</keyword>
</DOC>