<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00647998</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Numerous neuroprotectants have been effective when given prior to ischemic stroke in animals, yet they have all have failed when given after ischemic stroke in humans. A novel approach to ischemic neuroprotection is needed. Many patients who undergo cardiac, vascular, and neurosurgical procedures develop ischemic central nervous system (CNS) complications. These high risk surgeries present a unique opportunity to administer neuroprotectant medication prior to the injury, greatly increasing the likelihood that it will have a positive impact on outcomes. Patients undergoing descending thoracic aortic (DTA) and thoracoabdominal aortic (TAA) surgery have a particularly high rate of both brain and spine ischemia. In addition, these surgeries require placement of a lumbar cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) drain, allowing access to CSF in order to monitor markers of injury and penetration of medication into the CNS. We are performing a pilot dose finding trial of prophylactic darbepoetin alfa, a long-acting erythropoiesis medication with putative neuroprotectant properties, in patients undergoing DTA and TAA surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Darbepoetin Alfa for Ischemic Surgical Complications (DISC) Dose Finding Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Darbepoetin alfa</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Are men and women between the ages of 18 100 years old (inclusive) Require descending thoracic or thoracoabdominal aorta surgical repair Can provide informed consent Have a traumatic aortic dissection Have a baseline NIHSS &gt; 1 or modified Rankin Scale &gt; 1 Have a history of stroke or myocardial infarction within the past 30 days Have a preoperative hemoglobin &lt; 9 or &gt; 14 Have a history of polycythemia vera or essential thrombocytosis Have a history of hematologic malignancy Have a history of arterial or venous thrombosis in the past three months Have uncontrolled hypertension Have active malignancy requiring treatment Are receiving hemodialysis Are currently using recombinant human erythropoietin or darbepoetin alfa, or have an expectation to require these medications within 30 days of surgery. Have a known allergy to recombinant human erythropoietin or darbepoetin alfa Are pregnant or breastfeeding. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test (urine pregnancy test or serum betaHCG)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Surgical complications</keyword>
	<keyword>Spinal ischemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>Neuroprotection</keyword>
</DOC>