<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01259141</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Mycoplasma pneumoniae, an important pathogen of community acquired pneumonia,are becoming more and more resistant to macrolide. The study aim is to optimize anti-infection therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Optimization of Mycoplasm Pneumonia Antibiotic Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Mycoplasma pneumoniae was one of important atypical pathogens of community acquired pneumonia. As lack of cell wall, β-lactam medicines were invalid, however, macrolides, tetracyclines and quinolones were effective. But from 2001, many countries reported macrolide- resistant Mycoplasma pneumoniae. Typically, erythromycin was first-line antibiotic medicine. With the resistance increasing, Mycoplasm pneumonia treatment will become more and more difficult. Thus, optimization of Mycoplasm pneumonia antibiotic therapy is very important.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pleuropneumonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycoplasma Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia, Mycoplasma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Bacterial Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cephalosporins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Moxifloxacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibiotics, Antitubercular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Norgestimate, ethinyl estradiol drug combination</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Confirmed community acquired pneumonia 2. 60ys≥age≥18 ys 3. Respiratory symptom (cough accompanied by little or no sputum) 4. New infiltration showed by chest radiology(xray or CT) 5. Lung signs was not obvious 6. White blood cell&lt;10,000/mm3 7. Without underlying diseases or mild 1. Age&lt;18ys or &gt;60ys 2. Pregnancy or breastfeeding 3. Over one week after the onset of symptoms 4. HIV infection 5. Recent 90day hospitalized history(length of stay greater than 2 days) 6. Live in nursing homes or rehabilitation hospitals 7. Taken macrolides or quinolones medicines before enrollment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>macrolide- resistant Mycoplasma pneumoniae,</keyword>
	<keyword>Mycoplasm pneumonia antibiotic therapy</keyword>
</DOC>