<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01275742</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Heart failure (HF) affects 5 million people in the US and is the most common cause of hospitalization in elderly adults. One-third of patients who are hospitalized with HF have major depression. Depressed HF patients have double the rates of morbidity and/or mortality and worse health-related quality of life than non-depressed HF patients. The investigators previous pilot research suggests that a brief Cognitive Therapy (CT) intervention may improve short-term cardiac survival among depressed hospitalized HF patients compared to non-depressed HF patients who received usual care. Therefore, the investigators will conduct a larger study to evaluate the effects of the intervention on longer cardiac event-free survival, symptoms of depression, health-related quality of life, and stress levels in patients with HF. The investigators hypothesize that patients in the intervention group will experience longer cardiac event-free survival, lower levels of depressive symptom, better health-related quality of life, and lower salivary cortisol levels at follow-up than patients who receive usual care.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Helping Others Toward Positive Emotions in People With Heart Failure</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Admitted to the hospital with a primary or secondary diagnosis of congestive heart failure OR admitted to the hospital for cardiac reasons and has a history of chronic heart failure American College of Cardiology/ American Heart Association Stage C HF 21 years or older Coexisting terminal illness likely to be fatal within the next 12 months Endstage HF (defined as American College of Cardiology Stage D HF) Cognitive impairment that precludes the ability to give informed consent Active suicidality (defined choosing option 1, 2 or 3 on Item 9 of the PHQ9) History of the death of a spouse or child within the past month History of psychotic illness or bipolar illness Current alcohol dependence or other substance abuse NonEnglish speaking or possessing any other communication barrier</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Heart failure</keyword>
	<keyword>Depression</keyword>
	<keyword>Depressive symptoms</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Hospitalization</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality of life</keyword>
</DOC>