<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01275131</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if recombinant human hyaluronidase PH20 (rHuPH20) will change the exposure and action of approved insulin analogs when given by continuous subcutaneous insulin infusion (CSII) in participants with Type 1 diabetes mellitus (T1DM). This study is divided into Stage 1, 2, and 3. Stage 3 was started chronologically before Stage 2 and, prior to performing Stage 2, the Sponsor made the decision to terminate Stage 2. Stage 2 was not initiated due to a strategic business decision and termination was not based on safety or efficacy concerns. No participants were enrolled in Stage 2.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Randomized, Double-blind, Crossover, Pharmacokinetic (PK) and Glucodynamic (GD) Study of Continuous Subcutaneous Insulin Infusion (CSII) in Participants With Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus (T1DM)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin degludec, insulin aspart drug combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Aspart</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Long-Acting</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male or female aged 18 to 65 years, inclusive. Females of childbearing potential must use a standard and effective means of birth control for the duration of the study. 2. Nonsmoking participants with Type 1 diabetes mellitus (T1DM) treated with insulin for greater than or equal to 12 months. Nonsmoking means abstinence from cigarettes and cigars for 3 months and negative cotinine screening tests. 3. Body mass index (BMI) 18.0 to 35.0 kilograms per meter squared (kg/m^2), inclusive. 4. Glycosylated hemoglobin A1c (HbA1c) ≤10 % based on local laboratory results. 5. Fasting Cpeptide &lt;0.6 nanograms per milliliter (ng/mL). 6. Current treatment with insulin &lt;90 units per day (U/d). 7. Routine use of continuous subcutaneous insulin infusion (CSII) as the primary route of insulin administration. 8. Participant should be in good general health based on medical history and physical examination, without medical conditions that might prevent the completion of study drug infusions and assessments required in this protocol. 1. Known or suspected allergy to any component of any of the study drugs in this trial. 2. Previous enrollment in this trial (Exception: participants in Stage 1 are permitted to participate in Stage 2). 3. Use of drugs that may interfere with the interpretation of trial results or are known to cause clinically relevant interference with insulin action, glucose utilization, or recovery from hypoglycemia. Participants taking maintenance doses of blood thinners (eg, Coumadin or heparin) will be excluded. 4. Use of any longacting insulin injection within 72 hours of Stage 1 or Stage 3. 5. Recurrent major hypoglycemia or hypoglycemic unawareness, as judged by the Investigator. 6. Current addiction to alcohol or substances of abuse as determined by the Investigator. 7. Blood donation or phlebotomy (&gt;500 milliliters [mL]) within the previous 8 weeks of Screening. This applies both to new participants and to participants who have participated in Stage 1 and who wish to continue in Stage 2. 8. Pregnancy, breastfeeding, the intention of becoming pregnant, or not using adequate contraceptive measures (adequate contraceptive measures consist of sterilization, intrauterine device [IUD], oral or injectable contraceptives, or barrier methods). 9. Symptomatic gastroparesis. 10. Receipt of any investigational drug within 4 weeks of Stage 1 or Stage 2.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Insulin analog</keyword>
	<keyword>Type 1 diabetes mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacokinetic</keyword>
	<keyword>Glucodynamic</keyword>
	<keyword>Phase 1</keyword>
</DOC>