<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02061085</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Multicentre, prospective, non-controlled phase II clinical trial to evaluate the efficacy and tolerability of first line single agent Eribulin in patients with HER2-negative metastatic breast carcinoma previously exposed to taxanes for early stage. The primary objective of the study is to determine the median time to progression achieved with Eribulin. Other secondary objectives will be; overall response rate, clinical benefit rate, time to treatment progression, duration of response and toxicity profile.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Monotherapy With Eribulin In Her2 Negative Metastatic Breast Cancer as a First Line Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed metastatic breast cancer HER2 negative, stage IIIb/IV Previous history of early disease (stage IIIIb), surgically resected and treated with standard chemotherapy for at least 12 weeks at which included a taxane or ixabepilone Patients must have progressed in the 36 months after treatment with taxanes or ixabepilone. Age ≥ 18 years Given written informed consent Index of Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) of 0 or 1 Patients must have recovered from toxicities related with previous treatment (CTC ≥ 1) Measurable or evaluable disease (RECIST 1.1) Adequate bone marrow function Adequate hepatic function Adequate renal function Life expectancy ≥ 3 months Breast cancer patients initially diagnosed with local disease advanced or metastatic disease. Patients who have previously received cytotoxic therapy Hormone therapy permitted if the patients have interrupted it at least two weeks before the start of the study treatment. Major surgery or significant traumatic injury during the 4 weeks prior to study treatment or patients who may require major surgery during the assay. Brain metastases or leptomeningeal uncontrolled. Serious medical condition and / or not properly controlled (unstable angina, lung function severe impaired, uncontrolled diabetes, active serious infection,liver disease, HIV seropositivity, active bleeding diathesis) Other malignancies in the last three years, except: cervical carcinoma in situ, basal cell carcinoma or squamous cell skin carcinoma,that have been properly treated Patients who are pregnant or breastfeeding, or adults with reproductive capacity wich are not using effective contraception. Patients receiving chronic treatment with systemic corticosteroids or other immunosuppressive drugs (except corticosteroids with a daily dose equivalent to prednisone ≤ 20mg on a stable dose regimen one minimum of 4 weeks prior to study entry. Topical and inhaled corticosteroids are allowed Active alcoholism or drugs addiction documented. Prior history of noncompliance with medical regimens Patients who do not want or can not comply with the study protocol</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Breast Neoplasm Metastasis</keyword>
	<keyword>Receptor,HER-2</keyword>
	<keyword>Eribulin</keyword>
	<keyword>Furans, quetones</keyword>
	<keyword>Antimitotic agent</keyword>
</DOC>