<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02061800</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is a research study involving subjects who are diagnosed with a malignant disease, that has either failed standard therapy or is unlikely to be cured with standard non-transplant therapy, who will receive a peripheral blood stem cell transplant. A malignant disease includes the following: Chronic Myeloid Leukemia (CML) in chronic phase, accelerated phase or blast crisis; Acute Myelogenous Leukemia (AML); Myelodysplastic Syndrome (MDS); Juvenile Myelomonocytic Leukemia (JMML); Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia (ALL); or Lymphoma (Hodgkin's and Non-Hodgkin's) The purpose of this study is to learn more about the effects of CD34+ stem cell selection on graft versus host disease (GVHD) in children, adolescents and young adults. CD34+ stem cells are the cells that make all the types of blood cells in the body. GVHD is a condition that results from a reaction of transplanted donor T-lymphocytes (a kind of white blood cell) against the recipient's body and organs. Study subjects will be offered treatment involving the use of a Miltenyi CliniMacs CD34+ selection device to remove T-cells from a peripheral blood stem cell transplant in order to decrease the risk of acute and chronic GVHD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>CD34+ (Malignant) Stem Cell Selection for Patients Receiving Allogenic Stem Cell Transplant</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>CD34+ stem cells (the cells that make all the types of blood cells in the body) are selected (removed) from the donor's peripheral blood stem cells. In doing this, T-cells (a type of blood cell) are also removed. T-cells are the cells which are responsible for severe acute and chronic graft versus host disease (GVHD). GVHD is a condition that results from a reaction of the transplanted donor T-lymphocytes (a kind of white blood cell) against the body and organs. There are two forms: acute (early) and chronic (late). Acute GVHD may produce skin rashes, liver disease, diarrhea, and an increased risk of infection. Chronic GVHD can also appear in subjects without prior acute GVHD. Chronic GVHD may also produce skin rashes, liver disease, diarrhea and an increased risk of infection. Chronic GVHD may be mild and respond to agents which suppress the immune system, or it could be very severe. It may also last for over a year. Once this CD34 selection process is complete, the CD34+ stem cell AlloSCT is given to the recipient without most of the T-cells to see if this therapy will lessen the incidence and seriousness of graft versus host disease (GVHD). CD34+ stem cell selection AlloSCT has been studied in adults with malignant and non-malignant disease with successful engraftment and has shown some improvement in GVHD. We do not know if CD34+ stem cell selection will work to prevent severe GVHD in children, adolescents and young adults. Subjects are being offered this experimental treatment involving the use of a Miltenyi CliniMacs CD34+ selection device to remove T-cells from the peripheral blood stem cell transplant in order to decrease the risk of acute and chronic GVHD. There will be about 25 subjects participating in this study at Columbia University Medical Center. The purpose of this study is to learn more about the effects of CD34+ stem cell selection on GVHD in children, adolescents and young adults. The goals of this study are: - To determine how often acute GVHD occurs and how severe the acute GVHD is in the children, adolescents and young adults receiving CD34+ selection of their peripheral blood stem cell transplant from a family member or adult unrelated donor. - To determine how often primary graft failure and secondary graft failure occurs in the children, adolescents and young adults receiving a peripheral blood stem cell transplant from a family member or adult unrelated donor. - To see how quickly neutrophils (infection fighting white blood cells) will recover following CD34+ selection of their peripheral blood stem cell transplant from a family member or adult unrelated donor. - To see if the time for the immune system (the body's defense system) to recover will benefit from receiving CD34+ selection of their peripheral blood stem cell transplant from a family member or adult unrelated donor. - To see how often bacterial, viral, fungal and atypical mycobacteria (TB-like) infections will occur in the children, adolescents and young adults receiving CD34+ selection of their peripheral blood stem cell transplant from a family member or adult unrelated donor. Study specific requirements occur up to 2 years post-transplant, although the study team will collect data on the progress of subjects yearly until termination of the study to observe if subjects are responding to therapy and have no worsening GVHD.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myelodysplastic Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Preleukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Precursor Cell Lymphoblastic Leukemia-Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myelogenous, Chronic, BCR-ABL Positive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myelomonocytic, Juvenile</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tacrolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fludarabine phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thiotepa</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Melphalan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Busulfan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fludarabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alemtuzumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>General Eligibility (All Patients) Must be &lt; 22 years of age Diagnosed with a malignant disease Must be fully informed about their illness and the investigational nature of the study protocol (including foreseeable risks and possible side effects), and must sign an informed consent For unrelated donor: A human leukocyte antigen (HLA) 8/10, 9/10 or 10/10 matched unrelated adult donor (MUD) will be required for study entry For related donor: A 5/10, 6/10, 7/10, 8/10, 9/10 or 10/10 matched (or partially matched) family donor will be required for study entry Adequate renal function Adequate liver function Adequate cardiac function Adequate pulmonary function Patients with documented uncontrolled infection at the time of study entry are not eligible Females who are pregnant or breast feeding at the time of study entry are not eligible</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>22 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Unrelated donor transplant</keyword>
	<keyword>Allogenic Stem Cell Transplant</keyword>
	<keyword>Adult Bone Marrow Transplant</keyword>
	<keyword>Pediatric Bone Marrow Transplant</keyword>
	<keyword>Related donor transplant</keyword>
	<keyword>Haploidentical donor transplant</keyword>
	<keyword>Peripheral blood stem cell transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>Non-malignant disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Malignant disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Bone marrow failure syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Severe Aplastic Anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Severe Congenital Neutropenia</keyword>
	<keyword>Amegakaryocytic Thrombocytopenia</keyword>
	<keyword>Diamond-Blackfan Anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Schwachman Diamond Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Primary Immunodeficiency Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Histiocytic Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Familial Hemophagocytic Lymphocytosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Lymphohistiocytosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Macrophage Activation Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Langerhans Cell Histiocytosis (LCH)</keyword>
	<keyword>Hemoglobinopathies</keyword>
	<keyword>Reduced-Intensity Conditioning</keyword>
	<keyword>Sickle Cell Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Sickle Cell-beta-thalassemia</keyword>
</DOC>