<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02061813</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to determine the irritation potential of repeat applications of abametapir lotion on normal skin.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dermal Safety Study to Evaluate Potential Irritation of Abametapir Lotion</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This will be a randomized, evaluator-blind, single-center, controlled, within-subject comparison study of the investigational products (abametapir lotion) and its vehicle lotion and positive and negative controls under occlusive conditions in healthy volunteers. All subjects will have the investigational product (abametapir lotion), the vehicle product, the positive control patch, and negative control patch applied to 4 randomly assigned, adjacent skin sites on the infrascapular area of their back, for the purpose of determining irritation potential. The investigational products, vehicle, and controls will be applied to one side of the infrascapular area of the back. Evaluation of dermal reactions at the application sites will be assessed clinically using a visual scale that rates the degree of erythema, edema, and other signs of cutaneous irritation (see Section 3.5.5). A total of 21 applications of each product will be made.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>1. Are healthy (to be confirmed by medical history) males or females, 18 years of age or older; 2. In the case of females of childbearing potential, are using an acceptable form of birth control (oral/implant/injectable/transdermal contraceptives, intrauterine device, condom with spermicide, diaphragm with spermicide, abstinence, partner's vasectomy). Abstinence or vasectomized partner are acceptable if the female subject agrees to implement one of the other acceptable methods of birth control if her lifestyle/partner changes; 3. If female of childbearing potential, have a negative urine pregnancy test (UPT) at Day 1, and are willing to submit to a pregnancy test at the end of study (EOS); 4. Are free of any systemic or dermatologic disorder, which, in the opinion of the investigator, will interfere with the study results or increase the risk of adverse events; 5. Are of any skin type or race, providing the skin pigmentation will allow discernment of erythema; 6. Complete a patch study Medical Screening form as well as a Medical Personal History form; and 7. Read, understand, and provide signed informed consent. 1. Have any visible skin disease at the application site which, in the opinion of the investigative personnel, will interfere with the evaluation of the test site reaction; 2. Are not willing to refrain from using topical/systemic analgesics such as aspirin (daily use of 81 mg aspirin is acceptable), Aleve, Motrin, Advil, or Nuprin for 72 hours prior to and during the study (occasional use of acetaminophen will be permitted); 3. Are using inhaled/systemic/topical corticosteroids in the 3 weeks prior to and during the study, or systemic/topical antihistamines for 72 hours prior to and during the study; 4. Are using medication which, in the opinion of the investigative personnel, will interfere with the study results, including antiinflammatory medications; 5. Are unwilling or unable to refrain from the use of sunscreens, cosmetics, creams, ointments, lotions, or similar products on the back during the study; 6. Have psoriasis and/or active atopic dermatitis/eczema; 7. Are females who are pregnant, plan to become pregnant during the study, or are breastfeeding a child; 8. Have a known sensitivity to constituents present in the material being evaluated; 9. Have damaged skin in or around the test sites, including sunburn, excessively deep tans, uneven skin tones, tattoos, scars, excessive hair, numerous freckles, or other disfigurations of the test site 10. Have received treatment for any type of internal cancer within 5 years prior to study entry; 11. Have a history of, or are currently being treated for skin cancer; 12. Are currently participating in any other clinical trial, 13. Have any known sensitivity to adhesives; and/or 14. Have received any investigational treatment(s) within 4 weeks prior to study entry.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hatchtech</keyword>
</DOC>