<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00809367</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this research study is to determine if it is feasible to collect leukemia cells from patients ahead of time (before they undergo further treatments) so that these cells (after being radiated so they will no longer grow or divide) can be given back to them as a cancer vaccine if/after the participant receives a bone marrow or blood stem cell transplant in the future. The purpose of the research study will be to collect, freeze and store leukemia calls from participants blood or bone marrow. This study is a companion study to a vaccine study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Collection and Banking of Leukemia Cells MDS/AML</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>- Leukemia cells will be collected by one or more of the following methods: 1)Routine blood draw 2)Bone marrow aspirate 3) Leukapheresis. The physician and study staff will determine which of the methods above is best suited for each participant. - After collection, the leukemia cells will be transported to the Cell Manipulation Core Facility (CMCF) at the Dana-Farber Cancer Institute, where they will be frozen until the time of vaccine administration.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myelodysplastic Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Preleukemia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with AML will be eligible for banking at the time of relapse or primary induction failure or at the time of AML diagnosis they are 60 years of age or older, AML arising out of background MDS or MPD or AML known with high risk cytogenetics Patients with MDSRAEB1 or RAEBII, CMML1 or CMMLII Patients must have &gt;5% blast in bone marrow or peripheral blood ECOG Performance Status 02 Age greater than or equal to 18 years Reasonable likelihood, in the physician's opinion, that the patient will be a candidate for allogeneic stem cell transplant</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>MDS</keyword>
	<keyword>AML</keyword>
	<keyword>banking study</keyword>
</DOC>