<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00809445</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a randomized controlled clinical trial in which adults receiving drug abuse treatment will be recruited to participate in a multi-center HIV testing and counseling study. The purpose of this study is to assess the relative effectiveness of three HIV testing strategies on increasing receipt of test results: (1) on-site HIV rapid testing with brief, participant-tailored prevention counseling, (2) on-site HIV rapid testing with information only, and (3) referral for off-site HIV testing. The study will also assess the effectiveness of the three testing strategies in reducing HIV risk behaviors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Rapid HIV Testing and Counseling in Drug Abuse Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized controlled clinical trial in which individuals receiving drug abuse treatment will be recruited to participate in a multi-center HIV testing and counseling study. The purpose of this study is to assess the relative effectiveness of three HIV testing strategies on increasing receipt of HIV test results: (1) on-site HIV rapid testing with brief, participant-tailored prevention counseling, (2) on-site HIV rapid testing with information only, and (3) referral for off-site HIV testing. The study will also assess the effectiveness of the three testing strategies in reducing HIV sexual risk behaviors. Injection drug risk behavior will be a secondary outcome. Participants will complete a baseline assessment to report their demographics, HIV testing history and sexual and drug-using risk behaviors, and will be randomized to one of three groups. At one month post-randomization, participants will complete a follow-up assessment to determine whether or not they received their HIV test results. At six months post-randomization, participants will complete a follow-up assessment to assess any changes in their HIV sexual risk behaviors.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>At least 18 years of age HIVnegative or HIV status unknown No receipt of results from HIV test initiated within last 12 months Be able to communicate in English</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>