<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02929498</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase I/II, open-label, 2 arm study to evaluate the safety and clinical activity of GSK2879552 alone, or in combination with azacitidine in subjects with MDS. The study consisted of 2 parts. The objective of Part 1 is to determine the recommended phase 2 dose (RP2D) of GSK2879552 administered alone and in combination with azacitidine in adult subjects with high risk MDS previously treated with HMA. The objective of Part 2 is to evaluate clinical activity after treatment with GSK2879552, alone or in combination with azacitidine, in adult subjects with high risk MDS previously treated with HMA.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety, Clinical Activity, Pharmacokinetics (PK) and Pharmacodynamics Study of GSK2879552, Alone or With Azacitidine, in Subjects With High Risk Myelodysplastic Syndromes (MDS)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myelodysplastic Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Preleukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Azacitidine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>&gt;=18 years of age and provided signed written informed consent Subjects must have IPSSR high or very high risk myelodysplastic syndromes (MDS) by World Health Organization (WHO) classification Subjects must have failed hypomethylating treatment where "failure" is defined as: Progression (according to 2006 International Working Group [IWG] criteria) at any time after initiation of the hypomethylating treatment OR Failure to achieve complete or partial response or hematological improvement (HI) (according to 2006 IWG) after at least 4 cycles treatment OR Relapse after initial complete or partial response or HI (according to 2006 IWG criteria). Subjects are not a candidate, or have failed allogeneic stem cell transplantation. Subjects who underwent allotransplant in the past are eligible under following conditions: transplant was &gt;2 year prior to enrolment, and no evidence of active graftversushost disease (GVHD) Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 01. Subjects must have a life expectancy of at least 12 weeks, in the opinion of the investigator. Able to swallow and retain orally administered medication and does not have any clinically significant gastrointestinal abnormalities that may alter absorption such as malabsorption syndrome or major resection of the stomach or bowels. All prior treatmentrelated toxicities must be National Cancer Institute Common Toxicity Criteria for Adverse Events (NCICTCAE), version 4.0 &lt;=Grade 1 at the time of enrollment (except for alopecia). Adequate baseline organ function defined by: International Normalization Ratio (INR) and activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) &lt;=1.3xupper limit of normal (ULN); platelet count (PLT) &gt;=10,000 (transfusions permitted to bring PLT to &gt;10,000); total bilirubin &lt;=1.5xULN (Isolated bilirubin &gt;1.5xULN is acceptable if bilirubin is fractionated and direct bilirubin &lt;35% or subject has a diagnosis of Gilbert's syndrome); Alanine transaminase (ALT) &lt;=2.5xULN; creatinine &lt;=1.5xULN OR calculated creatinine clearance by Chronic Kidney Disease Epidemiology Collaboration (CKDEPI) equation or measured from 24 hour urine &gt;=50 milliliters (mL)/minute (min); and Ejection fraction &gt;=lower limit of normal (LLN) by Echocardiogram (ECHO) or multigated acquisition scan (MUGA) Women of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test within 7 days of first dose of study treatment and agree to use effective contraception during the study and for 7 days following the last dose of study treatment. Men with a female partner of childbearing potential must have either had a prior vasectomy or agree to use effective contraception from the administration of the first dose of study treatment until 3 months after the last dose of study treatment to allow for clearance of any altered sperm. AML according to world health organization (WHO) criteria (i.e. bone marrow blasts &gt;20%) Active hepatitis B or hepatitis C treatment Baseline Montreal Cognitive Assessment (MOCA) score of 22 or lower History of or concurrent malignancy of solid tumours, except for below: Exception: Subjects who have been diseasefree for 2 years, or subjects with a history of completely resected nonmelanoma skin cancer or successfully treated in situ carcinoma are eligible. Prior treatment with temozolomide, dacarbazine or procarbazine Prior treatment with poly adenosine diphosphate (ADP) ribose polymerase (PARP) inhibitors (example (e.g.), olaparib, veliparib [ABT888]) Currently receiving other anticancer therapy (chemotherapy, radiation therapy, immuno therapy, biologic therapy, hormonal therapy, surgery, and/or tumour embolization) Received major surgery, radiotherapy, or immunotherapy within 4 weeks of GSK2879552 administration Evidence of severe or uncontrolled systemic diseases (e.g., severe/chronic infection, unstable or uncompensated respiratory, renal, or cardiac disease). Any serious and/or unstable preexisting medical (aside from malignancy exception above), psychiatric disorder, or other conditions that could interfere with subject's safety, obtaining informed consent or compliance to the study procedures, in the opinion of the Investigator Current active liver or biliary disease (with the exception of Gilbert's syndrome or asymptomatic gallstones or otherwise stable chronic liver disease per investigator's assessment) Patients with any major bleeding current or within the past 4 weeks. (e.g. recent gastrointestinal [GI] hemorrhage or neurosurgery). Administration of an investigational drug within 14 days or 5 halflives, whichever is shorter, preceding the first dose of study treatment(s) in this study. Cardiac abnormalities as evidenced by any of the following: clinically significant uncontrolled arrhythmias or uncontrolled hypertension; history or evidence of current &gt;=Class II congestive heart failure as defined by New York Heart Association (NYHA); history of acute coronary syndromes (including unstable angina and myocardial infarction), coronary angioplasty, or stenting within the past 3 months; baseline Corrected QT (QTc) interval using Fridericia's formula &gt;450 milliseconds (msec) or &gt;480 msec in subjects with Bundle Branch Block. QTc value based on single or average of triplicate ECGs obtained over a brief recording period Current use of a prohibited medication including anticoagulants or platelet inhibitors or expected to require any of these medications during treatment with the investigational drug Consumption of Seville oranges, grapefruit, grapefruit hybrids, grapefruit juice, pommelos, or exotic citrus fruits, from 1 day prior to the first dose of study treatment(s) until the last dose of study drug Lactating female Have a known immediate or delayed hypersensitivity reaction or idiosyncrasy to drugs chemically related to GSK2879552 or lysinespecific demethylase 1 (LSD1) inhibitors that contraindicates their participation Known hypersensitivity to azacitidine or mannitol</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>GSK2879552</keyword>
	<keyword>Revised International Prognostic Scoring System (IPSS-R)</keyword>
	<keyword>azacitidine</keyword>
	<keyword>hypomethylating agents</keyword>
	<keyword>myelodysplastic syndrome</keyword>
</DOC>