<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02929797</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A Prospective Study on the Efficacy and Safety of CD8+NKG2D+ AKT cell immunotherapy to the pancreatic cancer patients treated with adjuvant chemotherapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Immunotherapy of CD8+NKG2D+ AKT Cell With Chemotherapy to Pancreatic Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Diagnosed as stage IIIII pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma patients by pathologic histology; 2. Pancreatic cancer after radical resection; 3. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group Performance Status less than 2; 4. Without radiotherapy or neoadjuvant chemotherapy; 5. The man or the gestation and lactation women Age between 18 to 80 years old; 6. Bone marrow functioned well: ANC more than 1.5*10^9/ L, PLT more than 100*10^9/LHgb more than 9 g/dL; 7. Blood biochemical indicators: AST（SGOT）less than 1.5 ULNALT（SGPT）less than 1.5 ULN, TBIL less than 1.5 ULN; 8. PT and PPT are in normal ranges; 9. Three months prior to clinical research did not receive any other clinical research trials; 10. patients are voluntary, and willing to sign informed consent. 1. Patients with other malignant tumors in the past five years; 2. Active viral or bacterial infection and cannot be controlled with appropriate antiinfection treatment; 3. Known as HIV infection, active hepatitis B virus or hepatitis C virus infection; 4. Known allergy to any kind of component of study drugs; 5. History of connective tissue disease(Such as lupus, scleroderma, nodular arteritis); 6. Patients with a history of interstitial pneumoniaSlowly progressive difficulty in breathing and hoose Sarcoidosissilicosis Fibrose pulmonaire idiopathiquehylactic pneumonia or A variety of allergy; 7. Suffering from mental illness or other illness, such as heart or lung disease, diabetes, etc. that can not be controlled, and can not cope with study treatment and monitoring requirements; 8. At the same time Patients participate in any other use of interventional medicine clinical research or checkers.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>pancreatic cancer</keyword>
</DOC>