<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02688192</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This clinical trial studies a mobile health fitness program for adolescent and young adult childhood cancer survivors. Adolescent and young adult childhood cancer survivors are at risk to have negative late effects from treatment and to develop chronic health conditions. A sedentary lifestyle may increase the risk of cardiovascular disease, osteoporosis, and early mortality. Physical activity reduces the risk for cardiovascular disease and early mortality, improves cardiorespiratory fitness, muscular fitness, bone health, and body composition, and it is also positively associated with quality of life. Programs and technologies that promote physical activity are important because health behaviors adopted by adolescent and young adult childhood cancer survivors are likely to continue into adulthood. A mobile health fitness application may motivate adolescent and young adult childhood cancer survivors to engage and maintain physical activity.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mobile Health Fitness Program for Adolescent and Young Adult Childhood Cancer Survivors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. Develop and evaluate the usability of cancer-specific and motivational tools in the mobile application (app). (Phase 1) II. Evaluate the feasibility of the technology-enhanced (electronic accelerometer + app + 8 weekly group sessions) fitness program in a pilot randomized clinical trial. (Phase 2) SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. Determine the effectiveness of the technology-enhanced fitness program on participants' cardiorespiratory fitness and muscular fitness. II. Examine the effects of the program on secondary outcomes of health related quality of life (HRQOL) and fatigue. OUTLINE: PHASE I: Participants attend individual or small group interviews and provide input about desired features for the app. After a usable app is developed, participants wear an electronic accelerometer, use the mobile app, and may engage in private social support messaging between individuals in the study. Participants may undergo an individual one time interview, perform an usability test over 1-2 hours, or perform a field trial using the app for up to 1 week. PHASE II: Participants are randomized to 1 of 2 arms. ARM I (TEENS LIVING WITH CANCER - FITNESS IMPROVEMENT TRAINING [TLC FIT]): Participants attend 8 group meetings over 90 minutes weekly, wear an electronic accelerometer, engage in private social support messaging within the app and Facebook private groups, and use the mobile app for up to 4 weeks without in-person groups. ARM II (WAIT-LIST CONTROL [WLC]): After the 6 month assessment, participants receive the TLC FIT intervention as in arm I.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fatigue</mesh_term>
	<criteria>PHASE I: Any diagnosis of cancer prior to age 21 PHASE I: Off treatment PHASE I: For patients &lt; 18 years, parents must give informed consent and patient must give assent; patients &gt;= 18 must give informed consent PHASE II: Any diagnosis of cancer prior to age 21 PHASE II: Off treatment for at least 6 months PHASE II: For patients &lt; 18 years, parents must give informed consent and patient must give assent; patients &gt;= 18 must give informed consent PHASE I: NonEnglish speaking PHASE I: Significant developmental delay per patient, parent, or physician report PHASE I: Pregnant (per patient report) PHASE II: Any medical contraindication to exercise according to a physician or physician's designee PHASE II: NonEnglish speaking PHASE II: Current physical activity level exceeding Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) guidelines for activity (60 min of moderatevigorous exercise/day for 5+ days/week (wk) including 3+ days of vigorous intensity activities and musclestrengthening exercises on 3+ days/wk and bone strengthening exercises on 3+ days/wk for children &lt; 18 and 150 min of moderate vigorous exercise or 75 min of vigorous exercise/wk and 2+ days of muscle strengthening activities for adults &gt;= 18); the CDC guidelines are used to determine exercise prescription in our intervention; individuals already exceeding the guidelines would be unlikely to benefit from participating PHASE II: Significant developmental delay per patient, parent, or physician report PHASE II: Pregnant (per patient report); if participant becomes pregnant during the course of the study, she will be removed from further participation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>25 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>