<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02666131</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether Granexin gel is safe and effective in the treatment of diabetic foot ulcers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Granexin Gel to Treat Diabetic Foot Ulcer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>DFU patients will undergo a one week screening period and those with changes in ulcer size of less than 30% will be eligible for randomization providing all other criteria are met. Participants enrolled in the study will receive treatment based on randomization into 1 of 2 treatment arms for up to 12 weeks. The participants will have an additional 12 week follow-up period beyond the treatment period to assess durability of wound closure.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetic Foot</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Foot Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age 18 years or older 2. Established diagnosis of diabetes mellitus (type I or II) 3. Glycosylated hemoglobin (HbA1c) value &lt; 10.0% at the screening visit 4. Diagnosis of neuropathic foot ulcer by 10g monofilament test, tuning fork (128 Hz), cotton wisp, or quantitative sensory test 5. Designated foot ulcer meets the following criteria at both the screening and baseline visits:a. Present for at least 4 weeks; b. Fullthickness cutaneous ulcer below the ankle surface; c. University of Texas grade A1; d. Diameter (after debridement) 1 to 40.0 cm2; e. Viable, granulating wound (investigator discretion) 6. Ankle brachial index 0.7 to 1.3 at both the screening and baseline visits 7. Signed informed consent 8. Female patients of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test at screening and must agree to use hormonal contraceptive, intrauterine device, diaphragm with spermicide, condom with spermicide, or abstinence throughout until 2 weeks after the last administration of study drug 1. Change (decrease or increase) in size of the designated target ulcer by ≥ 30% during the 7day screening period 2. Cannot tolerate the offloading method or cannot comply with studydefined standardofcare treatment 3. Has an ulcer that meets any of the following criteria: a. Shows signs of severe clinical infection, defined as pus oozing from the ulcer site; b. Requires operative debridement; c. Is positive for βhemolytic streptococci upon culture; d. Has &gt; 50% slough, significant necrotic tissue, bone, tendon, or capsule exposure; e. Is highly exuding (i.e., requires daily change of dressing) 4. Requires total contact cast 5. Ankle brachial pressure index &lt; 0.7 or &gt; 1.3 or ankle systolic pressure &lt; 70 mmHg 6. Has a local or systemic infection or local erythema ≥ 0.5 cm 7. Has any 1 of the following (only 1 of the 3 tests is required): a. On Doppler waveform analysis of the dorsalis pedis and posterior tibial arteries, a monophasic or biphasic flow (with loss of reverse flow) in either the artery of either foot; b. Toe:brachial index &lt; 0.75 or &gt; 1.3 c. Transcutaneous oxygen pressure &lt; 40 mmHg 8. Presence of active systemic or local cancer or tumor of any kind (exception: nonmelanoma skin cancer allowable at investigator discretion) 9. Congestive heart failure (New York Heart Association class IIIV) or coronary heart disease with ST segment elevation myocardial infarction or coronary artery bypass graft or percutaneous transluminal coronary angioplasty within the last 6 months 10. Active osteomyelitis of the foot with the target ulcer detected by xray, CT scan, or MRI 11. Active connective tissue disease 12. Acute Charcot's neuroarthropathy as determined by clinical and/or radiographic examination 13. Active treatment with systemic corticosteroids 14. Previous or current radiation therapy to the distal lower extremity or likelihood to receive this therapy during study participation 15. Pregnant or nursing 16. Uncontrolled anemia (hemoglobin &lt; 10 g/dL in females and &lt; 12 g/dL in males) 17. Estimated glomerular filtration rate &lt; 25 mL/min 18. Poor nutritional status, defined as an albumin &lt; 25 g/L (&lt; 2,500 mg/dl) 19. Significant peripheral edema as per investigator's discretion 20. Known inability or unavailability to complete required study visits during study participation 21. A psychiatric condition (e.g., suicidal ideation) or chronic alcohol or drug abuse problem, determined from the patient's medical history, which, in the opinion of the investigator, may pose a threat to patient compliance 22. Use of a plateletderived growth factor within 28 days before screening 23. Use of any investigational drug or therapy within 28 days before screening 24. Has any other factor which may, in the opinion of the investigator, compromise participation and/or followup in the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>diabetic foot ulcer</keyword>
	<keyword>diabetic complications</keyword>
	<keyword>diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>wound healing</keyword>
	<keyword>Granexin gel</keyword>
	<keyword>FirstString Research</keyword>
</DOC>