<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02666105</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a phase II single institutional therapeutic study of exemestane in post-menopausal women with advanced non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) who have failed at least 1, but not more than 3 previous treatment regimens.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Exemestane in Post-Menopausal Women With NSCLC</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Exemestane</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Recurrent or progressive advanced stage nonsmall cell lung cancer (no small cell component) NOTE: Pathology reports documenting the diagnosis of NSCLC are required to be reviewed to confirm outside diagnosis Treated with at least 1 and a maximum of 3 prior chemotherapy regimens for advanced NSCLC. NOTE: If the tumor is refractory (progressed) after a prior chemotherapy regimen, then that regimen would count. If a prior chemotherapy regimen has been changed due to other reasons than disease progression (e.g. poor tolerance, allergic reaction), then it would not count as a separate prior regimen. A chemotherapy drug added for "maintenance" following disease stabilization or response to a chemotherapy regimen (in the absence of prior disease progression) does not count as a separate prior regimen. Chemotherapy as part of initial potentially curative therapy (given as part of adjuvant or concomitant chemoradiotherapy) that was completed in &lt;1 year counts as 1 prior regimen. Measureable disease by RECIST version 1.1 (appendix III) Postmenopausal defined as Age ≥ 55 years and 1 year or more of amenorrhea Age &lt; 55 years and 1 year or more of amenorrhea with an estradiol assay &lt; 20 pg/mL Surgical menopause with bilateral oophorectomy ECOG performance status 0, 1 or 2 (appendix II) Adequate organ function within 14 days of study enrollment defined as Hematology: 1. Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1500/mm³, Platelets ≥ 100,000/mm³, Hemoglobin ≥ 9 g/dL 2. International normalized ratio (INR) ≤ 1.5 or prothrombin time (PT)/partial thromboplastin time (PTT) within normal limits (WNL) of the institution Biochemistry: 1. Total Bilirubin within normal institutional limits 2. AST/SGOT and ALT/SGPT ≤ 2.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN), except if there is known hepatic metastasis, wherein transaminases may be ≤ 5 x institutional ULN. 3. Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 mg/dl or glomerular filtration rate &gt; 50 ml/min Must have recovered to CTCAE grade 1 or better from the acute effects of any prior surgery, chemotherapy or radiation therapy. Chronic residual toxicity (i.e. peripheral neuropathy) is permitted A minimum time period must elapse between the end of a previous treatment and start of study therapy: 3 weeks from the completion of radiation therapy for recurrent/metastatic disease (2 weeks for brain metastases) 4 weeks from the completion of chemotherapy or any experimental therapy 4 weeks from prior major surgery (such as open biopsy or significant traumatic injury) 2 weeks from prior minor surgical procedures (such as chemotherapy infusion port placement or core visceral organ biopsy) Tissue block or slides available from most recent resection or original diagnosis Voluntary written consent before any research related procedures or therapy Known active CNS disease If patient has history of brain metastases, the brain lesions must have been treated with radiation and/or surgery and be stable on repeat imaging patients should be neurologically stable and on a stable or tapering dose of corticosteroids Known diagnosis of osteoporosis Inability or unwilling to swallow study drug Any gastrointestinal condition causing malabsorption or obstruction (eg, celiac sprue, gastric bypass surgery, strictures, adhesions, history of small bowel resection, blind loop syndrome) Currently using hormone replacement therapy (oral or patch) or/and phytoestrogen supplements (i.e. black cohosh) Known hypersensitivity to exemestane or its excipients Any serious underlying medical condition that, in the opinion of the enrolling physician, would impair the ability of the patient to receive protocol treatment Prior malignancy, with the exception of curatively treated squamous cell or basal carcinoma of the skin or in situ cervical cancer, unless there is a 3year diseasefree interval Concomitant use of strong CYP3A4 inducers such as rifampicin, phenytoin, carbamazepine, phenobarbital, or St. John's wort as these may significantly reduce the availability of exemestane</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>NSCLC</keyword>
</DOC>