<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01746264</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Vitamin D deficiency has been linked to endothelial dysfunction in adults. Obese adolescents have a high prevalence of Vitamin D deficiency as well as evidence of endothelial dysfunction. Our hypothesis is that supplementation of Vitamin D deficient adolescents with Vitamin D would lead to improvement in endothelial dysfunction.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Vitamin D Supplementation on Endothelial Function in Obese Adolescents</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Subjects had a brief screening visit with one of the study team members. Past medical history, current medications and a brief dietary history was taken. The dietary history was taken to assess calcium intake in a day and was obtained via the validated Short Calcium questionnaire. Blood pressure, heart rate as well as height,weight, waist and hip circumference measurement was obtained by study staff. In addition, a brief physical examination to determine Tanner stage was also completed. This involved examination of both breasts and genitalia for adolescent female and only genitalia in males. A physical activity questionnaire (IPAQ) was also administered by the study staff at this visit. A blood draw of 5 ml to measure plasma 25(OH) D, calcium, phosphorus was obtained as part of the screening visit. For girls who had started menstruating, a urine pregnancy test was also obtained. After the screening visit eligible subjects had baseline biochemical tests and an endothelial function assessment. Study participants received a pill container with six total pills of vitamin cholecalciferol (D3) (1 pill = 50,000 IU), with directions to take two pills once a month (100,000 IU) at the same time for a period of 3 months. Compliance was assessed at the 3 month visit by counting the number of pills remaining in the container. At 1 month, the subjects had tests for serum calcium and 25 hydroxy vitamin D levels. A urine test for random calcium to creatinine ratio was also obtained. At 2 months, the serum calcium, 25 hydroxy vitamin D levels, and calcium to creatinine ratio tests were repeated. At the end of 3 months, biochemical tests and an endothelial function assessment were repeated. Medical history, questionnaires, and the physical exam were also repeated.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholecalciferol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age 1218 years 2. BMI &gt;95% for age and gender 3. 25 (OH) D levels less than 30 ng/ml 1. 25 (OH) D levels &gt;30 ng/mL 2. Serum calcium &gt;10.4 mg/dL 3. Serum phosphorus &gt; 4.7 mg/dl 4. Pregnancy or nursing 5. Current cancer 6. Patients on vitamin D3 supplementation exceeding 400 IU/day 7. Hypertension defined as Blood Pressure over the 95th percentile for age, gender and height 8. Dietary calcium intake exceeding 1500 mg/day 9. Hepatic or renal disorders 10. Type 1 or type 2 diabetes mellitus 11. Subjects receiving insulin, metformin, or oral hypoglycemic medications 12. Subjects with malabsorption disorders (celiac disease, cystic fibrosis, inflammatory bowel disease)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>Endothelial dysfunction</keyword>
	<keyword>Vitamin D deficiency</keyword>
</DOC>