<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01746875</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine treatment effects in patients with retinal pigment epithelium detachment (PED) in relation to Age Related Maculopathy (AMD). Patients with newly diagnosed PED without choroidal neovascularisations (CNV), will be randomized to either treatment or observation. The treatment group will first be given injections with anti Vascular Endothelium Growth Factor (anti-VEGF). If the injections do not have any effect, Verteporfin Photodynamic Therapy (PDT) will be given. All patients will be followed for a period of 2 years. It is hypothesized that treatment stops the progression of the disease and stabilizes the vision in this subgroup of patients with AMD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study Testing if Medicine Can Make Pigment Epithelium Detachments Regress and Stabilize the Vision in Eyes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Retinal Detachment</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dissociative Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Verteporfin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Ability to provide written informed consent and comply with study assessments for the full duration of the study Age &gt; 50 years Pigment epithelium detachment in an eye not earlier treated with antiVEGF or verteporfin PDT. ETDRS Best Corrected Visual acuity 20/32 20/400 Prior treatment with verteporfin, or externalbeam radiation therapy, or transpupillary thermotherapy, Previous subfoveal focal laser photocoagulation involving the foveal center, History of vitrectomy, submacular surgery, or other surgical intervention for AMD. CNV, Subfoveal fibrosis or atrophy in study eye. Concurrent eye disease in the study eye that could compromise visual acuity (e.g., diabetic retinopathy, advanced glaucoma) or require medical or surgical intervention during the study. Active intraocular inflammation in the study eye.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Angiogenesis inhibitors</keyword>
	<keyword>Photochemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Vascular Endothelium Growth Factors</keyword>
	<keyword>Aflibercept</keyword>
</DOC>