<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01132820</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase II trial studies the side effects and how well cediranib maleate works in treating patients with endometrial cancer that has failed to respond to initial chemotherapy or has come back after surgery, radiation therapy, or other forms of treatment. Cediranib maleate may stop the growth of tumor cells by blocking proteins made by tumors that can stimulate growth of tumor cells as well as blood vessels in and around tumors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cediranib Maleate in Treating Patients With Recurrent or Persistent Endometrial Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To assess the activity of cediranib (cediranib maleate) in patients with either persistent or recurrent endometrial carcinoma. II. To determine the frequency and degree of toxicity of cediranib as assessed by the Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version (v.)4.0 in this cohort of patients. SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To determine the duration of progression-free survival and overall survival. II. To estimate the probability of response without restriction on the duration of response documentation since study enrollment. TERTIARY OBJECTIVES: I. To determine if the response to cediranib correlates with high-expression of its receptor targets (e.g., vascular endothelial growth factor receptor [VEGFR] [1, 2, 3] and platelet derived growth factor receptor [PDGFR]). II. To determine if the response to cediranib correlates with high endogenous circulating plasma levels of VEGFA, low-levels of its endogenous inhibitor, soluble fms-related tyrosine kinase 3 (sFlt-1) (the truncated, circulating portion of VEGFR-1), or circulating tissue factor (TF) or circulating prostate apoptosis response-4 (Par-4), both potential markers of tumor progression. III. To determine if a high-expression of VEGFA on pre-treatment tumor specimens correlates with response to cediranib. IV. To determine if expression of phosphorylated mitogen activated protein kinase (ERK) 1 and 2, c-Jun, signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (Stat3), protein kinase C (PKC), and phosphorylated ribosomal protein S6 (p70S6) kinase correlates with resistance or sensitivity to cediranib. OUTLINE: Patients receive cediranib maleate orally (PO) daily. Courses repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up every 3 months for 2 years and then every 6 months for 3 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cystadenocarcinoma, Serous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Uterine Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma, Clear Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Adenosquamous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cediranib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Maleic acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients must have recurrent or persistent endometrial carcinoma, which is refractory to curative therapy or established treatments; histologic confirmation of the original primary tumor is required Patients with the following histologic epithelial cell types are eligible: endometrioid adenocarcinoma, serous adenocarcinoma, undifferentiated carcinoma, clear cell adenocarcinoma, mixed epithelial carcinoma, adenocarcinoma not otherwise specified (N.O.S.), mucinous adenocarcinoma, squamous cell carcinoma, and transitional cell carcinoma All patients must have measurable disease; measurable disease is defined by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) (version 1.1); measurable disease is defined as at least one lesion that can be accurately measured in at least one dimension (longest diameter to be recorded); each lesion must be &gt;= 10 mm when measured by computed tomography (CT), magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) or caliper measurement by clinical exam; or &gt;= 20 mm when measured by chest xray; lymph nodes must be &gt;= 15 mm in short axis when measured by CT or MRI Patients must have at least one "target lesion" to be used to assess response on this protocol as defined by RECIST version 1.1; tumors within a previously irradiated field will be designated as "nontarget" lesions unless progression is documented or a biopsy is obtained to confirm persistence at least 90 days following completion of radiation therapy Patients must not be eligible for a higher priority Gynecologic Oncology Group (GOG) protocol, if one exists; in general, this would refer to any active GOG Phase III protocol or Rare Tumor protocol for the same patient population Patients who have received one prior regimen must have a GOG performance status of 0, 1, or 2; patients who have received two prior regimens must have a GOG performance status of 0 or 1 Recovery from effects of recent surgery, radiotherapy, or chemotherapy Patients should be free of active infection requiring antibiotics (with the exception of uncomplicated urinary tract infection [UTI]) Any hormonal therapy directed at the malignant tumor must be discontinued at least one week prior to registration Any other prior therapy directed at the malignant tumor must be discontinued at least three weeks prior to registration Patients must have had one prior chemotherapeutic regimen for management of endometrial carcinoma; initial treatment may include chemotherapy, chemotherapy and radiation therapy, and/or consolidation/maintenance therapy; chemotherapy administered in conjunction with primary radiation as a radiosensitizer WILL be counted as a systemic chemotherapy regimen Patients are allowed to receive, but are not required to receive, one additional cytotoxic regimen for management of recurrent or persistent disease according to the following definition: cytotoxic regimens include any agent that targets the genetic and/or mitotic apparatus of dividing cells, resulting in doselimiting toxicity to the bone marrow and/or gastrointestinal mucosa Note: Patients on this noncytotoxic study are allowed to receive one additional cytotoxic chemotherapy regimen for management of recurrent or persistent disease, as defined above; however, due to the novel nature of biologic compounds, patients are encouraged to enroll on secondline noncytotoxic studies prior to receiving additional cytotoxic therapy Patients must have NOT received any noncytotoxic chemotherapy for management of recurrent or persistent disease; prior hormonal therapy is allowed Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) greater than or equal to 1,500/mcl Platelets greater than or equal to 100,000/mcl Creatinine less than or equal to 1.5 x institutional upper limit normal (ULN) or creatinine (Cr) clearance &gt;= 60 ml/min Bilirubin less than or equal to 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) Serum glutamic oxaloacetic transaminase (SGOT) (aspartate aminotransferase [AST]) less than or equal to 2.5 x ULN Alkaline phosphatase less than or equal to 2.5 x ULN Neuropathy (sensory and motor) less than or equal to grade 1 Urine protein creatinine (UPC) ratio must be &lt; 1.0 gm If UPC ratio &gt;= 1, collection of 24hour urine measurement of urine protein is recommended Prothrombin time (PT) such that international normalized ratio (INR) is =&lt; 1.5 x ULN (or an inrange INR, usually between 2 and 3, if a patient is on a stable dose of therapeutic warfarin) and a partial thromboplastin time (PTT) =&lt; 1.5 x ULN Patients must have an amylase and lipase =&lt; ULN Patients must have a thyroid stimulating hormone (TSH) level and a free thyroxine (free T4) level within the institutional normal limits Patients must have signed an approved informed consent and authorization permitting release of personal health information Patients must meet preentry requirements as specified Patients of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test prior to the study entry and be practicing an effective form of contraception Patients who have had prior therapy with cediranib (AZD 2171) or other VEGF pathwaytargeted therapy Patient with a history of other invasive malignancies, with the exception of nonmelanoma skin cancer and other specific malignancies as noted, are excluded if there is any evidence of other malignancy being present within the last three years; patients are also excluded if their previous cancer treatment contraindicates this protocol therapy Patients who have received prior radiotherapy to any portion of the abdominal cavity or pelvis OTHER THAN for the treatment of endometrial cancer within the last three years are excluded; prior radiation for localized cancer of the breast, head and neck, or skin is permitted, provided that it was completed more than three years prior to registration, and the patient remains free of recurrent or metastatic disease Patients who have received prior chemotherapy for any abdominal or pelvic tumor OTHER THAN for the treatment of endometrial cancer within the last three years are excluded; patients may have received prior adjuvant chemotherapy for localized breast cancer, provided that it was completed more than three years prior to registration, and that the patient remains free of recurrent or metastatic disease Patients with serious, nonhealing wound, ulcer, or bone fracture; this includes history of abdominal fistula, gastrointestinal perforation or intraabdominal abscess within 28 days prior to the first date of cediranib (AZD 2171) therapy Patients with active bleeding or pathologic conditions that carry high risk of bleeding, such as known bleeding disorder, coagulopathy, or tumor involving major vessels Patients with history or evidence upon physical examination of central nervous system (CNS) disease, including primary brain tumor, seizures not controlled with standard medical therapy or any brain metastases Patients with clinically significant cardiovascular disease; this includes: Uncontrolled hypertension defined as systolic &gt; 150 mmHg or diastolic &gt; 100 mmHg despite optimized antihypertensive therapy Myocardial infarction or unstable angina within 6 months of the first date of cediranib (AZD 2171) therapy New York Heart Association (NYHA) grade II or greater congestive heart failure or serious cardiac arrhythmia requiring medication; women who have received prior treatment with an anthracycline (including doxorubicin and/or liposomal doxorubicin) and have an ejection fraction &lt; institutional lower limit of normal (LLN) will be excluded from the study CTCAE grade 2 or greater peripheral vascular disease History of cerebrovascular accident (CVA, stroke), transient ischemic attack (TIA) or subarachnoid hemorrhage within six months of the first date of cediranib (AZD 2171) therapy Mean corrected QT interval (QTc) &gt; 500 msec or history of familial long QT syndrome Patients with known hypersensitivity to Chinese hamster ovary cell products or other recombinant human or humanized antibodies Patients undergoing invasive procedures as defined below: Major surgical procedure, open biopsy or significant traumatic injury within 28 days prior to the first date of cediranib (AZD 2171) therapy Major surgical procedure anticipated during the course of the study Minor surgical procedures, fine needle aspirates, or core biopsies within 7 days prior to the first date of cediranib (AZD2171) therapy Patients who are pregnant or nursing</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>