<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01213251</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to demonstrate the feasibility of pacing as a therapy to prevent adverse remodeling of the myocardium following an acute myocardial infarction (MI) in patients at highest risk for adverse myocardial remodeling.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Post-Myocardial Infarction Remodeling Prevention Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Myocardial Infarction (MI) within the past 10 days Peak Creatine Phosphokinase (CPK) greater than 3000 Units/Litre (U/L) at time of MI, or a troponin T (TnT) greater than 10 micrograms/Litre (mcg/L) At least 18 years old Willing to comply with the protocol Documented MI greater than 10 days Chronic renal disease, as defined by estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) less than 30 milliliters/minute/1.73 square meter Life expectancy less than 18 months, as determined by a physician Existing pacemaker, Implantable Cardioverter Defibrillator (ICD), or Cardiac Resynchronization Therapy (CRT) device QRS duration greater than 120 milliseconds (ms) Coronary Artery Bypass Graft (CABG) within 30 days prior to MI, or CABG procedure planned Third degree atrioventricular (AV) block or symptomatic bradyarrhythmia Persistent atrial fibrillation (AF) that is not self terminating within 7 days or is terminated electrically or pharmacologically Permanent AF that is non self terminating, with cardioversion failed or not attempted within the past year New York Heart Association (NYHA) Class IV Nonischemic cardiomyopathy Pregnant or planning to become pregnant during the study Enrolled or planning to participate in a concurrent drug and/or device study during the course of this clinical trial. Coenrollment in concurrent trials is only allowed with documented preapproval from Medtronic, documenting that there is not a concern that coenrollment could confound the results of this trial. Breast feeding Of a vulnerable population as determined by local law or requirement, or a physician</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>