<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01213797</DOC>
	<brief_summary>With 11.000 deaths and 150.000 attempts each year in France, the suicide represents an important public health problem. For each death by suicide, one can count 6 "direct" bereaved people and 20 people in more indirect connection with this mourning (Terra 2001). In term of impact, there is thus 300.000 people (annually) touched by the deaths by suicide and 3.750.000 people (annually) touched by the "suicide attempt" of a close relative. It seems indeed important to have Public Health data on this cascade repercussion of the suicide attempt. A suicide attempt propagates a suffering cascade on the various circles of the family and close entourage, which can be measured in term of traumatic stress and medico-economic impact. Objective = To measure the medico-economic impact on the entourage, in the 3 months following the suicide attempt and at 1 year.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>IMTAP : Impact of the Suicide Attempt on the Nearly Entourage in Term of Traumatic Stress and Medico-economic Impact</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Secondary objectives = To measure the impact of the suicide attempt in traumatic term of stress on the close relatives of committing suicide confronted with the suicidal scene To compare the evolution of consumption of care of the close relatives and of committing suicide To measure the evolution of the general health condition of the close relatives and of committing suicide The study participants (committing suicide it and the relatives) will be recontacted by telephone, after 3 months and to 1 year. Consumption of care (number of consultations, drugs consumption) of the population of the close relatives of committing suicide will be compared with the data of the Research Institute and Documentation in Economy of Health (IRDES) on the French population (sample of 20.000 people, representative of 95% of the French households).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Suicide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Suicide, Attempted</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria for Suicide attempter : Men or women Older than 18 years Survivor with an suicide attempt going back to less than 15 days Inclusion Criteria for close relations of committing suicide : Men or women age more than 18 years Members of the entourage of committing suicide Living under the same roof as committing suicide it</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Suicide</keyword>
</DOC>