<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01536951</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This will be a 2-part, randomized, subject- and investigator-blind study in healthy males and females. Part A of this study is to determine a safe and tolerable single oral dose of LY3009104 that yields drug exposures slightly exceeding typical exposures anticipated from repeated administration of an efficacious dose to patients. The concentration of the drug in the blood stream will be measured and information about any side effects that may occur will also be collected. Part B of this study is to evaluate the effect of LY3009104 on the electrical activity of the heart as measured by electrocardiogram (ECG) in relation to placebo following a single oral dose.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of LY3009104 in Healthy Volunteers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Moxifloxacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluoroquinolones</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Norgestimate, ethinyl estradiol drug combination</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Are overtly healthy males or females as determined by medical history and physical examination. Are drug free, disease free, and no cardiac abnormalities. Have clinical laboratory test results within normal reference range for the population or investigator site, or results with acceptable deviations that are judged to be not clinically significant by the investigator. Have a clinically normal screening electrocardiogram (ECG) with a measurable QT interval as judged by the investigator, and which in Part B allows accurate measurements of QT interval. Have a history or presence of cardiovascular, respiratory, hepatic, renal, gastrointestinal, endocrine, hematological, or neurological disorders capable of significantly altering the absorption, metabolism, or elimination of drugs; of constituting a risk when taking the study medication; or of interfering with the interpretation of data. Have an abnormality in the 12lead ECG that, in the opinion of the investigator, increases the risks associated with participating in the study or affects or confounds the QTc analysis or have QTc greater than 450 msec. Regularly use known drugs of abuse and/or show positive findings on urinary drug screening.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>