<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01536808</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The potential clinical implications of this study are to optimise the selection of a population at risk for developing a diabetic cardiomyopathy among diabetic patients in order to develop early therapeutic strategies to prevent the left ventricular remodelling. Therefore, the originality of this project is to hypothesize that : - Diabetes mellitus is often associated with a premature aging syndrome - Cellular senescence may potentiate the mechanisms that are involved in decreasing myocardial contractility in DM and, - DM associated to premature aging may increase the risk of developing a cardiomyopathy Thus, the modulation of telomerase activity and the control of telomere length, together with the attenuation of the formation of reactive oxygen species, might represent important new targets in order to develop therapeutic tools in prevention of diabetic cardiomyopathy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Premature Aging and Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus: an Increased Risk of Cardiomyopathy?</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cardiomyopathies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aging, Premature</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Type 2 Diabetes mellitus 40 &lt; Age &lt; 55 years old oral antidiabetic or insulin treatment No symptoms Sinus rhythm no sign or history of heart disease LVEF &gt; 55% Absence of regional left ventricular motion abnormalities. absence of sinus rhythm, silent ischemia defined as positive exercise test or positive stress echocardiography, history of cardiomyopathy or CAD, valvular heart disease hemodynamically significant, severe renal insufficiency defined as creatinine clearance &lt; 30 mL/min, echocardiographic images unsuitable for quantification, type 1 diabetes mellitus, Important diabetes mellitus imbalance defined as glycated hemoglobin &gt; 9% or glycemia &gt; 3g/L uncontrolled hypertension (&gt; 180/100 mmHg).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetes mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>accelerated aging</keyword>
	<keyword>cellular senescence</keyword>
	<keyword>diabetic cardiomyopathy</keyword>
	<keyword>strain imaging</keyword>
	<keyword>strain rate imaging,</keyword>
	<keyword>echocardiography</keyword>
</DOC>