<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01536262</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to assess the safety of 52 weeks once daily treatment with orally inhaled tiotropium + olodaterol FDC and olodaterol (delivered by the RESPIMAT Inhaler) in Japanese patients with Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Japan Long-term Safety for Tiotropium Plus Olodaterol</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Olodaterol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tiotropium Bromide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: 1. Diagnosis of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. 2. Relatively stable airway obstruction with post FEV1&lt; 80% predicted normal and post FEV1/FVC &lt;70%. 3. Male or female Japanese patients, 40 years of age or older. 4. Smoking history of more than 10 pack years. Exclusion criteria: 1. Significant disease other than COPD 2. Clinically relevant abnormal lab values. 3. History of asthma. 4. Diagnosis of thyrotoxicosis 5. Diagnosis of paroxysmal tachycardia 6. History of myocardial infarction within 1 year of screening visit 7. Unstable or lifethreatening cardiac arrhythmia. 8. Hospitalization for heart failure within the past year. 9. Known active tuberculosis. 10. Malignancy for which patient has undergone resection, radiation therapy or chemotherapy within last five years 11. History of lifethreatening pulmonary obstruction. 12. History of cystic fibrosis. 13. Clinically evident bronchiectasis. 14. History of significant alcohol or drug abuse. 15. Thoracotomy with pulmonary resection 16. Oral ßadrenergics. 17. Oral corticosteroid medication at unstable doses 18. Regular use of daytime oxygen therapy for more than one hour per day 19. Pulmonary rehabilitation program in the six weeks prior to the screening visit 20. Investigational drug within one month or six half lives (whichever is greater) prior to screening visit 21. Known hypersensitivity to ßadrenergic drugs, anticholinergics, BAC, EDTA 22. Pregnant or nursing women. 23. Women of childbearing potential not using a highly effective method of birth control 24. Patients who are unable to comply with pulmonary medication restrictions 25. Patients with narrowangle glaucoma or micturition disorder due to prostatic hyperplasia etc.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>