<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02282033</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to evaluate the safety and performance of the Moderato System by implanting the Moderato pacemaker in patients who require a dual chamber pacemaker, and who also have hypertension, in order to reduce their blood pressure.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Performance Study of the Moderato System</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Bradycardia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atrioventricular Block</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Vasospasm</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject is ≥ 18 years of age Subject is indicated for implantation or replacement of a dual chamber permanent pacemaker where no lead extraction is necessary. Subject has stable regimen of 2 or more maximally tolerated antihypertension medications, which is anticipated to be able to be maintained without changes for 3 months. Subject has office systolic blood pressure measurements &gt; 140 mmHg on two separate days within a one week period prior to enrollment, and the average of these two measurements is ≥150 mmHg Subject has known secondary cause of HTN Subject has a history of atrial fibrillation Subject has ejection fraction &lt;50% Subject has symptoms of heart failure of NYHA Class II or more Subject has hypertrophic cardiomyopathy, restrictive cardiomyopathy or interventricular septal thickness ≥15 mm Subject is on dialysis Subject has estimated Glomerular Filtration Rate (GFR) &lt;30 ml/min/1.73m2 Subject has prior neurological events (stroke or TIA) or carotid artery disease Subject has known autonomic dysfunction Subject has a history of clinically significant tachyarrhythmia Subject has had previous active devicebased treatment for hypertension Subject has an existing implant, other than a pacemaker that needs replacing Subject with average Systolic BP &gt;190 mmHg</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>