<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03011957</DOC>
	<brief_summary>MATCH is an observation study of HIV-infected adults on effective antiretroviral therapy (ART) and demographically matched uninfected adults to evaluate muscle and aging.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Biomarkers for Muscle Function and Aging in Chronic HIV Infection</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>MATCH is a non-randomized observational longitudinal study. We will recruit HIV infected adults (50 to 65 years old) and demographically matched uninfected control subjects to be followed for 4 years over the course of a 5 year study. The targeted age range of 50-65 is chosen to evaluate aging HIV infected individuals at risk for early frailty in the United States. All subjects will undergo blood draws and physical function assessment, and a subset will undergo a CT scan of muscle and will have a muscle biopsy taken. A substudy will be performed on a subgroup of HIV-infected and HIV-uninfected men from the main cohort to measure daily physical activity by using an activity tracker.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Group 1: HIV positive subjects HIV positive English speaking 5065 years old On Antiretroviral therapy and an HIV viral load below 200 copies/ml CD4 equal to or greater than 350 cells/mm3 Postmenopausal (women) Lower extremity mobility sufficient to participate in functional assessment. Group 2: HIV negative subjects Inclusion Criteria for Group 2 subjects English speaking 5065 years old Negative for HIV (based on an HIV antibody test at Study Visit 1) Matched to Group 1 for sex (50% W, 50% M) and age (50 65yo) Postmenopausal (women) Lower extremity mobility sufficient to participate in functional assessment. Exclusion Criteria for Group 1 Subjects Acute or serious illness within 60 days prior to entry Use of pharmacologic doses of corticosteroids in the past 6 months. Use of anabolic therapy in the past 6 months. Lower extremity mobility insufficient to participate in functional assessment. Current use (last 30 days) of anticoagulants or known bleeding disorder. Exclusion Criteria for Group 2 subjects Acute or serious illness within 60 days prior to entry Use of pharmacologic doses of corticosteroids in the past 6 months Use of anabolic therapy in the past 6 months Lower extremity mobility insufficient to participate in functional assessment Current use (last 30 days) of anticoagulants or known bleeding disorder.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>