<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03011372</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of INCB054828 in subjects with myeloid/lymphoid neoplasms with fibroblast growth factor receptor (FGFR) 1 rearrangement.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of INCB054828 in Subjects With Myeloid/Lymphoid Neoplasms With FGFR1 Rearrangement</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Documented lymphoid or myeloid neoplasm with 8p11 rearrangement known to lead to FGFR1 activation, based on standard diagnostic cytogenetic evaluation performed locally, before signing informed consent for this study. Subjects must be relapsed/refractory. Prior stem cell transplantation is allowed. Life expectancy ≥ 12 weeks. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 0 to 2. Prior receipt of a selective FGFR inhibitor. History and/or current evidence of ectopic mineralization/calcification, including but not limited to soft tissue, kidneys, intestine, myocardia, or lung, except calcified lymph nodes and asymptomatic arterial or cartilage/tendon calcifications. Current evidence of corneal disorder/keratopathy, including but not limited to bullous/band keratopathy, corneal abrasion, inflammation/ulceration, and keratoconjunctivitis, as confirmed by ophthalmologic examination. Use of any potent cytochrome P450 3A4 inhibitors or inducers within 14 days or 5 halflives (whichever is shorter) before the first dose of study drug.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Myeloid neoplasm</keyword>
	<keyword>fibroblast growth factor receptor inhibitor</keyword>
	<keyword>FGFR1 rearrangement</keyword>
	<keyword>8p11</keyword>
	<keyword>eosinophilia</keyword>
	<keyword>eosinophilic syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Lymphoid neoplasm</keyword>
</DOC>