<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03011125</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a single center, randomized, double-blind, dose-escalation, placebo-controlled phase 1 clinical trial. This study will determine the safety and side-effect profile of an investigational dexlansoprazole injection after single intravenous administration in healthy Chinese adults.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Clinical Trial to Evaluate the Safety and Tolerability of Dexlansoprazole Injection in Healthy Chinese Adults (Part 1)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a single center, double-blind, dose-escalation, placebo-controlled clinical trial. Dose escalation will be proceeded according to 3+3 design in five predefined dosing groups. After completion of the 90mg dosing study, dose-escalation will be stopped, even though MTD is not be observed. A total of 28 participants is scheduled to be recruited. The whole follow-up period for each participant will be 3 days.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dexlansoprazole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lansoprazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥18 Years; Male (weight ≥50kg) or female (weight ≥45kg); BMI between 19~28 kg/m2; Healthy subjects (at screening); Subject who totally understand the aim and progress of this clinical trial, make decision by his/her free will, and signed a consent form to follow the progress. Allergy/hypersensitivity (including drug allergy) which is deemed relevant to the trial as judged by the investigator; Subject who has past or present history of any serious diseases, including (but not limited to) digestive, cardiovascular, respiratory, urinary, musculoskeletal, endocrine, psychiatric or neurological, hematologic, immunological or metabolic disorders; Medical examination, laboratory tests or ECG judged by the investigator to differ significantly from normal clinical values; HIV, HBV, or syphilis positive; Drug dependency or abuse; Heavy smokers (&gt;5 cigarettes per day); Alcohol use; Participation in another study with an investigational drug within the last 3 months preceding this study; Blood donation within the last 2 months (&gt;= 400 ml), or have a plan to donate blood within 1 month after this study; Intake of any other drug which might influence the results of the trial during two weeks previous to the start of the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>