<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03011021</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate the safety and therapeutic effect of ex-vivo expanded umbilical cord blood regulatory T cells adjunct with Liraglutide on autoimmune diabetes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of Umbilical Cord Blood Regulatory T Cells Plus Liraglutide on Autoimmune Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Autoimmune Diabetes Mellitus (AIDM) is a subtype of diabetes mellitus caused by autoimmune destruction of beta cells in the islet, including Type 1 diabetes and Latent Autoimmune Diabetes in Adults (LADA). Insulin has been used as a routine therapy for AIDM to alleviate the hyperglycemic status, yet cannot effectively prevent the progressing destruction of beta cells or preserve its function. Regulatory T cells expanded from umbilical cord blood (UCB-Treg) ex-vivo have shown strong capacity to control immune responses in autoimmune diseases, offering a hopeful therapeutic way for AIDM. Glucagon-like peptide (GLP-1) analog Liraglutide has been tested in large-scale clinical trial to prove its various benefits for beta cells and glucolipid metabolism in Type 2 diabetes and obesity patients. However, its clinical application in AIDM is not well-defined so far. The aim of this study is to investigate the potential use of Liraglutide with UCB-Treg infusion in AIDM and examine the safety and efficacy of this new therapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liraglutide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Type 1 diabetes according to ADA criteria &lt;3 years. Age≥ 18 years. Positive for at least one of the antiislet autoantibodies: GADA, IA2A, ZnT8A Fasting or postprandial plasma Cpeptide more than 100 pmol/L Written informed consent from the patient or family representative. History or family history of medullary thyroid carcinoma or MEN 2 syndrome; History of chronic or acute pancreatitis; Allergic to liraglutide or any components in Victoza®; Hepatic abnormalities (transaminase &gt; 2 times normal); Renal impairments (serum creatinine &gt;133 umol/L); Cardiovascular diseases (hypertension, coronary heart disease, etc.); Presence of anemia (Hb ≤100g/L), leukopenia (&lt;3.5×109/L); Presence of disorder in coagulation or anticoagulation, or thrombocytopenia (platelets &lt;100×109/L); Presence of acute metabolic disorders; In the case of acute ketone acidosis, with blood ketone over 0.3mmol/L and pH lower than 7.30; Presence of any kind of chronic infection or immune deficiency, including hepatitis B, hepatitis C, HIV, syphilis or tuberculosis, etc.; Chronic use of systemic glucocorticoids or other immunosuppressive agents for over 3 months; Any history of malignancy; Female patients who are pregnant or breastfeeding; any female who is unwilling to use a reliable and effective form of contraception for 2 years after recruitment; Presence of any infectious diseases, including active skin infections, flu, fever, upper or lower respiratory tract infections; those who wish to participate in the study should keep the infection under control for at least 1 week before receiving Treg product infusion; Any medical condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, will interfere with safe participation in the trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Autoimmune Diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Umbilical Cord Blood Regulatory T Lymphocyte</keyword>
	<keyword>Liraglutide</keyword>
</DOC>