<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02210728</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the project is to evaluate the efficacy of cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) for adults with attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) with and without stimulant medication and compare it to medication alone. Subjects will be randomly assigned to stimulant medication only, CBT only and combined CBT and stimulant medication group. Patients will be evaluated at baseline, following mediation optimization (for medicated groups), following 12 months of treatment, after 3 months of follow up, and after 6 months of follow up. The investigators hypothesize that the combined group will have the best outcome at all evaluation points. ADHD in adults is associated with significant morbidity and impaired academic, occupational, social, and emotional functioning. Developing optimal treatment approaches for this population is key in improving their functioning.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Cognitive Behavioral Therapy in Treatment of Adults With Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperkinesis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amphetamine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylphenidate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, 4th edition, text revision (DSMIVTR) criteria for adult ADHD of any of three subtypes via Conners' Adult ADHD Diagnostic Interview for the DSMIV (CAARD) and clinician's assessment; Barkley Childhood and Current Symptom of ADHD (1998) completed by self and informants (parents or siblings). Required cut off's on these scales are scores 1.5 Standard Deviation above relevant gender and age norms; Conners' Adult ADHD Rating Scale (1999). Required cut off's on these scales are scores 1.5 Standard Deviation above relevant gender and age norms; Between 18 and 60 years old Be able to give informed consent and comply with study procedures; I.Q. of 80 or above on Wechsler Adult Intelligence Scale, 3rd edition (WAISIII) subtests of three verbal and three nonverbal subtests Adequate command of English to be able to participate in CBT group. Psychotic symptoms, past or current Current psychiatric comorbidity, e.g. bipolar disorder, depression, suicidality, current substance use disorder (must be free of substance abuse for 6 months) Medical condition that preclude use of the stimulant medication, e.g. hypertension, cardiac disease, Tourette's Syndrome, etc. Organic mental disorders or other significant neurological disorders, e.g. epilepsy, head injury, chorea, multiple sclerosis, deafness, blindness.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>cognitive behavioral therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>stimulant medication</keyword>
	<keyword>efficacy</keyword>
	<keyword>symptoms</keyword>
	<keyword>functional outcomes</keyword>
</DOC>