<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02999984</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a prospective, non-randomized, single-cohort, longitudinal, single-center, clinical study designed to assess the efficacy and safety of a cryopreserved formulation of OTL-101 (autologous CD34+ hematopoietic stem/progenitor cells transduced ex vivo with EFS LV encoding for the human ADA gene) administered to ADA-SCID subjects between the ages of 30 days and 17 years of age, who are not eligible for an HLA-matched sibling/family donor and meeting the inclusion/exclusion criteria. The OTL-101 product will be infused after a minimal interval of at least 24 hours following the completion of reduced intensity conditioning. For subjects who have successfully received the OTL-101 product, PEG-ADA ERT will be discontinued at Day+30 (+/-3) after the transplant. After their discharge from hospital, the subjects will be seen at regular intervals to review their history, perform examinations and draw blood samples to assess immunity and safety.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Autologous Cryopreserved CD34+ Hematopoietic Cells Transduced With EFS-ADA Lentivirus for ADA SCID</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a prospective, non-randomized, single-cohort, longitudinal, single-center, clinical study designed to assess the efficacy and safety of a cryopreserved formulation of OTL-101 (autologous CD34+ hematopoietic stem cells transduced ex vivo with EFS LV encoding for the human ADA gene) administered to ADA-SCID subjects between the ages of 30 days and 17 years, who are not eligible for an HLA-matched sibling/family donor and meeting the inclusion/exclusion criteria. The aim of this study is to assess the success of treatment for overall survival and event free survival. Eligible subjects will be hospitalized to undergo the harvesting of autologous CD34+ cells. To enable the release of the cell product for infusion, the product must meet various quality control criteria for safety, identity, viability, purity and potency. If OTL-101 meets the acceptance criteria and is released, the subjects will be readmitted for conditioning prior to infusion of OTL-101. For subjects who have successfully received the OTL-101 product, PEG-ADA ERT will be discontinued at Day+30 (+/-3) after the transplant. After their discharge from hospital, the subjects will be seen at regular intervals to review their history, perform examinations and draw blood samples at Months 1, 3, 6, 9, 12, 18, and 24. Any medically-indicated interventions will be determined at these visits. After Month 24 visit, the subjects will have completed the study and may enter a long term registry.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Severe Combined Immunodeficiency</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Eligible subjects aged ≥30 days and &lt;18 years Diagnosis of ADASCID Ineligible for matched family allogeneic bone marrow transplantation Ineligible for autologous HSCT as per clinical site criteria Other conditions which, in the opinion of the Principal Investigator and/or Co Investigators, contraindicate the harvest of bone marrow, the administration of conditioning and the infusion of transduced cells, or which indicate an inability of the subject or subject's parent/legal guardian to comply with the protocol Hematologic abnormality, defined as: Anemia Neutropenia Thrombocytopenia Coagulation abnormality Cytogenetic abnormalities Prior allogeneic HSCT with cytoreductive conditioning. Pulmonary abnormality Cardiac abnormality Neurologic abnormality Renal abnormality Hepatic/gastrointestinal abnormality Oncologic disease other than dermatofibrosarcoma protuberans (DFSP) Known sensitivity to conditioning agents Confirmation of an infectious disease (HIV1, Hepatitis B, Parvovirus B19) Pregnancy or major congenital anomaly Is likely to require treatment during the study with drugs that are not permitted by the study protocol Previous gene therapy procedure</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>