<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02999360</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to determine if speech therapy can be enhanced by Aerobic Exercise (AE). Investigators will use a single subject design to determine if aphasia therapy result in greater gains when combined with aerobic exercise.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Aerobic Exercise and Aphasia Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Aim 1: To test the feasibility of a research study that combines speech therapy with aerobic exercise (AE). Participants will be alternately assigned to receiving AE during during a 30 minute break from speech therapy. Aim 2: To test the preliminary efficacy of combining speech therapy with AE to promote language improvements in aphasia. These data will inform the design of a large, controlled clinical trial</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Aphasia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Aphasia based on Western Aphasia Battery (WAB) severity quotient=mildmoderate aphasia. English is primary language (patient report). At least 12 months post CVA (patient report and confirmed by medical records review). Able to participate in AE based on MD screening. Have a history of only one stroke. Independent in walking (with or without assistive device). Medically stable. No previous myocardial infarction. No significant musculoskeletal problems from conditions other than stroke. MD considers participant unable to comply with study requirements. Stroke due to intracranial hemorrhage primarily due to bleeding from ruptured aneurysm or arteriovenous malformation. Progressive stroke. Comorbid neurological diagnosis (e.g. MS, PD, dementia) Unable to perform the required exercises due to a) medical, b) musculoskeletal, or c) neurological problems (for details see below, ac) 1. medical problems: unstable cardiovascular condition, or other serious cardiac conditions (for example, anyone meeting New York Heart Association Class IV criteria, hospitalization for myocardial infarction or heart surgery within 120 days, severe cardiomyopathy or documented serious and unstable cardiac arrhythmias) 2. musculoskeletal problems: restricted passive range of motion in the major lower limb joints (that is, an extension deficit of &gt;20° for the affected hip or knee joints, or a dorsiflexion deficit of &gt;20° for the affected ankle) 3. neurological problems: severity of strokerelated deficits Required help of at least 1 person to walk before stroke due to neurological (for example, advanced Parkinson's disease, amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, multiple sclerosis) or nonneurological (for example, heart failure, orthopaedic problems) comorbidities with life expectancy of less than 1 year as determined by physician. Drug or alcohol addiction within the last 6 months. Significant current psychiatric illness defined as affective disorder unresponsive to medication or bipolar affective disorder, psychosis, schizophrenia or suicidality. Current participation in another interventional trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Aphasia</keyword>
	<keyword>Speech Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Aerobic Exercise (AE)</keyword>
</DOC>