<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02999373</DOC>
	<brief_summary>About 37% of neonatal mortality are caused by infection worldwidely . Excessive application of broad-spectrum antibiotics increased drug-resistance, however does not decrease morbility and mortality of neonates. Based on the investigator' early in vitro experiments which found cord blood mononuclear cells can inhibit bacterial growth and reduce of drug-resistance, along with other studies conducted recently from other groups who have reported the successful use of umbilical cord blood mononuclear cells in animal sepsis.The investigator would like to investigate the effects of umbilical cord blood mononuclear cells on prevention effect of preterm infection.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prevention of Preterm Infection by Autologous Umbilical Cord Blood Mononuclear Cells Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase 1 clinical trial that constitutes two time points cohorts with 80 participants per cohort who will receive intravenous doses of Autologous Umbilical Cord Blood Mononuclear Cells --25 million cells/kg,6 hours or 48 hours after birth. And the placebo will be 0.9% sodium chloride.The investigator will proceed the groups during the same period. 1. Eligibility Criteria:Preterm (gestational age more than 28weeks and less than 37weeks ) 2. Exclusion criteria:Preterm infants with major congenital malformations, chromosomal anomalies, inborn errors of metabolism and clinical or laboratory evidence of a congenital infection 3. Demographic Data and Baseline Characteristics of the Studied Groups were collected : Gestational age (weeks) Birth weight (g) gender Cesarean section delivery Antenatal steroids Prolonged rupture of membrane Multiple pregnancies APGAR score at 5 minutes Thrombocytopenia before intervention CRP before intervention (mg/L) TNF-α(tumor necrosis factor α ) before intervention (pg/mL) 4. Assessment of clinical condition in the course by measurement of arterial blood pressure, heart and respiratory rates and skin temperature was recorded continuously 5. Autologous cord blood mononuclear cells doses is 25 million cells/kg ，the infusion speed is 4ml/kg/h， 8-12h，and with same volume of 0.9% sodium chloride as placebo. When the clinical symptoms suggests infection, blood cultures were performed before administration of antibiotics, and antibiotics were adjusted according to the susceptibility of the isolated bacteria. 6. The following are monitored at 3、7、14、21days after birth : panels of cytokine and biomarkers(CRP、TNF-α、IL-6、IL-10、MCP-1) are examined by Elisa, circulating stem cell levels, immune cells subgroup ,platelet activation related markers CD62P、CD63 , number of megakaryocyte are evaluated by flow cytometry, infectious rate, mortality, incidence of multiple drug-resistant bacteria ,clinical complications: sepsis, bronchopulmonary dysplasia(BPD), retinopathy of prematurity (ROP), necrotising enterocolitis (NEC), intraventricular haemorrhage (IVH), anaemia before hospital discharge 7. Long-term follow up: in 1m, 3m, 6m,1y: neurodevelopment [Bayley Scales of Infant], asthma, anemia and physique growth .</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Perinatal Death</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bacteroides Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>twentyeight weeks to thirtyseven weeks Preterm infants with major congenital malformations, chromosomal anomalies, inborn errors of metabolism and clinical or laboratory evidence of a congenital infection</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>28 Weeks</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>36 Weeks</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>prevention, infection, preterm, cord blood mononuclear cells</keyword>
</DOC>