<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02999711</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Purpose of this study is to assess the safety and tolerability of multiple ascending subcutaneous doses of REGN3500 to moderate asthmatics.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Safety, Tolerability, and Pharmacokinetics of Multiple Ascending Doses of REGN3500 in Adults With Moderate Asthma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female between the age of 18 and 55 years, Body mass index (BMI) of 18 to 32 kg/m2 A diagnosis of moderate asthma (according to GINA 2015) for a period of at least 2 years prior to screening. Patient must use a stable medium daily dose level of inhaled corticosteroids (ICS) as defined by GINA guidelines, ie, total daily dose of ICS &gt;400 μg and ≤800 μg/day of budesonide or equivalent for at least 1 month prior to screening and during the study A prebronchodilator forced expiratory volume in the first sec (FEV1) ≥60% and ≤85% of the predicted normal values at screening and predose at randomization A documented positive response to the reversibility test at the screening, defined as improvement in FEV1 ≥12% and ≥200 mL over baseline after 400 μg salbutamol Pmdi Willing and able to comply with clinic visits and studyrelated procedures Provide signed informed consent. Clinically significant abnormal CBC, clinical chemistry, and urine analysis at screening. Treatment with an investigational drug within 8 weeks or within 5 halflives (if known), whichever is longer, prior to screening. History of lifethreatening asthma Occurrence of asthma exacerbations or respiratory tract infections within 4 weeks prior to screening. Diagnosis of any other airway/pulmonary disease such as Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) as defined by the Global Initiative for Chronic Obstructive Lung Disease (GOLD) guidelines (GINA 2015); or other lung diseases (eg, emphysema, idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis, ChurgStrauss syndrome, allergic bronchopulmonary aspergillosis cystic fibrosis, bronchiectasis or alpha1 antitrypsin deficiency or restrictive lung disease). Chronic or acute infection requiring treatment with systemic antibiotics, antivirals, or antifungals within 1 month prior to screening. Use of oral antibiotics/antiinfectives within 2 weeks prior to screening. Known sensitivity to doxycycline or tetracyclines, or to any of the components of the investigational product formulation. Recent (within the previous 2 months) bacterial, protozoal, viral, or parasite infection. History of tuberculosis or systemic fungal diseases Patients treated with a monoclonal antibody based therapy (such as an antiIgE, antiIL5), a biologic therapy or immunotherapy (subcutaneous immunotherapy [SCIT], sublingual immunotherapy [SLIT], or oral immunotherapy [OIT]) in the previous 12 weeks prior to screening and during the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>