<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01742884</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if Thealoz is effective in Dry Eye Syndrome exposed to controlled adverse environmental conditions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of a Treatment for Dry Eye Syndrome: Thealoz</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Keratoconjunctivitis Sicca</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dry Eye Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Man/woman ≥ 18 years old, able to freely give consent to participate in the study Fluorescein corneal staining ≥ 1 and ≤ 3 in Oxford Scales At least 2 of the following tests altered: Ocular Surface Disease Index (OSDI) Test symptoms between 12 and 40 BUT ≤10 seconds Lissamine green conjunctival staining ≥ 1 Schirmer Test without anesthesia ≤ 5 mm Informed consent signed Data protection consent signed Sensitivity or known intolerance to any of the product used in the study Story of ocular infections or severe ocular inflammation within the 6 previous months to study inclusion Any active ocular pathology other than Dry Eye Syndrome Any traumatize or ocular surgery that may affect corneal sensitivity and/or normal tear distribution (e.g. cataract surgery, refractive surgery) within the 6 previous months to study inclusion Use of contact lenses in the 3 previous months to study inclusion Use of any ocular topical medications other than the treatment for Dry Eye Syndrome Ocular treatment for Dry Eye Syndrome with corticosteroids 1 month before inclusion visit or Cyclosporin A 3 months before inclusion Diagnosis of Rosacea or Severe Blepharitis (associated to systemic or ocular pathologies) Any severe uncontrolled systemic disease that may affect the eye (except for primary or secondary Sjögren) Start, discontinuation or change within the study of the dosage of antihistaminics, cholinergic agents, beta blockers, anti depressants or any other systemic drugs with potential effects in the tear film No pregnant or breastfeeding women is allowed to participate in the study. Childbearing potential women must use contraceptive means during the whole study. Participation in another clinical trial in the last 30 days before study inclusion</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dry Eye Syndrome</keyword>
</DOC>