<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01818375</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Despite Goal Directed Fluid Therapy (GDFT) has shown a reduction of hospitalization and overall complications in patients undergoing abdominal surgery, there is a need to address the effect of implementing GDFT on the incidence of specific surgical complications and in a context of en enhanced recovery program (ERP). Specifically, studies investigating the impact of GDFT on primary postoperative ileus (POI) in patients undergoing laparoscopic colorectal surgery and using an ERP are missing. It is hypothesized that the incidence of primary POI will be reduced in patients receiving intraoperative GDFT compared to patients receiving Standard Fluid Therapy (SFT) after elective laparoscopic colorectal surgeries with an ERP program.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Goal Directed Fluid Therapy and Postoperative Ileus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Randomized Controlled Trial. Study population: elective laparoscopic colorectal resections with an Enhanced Recovery Program (ERP) Sample size: 128 patients (140 accounting for drops out) Two arms: GDFT: patients will receive GDFT esophageal doppler guided; SFT: patients will receive SFT based on standard anesthesia formula and international guidelines to calculate fluid requirements. Study Hypothesis: the incidence of primary POI will be reduced in patients receiving intraoperative GDFT compared to patients receiving SFT after elective laparoscopic colorectal surgeries with an ERP program. ERP: all patients will receive the same perioperative care according to the Enhanced Recovery After Surgery ERAS® program guidelines. Intravenous fluid will be stopped the first day after surgery. Patients will be allowed to have clear fluids the same day of surgery and diet, as tolerated, the first day after surgery.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ileus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All patients undergoing elective laparoscopic colorectal resection with an Enhanced Recovery Program 1. Age &lt;18 yr 2. Emergency surgery 3. Patients who do not understand, read or communicate in either French or English 4. Patients who had undergone esophageal or gastric surgery 5. Esophageal pathology (esophageal varices or cancer) 6. Patients with coarctation of the aorta or aortic stenosis 7. Chronic atrial fibrillation 7. Preoperative bowel obstruction 8. Coagulopathies 9. Chronic use of opioids</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>