<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01818245</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will include two groups (cohorts) of participants: In Group A, this study will look at the amount of LY2605541 that is present in the body after it is injected in 3 different locations in the body of the same participant. At least 16 days will pass between each injection. In Group B, the study will look at how the body absorbs, distributes, and gets rid of LY2605541 in participants over age 65. Participants may enroll in only one group.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of LY2605541 in Healthy Participants and in the Elderly</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Cohort A: are overtly healthy male or female participants, as determined by medical history and physical examination, aged ≥18 to ≤55 years of age Cohort B: are male or female elderly (≥65 years of age) participants that are overtly healthy, or have stable, chronic medical conditions [including Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus (T2DM)] that, in the investigator's opinion, will not significantly alter the disposition of the drug, will not place the participant at increased risk by participating in the study, and will not interfere with interpretation of the data Male participants agree to use a reliable method of birth control during the study and for 3 months following the last dose of the investigational product Female participants are women of childbearing potential who test negative for pregnancy at the time of screening based on a urine pregnancy test and agree to use a reliable method of birth control during the study and for 1 month following the last dose of the investigational product Female participants are postmenopausal women, or women not of childbearing potential due to surgical sterilization (at least 3 months after surgical hysterectomy, or at least 3 months after bilateral oophorectomy or bilateral tubal ligation/occlusion with or without hysterectomy) confirmed by medical history, or menopause Have a body mass index (BMI) of 18.5 to 40 kilogram per meter square (kg/m^2), inclusive at time of admission for Period 1 Have given written informed consent approved by Lilly and the ethical review board (ERB) governing the site Are participants that intend to start a change in diet or lose weight during the study; participants will be expected to maintain their approximate current weight throughout the study Are excessive smokers (&gt;10 cigarettes per day); participants who smoke less than or equal to (≤)10 cigarettes per day must be able to stop smoking whilst resident at the clinical research unit (CRU) Healthy Participants Cohort A Have Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus (T1DM), Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus (T2DM), or a fasting blood glucose (BG) greater than (&gt;) 110 milligrams per deciliter (mg/dL) [6.1 millimoles per liter (mmol/L)] with a glycated hemoglobin (HbA1c) of &gt;6.2% Intend to use overthecounter medication within the 7 days or prescription medication within 14 days prior to dosing (apart from contraceptive medication, vitamin/mineral supplements, occasional paracetamol, thyroxine replacement therapy, and hormone replacement therapy). Antihypertensive and lipid lowering agents are permitted, but must have been administered at stable dose(s) for at least 1 month Elderly Participants Cohort B Have T1DM Are T2DM participants that require insulin treatment, or have a HbA1c of &gt;10% Have started new chronic medication(s) or changed the dose of an existing chronic medication &lt;1 month prior to dosing. Participants are permitted to continue ongoing chronic medications (for example antihypertensive agents, aspirin, nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs, lipid lowering agents, thyroxine, hormone replacement therapy, and/or oral antidiabetic if participants have T2DM). Other stable chronic conditions may be permitted if deemed acceptable by the investigators and Lilly clinical pharmacologist or clinical research physician</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>