<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00329797</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Zoledronate may prevent bone loss in patients with prostate cancer undergoing radiation therapy and hormone therapy. It is not yet known whether zoledronate is more effective than calcium and vitamin D alone in preventing osteoporosis and bone fractures in patients with prostate cancer. PURPOSE: This randomized phase III trial is studying zoledronate to see how well it works compared to calcium and vitamin D alone in preventing osteoporosis and bone fractures in patients with locally advanced nonmetastatic prostate cancer undergoing radiation therapy and hormone therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Zoledronate in Preventing Osteoporosis and Bone Fractures in Patients With Locally Advanced Nonmetastatic Prostate Cancer Undergoing Radiation Therapy and Hormone Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Compare the potential benefit of bisphosphonate therapy comprising zoledronate plus vitamin D and calcium supplement vs standard therapy with vitamin D and calcium supplement in the prevention of osteoporosis and associated bone fractures in patients with locally advanced nonmetastatic adenocarcinoma of the prostate undergoing radiotherapy and luteinizing hormone-releasing hormone (LHRH) agonist therapy. Secondary - Evaluate the potential benefit of these regimens on quality of life in these patients. - Evaluate the potential benefit in bone mineral density over a period of 3 years for patients treated with these regimens. OUTLINE: This is randomized multicenter study. Patients are stratified according to T score of the hip by dual x-ray absorptiometry (DXA) scan (&lt; -1.0 but &gt; -2.5 vs ≥ - 1.0) and planned duration of luteinizing hormone-releasing hormone (LHRH) agonist therapy (1-2½ years vs &gt; 2½ years). Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 treatment arms. - Arm I: Parents receive zoledronate IV over 15 minutes once every 6 months. Patients also receive oral calcium and oral cholecalciferol (vitamin D) once daily. Treatment continues for 3 years in the absence of bone fractures, disease progression, or unacceptable toxicity. - Arm II: Patients receive oral calcium and oral vitamin D once daily. Treatment continues for 3 years in the absence of bone fractures, disease progression, or unacceptable toxicity. All patients also undergo concurrent radiotherapy (external beam, brachytherapy, or both) and LHRH agonist (e.g., leuprolide acetate, goserelin, buserelin, or triptorelin) therapy. Quality of life is assessed at baseline and every 6 months during treatment. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 1,272 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoporosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Zoledronic acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium, Dietary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholecalciferol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leuprolide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Buserelin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triptorelin Pamoate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Goserelin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium Carbonate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically or cytologically confirmed adenocarcinoma of the prostate Diagnosed within the past 12 months Any 1 of the following clinical stages: Clinical stage T3, any N, M0 with any Gleason score and any prostatespecific antigen (PSA) Any T, any N, M0 with one of the following: Gleason score ≥ 8 and any PSA Gleason score 7 and PSA ≥ 15 ng/mL Gleason score &lt; 7 and PSA ≥ 20 ng/mL Baseline T score &gt; 2.5 in both the L spine and the total hip by dual xray absorptiometry (DXA) scan Planning to receive luteinizing hormonereleasing hormone (LHRH) agonist therapy If patient is receiving LHRH therapy before study entry, therapy must have begun ≤ 6 months prior to study entry Scheduled to receive a LHRH agonist for ≥ 1 year Planning to undergo radiotherapy (i.e., externalbeam, brachytherapy, or both) No distant metastases Must have negative bone scan for metastatic disease PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Zubrod performance status 01 Creatinine clearance &gt; 30 mL/min Calcium 8.410.6 mg/dL Fertile patients must use effective contraception during and for ≥ 3 months after completion of study treatment No history of Paget's disease No uncontrolled thyroid or parathyroid dysfunction No known hypersensitivity to zoledronate or other bisphosphonates No infection of the teeth or jawbone No dental or fixture trauma No current or prior diagnosis of osteonecrosis of the jaw No exposed bone in the mouth No slow healing after dental procedures No other active dental problems No other diseases that influence bone metabolism No other malignancy within the past 3 years except nonmelanomatous skin cancer or carcinoma in situ of the breast or oral cavity PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: See Disease Characteristics More than 6 weeks since prior dental or jaw surgery (e.g., extraction, implants) No prior bisphosphonate therapy No prior pelvic radiation No prior systemic radiotherapeutic agents, such as strontium chloride Sr 89 or samarium Sm 153 lexidronam pentasodium No concurrent systemic chemotherapy No concurrent steroids No concurrent growth hormones No concurrent calcitonin No concurrent dental or jaw surgery</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>osteoporosis</keyword>
	<keyword>adenocarcinoma of the prostate</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIB prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIA prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV prostate cancer</keyword>
</DOC>