<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01225458</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The trial is a multicenter, prospective, randomized, open study. A total of 500 elderly patients aged over 75 years with renal insufficiency stage 5 will be included in the study after signed informed consent. Patients will be randomized 1/1 in two arms : 250 patients in the "exclusive nephrology follow-up" arm will continue their usual follow-up; 250 patients in the "geriatric follow-up" arm will have both their usual nephrology follow-up and a geriatric follow-up. The aim of the study is to determine if a systematized gerontologist evaluation delay the occurrence of a composite primary endpoint : death, dementia, depression and severe dependency. The hypothesis is that the functional and vital prognosis of a patient with renal insufficiency depends not only on common and classical factors but also on cognitive and psychological functions and dependence, particularly in elderly patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Behaviour and Cognitive Evaluation for Dialysis Elderly Patients (BCDE)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria : Patients aged of 75 years old or more, Chronic kidney disease stage 5 defined by : either an estimated GFR (MDRD) ≤ 15ml/mn/1,73 m² in a nondialysis patient with a nephrology followup &gt; 3 months ("Predialysis cohort"), or a dialysis treatment started for more than 3 months and less than one year, after a predialysis followup &gt; 3 months ("postdialysis cohort"), Signed and dated informed consent. Exclusion criteria : Moderately severe to severe dementia (MMS ≤ 15), Major depression and/or GDS15 &gt; 10/15, Severe dependency (ADL &lt; 3/6)., Psychosis, mutism or aphasia, Malignancy or any pathology with life expectancy &lt; one year. Ongoing specialized geriatric care</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>75 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Elderly patients</keyword>
	<keyword>renal insufficiency</keyword>
	<keyword>systematized gerontologic evaluation</keyword>
</DOC>