<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="133650">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01361867</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2009-P-002030</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01361867</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Robotic Assessment of Lower Extremity Motor Learning</brief_title>
  <official_title>Robotic Assessment of Lower Extremity</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Spaulding Rehabilitation Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Spaulding Rehabilitation Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators hypothesize that the motor learning processes observed in the lower
      extremity will be similar to those seen in upper arm experiments. Furthermore, the
      investigators hypothesize that lower extremity motor learning can be quantified with an
      adapted model of the force-field adaption paradigm (FFAP) introduced by Shadmehr et al. for
      studying motor learning in the upper extremities.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Current rehabilitation assessment techniques make it difficult to monitor the day to day
      changes in patient functional abilities. In an ideal setting, one would like to be able to
      observe how subtle changes in the way that therapy is delivered affects the manner and the
      time it takes patients to learn the adaptations necessary to recover lost function. To this
      end, the investigators seek to apply a paradigm that has been used to study motor learning
      in the upper extremity (the FFAP) to the Lokomat gait orthosis platform. Over the last
      decade the FFAP has been used to elucidate the mechanisms and processes that contribute to
      motor learning in the upper extremity. The broad acceptance of this paradigm within the
      motor control community sets a precedent for application to the lower extremity and its use
      in clinical environments.

      Implementation of the FFAP in the Lokomat system will allow motor learning to be assessed
      during lower extremity motor tasks. Such a tool could be used to systemically assess the
      effectiveness of different aspects of therapy, such as the effects of training session
      duration, number of exercise repetitions, inter-trial (inter-session) intervals, and
      magnitude of perturbation.

      In this initial pilot, the investigators seek to apply our Lokomat implementation of the
      FFAP to healthy adult subjects in order to understand the feasibility of this approach and
      form a database of healthy subject learning rates. This initial step will allow us to bridge
      the scientific gap between lower extremity and upper limb motor learning research, while
      yielding data that can serve as a basis of comparison for future studies with patients.
      Additionally, such a methodology would suggest new avenues of research for lower limb motor
      learning and create an increased understanding of the motor principles that govern the
      spectrum of human movements.

      Ultimately, by understanding the fundamental motor learning principles that drive
      neurorehabilitation the investigators can better understand what makes rehabilitation
      successful and attempt to better improve current rehabilitation protocols.

      Before the testing session begins, the subject will be placed within the Lokomat by securing
      subjects at the trunk, pelvis, and lower extremities using adjustable cuffs with Velcro
      straps, so that the hip and knee joints are aligned to those of the Lokomat. Each testing
      session will begin with walking for approximately 5 minutes in the standard clinical mode of
      operation.

      Optional use of body weight support and foot straps can be used to ensure subject is walking
      comfortably within the Lokomat. Clinical mode allows subject to be walked by the Lokomat
      along a predefined trajectory with the pace of the treadmill matched to the robotic legs.
      After subject has acclimated to Lokomat walking, the motor learning experiments will begin.
      The format of the motor learning experiments is as follows:

        -  &quot;Free-run mode&quot;- Subject walks as normally as possible within the Lokomat, while the
           Lokomat compensates for its own weight, but does not restrict the subject's movements.
           Subject's walking pattern is recorded as the baseline movements of the experiment.

        -  Force field mode- Subject experiences small force perturbations from the Lokomat. These
           forces are perpendicular to their path (moving the foot upward), velocity dependent,
           and occur primarily in swing phase (when velocity is greatest). These forces are able
           to slightly alter the subject's walking trajectory. This generates error which drives
           the motor learning system and causes adaptation, which takes the form of compensatory
           forces equal and opposite to the force field. It is important to note that any forces
           outside the standard Lokomat safety range will not be experienced by the subject since
           the standard safety limits for clinical use remain present in the device.

        -  Error clamp mode- Similar to the clinical mode, where the subject is limited to walking
           along a predefined trajectory, during the error clamp mode, the subject is required to
           walk along their average baseline trajectory (recorded during the Free-run mode), but
           can do so at the speed of their choosing. Error clamp trials are interspersed between
           force field trials, and used to measure adaptive compensatory forces. Any forces not
           used to move the subject along the path are instead compensatory forces that reflect
           the subject's adaptation. These forces can be measured throughout the experiment and
           used to infer the subjects' rate of learning.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>February 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of subject motor adaptation</measure>
    <time_frame>4 hours</time_frame>
    <description>rate subject motor adaptation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy Subjects</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lokomat session</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The subject is put on the Lokomat and the program will vary between free walking and perturbed walking.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lokomat</intervention_name>
    <description>The subject is put into the Lokomat and the program will vary between free walking and perturbed walking.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lokomat session</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Males and females, healthy adults age 18-55 years, with normal gait.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Lower extremity fractures

          -  Current or previous history of orthopedic injury that would prevent safe use of the
             Lokomat

          -  Body/femoral length size beyond the limits of Lokomat robotic arm (femur length
             between 350-470mm)

          -  Body weight &gt; 135kg (~298 lbs) maximum limit of the body weight support system

          -  Skin lesions on the lower extremities

          -  Cardiovascular or pulmonary contraindications

          -  Motor system or proprioceptive impairments

          -  Severe cognitive impairments that would prevent the use of the Lokomat
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Paolo Bonato, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Spaulding Rehabilitation Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Spaulding Rehabilitation Hospital Boston</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02129</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>January 3, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>May 25, 2011</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Spaulding Rehabilitation Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Paolo Bonato</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director, Motion Analysis Laboratory</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>motor adaptation</keyword>
  <keyword>force-field adaptation paradigm</keyword>
  <keyword>lower extremity motor learning</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
