<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02512692</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the safety and maximum tolerated dose (MTD) of 90 Y TARE (Y90) in combination with gemcitabine and cisplatin in patients with unresectable intrahepatic cholangiocarcinoma (ICC).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>90Y Transarterial Radioembolization (TARE) Plus Gemcitabine and Cisplatin in Unresectable Intrahepatic Cholangiocarcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Cholangiocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologic Documentation: Core needle biopsy or surgical specimen that confirms intrahepatic cholangiocarcinoma (ICC). Patients must be determined to be unresectable by a multidisciplinary team that includes a hepatobiliary surgeon. No prior liver radiation therapy or immunotherapy for cholangiocarcinoma. Only previous single agent chemotherapy for ICC allowed. Patient may have prior liver resection. Age &gt; 18 years of age. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status &lt; 2 (see Appendix E) Child's Pugh score of A (see Appendix F) Life expectancy of greater than 4 months Normal organ and marrow function as outlined in the protocol. Willingness to use effective contraceptive methods during the study. Patient may participate in the female (or female partner of male subject), either is not of childbearing potential (defined as postmenopausal for &gt; 1 year or surgically sterile) or is practicing two forms of contraception. Sexually active male participants must agree to use a physical barrier method (male latex rubber condom with or without spermicide). Patients with well controlled HIV infection are eligible if their CD4 count is &gt;499/cu mm and viral load is &lt; 50 copies/ml. Precertification for the 90Y TARE should be performed prior to enrollment on this study. All patients must be informed of the investigational nature of this study and must have the ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document. Patients who have had major surgery within 4 weeks prior to entering the study or those who have not recovered from complications from a surgery more than 4 weeks earlier. Patients may not be receiving any other investigational agents. Patients must not have any grade III/IV cardiac disease as defined by the New York Heart Association (NYHA) Criteria Patients must NOT have liver disease such as cirrhosis or sever hepatic impairment as defined by ChildPugh Class B or C Pregnant women are excluded from this study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>intrahepatic cholangiocarcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>cholangiocarcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>90Y TARE</keyword>
	<keyword>radioembolization</keyword>
	<keyword>gemcitabine and cisplatin</keyword>
</DOC>