<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02348502</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Chronic hepatitis B (CHB) is a serious liver disease worldwide, and the leading cause of cirrhosis and hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC). HBsAg loss/seroconversion is considered to be the ideal endpoint of antiviral therapy in both HBeAg-positive and -negative patients, and the ultimate treatment goal in CHB, However HBsAg loss occurred rarely by interferon treatment. Although It was reported that in nature history HBsAg level≤100 IU/ml can bring good long term outcomes in patients with chronic hepatitis B. it was not clear whether patients who achieved HBsAg level≤100 IU/ml by interferon treatment could maintain sustained viral response and the state of HBsAg level≤100 IU/ml.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sustained Viral Response in Patients Achieved HBsAg Level≤100 IU/ml After Completed Interferon Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The patients with chronic hepatitis B and achieved HBsAg level≤100 IU/ml after completed interferon treatment will be enrolled and observed for 96 weeks. Serum HBV DNA, HBsAg, anti-HBs, HBeAg, and anti-HBe will be measured every 3 months during the observation period, liver function tests were performed every 3 months also. The liver ultrasonic examination would be taken every 3-6 months. The primary endpoint is HBV DNA reaction. The secondary endpoints is HBsAg loss.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients who had chronic hepatitis B and achieved HBsAg level≤100 IU/ml with undetectable HBV DNA level by interferon treatment Active consumption of alcohol and/or drugs Coinfection with human immunodeficiency virus, hepatitis C virus, or hepatitis D virus History of autoimmune hepatitis Psychiatric disease Evidence of neoplastic diseases of the liver</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>HBsAg loss</keyword>
	<keyword>interferon</keyword>
	<keyword>HBV reaction</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatitis B</keyword>
</DOC>