<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01237574</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Chronic alcoholic and metabolic liver diseases are the two main liver diseases in France. The long-term prognosis of these two diseases are not well known because main studies are retrospective and with only alcoholic patients. The knowledge of the natural history of these diseases should improve the management of patients with such diseases. The aim of this prospective cohort is to describe the natural history of patients with chronic liver disease due to alcohol or metabolic disease and to identify factors associated with complications of these liver diseases (cirrhosis, hepatocellular carcinoma, ascites. ..).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multicentre Prospective Cohort Study of Patients With Chronic Alcoholic and/or Metabolic Liver Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In 2010, the two most frequent chronic liver diseases are alcoholic and metabolic disease. The natural history of these two diseases is not well known. Indeed, most of the studies were retrospective and evaluated alcoholic disease or metabolic disease but never both diseases. However, these two diseases have the same histological lesions and can be associated. The knowledge of the natural history of these diseases could improve the management of patients in order to decrease complications and improve survival. The aim of this prospective study is to describe the natural history of chronic liver disease due to alcohol and/or metabolic syndrome and to identify factors associated with complications (ascites, encephalopathy, death, complications of obesity, diabetes or chronic alcohol abuse). All patients will be followed every 6 months for 3 years with clinical, biological and morphological parameters.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Diseases, Alcoholic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age over 18 years chronic liver disease (liver biopsy with bridging fibrosis or cirrhosis) or noninvasive markers of fibrosis (fibrotest &gt; 0.58, FibroScan &gt; 7.9 kPa) no decompensated cirrhosis chronic alcohol use and/or metabolic syndrome (at least 3 criteria of metabolic syndrome) Written informed consent Patient covered by the French health insurance system short term life threatening disease Other cirrhosis causes Impossibility of regular followup Under guardianship major Patient Presence of focal hurt suggestive of CHC pregnant women cirrhosis complication Childpugh score superior or equal to 7</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Liver Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Alcoholic</keyword>
	<keyword>Metabolic Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>cohort</keyword>
	<keyword>liver disease</keyword>
</DOC>