<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01237704</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In Hong Kong, every 30 and 12.9 in 100,000 males and females respectively has nasopharyngeal carcinoma (NPC). With early detection and advances in medical care, the number of NPC survivors post radiotherapy is rapidly growing in Hong Kong. One of the most distressing consequences post radiotherapy for NPC patients is swallowing disorder, or dysphagia. Dysphagia in NPC patients almost certainly cause frequent chest infection, dehydration, malnutrition and limitations to concurrent treatment such as oral medication. Given the existing large costs NPC patients incur to the healthcare system, dysphagia only serves to further inflate the soaring costs. In an attempt to reduce dysphagia related costs to the healthcare system, swallowing rehabilitation is offered to NPC patients. Currently, two major swallowing rehabilitation approaches are commonly adopted. The first is traditional rehabilitation, which involves patients performing various oropharyngeal exercises aimed at improving swallowing physiology. The other swallowing rehabilitation approach is transcutaneous electrical stimulation, which entails using small amount of electric current to increase muscle strength while patients are engaged in swallowing activities. These two methods are proven as effective in patients with stroke and head and neck carcinoma patients. Neither of these methods, nevertheless, yields any efficacy studies in treating NPC patients. Yet, clinicians continue to use either one or both rehabilitation methods as swallowing rehabilitation. This study aims to address the gap in efficacy studies on swallowing rehabilitation for NPC patients post radiotherapy. The research results should provide justification for rehabilitation time, clinicians' efforts, costs involved and resources used in rehabilitating the swallowing difficulties of the NPC patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dysphagia Rehabilitation for Nasopharyngeal Carcinoma Patients Post Radiotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nasopharyngeal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>able 18 years of age undergone primary radiotherapy or chemoradiotherapy as the treatment are expected to complete the 12 month followup prior history of head and neck surgery except biopsies of the NP or the neck nodes previous history or having a concurrent neoplasm other than NPC other severe medical problems that might contribute to dysphagia, e.g. cerebral vascular accident, neuromuscular diseases, respiratory diseases that may cause dysphagia present contraindications for the use of electrical stimulation which include pregnancy, pacemaker, other implanted electrodes or significant reflux nonoral feeding is contemplated in prior to treatment inability to complete the assessment including cognitive impairment of a low life expectancy related to NPC or other illnesses history of dysphagia prior to radiotherapy or chemoradiotherapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>