<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01482000</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the exercise capacity and pulmonary function test parameters of Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) patients who underwent usual care with and without pulmonary daoyin therapy of China in community.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Does Pulmonary Daoyin of China Give Additional Benefit Over Usual Therapy in Management of Stable Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease?</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a multicenter, randomized, none-blind, controlled study to evaluate the effect of pulmonary daoyin therapy in moderate to very severe COPD subjects. Following a 14 day run-in period, approximately 464 subjects will be randomly assigned to none-blind treatment for 3 months. The primary measure of efficacy is the Exercise Capacity (6MWD) and spirometric values (e.g. FEV1). Secondary efficacy measures include Dyspnea (MMRC), Quality of life (CAT,SF-36), frequency of exacerbations. Safety will be assessed through the collection of adverse events. There will be a total of 4 study visits (randomization, and after 1,2,3 months of treatment).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>A confirmed diagnosis of moderate to very severe COPD. Age between 40 and 80 years. Without participation in other interventional trials in the previous one month. With the informed consent signed. Patients with poor mobility that can not do the exercise, i.e. wheelchair bound. Pregnant or breastfeeding women. Resting pulmonary artery pressure &gt; 45mmHg. Any psychiatric condition rendering the patient unable to understand the nature, scope and possible consequences of the study. Patients with severe comorbidities, including acute myocardial infarction and unstable angina pectoris. Patients with post exercise syncope and osteoarthrosis that affect movement. Complicated with severe heart failure (class II to IV NYHA heart function). Complicated with bronchial asthma, bronchiectasis or active tuberculosis; Complicated with obliterative bronchiolitis or diffuse pantothenic bronchiolitis， Complicated with pneumothorax, pleural effusion or pulmonary embolism. Complicated with neuromuscular disorder which affects the respiration. Complicated with tumors . Complicated with serious hepatic and renal diseases. Long periods of bed rest . Participating in other trials or allergic to the used medicine.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</keyword>
	<keyword>Adult</keyword>
	<keyword>therapeutic use</keyword>
	<keyword>Humans</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment Outcome</keyword>
	<keyword>daoyin therapy</keyword>
</DOC>