<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01487096</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study was to determine the safety and efficacy of teriflunomide in multiple sclerosis (MS) with relapses. Secondary objectives were: - To determine the effect of teriflunomide on additional magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) variables as well as clinical and quality of life measures. - To investigate the pharmacokinetic and pharmacodynamic relationships.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of Teriflunomide (HMR1726) in Multiple Sclerosis With Relapses</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The total duration of the study period per participants was 46 weeks comprising 3 periods: - a 4-week screening period, - a 36-week double-blind treatment period, - a 6-week post-treatment follow-up period. Participants who successfully completed the double-blind treatment phase were offered the possibility to continue study treatment in the extension study LTS6048 - NCT00228163.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clinically confirmed multiple sclerosis [MS]; Expanded Disability Status Scale [EDSS] score less or equal to 6; Two documented relapses in the previous 3 years, and one clinical relapse during the preceding year; Screening magnetic resonance imaging [MRI] scan fulfilling the criteria for a diagnosis of MS. Clinically relevant cardiovascular, hepatic, hematologic, neurological, endocrine or other major systemic disease; Pregnant or nursing woman; Wish to parent children during the trial or following the trial (men and women were required to practice effective contraception during the trial and for 24 months after drug discontinuation); Prior treatment with interferon [IFN], gammaglobulin, glatiramer acetate, or other noncorticosteroid immunomodulatory therapies in the 4 months prior to the trial; Use of cladribine, mitoxantrone, or other immunosuppressant agents such as azathioprine, cyclophosphamide, cyclosporin, methotrexate or mycophenolate before enrollment; Any known condition or circumstance that would prevent in the investigator's opinion compliance or completion of the study. The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>