<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02626611</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a phase 2 randomized, double-blind, placebo controlled study which will be conducted at multiple centers in the U.S. All subjects will receive oral immunotherapy for their specific food allergies (limited to 5 of those food allergens in Investigational New Drug (IND) 14831). All subjects will receive Omalizumab for 16 weeks. The subject's allergens will be introduced in a rush desensitization day at week 8. Subjects will return to clinic to escalate the dose of their allergens until 2,000mg protein of each allergen is reached Subjects will return to clinic for a DBPCFC to each allergen at week 30. If subjects are nonreactive to 2 or more allergens during their DBPCFC at week 30 they will be randomized to one of three double blinded arms: Arm A- continue with current dose (2000 mg each food allergen protein), Arm B-300 mg of each food allergen protein, Arm C-placebo (avoiding food allergen protein), their current dose. All subjects will return to clinic for a DBPCFC to each allergen at week 36. The final challenge of week 36 will be the final end of study visit. Safety is a paramount concern in the study design and will be monitored carefully throughout the study. Study subjects and their parents/guardians will receive extensive education on food allergy reactions and medication use.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multi Immunotherapy to Test Tolerance and Xolair</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigators will enroll multi food allergic subjects (4-55 years of age) with proven multi food allergies. The investigators anticipate enrolling 70 subjects with multi food allergies at more than one site. Subjects must have food specific Immunoglobulin E &gt;4 kilo Units/Liter for each allergen or a skin test reactivity to each food allergen greater than or equal to 6mm wheal diameter. In addition, subjects must have a total Immunoglobulin E &lt;2,000 kilo Units/Liter, a clinical reaction during a double blind placebo controlled food challenge (DBPCFC) with food protein/powder to establish sensitivity to given food protein/powder (pecan, milk, egg, peanut, almond, wheat, cashew, sesame seed, soy, walnut, hazelnut, shrimp, cod, salmon) and no clinical reaction during placebo (oat) as per Chemistry Manufacturing and Control section of Investigational New Drug. Each subject is planned to be enrolled in the active phase of the study for 36 weeks. Food protein and powder will be obtained and prepared as per Investigational New Drug 14831 and will be in compliance with all applicable regulations. Omalizumab is approved by the European Medicines Agency (European FDA) for patients with severe asthma &gt;6 years of age, and by the US FDA for patients &gt;12 years of age. Omalizumab will be dosed according to Genentech Dosing Omalizumab will be provided by the site.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Food Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Omalizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participant and/or parent guardian must be able to understand and provide informed consent and/or assent as applicable. Age 4 to 55 years with moderate to severe allergy to milk and/or egg and/or peanut and/or almond and/or wheat and/or cashew and/or sesame seed and/or soy and/or pecan and/or walnut and/or hazelnut Positive skin prick test result greater than or equal to 6 mm wheal diameter to each allergen OR ImmunoCAP Immunoglobulin E (IgE) level &gt;4 kilo Unit/Liter for each allergen and A clinical reaction during a DBPCFC to small doses of food defined as &lt; dose of 500 mg food protein No clinical reaction observed during the placebo (oat) challenge and If female, must have a negative urine pregnancy test on the same day (using a Clinical Laboratory Improvement Amendment (CLIA) approved urine test) If female, of childbearing potential, must agree to be compliant with a medicallyapproved method of contraception (please see Pregnancy section under Patient Disposition in this protocol) Plan to remain in the study area of the research center during the trial Be trained on the proper use of the Epinephrine autoinjector Avoid open or blinded food challenges to other allergens outside this study Inability or unwillingness of a participant/parent/guardian to give written informed consent or comply with study protocol History of cardiovascular disease History of other chronic disease (other than asthma, atopic dermatitis, or rhinitis) requiring therapy (e.g., heart disease, diabetes) that, in the opinion of the Principal Investigator, would represent a risk to the participant's health or safety in this study or the participant's ability to comply with the study protocol A total IgE at screening of &gt;2,000 kU/L Previous adverse reaction to Xolair A history of severe anaphylaxis (defined as requiring intubation or admission to an ICU) to food allergens that will be used in this study Unstable angina, significant arrhythmia, uncontrolled hypertension, current smokers, chronic sinusitis, or other chronic or immunological diseases that, in the judgment of the investigator, might interfere with the evaluation or administration of the test drug or pose additional risk to the participant. Current use of oral, intramuscular, or intravenous corticosteroids, tricyclic antidepressants, or betablockers (oral or topical) Routine use of medication that could induce adverse gastrointestinal reactions during the study Refusing to sign the Epinephrine autoinjector Training Form Pregnant or breast feeding women A history of oat allergy (since oat is the placebo agent in the DBPCFC), or an objective reaction to the screening DBPCFC to oat Unwilling to avoid all food allergencontaining items except those given as part of the Oral Immunotherapy as well as any other food allergens you are allergic to that are not included in the 10 foods listed in the study Concurrent/prior use of immunomodulatory therapy (within 1 month) ie, omalizumab, nontraditional forms of allergen immunotherapy (e.g., oral or sublingual) Severe asthma (2007 National Heart Lung and Blood Institute (NHLBI) Criteria Steps 5 or 6) at time of enrollment Mild or moderate asthma (2007 NHLBI Criteria Steps 14) at time of enrollment with any of the following criteria met: Forced Expiratory Volume at one second (FEV1) &lt; 80% of predicted, or FEV1/Forced Vital Capacity (FVC) &lt; 75%, with or without controller medications (only for age 6 or greater and able to do spirometry) or Inhaled Corticosteroid (ICS) dosing of &gt; 220 mcg daily fluticasone (or equivalent inhaled corticosteroids based on NHLBI dosing chart) or 1 hospitalization in the past year for asthma or ER visit for asthma within the past six months Use of steroid medications (Intravenous (IV), Intramuscular (IM) or oral) in the following manners history of daily oral steroid dosing for &gt;1 month during the past year or steroid burst course ( 5 or more days) of 1 mg/kg prednisone) course in the past 3 months or &gt;2 steroid burst courses in the past year Use of complementary and alternative medicine (CAM) treatment modalities (e.g., herbal remedies) for atopic and/or nonatopic disease within 90 days preceding rush desensitization at week 8or at any time . Inability to discontinue antihistamines for the initial day of escalation, skin testing or Oral Food Challenges (OFCs) Use of investigational drugs within 24 weeks of participation Past or current medical problems or findings from physical assessment or laboratory testing that are not listed above, which, in the opinion of the investigator, may pose additional risks from participation in the study, may interfere with the participant's ability to comply with study requirements or that may impact the quality or interpretation of the data obtained from the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>