<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02626793</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this Non-interventional study (NIS) is the collection of data on the utilization of Apremilast under routine conditions in Germany. Patients' quality-of-life and treatment satisfaction on treatment with Apremilast in daily practice will be documented. Moreover, physician's and patient's assessments of the effectiveness and safety of Apremilast will be recorded.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Otezla® in Patients With Plaque Psoriasis Under Routine Conditions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The objective of this NIS (according to section 67(6) of the German Medicinal Products Act) is the documentation of data on the effectiveness and tolerability of an Apremilast treatment under routine clinical conditions in German patients with plaque psoriasis. This NIS is intended to reflect the apremilast treatment of patients with plaque psoriasis who have received at least one prior conventional, systemic therapy or, if a contraindication is present, did not receive a systemic therapy so far, and who were diagnosed by their treating physicians to be eligible for an apremilast treatment. The treatment of Apremilast will be documented for a period of approximately 52 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Psoriasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Apremilast</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The decision for a therapy with Apremilast was made before enrolment and independent of this study. Patient ≥ 18 years of age Diagnosis of moderate to severe plaque psoriasis Inadequate response or intolerance to a previous systemic treatment, or contraindication for systemic therapies. Written informed consent by the patient for data recording, statistical analysis, filing and forwarding of the data Pregnancy Hypersensitivity to apremilast or any of the excipients of the filmcoated tablet Other criteria according to the Summary of product characteristics (SmPC).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Plaque psoriasis</keyword>
	<keyword>Apremilast</keyword>
	<keyword>Otezla®</keyword>
	<keyword>LAPIS-Pso</keyword>
	<keyword>Observational</keyword>
	<keyword>CC-10004</keyword>
	<keyword>non-interventional</keyword>
	<keyword>Germany</keyword>
</DOC>