<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00107120</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Depression affects approximately 2.5% of children and 8% of adolescents. Escitalopram is the S-enantiomer of citalopram. Both escitalopram and citalopram are selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs) and are used to treat depression in adults. This study is designed to provide a systematic evaluation of the safety and efficacy of escitalopram in the treatment of depressed pediatric patients, 12 to 17 years of age. Patients completing the study will be eligible to enter an open-label extension study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Safety and Efficacy of Escitalopram in Pediatric Patients With Major Depressive Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Citalopram</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexetimide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient must meet Diagnostic and Statistical Manual, Fourth Edition (DSMIV) diagnostic criteria for Major Depressive Disorder. Patient's current depressive episode must be at least 12 weeks in duration Patient must have a parent or caregiver who must agree to accompany the patient to all clinic visits. Patients who currently meet DSMIV criteria for: 1. attention deficithyperactivity disorder 2. obsessivecompulsive disorder 3. posttraumatic stress disorder 4. bipolar disorder 5. pervasive developmental disorder 6. mental retardation 7. conduct disorder 8. oppositional defiant disorder Patients who are considered a suicide risk (have active suicidal ideation), who have made a suicide attempt, or who have ever been hospitalized because of a suicide attempt.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Major Depressive Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Depression</keyword>
	<keyword>Adolescents</keyword>
	<keyword>Escitalopram</keyword>
	<keyword>Pediatrics</keyword>
</DOC>