<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00107081</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether, in children with cancer presenting with fever in severe chemotherapy-induced neutropenia at low risk for medical complications, oral antibiotics in an outpatient setting after an initial phase of intravenous antibiotics and in-hospital observation for 8 to 22 hours, is not inferior as to safety and efficacy compared to continued intravenous antibiotics given in-hospital.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Low-risk Fever and Neutropenia in Children With Cancer: Safety and Efficacy of Oral Antibiotics in an Outpatient Setting</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Details on antimicrobial therapy - At presentation with FN (fever and neutropenia) and during an initial inpatient observation period of 8 to 22 hours, empirical intravenous broad-spectrum antibiotics are given. Type and dosage are chosen by the treating physician. - Patients randomized to continued intravenous antibiotics continue with these antibiotics. - Patients randomized to oral antibiotics receive a combination of oral ciprofloxacin (25 to 30 mg/kg/day, top dose 1500 mg/day) plus oral amoxicillin (65 to 80 mg/kg/day, top dose 2250 mg/day), both given in two doses per day. - In both groups, the study gives guidelines (for certain situations) and rules (for other situations) when to change and when to stop antibiotics. Details on clinical and laboratory controls - During antibiotic therapy, patients are seen daily, either as inpatients or as outpatients according to randomization. Complete blood counts are performed at least every second day. - After stopping antibiotic therapy and until resolution of severe neutropenia (if applicable), patients are seen every other day, with a complete blood count. - Patients randomized to outpatient management have the possibility to contact at any time of the day (and night) a pediatric oncologist in case of problems, in order to discuss necessity for emergency control and/or rehospitalization.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fever</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neutropenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Bacterial Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ciprofloxacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amoxicillin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibiotics, Antitubercular</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Chemotherapy because of malignancy Severe neutropenia (absolute neutrophil count ≤ 0.5x10E9/L) Fever (axillary temperature ≥ 38.5°C once or ≥ 38.0°C during ≥ 2 hours) Able to swallow oral medication Written informed consent from patients and/or parents Status post myeloablative chemotherapy Diagnosis: acute myeloid leukemia, Bcell acute lymphoblastic leukemia, or Bcell NonHodgkin lymphoma Bone marrow involvement by malignancy ≥ 25% Any comorbidity requiring hospitalization: [1] mean arterial blood pressure &lt; 50 mmHg (up to 10 years) / &lt; 60 mmHg (older than 10 years); [2] oxygen saturation &lt; 94% at room air; [3] radiologically defined pneumonia; [4] focal bacterial infection; [5] blood cultures taken at presentation reported positive at reassessment; [6] need for inpatient treatment or observation due to any other reason, as judged by the physician in charge Ever shaking chills Ever axillary temperature ≥ 39.5°C Antibacterial treatment before presentation with fever and neutropenia (except for prevention against Pneumocystis jiroveci [formerly P. carinii] pneumonia) Modification or de novo institution of a prophylaxis against P. jiroveci pneumonia Modification or de novo institution of a therapy with GCSF or GMCSF. Allergy to ciprofloxacin and/or amoxicillin Serum creatinine level above the upper limit of normal range</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>children</keyword>
	<keyword>oral antibiotics</keyword>
	<keyword>outpatient treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>fever and neutropenia</keyword>
</DOC>