<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02718898</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of the study drug ixekizumab compared to placebo in participants with moderate-to-severe genital psoriasis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Ixekizumab (LY2439821) in Participants With Moderate-to-Severe Genital Psoriasis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Psoriasis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Have chronic plaque psoriasis based on a diagnosis of chronic plaque psoriasis for at least 6 months before baseline. Have moderatetosevere psoriasis in the genital area at screening and baseline. Have plaque psoriasis in a nongenital area at screening and baseline. Have failed to respond to, or are intolerant of, at least 1 topical therapy used for treatment of psoriasis affecting the genital area. Must agree to use reliable method of birth control, which could include abstinence, during the study and for at least 12 weeks following the last dose of study drug. Pustular, erythrodermic, and/or guttate forms of psoriasis. History of druginduced psoriasis. Have recently received certain treatments for psoriasis (in particular, within the past 4 weeks but the restriction can go up to 12 months for some treatments). Have ever received treatment with ixekizumab, secukinumab, brodalumab, or another drug with a similar mode of action. Cannot avoid excessive sun exposure or use of tanning booths for at least 4 weeks prior to baseline and during the study. Are currently enrolled in any other clinical trial involving an investigational product. Serious disorder or illness other than plaque psoriasis. Active or history of malignant disease within 5 years prior to baseline. Serious infection within the last 3 months. Have received a live vaccine within 3 months of baseline or plan to do so during the study. Have received a vaccination with Bacillus CalmetteGuérin (BCG) within the past year. Pregnant or breastfeeding (lactating) women.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>genital</keyword>
</DOC>