<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02419170</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this research study is to study the safety and immune response of people who receive a personalized dendritic cell vaccine with the intention of stimulating the immune system to react to lung cancer cells.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mature Dendritic Cell Vaccination Against Unique Immunogenic Peptides in Patients With Non Small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Tumor vaccines represent a promising area of clinical investigation in solid tumors based on evidence of clinical activity and minimal toxicity. The underlying hypothesis of this research is that immunization against tumor neoantigens is effectively required to elicit antigen-reactive T cells capable of recognizing and eliminating cancer. Moreover, both quantitative and qualitative improvements in CD8 immunity are necessary (but not sufficient) for clinical response and improved survival. The goal of this study is to build on our prior clinical trial results in melanoma by studying the immune response to tumor neoantigens in patients with stage 1 NSCLC.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with completely resected stage I nonsmall cell lung cancer who are not considered for adjuvant post operative therapy. Age ≥ 18 years. ECOG performance status 01. HLAA2 positive. Required initial laboratory values (submitted within 14 days prior to registration): WBC &gt; 3,000/mm3 Hg ≥ 9.0 gm/dL Platelets &gt;75,000/mm3 Serum bilirubin &lt; 2.0 mg/dL Serum creatinine &lt; 2.0 mg/dL Sexually active women of childbearing potential must use effective birth control during the trial and for at least two months following the trial, and sexually active men must be willing to avoid fathering a new child while receiving therapy. Able to understand and willing to sign an IRBapproved written informed consent document. Prior treatment with cytotoxic chemotherapy Prior treatment with targeted therapy or immunotherapy. Active untreated CNS metastasis. Active infection. Prior malignancy (except nonmelanoma skin cancer) within 3 years. Pregnant or nursing. Concurrent treatment with systemic corticosteroids; local (inhaled or topical) steroids are permitted. Known allergy to eggs. Prior history or uveitis or autoimmune inflammatory eye disease. Known positivity for hepatitis B sAg, hepatitis C antibody, or HIV antibody.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>