<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02419183</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the psychometric properties of a Self-administered Memory Screening Test with Automated Reporting (SAMSTAR) adapted from the Rey Auditory Verbal Learning Test (RAVLT) in normal control (NC) participants and participants with Mild Cognitive Impairment (MCI) against a standard version of the RAVLT test, administered by an examiner under the same conditions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of a Self-Administered Memory Screening Test With Automated Reporting (SAMSTAR) in Participants With Mild Cognitive Impairment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a single-center (when only one hospital or medical school team work on a medical research study), randomized (participants are assigned to treatment by a chance), crossover (participants may receive different treatments sequentially during the trial) study. The study consists of a Screening Phase (Day -3 up to and including Day 1), Test Phase (Test Day 1 and Test Day 2 [within 7 to 14 days following Test Day 1]) and an optional follow-up visit within 7 days after the last study-related activity for participants who experienced an adverse event that had not resolved by the end of the last test visit.The NC and MCI participants will initially either undergo a standard version of the RAVLT test or the SAMSTAR version of the RAVLT test on Test Day 1 or on the same day as screening, with follow-up testing using the other test using a crossover design to be conducted within 1 to 2 weeks at the same venue (Test Day 2). There will be a 7-to 14-day memory washout period between the test periods. No investigational medicinal product will be administered. The maximum study duration for a participant will not exceed 3 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mild Cognitive Impairment</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participant must have normal visual and hearing acuity (corrected or uncorrected) as assessed in the Screening cognitive test (MoCA) Screening Criteria: 1. NC participants: meet inclusion/exclusion criteria, Dementia Screening Interview (8 item) (AD8) score 01, MoCA score 28 or higher (educationadjusted) 2. MCI participants: meet inclusion/exclusion criteria, AD8 score 2 or higher, MoCA score 24 to 27 (educationadjusted) Participant must be Englishspeaking and able to understand and follow the examiner/trial instructions Each participant must sign an informed consent form (ICF) indicating that he or she understands the purpose of and procedures required for the study and are willing to participate in the study Participant has an acute or chronic medical condition (eg, Alzheimer's disease [AD] or depression) that would interfere with the participant's ability to complete either memory test assessment or comply with other study requirements Participant has an acute or chronic psychiatric condition that would interfere with the participant's ability to complete either memory test assessment or comply with other study requirements Participant has any acute or chronic neurological conditions (eg, stroke, epilepsy, Parkinson's disease) Participant has any sensory, motor or speech impairment that would interfere with the participants' ability to complete memory testing that relies on speech recognition Participant has any condition for which, in the opinion of the investigator, participation would not be in the best interest of the participant (eg, compromise the wellbeing) or that could prevent, limit, or confound the protocolspecified assessments</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>84 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Mild Cognitive Impairment</keyword>
	<keyword>Self-Administered Memory Screening Test With Automated Reporting (SAMSTAR)</keyword>
	<keyword>Rey Auditory Verbal Learning Test (RAVLT)</keyword>
	<keyword>Word List Recall (WLR)</keyword>
</DOC>