<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02419885</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Fingertips facilitate smooth motor activity, precise sensation, and the delicate movement of the hands and have an aesthetic function. Fingertip injuries are defined as injuries occurring distal to the insertion of the flexor and extensor tendons. These injuries are one of the most common trauma injuries presented in acute care settings, accounting for approximately 4.8 million emergency department visits per year in the United States.(1) Fingertip amputations may not constitute the majority among these fingertip injuries but can have a complex spectrum of injury. In these cases, the reconstruction methodologies focus on preserving the digital length, ensuring adequate soft tissue coverage, preserving the nail structure, achieving a well-contoured and painless fingertip, and restoring durable and sensate skin. There are so many factor that influence the result of composite graft in distal finger tip amputation. Investigators will collected the data including the size of amputee , shape, level of amputation, mechanism of amputation, if hyperbaric oxygen therapy, operation procedures.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Result and Influence Factors on Composite Graft in Fingertip Amputation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Fingertip amputations underwent 1. modified composite grafting with pulp Adipo-fascia advance flap 2. composite graft 3. revision amputation was collected in this study Follow-up was arranged in out-patient department, including: type of amputation ( Hirase classification, ) 2-point discrimination test, DASH(Disabilities of the Arm, Shoulder, and Hand) outcome measure, graft survival, pain evaluation with visual Analog scale other associated treatment such as hyperbaric oxygen therapy length of finger shortening at 6 month after operation</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Amputation, Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Somatosensory Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>February 1990 and June 2015, patients received composite graft in fingertip amputation patients refused to participate the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 1990</verification_date>
	<keyword>finger amputation</keyword>
	<keyword>composite graft</keyword>
	<keyword>adipo-fascia flap</keyword>
</DOC>