<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02124148</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main purpose of this study is to investigate the safety of prexasertib in combination with other anti-cancer drugs (cisplatin, cetuximab, pemetrexed, fluorouracil or LY3023414) in participants with advanced cancer or cancer that has spread to another part of the body. The study has multiple parts (A, B, C, D and E). Participants will only enroll in one part.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Prexasertib (LY2606368) With Chemotherapy or Targeted Agents in Participants With Advanced Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary purpose of Parts A, B, C, D and E of this study is to determine a recommended dose level and schedule of prexasertib (an inhibitor of checkpoint kinase 1 and 2 [CHK1/CHK2] in combination with: - cisplatin (Part A) - cetuximab (Part B) - pemetrexed (Part C) - fluorouracil (Part D) - LY3023414 (Part E) [An inhibitor of phosphoinositide 3-kinase alpha (PI3K alpha) and mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR), DNA-dependent protein kinase (DNA-PK), and other class I phosphoinositide 3-kinase (PI3K) family members] in participants with advanced or metastatic cancer. Part A dose expansion of the study will evaluate the safety and toxicity of prexasertib at the recommended dose level in combination with cisplatin in participants with advanced or metastatic cancer, Part B dose expansion of the study will evaluate the safety and toxicity of prexasertib at the recommended dose level in combination with cetuximab in participants with advanced or metastatic colorectal cancer, Part C dose expansion of the study will evaluate the safety and toxicity of prexasertib at the recommended dose level in combination with pemetrexed in participants with advanced or metastatic cancer, Part D dose expansion of the study will evaluate the safety and toxicity of prexasertib at the recommended dose level in combination with fluorouracil (5-FU) in participants with advanced or metastatic cancer and Part E dose expansion of the study will evaluate the safety and toxicity of prexasertib at the recommended dose level in combination with LY3023414 in participants with advanced or metastatic cancer. In Parts A and B the effect of adding granulocyte colony stimulating factor (G-CSF) to cisplatin in combination with prexasertib and cetuximab in combination with prexasertib will be explored. In Part A the effect of changing the schedule of prexasertib and cisplatin also will be explored.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cetuximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pemetrexed</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Must be appropriate candidate for experimental therapy, as determined by investigator, after available standard therapies have failed Have adequate organ function Prior Therapies: Systemic treatments: must have discontinued previous systemic treatments for cancer and recovered from the acute effects of therapy. Participants must have discontinued mitomycinC or nitrosourea therapy at least 42 days and have discontinued any cytotoxic therapies at least 28 days prior to study enrollment. Radiation therapy and surgery: must be completed at least 4 weeks before study enrollment All parts except Part B dose expansion: Must have diagnosis of cancer that is advanced or metastatic Part B dose expansion: Must have confirmed Kirsten rat sarcoma viral oncogene homolog (KRAS) wildtype colorectal cancer that is metastatic or recurrent and has failed oxaliplatin and irinotecanbased chemotherapy or who are intolerant of irinotecan or oxaliplatin Must be available during the duration of the study and willing to follow the study procedures If participant is of reproductive potential, must agree to use medically approved contraceptive precautions during the study and for three months following the last dose of study drug If the participant is a female of childbearing potential, must have had a negative serum or urine pregnancy test within 14 days of the first dose of study drug and must not be breast feeding Part E: Are able to swallow capsules or tablets Have received more than 2 previous lines of cytotoxic chemotherapy (if receiving cisplatin or pemetrexed) Must not have taken an unapproved drug as treatment for any indication within the last 28 days prior to starting study treatment Must not have an active symptomatic fungal, bacterial or viral infection, including human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or Hepatitis A, B, or C Must not have a serious heart condition, such as congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, or heart attack within the last three months Must not have a family history of long QTc syndrome Must not have a serotoninsecreting carcinoid tumor or a prior history of druginduced serotonin syndrome Must not have acute leukemia Part E: Have insulindependent (type I) diabetes or a history of gestational diabetes Part E: Prior treatment with a PI3K/mTOR inhibitor</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>cancer</keyword>
</DOC>