<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02124785</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the long-term persistence of immunity to hepatitis A in adults who were vaccinated 21-25 years earlier with hepatitis A vaccine, Havrix®.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Long-term Persistence of Hepatitis A Antibodies in Healthy Adults Who Were Vaccinated 21-25 Years Earlier With GlaxoSmithKline (GSK) Biologicals' Hepatitis A Vaccine, Havrix®</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a long-term persistence study in which subjects who participated in the primary studies HAV-112 (208109/108) or HAV-123 (208109/114) and did not receive an additional dose of hepatitis A vaccine since then, will be invited to provide a blood sample at Years 21 to 25 after their second vaccine dose. No vaccine will be administered during the study period.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<criteria>A male or female who received two doses of Havrix in study HAV112 (208109/108) or HAV123 (208109/114), and received no further booster dose since then. Subjects who, in the opinion of the investigator, can and will comply with the requirements of the protocol (e.g. return for followup visits). Written informed consent obtained from the subject. History of hepatitis A disease since completion of the primary vaccination series in studies HAV112 (208109/108) or HAV123 (208109/114). Administration of a hepatitis A vaccine at any time since completion of the primary vaccination series in studies HAV112 (208109/108) or HAV123 (208109/114) including a challenge dose of the study vaccine, as a part of the study procedures, during the longterm persistence phase. Any confirmed or suspected immunosuppressive or immunodeficient condition, based on medical history. Administration of hepatitis A immunoglobulins and/or any blood products and/or longacting immunemodifying drugs within six months prior to study entry. Chronic administration of immunosuppressants or other immunemodifying drugs within six months prior to study entry. For corticosteroids, this will mean prednisone ≥ 20 mg/day, or equivalent. Inhaled and topical steroids are allowed. Administration of longacting immunemodifying drugs within six months prior to study entry (e.g. infliximab). Concurrently participating in another clinical study during the period starting 30 days before and ending 30 days after each study visit, in which the subject has been or will be exposed to an investigational or a noninvestigational vaccine/product (pharmaceutical product or device).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Long-term persistence</keyword>
	<keyword>Havrix</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatitis A</keyword>
</DOC>