<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02560584</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate if blue light cystoscopy with Cysview improves detection of tumors in patients with bladder cancer during surveillance cystoscopy, using the KARL STORZ D-Light C PDD Flexible Videoscope System. Another purpose is to investigate if Cysview and blue light is safe and effective when used repeatedly.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Blue Light Flexible Cystoscopy With Cysview in the Detection of Bladder Cancer in the Surveillance Setting</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aminolevulinic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients with bladder cancer in followup for tumor recurrence (Note: Patients must be included only at the first surveillance cystoscopy after a histologically confirmed tumor. The histologically confirmed tumor could either be from a TURB or from a surveillance cystoscopy where a biopsy was taken and a tumor was confirmed by histology) 2. History of one or more of the following: Multiple tumors Recurrent tumors High grade tumor(s) 1. Gross haematuria. (Note: Gross haematuria is defined as a heavy bladder bleed resulting in significant amounts of blood in the urine, which may visually limit cystoscopy. Where the haematuria is light, the patient should not be excluded, if in the investigator's opinion, rinsing and/or electrocautery during cystoscopy will alleviate the haematuria limitations to cystoscopy) 2. Patients who cannot undergo inoffice or operating room cystoscopy (Note: Training patients are eligible even if they cannot undergo operating room cystoscopy) 3. Patients who have received Bacillus CalmetteGuérin (BCG) immunotherapy or intravesical chemotherapy within the past 6 weeks prior to the procedure 4. Porphyria 5. Known allergy to hexaminolevulinate hydrochloride or a similar compound 6. Pregnancy or breastfeeding (all women of childbearing potential must document a negative urine pregnancy test before study inclusion and use adequate contraception during the study 7. Participation in other clinical studies with investigational drugs either concurrently or within the last 30 days 8. Patient is the investigator or any sub investigator, research assistant, pharmacist, study coordinator, other staff or relative thereof directly involved in the conduct of the protocol 9. Patients that the investigator believes are unlikely to comply with the protocol, e.g. mental condition rendering the patient unable to understand the nature, scope, and possible consequences of participating in the clinical study, uncooperative attitude or unlikelihood of completing the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Non-muscle invasive bladder cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>NMIBC</keyword>
	<keyword>Cysview</keyword>
</DOC>